Chapter 1

This could more accurately be described as a prologue. It's a bit grim, as you can probably guess from the story description, but essential to set things up.

Author’s Notes: The plot for this story came to me while I was working on another story — I started working on it so it would leave me alone. Kokopelli says that I don’t really need a disclaimer, as this story is non-profit writing exercise under the Fair Use Doctrine. If you recognize something in this story, it’s probably the property of J.K. Rowling and her licensees. Stuff you don’t recognize is mine.

Chapter 2

You didn't really think the story would end with that, did you?

Chapter 3

No notes

Chapter 4

Yes, the title of this chapter is a nod toward Kokopelli, who has been pulling yeoman duty polishing up my grammar and occasional Americanism. (Though I could swear I heard the word 'gotten' used during a Monty Python skit...)

Chapter 5

The ripples are starting to spread, and some things change for the worse...

Chapter 6

No notes

Chapter 7

Any questions and announcements will also be addressed on my blog, Viridian Dreams. The URL is in my author profile.

-Matthew

Chapter 8

This marks the end of Year One, as defined by the events of Harry Potter and the Sorceror/Philosopher’s Stone. If you have questions, or want to join in on the discussions regarding this story, my other fanfics, or my original fiction, please visit my blog, Viridian Dreams. The URL is in my author profile.

Chapter 9

If you have questions about the story or the NFP universe, feel free to visit my blog, Viridian Dreams, linked in my profile. I’m also distributing some of my original fiction to group members, starting with the novel Viridian Awakening.

I’d also like to take a moment to thank my Pre-Beta Runsamok, and my Final-Beta, Kokopelli. The final product would be much less polished without their efforts.

Stay tuned for the next chapter of Nightmares of Futures Past — wherein Harry makes a grave miscalculation and pays a heavy price.

-Matthew

Chapter 10

Insert author’s note here — sing the praises of the venerable Kokopelli and include a pay-pal address for contributing to the buy-the-beta-a-better-laptop-fund — or to pay for his next weekend away with Mrs Kokopelli, whichever comes first.

The Real Author Notes:

Unfortunately, I don’t have Kokopelli’s paypal address, so I was unable to comply with my Beta’s instructions. I’m a bad author.

The original release of this chapter introduced a bit of controversy. Yes, Harry could have and should have stopped Vernon in his tracks. He miscalculated, quite badly, and is paying for his desire to avoid diverging the timelines too much. An easy win against Quirrel made him over-dependent on his foreknowledge, and this is one change that caught him completely off guard. Keep reading to get some hints as to why…

Chapter 11

These last two chapters raised a few eyebrows, and led to some gruesome threats when they were first published. I address some of the concerns raised below, if anyone is interested…

Anyway, it should be clear now that Harry did, in fact, badly misread the situation. He has four main worries, and Voldemort is not the most immediate of those. In no particular order, they are:

·               One, making sure he doesn’t blow his cover.

·               Two, helping his friends realize their potential and are ready for what is to come.

·               Three, figuring out how to neutralize Voldemort before he kills everyone

·               Four, not disrupting the sequence of events so much that his foreknowledge becomes useless.

Number four is becoming a lost cause, and Harry is finally starting to realize it. He repeated his reasons to himself as he left the Knight Bus, but now he knows that even the subtle changes (like complaining to Dumbledore, though he doesn’t know it yet, and punching out Malfoy) have spawned their own consequences and his foreknowledge has already been compromised. He’s going to have to start figuring things out for himself more and rely on his memories less. If you had a choice between working to solve problems on a test or using the answer key, which would you prefer?   Harry just got caught out when somebody changed the questions.

The Dursleys cannot be described in any way other than abusive, even though JKR doesn’t focus much on that in the books. Petunia’s frying pan swing at Harry’s head is called "assault with a deadly weapon" at best and "attempted murder" where I come from. Either one involving a minor results in all kinds of people coming to pay you a visit. Withholding food as a punishment for misbehavior (one cup of soup in two days) went out with Oliver Twist.

And yes, I hate Vernon too. And technically, I’ve already killed him once in this story.

Like I said, I sort of expected chapter ten to raise some eyebrows. People don’t like it when heroes do stupid things, even if there are reasons. But merged-Harry isn’t infallible, and it would probably be a *really* boring story if he was, eh?

-Matthew

Chapter 12

<< Insert high praise for the Venerable Kokopelli here, then random blathering about the story, along with a pitch for the Yahoo discussion group.>>

Okay, John! ‘Kokopelli = cool’, everyone understand? And my yahoo group, Viridian Dreams, is also highly entertaining… not to mention the only means by which you can get a chance to review the first original novel I ever (badly) wrote.

Random story blather as follows:

A bit of fluff, a stirring of plot, and a pinch of character development. *sniff* Smells like another update brewing.

Before you ask, no Harry is not even close to done with the Dursleys. Revenge is a dish best served cold, not microwaved like fast food.

If you’re curious, Stanhope is actually describing Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder.

Chapter 13

Harry doesn’t know what form Fate really is taking. Does it exist? Is it a presence, or more of an impersonal force? Of course, that just means Harry is asking the same questions that started with the ancient Greek dudes.

I’m not always a huge fan of "Hollywood Endings" — which is one reason I like anime. On the other hand I’m not an angst-junkie either. Which means I’ve pretty much told you nothing about how all this will end…

For faster response to questions — feel free to visit my blog, Viridian Dreams and post there. I check it often.

-Matthew

Chapter 14

Disclaimer?   We don’t need no stinkin’ disclaimer, and if we did, we already did it back in Chapter 1.

Yes, I know JKR said that Ollivander only makes wands with Dragon Heartstring, Unicorn Hair, or Phoenix Feather cores. Given the rarity of Phoenixes, and the number of combinations involved, it seems rather limited in terms of ‘every wizard needs to find the wand that fits them’. Two or Three, multiplied by a couple dozen varieties of wood, would hardly fill a shop. It wouldn’t be the first time that the numbers don’t seem to support the story.

However, if we posit the existence of other wandmakers, each making their foci using the available local ingredients, we return to the idea of the wand choosing the wizard, and Ollivander having a sufficiently varied inventory. All the various wandmakers do is ship their products to each other, for money or barter, to ensure that each member can always find something in their shop for that hard-to-suit eleven year old.

Chapter 15

No notes

Chapter 16

Beta’s Author Notes:   Still looking for the disclaimer here?   Nope, still not here, try Chapter 1.

Real Author’s Note: A bit of tension, a bit of future sadness, and now — a bit of fluff. Enjoy!

Chapter 17

Insert stock beta comment — Disclaimer is in chapter one.

Space for mundane author muttering — Well, I’m finally getting into Chamber of Secrets territory for real now. Hope you enjoyed taking a look through Ginny’s eyes as well.

If you have questions or issues with the plot you’d like to debate (is Harry too vindictive with the Dursleys, or too hard on Dumbledore? Etc…) outside the reviews, please visit my blog, Viridian Dreams. Link is in my profile.

Chapter 18

My Beta says that 17 USC 107 means never having to issue a disclaimer when I’m not getting paid for the writing — so there!

This is the end of the summer, next chapter starts with the trip back to Hoggy Warty Hogwarts!

Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 19

Hmmm… over ten thousand words to cover two days. But a lot did happen.

In case anyone was wondering, I’m not a Gilderoy Lockhart fan.

 Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 20

Yes, I’m having fun with Luna… as I’m sure you all noticed.

I’m offering one (1) original character for the person who recognizes the homage I paid with Neville and Luna in this chapter.

Plot discussions and Q&A will be addressed on my blog, Viridian Dreams, see my author profile for the link.

Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 21

Still no disclaimer — if you’ve read this far, you know why.

Plot discussions and individual Q&A will be addressed on my blog, Viridian Dreams, see my author profile for the link. A lot of interesting discussions are taking place there as well.

Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 22

Plot discussions and individual Q&A will be addressed on my blog, Viridian Dreams. A lot of interesting discussions are taking place there as well.

Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 23

Plot discussions and individual Q&A will be addressed on my blog, Viridian Dreams. A lot of interesting discussions are taking place there as well.

Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 24

As discussed in my previous author notes, I am now working full time and my update pace has taken a serious hit. 50-55 hours a week I was spending on writing and editing are now being spent as a spreadsheet jockey and on my unpleasantly long commute.

Plot discussions and individual Q&A will be addressed on my blog, Viridian Dreams. A lot of interesting discussions are taking place there as well, as well as some looks at my original fiction.

Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 25

As discussed in my previous author notes, I am now working full time and my update pace has taken a serious hit. 50-55 hours a week I was spending on writing and editing are now being spent as a spreadsheet jockey and on my unpleasantly long commute.

That said, well thought out reviews do encourage me to devote more of what little time remains to writing. I find it a little curious that my Naruto story, Team 8, averages well over two hundred reviews per update, significantly more than NFP, despite the fact that more people read this story

Plot discussions and individual Q&A will be addressed on my blog, Viridian Dreams. A lot of interesting discussions are taking place there.

Thanks for reading!

-Matthew

Chapter 26

Yes, it’s a cliffhanger. Second year is heating up a bit as the law of unintended consequences smacks Harry in the head. Or is that a broken neck?

In any event, I’d like to thank my betas, Runsamok, Kokopelli, and Malkin for their work in helping polish this up.

As stated before, my writing time is a bit curtailed. I’ve made a start on the next chapter of Team 8, but this one was flowing better — so I invest my time in whatever seems to be the most productive venue at the moment.

Questions, answers, speculation, and progress reports can be found on my blog, Viridian Dreams.

Enjoy and thanks for reading!

Chapter 27

Well, that is the climax for year two. A lot of loose ends are wrapped up, and the original timeline is, shall we say, toast?

There will be another chapter to wrap up Harry’s second year. (You didn’t think I’d skip the Quidditch Championship, did you?). I was originally planning to do it all in 27, but this is already the longest chapter in Harry Potter and the Nightmares of Futures Past.

The ride will continue in Year 3: Harry Potter and the Dementors of Azkaban. (Yes, this will be the first year to have a different title.)

Before we go, I’d like to thank my Betas, Runsamok, Kokopelli, the illustrious Kokopelli (beta correction) and Malkin. Without them, this would be messier, and no doubt read like it was written by one of those nasty Yanks. =)

Chapter 28

This marks the end of Year 2.

The next chapter begins the Harry Potter and the Dementors of Azkaban story arc.

Yes, I know that first and second year students don’t normally know stunning spells. That’s one thing that the DA training is covering, for obvious reasons.

Many thanks to my Betas: Runsamok and Kokopelli.

Chapter 29

Welcome to Year 3: The Dementors of Azkaban.

Many thanks to my Betas, the comely Runsamok and the brilliant, if twisted Kokopelli! (Funny how my author notes seem to get edited, isn’t it?)

Sorry for the delays, my home computer was in the shop for a couple of weeks, and it’s the one I do ninety-five percent of my writing on.

I was tempted to end the chapter after the scene with Hermione and Neville dying, but I really would get tired of the death threats I’d receive if I did that. *grin*

Yes, reviews inspire me to write more often and for longer, and the â€˜meatier’ the better. What did you like or dislike? What made you laugh out loud or gasp (if anything).

A couple of issues seem to pop up every so often that I will address:

Maturity level of the students: First, keep in mind that Wizarding children are born into a society where they are given access to deadly weapons at the age of eleven. Also, despite Wizarding life-spans, James and Lily getting married right after graduating from Hogwarts was not seen as anything unusual. Those two facts highlight that (well-adjusted) children grow up rather quickly in the Wizarding world.

Second, Harry acts more mature than his apparent age for obvious reasons. When you have a group of children when one member acts much more mature than the others, one of two things will happen. The outlier will regress to match the cohort, or the cohort will progress to meet the higher standard of behaviour. When the abnormally mature outlier is also the social dominant of that group, the second outcome becomes far more likely. This is why you see Ron and the others act more mature the longer he’s been friends with Harry. (With the occasional backsliding, of course.)

Romance/shipping: Yes, I am aware of the ages of the characters. Keep in mind the points raised above regarding Wizarding society, but relax for now. Harry hasn’t even definitely finished going through puberty yet. (He notices Cho Chang is pretty during the match in his third year, and that’s the first strong indicator of interest from canon-Harry. It also surprised him a bit.) So, while some characters are very aware of other characters, they haven’t forgotten what age they are either.

Well, maybe in Luna’s case, but she’s a little odd.

For most of them, call it "good friend for now, let’s wait and see what happens later on."

And of course, that doesn’t mean that other parties might not make assumptions…

Chapter 30

Welcome to Year 3: The Dementors of Azkaban.

Many thanks to my witty, diligent, and very personable Betas: Runsamok, Kokopelli, and Sherylyn!

If you have any questions about this, or any of my other stories, you can check out my blog, Viridian Dreams.

Once the training schedule has been set up, I’m not going to spend tremendous amounts of time detailing every topic covered. Rest assured that, among other things, they are getting a lot of practice with their wands. This will build up their accuracy and timing, as well as speeding increases in their magical power. This is a natural extension of the morning training they’ve been all been doing since the beginning of last term (or longer in some cases).

Note: When a dog has been running at top speed for extended periods of time, it will get little bits of foam around its muzzle. Sirius is not rabid.

Chapter 31

Welcome to Year 3: The Dementors of Azkaban.

Many thanks to my Betas: the comely Runsamok, the brilliant, but twisted Kokopelli, and the ultimate Beta: Sherylyn! (Note to self: Stop letting Kokopelli edit the Author’s Notes.)

If you have any questions about this, or any of my other stories, you can check out my yahoo group, Viridian Dreams. (The link is in my profile.)

I’ve also started a blog to show progress on the current chapters. The link for that is available in my profile.

A personal note to a thankfully small portion of my readers:

Positive, thoughtful reviews encourage me to continue the story and work on the next update. Obscene, threatening, and insulting messages, emails and reviews from readers angry at me because I don’t update faster have the opposite effect.

When you are paying my salary, you will have the right to impose deadlines… and not until then.

-Matthew

Chapter 32

Yes, it’s been a while. This story isn’t going away, but factors in the story, as well as outside situations have been holding it up a bit. I’m trying not to release any chapters smaller than 10,000 words, so it’s been a while. (My beta had a better idea for where to end this one, so I have a head start on chapter 33.) My blog has the progress meters for the chapters I’m currently working on, so you can check that if you are curious. The link is in my profile.

Regarding this chapter, I’ve been working on the pacing a bit. This chapter spans the time covered by chapters 4, 5, 6, & 7 of the Prisoner of Azkaban, with some groundwork laying, character development, and bit o’ magical action. Bit of a oops at the end there, eh?

And yes, I know magical trunks are a bit of a cliche, but really… Harry saw it used in book 4, he has a need for one and a lot of money… it would be stupid of him to ignore their existence, wouldn’t it? Sometimes a plot device becomes overused and cliched simply because it makes sense. Hermione hitting the books to research a solution to a problem is just as much a cliche, isn’t it?

Chapter 33

Here’s the latest chapter. As always, a big thank you to my Betas: Runsamok, Kokopelli, and Siriusseeker!

On a side note: Some people have sent me objections regarding the presence of the American Expeditionary Force in the prologue. I’m sorry, but while I do live in the States, regarding their presence as some sort of jingoistic ethnocentrism displays an appalling ignorance of history. Or, to put it more poetically:

"The British PM was somewhat trapped, somewhat unpleasantly because of the surprise factor, but the substance of the trap was that Britain and America always supported each other. The "special relationship" was as alive and well today as it had been under the governments of Franklin Roosevelt and Winston Churchill. It was one of the few constants in the diplomatic world for both countries, and it belied Kissinger’s dictum that great nations didn’t have friendships, but rather interests. Perhaps it was the exception proving the rule, but if so, exception it was." —Tom Clancy, The Bear and the Dragon.

The only countries as likely to intervene as quickly would be other members of the Commonwealth. However, either due to philosophical issues or population density, none of those Muggle governments maintain as large a standing military. While the Canadian and Austrailian Magical Governments may have engaged in their own relief efforts, the American equivalent of the Ministry is the most likely to field a large contingent of Wizarding troops. That’s not to say there might be some Canadians, or Australians, or other troops somewhere in future-Britain, but the Americans were who Harry and Ron ran into. Besides, it let me pattern Hastings after some people I knew…

And on another note, why do people ask me pointed questions in an anonymous review? If you don’t sign in and don’t leave an email address, that’s pretty useless, isn’t it?

Finally, if you want to know the progress on the next chapter, or to see excerpts and previews of coming chapters, please visit my blog, the address for which is posted in my profile. That’s the first place I update, so checking there is a lot faster than sending me an email or private message.

Chapter 34

It’s been a while; for some reason the conversation in Dumbledore’s office wasn’t cooperating. DH is out, but it’s not going to be as hard to incorporate the new canon as I feared. The AU divergence point will be Voldemort’s decision to make the Hat a Horcrux right under Dumbledore’s nose. That means he had one more Horcrux when he went after the Potters, and his soul was even less stable.

In the first timeline, Voldemort discovered Snape’s treachery, earning the spy a shallow, unmarked grave. The Dark Lord’s even more tattered soul made him more violent and vicious, so he went for a more destructive conquest than was seen in Deathly Hallows.

In the first timeline, Harry was unaware of the Horcrux within himself, but during that final Legilimency barrage, the fragment was expelled through the link between himself and Voldemort. It briefly re-united with Voldemort’s soul as he was experiencing a hint of regret as his mind was destroyed… just in time for the Blasting Curse that marked the beginning of the prologue.

In the new timeline, the arrival of Future-Harry’s soul, replete with memories of Occlumency training and a burning hatred of Voldemort, annihilated the accidental Horcrux, even as the two souls began to merge. I’m here to write an action/adventure story, not a passion play.

If you want to debate other elements of the new canon, we’ve been doing that on the Viridian Dreams blog. (I’d rather do it there than in reviews and review replies.)

And as always, many thanks to my betas: the comely Runsamok, the somewhat scarce Kokopelli, and the always final Sherylyn.

Chapter 35

And so we come to the end of another chapter. Tensions are rising in the Wizarding World and people are starting to point fingers. Harry has a plan, but as we’ve seen before, his plans don’t always go right.

Many thanks go out to Runsamok, Kokopelli, and SiriusSeeker for excellent beta work. Any mistakes in the final version are despite their heroic efforts to keep me on the straight and narrow.

And now a few polite suggestions for select portions of my readership:

Please realize that at least four pairs of eyes have gone over every new chapter before you see it. If you think you see a glaring canon error, you might want to double-check before bringing it up in a review visible on a public forum. Periodically some well-meaning soul ends up embarrassing themselves. Don’t let this be you.

My blog (the address is in my profile) has the latest information and updates on chapter progress. I do not respond to private emails that say "when is the next chapter going to be ready?" with anything more than the URL. I’m paying those hosting fees for a reason, folks. *grin*

A few people have remarked that they don’t like how merged-Harry reacts to things in this story. I’ll let you in on a secret: At times, I don’t either. No one could have gone through all the things that occurred in the future timeline and emerged unscathed. Harry has some serious issues to work through. Yes, he escalated things with Draco and Snape a lot faster than he needed to. That’s because he never knew that Snape was working for Dumbledore (the portrait kept the promises made in life) and Voldemort discovered Snape’s treachery and killed them both for it. I’d actually left it open to go either way before Deathly Hollows was released — you can check old Author Notes where this is discussed.

So yeah, Harry’s reasoning can be flawed and his reactions can be overly emotional. Despite everything, he still has some growing up to do. But aren’t perfect heroes kind of boring after a while?

Chapter 36

Time moves on, and while Harry is making plans and forming tentative alliances, he has no real idea of the forces moving to oppose him. *cues sinister laughter*

For some reason the argument between the adults was difficult to write. There were no right or wrong parties there, so it was important to keep it balanced, both in my head and on paper.

Thanks as always go out to Runsamok, Kokopelli, and Sherylyn for wonderful beta work. Going back and fixing minor errors, the majority of which were in the very early chapters, has only emphasized how much my betas have contributed to what could otherwise become a completely unwieldy task. I’ll post the revised chapters when I’m fairly sure I’ve swatted all the bugs.

As always, there are news and progress updates available on the Viridian Dreams blog - the address is displayed in my profile, along with our new forums (there’s already a discussion thread set up for this chapter). Runsamok and I were recently interviewed about this story on the PotterFicWeekly podcast, and I’ll have a link to it posted on my blog when it goes live.

Chapter 37

And with the end of the year comes the end of the chapter. Many thanks to Runsamok, Kokopelli, and Sherylyn, the betas that make this readable.

I’d also like to thank the people on the Viridian Dreams forums for commentary and encouragement. If you have questions regarding this or any of my other stories, you can get a lot of answers there, as well as preview new stuff before it is released. My blog also displays progress bars for whichever chapters I’m currently working on.

Chapter 38

Many thanks to Runsamok, Kokopelli, and Sherylyn for awesome beta work.

As you can no doubt guess, the new job has sharply curtailed my writing time, but I’m still at it. You can find a progress bar for the latest chapter I’m working on at the Viridian Dreams website, as well as multiple tangential discussions on the forums.

I hope everyone has a happy and joyous holiday season.

Chapter 39

A little short, but with a bit of excitement to cap off Year Three. As you can tell, this chapter fought harder than most, and I had some other issues limiting my productivity. Kudos to both Runsamok and Kokopelli for putting up with me and my irregular spelling!

Before anyone asks — no, this story is not abandoned. If had abandoned it, I would at the very least post my outline and all the snippets I've already worked out. (They currently reside at the bottom of my working file for easy reference.)

Also, there are no real-world political statements being made in the chapter. I have both English and Irish ancestors. Peter and his master are merely taking advantage of the situation, and those were the closest Muggles that met their criterion. If you don't think someone under the Imperius Curse would actively work to help formulate a cover story to fool their mates, I would only point out how that same curse was used on Pius Thicknesse in canon to subvert the Ministry of Magic — he was actively participating in the new regime as well. In the long run, I think that Unforgiveable has the scariest implications if used intelligently.

Any questions you might have will probably get the quickest answers on the Viridian Dreams forums.

Chapter 40

Yes, I am back on a semi-regular writing schedule again. An up-side to down-sizing? I’d like to thank Runsamok, Tempest, and Torbin for alpha-reads, and the illustrious Kokopelli for his beta-work! Some embarrassingly mis-used Brit-slang was avoided thanks to their efforts. I’d also like to thank the person who was cameo-ed in this chapter. Given what has been going on lately, your timing was simply amazing!

I’m off to work on Team 8 now. Yes, you could consider this a cliffhanger… but not when you think about it. Enjoy!

Chapter 41

Hello, back again with another update to Year 4 of NoFP… Yes, I am bringing in one of the most detested characters in the Potterverse, and I’m doing it early!

I’d like to thank Runsamok, Tempest, and Torbin for alpha-reads, and the ever-awesome consistently outstanding Kokopelli for his beta work.

In other news, I’m posting some of my original fiction on Patreon.

Chapter 42

Well now, history repeating itself. Fancy that.

As always, many kudos to Runsamok and Kokopelli for awesome beta work. Any delays in the production of this chapter rest solely on my shoulders (or rather my gimpy foot). I’d also like to thank my awesome Patreon supporters for helping make this continuation happen. They are also reading my original novel, Rhiyen’s Deal (which they helped rename). I’m listed on Patreon as Viridian Dreams. There’s even a real life picture of my face, so be warned…

As always, any questions can be addressed best on the Viridian Dreams forums because for every question you have, I bet ten fellow readers are asking the same thing. So feel free to register, wave hello to the captcha as it snares spam-bots, and say hello!

Chapter 43

No notes

1

Prologue: The End of Days

Harry Potter, thirty years old and the last surviving member of the Order of the Phoenix, blinked his eyes rapidly, trying to restore his vision. His ears still rang from the explosion and being half-blinded left him close to helpless. He dashed the tears from his eyes, ignoring the debris that rained down around him. I have to see this, he thought, I’ve spent so long… I have to do this. He squinted, holding up a shaking hand to shield his face.

Gobbets of flesh, drops of blood, bits of gravel rained down, but the deluge eventually trailed off. Before him was a smoking crater, almost twenty feet across. Harry’s breath hitched painfully in his lungs. Is it finally over? He blinked rapidly again when he saw a twisted mass of half-melted steel embedded in the lip of the crater. The sword of Gryffindor was no more, its purpose finally ended along with the line of Salazar Slytherin. Harry mourned the vague awareness he could sense in the blade.

Whatever bit of Godric he left of himself in the sword is probably happier now, Harry mused; it’s served its purpose, so it can move on to the next great adventure, as Albus used to say.

“I suppose it’s my turn now,” Harry said aloud. With one last glance at his final battlefield, he Disapparated.

Harry appeared in the ruined Great Hall. The steady drip of water from the shattered ceiling beat a quiet tattoo on the cracked flagstones. It seemed to rain constantly these days and Harry wondered if it was a consequence of the battle that had been fought here. If the heavens wanted to weep over what had happened here so many years ago, who was he to disagree?

Still, the patter of droplets on stone was soothing in its own way. Any balm for his grief was welcome indeed. The rage was gone, burned out in the apocalyptic fury that ended the war, and now Harry was left feeling hollow and cold… like a burned out building after the flames had died. Like Twelve Grimmauld Place.

The gaunt man in his tattered and blood-stained robes sank to his knees on the wet stone floor. Memories of happier times in this place overwhelmed him and he wept bitterly until darkness claimed him.

Harry awoke cold, wet, and shivering. He slowly rose to his feet, trying to massage feeling back into his fingers. That was stupid, he thought as old scars and badly-mended fractures began to all throb in time with his pulse. I’m not in my bloody twenties anymore. I’m going to be sore all day, if someone ambushes—

He cut that thought off. The war was over. He’d finally killed that bastard. If he’d had any Death Eaters left, Tom would have had them with him at the end, hoping for some advantage. Even if some had fled the conflict, Harry remembered what Hermione told him about her examinations of the Dark Mark, a corruption of the ancient Protean Charm. With the final death of the bearer of the Master Mark, everyone else that carried the mark would eventually perish as well. Harry imagined that little surprise was kept from the Death Eaters though.

Harry took in a deep breath and let it out. It was over, and he could finally relax. He looked up, past the shattered stone vaults, at the storm clouds brewing overhead. The war was over, but the price had been far, far too high. He felt his hands curl into fists, the ragged nails digging into his palms. Too many…

The rubble around him began to shift, smaller pieces tumbling down, the haphazard piles of stone left from the cleanup settling. The ministry had barely been organized enough to send Aurors out to retrieve the bodies; they never had a chance to even discuss rebuilding before they were gone as well.

Harry swallowed, ruthlessly forcing his magic back down. A small corner of his mind wanted to set it loose, let it rage out of control, even if it brought the remaining walls down on his head. I need to let Albus know, he thought to himself, desperate for any distraction at this point.

He still remembered the way to the headmaster’s office, and barely noticed when he had to detour around collapsed stonework or jump over a crack in the floor. When he reached the half-melted gargoyle, he laid his hand on its distorted face and whispered, “The end of days.” The charm he had replaced on the statue caused it to swing aside with a grumble of stone on stone. Harry slowly ascended the stairs.

The headmaster’s office still looked like a disaster area. The stone walls were black with scorch marks and the furnishings were little more than ashes. Harry remembered Hermione wincing when she first saw that the priceless tomes had been reduced to char. Of course they had all been numb by that point, but that reaction was the kind of thing Ron and he had kidded her about since they were first years. That memory brought it all back to him again, and bile flooded the back of his throat as other thoughts rose unbidden.

“Harry?” The headmaster’s voice brought him out of it. He nodded gratefully. “I’m back, Albus.”

The face in the portrait smiled, but the eyebrows were knitted above eyes that hadn’t twinkled in years. The corner where Dumbledore’s picture hung was the only area that had been spared the flames. Tom Riddle had cast a shield to protect the magical portrait when he came here thirteen years ago. He’d wanted to talk to the only remaining vestige of his former teacher, to gloat over how they’d never detected the horcrux embedded in the Sorting Hat, the piece of his soul shrouded by the magical intelligence created by Godric Gryffindor.

“Was your plan a success?”

Harry nodded slowly, struggling against his memories. When the silent alarm charm placed on Helga Hufflepuff’s cup was triggered, Voldemort quickly checked on the hiding places of the other pieces. When he found most of them missing, he massed his forces and stormed Hogwarts to retrieve the piece hidden in the headmaster’s office. While Harry, Ron, and Hermione had been quietly searching Little Hangleton, their school was sacked and burned. Their first warning came at the end, when Voldemort’s joy and relief burst through Harry’s Occlumency shields like they weren’t even there… and by then it was too late.

There were so few survivors of the Hogwarts Massacre that most of what they knew was based upon the positions of the bodies and what little the ghosts could tell them. Neville Longbottom, who took over leadership of the DA when Harry and his friends left, had led the students out into the courtyard to help the teachers defend the school. From the number of slain Death Eaters, they appeared to have held their own. Finally Voldemort himself stepped in, and brought down the outer walls with horrifically powerful blasting curses, and the resistance quickly collapsed.

When Harry regained consciousness and the three of them Apparated to Hogsmeade, it was already over. He barely recalled their breathless terrified run to the smoking castle. Villagers were already picking through the ruins, desperate to find any survivors. They found Luna next to Neville in the centre of the courtyard. Their eyes were wide open and glassy, signs of the killing curse. Amongst the black-robed bodies in front of them was a familiar face. Harry stopped and stared at Bellatrix Lestrange, her mask thrown aside in her death agonies and most of her ribcage reduced to a red ruin. He hoped Neville realized before his end that he’d gotten the woman who’d tortured his parents to insanity.

He lingered there, not wanting to leave. There was another body he needed to look for, one he dreaded finding. As long as he didn’t see it, as long as he didn’t know for sure, he could maintain a little hope. Ron’s strangled cry turned his blood to ice, but he couldn’t let his friend face this alone.

Ron was on his knees in one corner of the courtyard, Hermione kneeling next to him holding his shoulders. Harry felt his feet moving, but he’d remember how long it took to walk that distance for the next thirteen years. His eyes were locked on the ground in front of his feet. As long as he didn’t look up, as long as he didn’t acknowledge it, there was a chance, a hope… Harry stopped next to Ron and looked up.

Ginevra Molly Weasley laid spread eagle on the ground. His eyes locked onto her face, ignoring the shredded robes, the bloody wounds, the signs that she had not died easily or quickly. Her face was pale, the spray of freckles across her nose vivid in the fading light… but she looked almost peaceful now, relaxed like she was only asleep. Harry had only gotten to see her sleep a few times. After they’d started dating in his sixth year, she’d once dozed off with her head in his lap while studying in the common room. The crease between her eyebrows flattened out, and her lips relaxed into a soft curve. He remembered staring at her for hours, his textbook forgotten, until she shifted and woke up embarrassed. He stared at the face of the girl he loved, knowing that she would never wake. No prince could kiss death away.

His next clear memory was sitting on a bed at The Burrow, staring at the end of his wand, knowing that it would only take two words to make it all end. Thinking about Ginny’s disgust with him if he let Tom win helped him put the wand down and go to sleep.

“Harry?” Dumbledore said softly.

Harry shook himself, pulling himself back from his memories. He wasn’t surprised to find himself sobbing. He found himself doing that more often this past year, since he’d started travelling alone. He hadn’t wanted to worry Hermione, and it made Ron uncomfortable, though in the end he understood better. He took another deep breath to steady his voice. “You were right; someone with the Americans was feeding him information. The plan worked.”

Since the collapse of the English Ministry, along with most of the European Ministries of Magic, the American Department of Magical Affairs deployed several divisions of their war-mages in an expeditionary force. Their commander was given orders to do whatever was necessary to ‘contain the situation’ and keep the Dark Lord East of the Atlantic. At first, the green troops were no match for the battle-hardened remnant of the Death Eaters. However, they learned quickly and were soon able to liberate the larger cities, though the cost was high. Diagon Alley was left a smoking ruin before the last Death Eater fell. The only thing the well-equipped Yanks couldn’t handle was Voldemort himself. Military-grade curses that should have turned him into charred meat either missed or had little to no effect. As the death toll mounted, Harry reluctantly made contact with Alexander Hastings, the American general, and explained the convoluted tale about his role in the war and the prophecy.

The Americans were helpful, and the relief they brought to his countrymen, Wizard and Muggle, was welcome – even if it came too late for most of the people Harry cared about. Unfortunately, as he continued to use the curse bond from his scar to search for Voldemort, his quarry had become more and more elusive. Their Occlumency and Legilimency duels were practically a nightly occurrence, almost always ending in a stalemate. Though Harry could get little more than glimpses of Voldemort’s surroundings, sometimes that was enough to make a guess about where he was located. The maddened wizard still struck, seemingly at random, but he always left before Harry could arrive. After raiding another of Voldemort’s bolt holes, which showed signs of having been vacated just minutes earlier, Harry and Albus began to wonder if there was a leak among the Americans.

The trap was crude, but effective. Harry, covered with blood and screaming in pain, Apparated into the American encampment. He talked deliriously, but quite loudly, about being injured by something in the dungeon of ruined Hogwarts. Once he was alone with the healer, he ruthlessly stunned the man and performed a memory charm. Harry had no idea who was giving information to Voldemort, so he wasn’t taking any chances.

The rest of the encampment was treated to a loud argument between the head medical officer and a very stubborn Harry Potter. The latter walked out of the infirmary with a large bandage wrapped around his head, and swatches of gauze showed through the rents in his filthy robes. While the medi-wizard lectured him about brain trauma and depleted magical reserves, Harry yelled back that he’d found out that something crucial to ending the war was located near his parents’ house in Godric’s Hollow, and nothing would stop him from retrieving it now.

Harry then Apparated to a location near Tom Riddle’s latest lair in Surrey. Ignoring his scar, Harry sent tendrils of Legilimency into the surrounding area. The gossamer thin wisps of mental energy detected the brooding malevolent intelligence that lurked within the townhouse. He sat quietly while the faint echo of smug superiority flared up and then completely disappeared. Harry quickly approached the now-empty building. The door was a solid mass of alarm and detection spells. Harry smiled grimly as he pulled out a set of picks. He remembered the long-dead twins showing him how to pick locks the Muggle way.

Harry found the Sorting Hat on a table in the basement. When he picked it up, the rip near the brim rippled. “You know what you need to do,” it whispered. There wasn’t time to try and unravel the hellishly complicated magics bound into the hat, and the school that was the focus of its existence was no more.

“I’m sorry,” he said as he carried the hat outside.

“Don’t be,” it said. The lips curved into what Harry swore looked like a smirk. “That was really a clever plan. I still say you would have done well in Slytherin.”

“Maybe so,” Harry agreed as he set the hat down and stepped back, raising his wand. “Thank you,” he whispered. Then he blasted the hat out of existence.

Tom was still tearing into the ruins of the house where Harry had been born when the anti-apparition barrier suddenly went up. “Ah, Potter,” he drawled as the filthy muggle-lover appeared before him, “I was worried you’d gotten splinched trying to get here.” His eyes travelled from the wand clenched in Harry’s fist to the bulky bandage wrapped around the younger man’s head.

“Sorry,” Harry growled, “I had to make a stop in Surrey to talk to an old friend.” His arm snapped up and he snarled “Reducto!”

Voldemort’s shield charm was cast with plenty of time, but the pillar of white light from Harry’s wand was blinding in its intensity. The curved wall of blue light fractured and Voldemort was forced back several steps. “You aren’t as enfeebled as I thought,” Voldemort sneered. “Good. I was hoping this wouldn’t be boring.”

Despite his tone, Harry could tell his foe was shaken by the destruction of the last Horcrux. He pressed his advantage, forcing the Dark Lord to stumble backward as he battered at his defences.

“It won’t do any good to kill me, you know,” Voldemort said as they crested a hill. “I’ve already won, I’ve killed everyone you care about, Harry. They all died for you, and there is nothing you can do to help them now.” He patted the Sword of Gryffindor on his belt. The Dark Lord couldn’t wield it, but it was a trophy from the Hogwarts Massacre.

Harry forced himself to intensify the rate of his attacks, even as the words tore at him. Ginny would want him to finish the bastard, no matter what it took. Thinking of her made his heart lurch just like it did thirteen years ago and he knew what he had to do. He finally got a cutting curse past the Dark Lord’s guard and tore away a good piece of his shoulder. Voldemort fell to one knee as his wand tumbled to the grass.

Harry shunted aside the pain of his own injuries and thought about all he had lost during the war, starting with his parents. He thought about his friends, his teachers. He thought about the Weasleys, who’d become the second family he’d lost. He thought of Ron and Hermione who’d been with him from the start almost to the end. He thought of Ginny and the dam broke. He dropped his Occlumency shields and sent everything he was feeling through the link he shared with Voldemort’s mind. The grass in front of him was lit with a green radiance that he knew was coming from his scar.

Voldemort screamed as the emotional torrent swept aside his defences and ripped through his mind. His black soul withered in the deluge of love and grief as ‘the power he knew not’ gave him agony that made Cruciatus feel like a soft caress. Harry wondered if Voldemort was already driven mad by the time he was able to raise his wand and cast the blasting charm. He supposed it didn’t really matter.

“Harry? Did the plan succeed?”

Harry blinked dully as the old headmaster’s voice finally penetrated. “Yeah, it did.”

“Then it is finally over,” the portrait said with relief.

“I guess,” Harry said quietly.

“I know, Harry, that we have suffered many grievous losses. Defending the light always exacts a high toll,” Dumbledore said sententiously. At one time, it would have driven Harry wild, but now he’d come to understand that it was how the old man dealt with his own grief. His excessive formality helped him keep his own ghosts at bay.

Harry tuned the old man out and conjured a chair. He slumped down and sat with his head in his hands, elbows braced on his knees.

“Harry, you have done a great thing.”

“Not really,” the man replied absently, his voice sounding hollow even to his own ears. It was finally over. The war was over. Too bad there was no one left to celebrate.

“I think you should rest,” the headmaster suggested, “things will look better when you’ve had some time to recuperate and gain some perspective on what happened.”

Harry slowly shook his head, but nonetheless slowly rose to his feet. He laid his hand on the wall next to the portrait and a section of wall slid inward and to the side.

The headmaster’s private quarters, adjacent to his office, were heavily warded and survived better than much of the remainder of the school. Professor McGonagall had not the heart to even touch the room during her short tenure as interim headmistress, and the fire had not even warmed the walls. The portrait told Harry and his friends how to open the door when they first explored the office to see what had survived.

Harry’s eyes grazed over the groaning bookshelves. Dumbledore’s private collection of restricted books was supplemented with everything that Hermione could salvage from the ruined library. Just thinking about her made Harry’s eyes prickle and he looked away. He quickly stripped off his robes and took a quick bath. By the time he was clean, his limbs were trembling with fatigue. He was asleep the moment his head hit the pillow.

Harry Potter slept without dreams for the first time in well over a decade.

Harry had developed the habit, through the years of constant struggle, of formulating a ‘to do’ list each night as he performed his Occlumency exercises and prepared to sleep. That way, when he woke up, he could immediately start working and stop thinking about his dreams. At first Hermione had admired his industriousness, though later she seemed to realize he was using it as a distraction. At least she learned to let him deal with his memories on his own, instead of always trying to get him to talk about what had happened. Ron just thought he was crazy for leaping out of bed and immediately setting to work. In their last year together, after Hermione died, Ron was doing the same thing.

Today, he awoke with a strange sense of lassitude. He tried frantically to recall his list before he remembered that he didn’t have one for today. Everything was done.

Finished.

Oh Bugger.

He stared up at the ceiling, willing himself not to think about the past. Should he leave the country? Europe wasn’t in much better shape. America was a possibility, but he knew there was little chance of being left alone. Enough word had filtered back with the fleeing refugees for them to understand who Harry Potter was. They might even try to lock him up or at least refuse him entry, reasoning that someone like him could be dangerous.

Besides, he’d spent the best years of his life in Scotland, and Hogwarts was the closest thing he could call to home. Of course, ‘home’ was a burned out hulk, but one couldn’t have everything. Harry’s train of thought was derailed by his stomach growling, reminding him that he hadn’t eaten anything since breakfast yesterday.

Sighing, he retrieved his wand from the night stand and conjured a simple breakfast of tea and toast. One could subsist a while on conjured food if you weren’t picky about nutrition. Or taste. After a while, one’s memories of what food really tasted like began to fade, and the examples produced from that memory became even more tasteless. Harry’s toast was remarkably similar in taste and texture to cardboard, but it quieted the growling of his stomach.

When he finished eating and stood up, Harry winced. He accumulated a fair number of nicks and scrapes during the previous day, and he was covered with dark blue bruises. From the deep ache in his chest and the fatigue that already weighed him down, he guessed he also had a pretty bad case of magical exhaustion as well. He made his way to the bookshelves and grabbed a couple of books at random, then settled back onto the bed to read. He also didn’t really want to talk to Dumbledore just yet.

The last four years had seen a dramatic change in Harry’s study habits. With Hermione gone, it had been up to him to research new spells and ways to stop Voldemort. Ron was an excellent strategist, but he was the less scholarly of the two. Also, the death of his common-law wife had left Ron a bit less able to concentrate than his equally grief-stricken best friend. Harry was only able to focus by conducting mental discussion about whatever he was reading with his bushy-haired friend. Just imagining her lecturing them about the latest thing he’d read had helped him keep it together. In some way it was his private tribute to the smartest witch he’d ever known.

On one particularly bad night in an abandoned inn, Ron angrily demanded to know why Harry was smiling as he read an old book they’d scavenged from Flourish and Blotts. Harry looked up at his furious friend and found himself explaining his conversations. Ron just stared at him for the longest moment and said “You’re barmy” and walked away from the fireplace. Harry followed his friend into the darkness. He could barely make out Ron’s large frame in the dim light, and when he put his hand on the redhead’s shoulder, he found it was shaking. Harry turned him around and saw tears pouring down his friend’s face. Harry hugged him while his friend cried for the first time since The Burrow burned down.

Harry took a shaky breath and swiped at his face. He couldn’t seem to stop crying, and he felt like he was falling to pieces every time he turned around. He needed to pull himself together if he was going to get over this. A small voice in the back of his mind asked if he really wanted to get over this. Harry wondered for a moment if he’d retained an echo from Voldemort through their connection, or if maybe he was hearing from that part of himself that wanted to die after they’d found Ginny’s body.

Harry gritted his teeth and opened the thickest of the books he’d pulled down from the shelf, “Essays in Advanced Theoretical Thaumaturgy, vol. MCXII”. Soon Hermione’s voice echoed through his mind, explaining how the interaction of precisely-timed cheering, calming, and confusion charms could be used to treat certain varieties of psychological disorders.

It was on the second day of bed-rest and reading that it came to Harry. Something about that last article had piqued his interest. He went back and read it again, trying to see why it had grabbed his attention. It seemed to be a purely theoretical exercise in temporal translation theory, and both the author’s notes and the abstract indicated that it was published solely as an arithmantic exercise and proof of theorem. Harry read back through the equations again, trying to channel Hermione’s brilliance as well as her voice.

The formulas dealt with conjuring the balanced spatial tensions required to create a temporal shift. The focus of the dynamic interface would be a curved field, the parameters of which would be dependent on the magnitudes of the forces involved. Any object that crossed through this curved field would experience a temporal translation, the magnitude of which would also be varied as the interacting forces were altered.

The reason why this exercise was a purely theoretical one was due to the energy requirements. Relativistic mass is a function of mass and velocity squared. The energy required for a temporal shift is a function of time travelled and mass taken to the infinite power, or basically infinity minus one. Anything with actual mass interacting with the field, even a molecule of air, would instantly consume all of the energy and collapse the field.

Once he was fairly sure he had a grasp of the theory, Harry wondered why he even thought it was useful. Yes, if he could go back in time, or just send word, a lot of misery could have been avoided. But even a simple parchment with a warning message to Dumbledore would be far too massive. The article was quite clear that vision was not possible across the field, nor was any sort of scrying or divinatory magic. There would be no way to communicate.

How could anyone possibly send information without any mass, and not using magic? Hell, how many things did he know of that had no mass anyway? Harry pummelled his ‘inner Hermione’ with questions. He knew somehow this was dreadfully important. Something in this article had seized his attention and made him feel something he hadn’t felt in a long time.

Hope.

Finally, at the dawn of his third day, Harry decided to leave his sanctuary. He needed food that hadn’t come out of wand, and he needed to talk to his former mentor.

“Harry, this is very interesting, and I’m glad to see you are finding ways to occupy yourself in a profitable fashion. However, I don’t understand why you are so enthusiastic about this article,” Dumbledore said as he frowned down at Harry from the portrait after he read the article aloud.

Harry got up from his conjured chair and began to pace as he thought. It was a habit he’d first developed while revising in the Gryffindor common room. Thinking about those days made his stomach twist, as the entire Gryffindor tower had been blasted and collapsed during the sacking of Hogwarts.

“I understand the power requirements make any ordinary use impossible. But what about transferring something that has no mass?”

“From what I read, they found that spells could not cross the barrier without being disrupted as well,” the headmaster replied. Harry didn’t have to look up to know that the blue eyes were starting to twinkle again. The portrait of his mentor hadn’t had much opportunity for magical theorizing, and he could tell it was something the professor enjoyed immensely.

“True,” Harry said, looking up. “But what about memories, spirits… souls?”

Dumbledore adjusted his half-moon spectacles as he thought. “No, I’m afraid an astral projection spell would still carry enough magical energy to disrupt the field.”

“What about…” Harry’s voice trailed off. “What about magic that moved the spirit from the body as a side effect? If the spirit was… moving on its own…”

Dumbledore frowned. “Harry, there isn’t a spell that I know of for moving spirits out of bodies. Unless you…” his eyes widened. “My dear boy, you don’t seriously propose to…”

Harry was lost in his own musings, staring off into space. “Curve the field around my body, and then use Avada Kedavra. Hopefully, if my spirit departs, it will interact with the field… and then?”

“Harry, you can’t mean to…”

“Albus,” Harry’s voice cracked like a whip. “If my spirit were to suddenly appear in a time when my body was alive, what would happen?”

“Harry, this is not a…”

“Albus, I’ve fulfilled your prophecy. If you ever gave a damn about me, not the bloody Boy-Who-Lived, but me, Harry James Potter, then answer the bloody question,” Harry snarled. The silence stretched between them like a bottomless abyss.

The headmaster’s portrait looked down. “Theoretically, Johanssen’s Principle of Conjoining would apply, and the spirit would be reabsorbed into the body, similar to a Muggle who nearly passes away and reports an out of body experience. That’s where Karl originally got the idea you know. It’s a very fascinating story, how he came to…”

“Thank you, Albus,” Harry said, smiling thinly. The headmaster wasn’t going to distract him quite that easily.

“Harry,” the portrait said quietly. “What you are proposing is unbelievably foolhardy. You’re going to kill yourself, hope your spirit will physically move through the field, hope the temporal field behaves as you think it will and transports your spirit to the past, and hope that your spirit will be drawn to your body. This isn’t a plan, Harry, this is little more than guesswork and good intentions.”

“I suppose it is. But you said ‘hope’ three times. I haven’t had any hope for a long time,” the young man replied, sighing.

“Harry,” Dumbledore said, growing a little exasperated for the first time Harry could remember. “You won. Voldemort is dead. You have the rest of your life to live, not to throw away…”

Harry snapped. “The rest of my life, you say? What the hell do I have to look forward to? Everyone I ever loved, everyone I ever gave a damn about is dead! Every place I cared about is in ruins! I don’t have a single reason left to go on.”

“Harry,” Dumbledore responded, getting his emotions back under control with visible effort. “Many people have given their lives to defend you, to make sure you survive. To throw that away now is to dishonour everything they sacrificed.”

“They didn’t do it for me,” Harry replied coldly. “At least most of them didn’t. They did it for The Boy Who Lived, their weapon to destroy Voldemort. And if you’ll recall, I didn’t ask anyone to die for me, not even your precious Order of the Phoenix.”

Dumbledore sighed, pinching the bridge of his nose between thumb and forefinger. “I’m sorry, Harry. I didn’t wish to bring that up in such a fashion. I care about you and I don’t want you to throw your life away. In time, your grief will pass. That is a lesson I learned long ago.”

Harry sank down into the chair again. Arguing with the headmaster’s portrait was just as exhausting as arguing with him when he was alive. “I don’t think I have that much time,” he said slowly, his face in his hands. “I came close to killing myself after what happened here. I’ve had to talk myself out of it a few times each year, and it gets a little harder every time. Stopping Tom gave me a goal to work toward, but now I have nothing left.” He looked up again. Albus had gone as still as a Muggle portrait. “I might as well make it possibly count for something.”

“Harry,” the headmaster said softly, “I have never regretted my passing more than I do today. You are too alone now, and there is nothing I can do.”

Harry took a deep breath and willed himself to maintain his composure. “You can help me with this.”

“Very well,” Dumbledore said. He frowned. “There is also the consideration, if everything works correctly, of how your actions will affect causality.”

“I have thought about that,” Harry said straightening up. The hardest part of the conversation seemed to be over. “Either my travelling back will change this reality, hopefully for the better, or it will create an alternate reality. Or if Hobson’s Paradigm is correct, my temporal journey will deposit me in an alternate reality where time has not progressed as far. Anything,” he said emphatically, “is better than living here.”

“If your spirit merges with your past self, you will be effectively eliminating your own awareness or that of your younger self. Is that not the same as murdering your younger self?”

Harry sat in thought for a moment. “If I knew that giving up my existence meant a chance to save them, I’d do it in a heartbeat. I’d do it when I was younger as well. I haven’t changed that much, Albus.” He smiled faintly.

The headmaster wasn’t quite done. “You do understand that you will be effectively resurrecting Tom Riddle?”

“If I do,” Harry allowed, “it will be a small price to pay for the lives of everyone who died in this war. Fighting him again is nothing, if I have a chance to do it better this time.”

“Do it better, Harry?”

“I plan to cheat like Draco Malfoy on a potions exam,” Harry replied, smiling grimly.

After his magical reserves were replenished, Harry Apparated to the American Expeditionary Force’s encampment. After they first arrived, Harry and Ron made contact with the war-mages, and struck up a loose alliance. After seeing some of what Harry was capable of doing over the course of the following two years, General Hastings had no difficulty in treating the haunted young man as an ally.

In a closed meeting with the white-haired general, Harry explained his suspicions about some of Voldemort’s escapes, and apologized for the subterfuge with the medical wizard. Hasting was annoyed at first, but grew chagrined as Harry repeated Voldemort’s comments that confirmed the younger man’s suspicions. When he told the American that Voldemort was finally gone, the man let out a vast sigh and offered Harry a shot of something called ‘Jack Daniels’.

After they downed the shots, Hastings bluntly asked Harry what he planned to do next.

“I plan to go away. Somewhere nice and quiet and hopefully peaceful,” was all he said.

“I’m glad to hear that,” Hastings replied amiably. “I imagine there are people in Washington who are going to be even happier to hear that.”

Harry just shrugged. Comforting warmth was spreading from the pit of his stomach. It almost made up for the burning in his throat.

“You know, you could probably run for King right now if you wanted to,” Hastings mused, a sly look in his eye. “There’s not much left of the old government, magical or non-magical. You just offed the next best thing to the Anti-Christ. With everyone who considers you a genuine hero, you could write your own ticket.”

Harry’s face took on an expression of utter horror. He scowled as the American General broke down laughing and slapping his knee.

“Good Lord, boy, you should have seen the look on your face! Go on and enjoy your nice quiet life. But if you ever get bored with it, look me up. I’ll notify Washington that they can ramp up the relief efforts now that damn madman is dust.”

Harry shook his head as he stood up. He sketched a crude approximation of an American Military salute and Apparated back to Hogwarts.

It was over a month before Harry’s preparations were complete. He filled reams of scavenged parchment with equations and notes. He wasn’t sure if he’d have been able to finish the calculation without the headmaster’s aid. Fortunately, the Hogwarts dungeons were relatively undamaged, though the books were starting to draw dampness and go green with mould. Nevertheless, Harry found the materials and tools he needed to prepare the prisms that would define and maintain the temporal field.

When taking a break or while eating meals, Harry talked to the headmaster’s portrait. They mainly talked about the past, and how things came to happen as they did. It was a bittersweet time for both of them. Harry had long ago forgiven the headmaster for the things he had and hadn’t done. For his part, death had also brought a note of humility to the Supreme Mugwump’s worldview. In the end, they had to agree that Albus had tried his best to make sure things worked out, even if it had ended badly. Now it would be Harry’s turn.

The grief that normally came from talking about long-lost friends was tempered by the fact that there was a small chance that he might see them again. Indeed, if he were mistaken in his assumptions, he’d suddenly find himself seeing a lot of people again – though he’d also have some serious explaining to do. When he looked at his options like that, Harry almost felt like he was in a ‘can’t lose’ situation. The only fate that truly frightened him was growing old alone in a world filled with despair and grief. Sharing that observation with Albus shocked him at first, but after a while he seemed to understand, and his assistance in Harry’s project became noticeably more enthusiastic.

After they quadruple-checked his calculations, Harry carefully and deliberately burned his notes, retaining only the final sheet with the precisely calculated prism layouts. They both agreed that this sort of magic was not something to leave lying around. Harry also wrote out a short note for General Hastings and pinned it to the sleeve of his robes.

“Hastings may come to see you some day, Albus. He’s done all right by me. I suggested he may want to keep you around as a local advisor.”

The headmaster’s portrait looked up at Harry curiously. The boy smiled faintly.

“I don’t want to leave you sitting here alone until you mildew. If what I do doesn’t alter this timeline, then, well, you can probably help a lot with the reconstruction.” Harry paused and then continued in a rough voice, “Maybe you can tell people about a wonderful school that was built to share the knowledge of magic with each new generation as they grew up.”

“Harry, no matter what happens here, I know you will make a positive impact no matter where you go. I want you to know that the small help I’ve given you through the years has been one of the things I’m most proud of doing with my life.”

Harry stared at the portrait for a long moment. “It was more than a small help.”

“Goodbye Harry. I wish you well on your next great adventure.”

“Goodbye Albus. I wish you the same,” he said as he Disapparated from the damaged office for the last time.

Number Four Privet Drive was exactly identical to the properties on either side and across the street, a fact that the Dursleys were intensely proud of. Of course, the fact that the houses were all burned-out ruins was something to be less happy about.

As Harry poked through the rubble, he felt a guilty twinge of relief that the house was unrecognizable. He’d gone through some very bad times with his aunt’s family, and he needed no reminders of that now. Theoretically, the temporal transit should occur at roughly the same spatial coordinates. Harry’s plan had enough unknowns that he didn’t want to push his luck. So he wanted his spirit to appear in the past as close to his physical body as possible. With that in mind, he calculated his arrival for the middle of August, 1991. That far back, it was difficult to pick an exact day to arrive, and his Uncle’s panicked flight in July made it tricky to make sure his body would be near Privet drive when his spirit arrived. Harry would have liked to have gone a little farther back, but the temporal field would have required even more energy to establish, and he had to make sure he had enough magic left for one spell; one very powerful spell.

Harry found a relatively clear spot near the front door and next to the remains of the stairs. He cleared away bits of charred wood and began to set the prisms on the floor. As he positioned them, he used measuring charms to check the spacing and the angle of each one. He had to get this absolutely perfect the first time. The article suggested that even if the energy problem were solved, a ‘temporal’ charge was likely to accumulate during transit. This was why the farther back you wished to focus the temporal transit field, the more energy it required as well. If he didn’t do this right, there was no chance of trying it again – the energy build-up would be too great.

Harry set the last prism in place and recast all the measuring charms. After re-checking everything with his chart, he lit that on fire as well. When the parchment was consumed, he pointed his wand at each prism in order and cast the energizing charm. As each prism began to glow, adjacent crystal wedges were joined with threads of light. When all the crystals were charged, an elongated hemisphere sprang up around Harry. He peered closely at the three-ply fields that enclosed him. The first and third fields formed a barrier that kept the air away from the second field. The modified bubblehead charm worked perfectly; otherwise the transit field would have collapsed from trying to send a random atom of atmosphere nineteen years into the past.

Harry took a deep breath as a deep weariness set into his bones. There was only one spell left to do, and then it would all be over. He set the tip of his wand between his eyes and thought of Ginny. Her memory had kept him from doing that after he lost her… now he would do this to get her back.

Harry pushed aside that thought and focused on how many people he’d lost over the years, how many he’d let die. The spell required true hate to cast. Fortunately, Harry had more than enough self loathing.

“Avada Kedavra!”

As the blinding green light swept over his eyes, Harry Potter heard a rushing sound and knew no more.

Sometimes when the body knows death is imminent, it will react reflexively, even if it is useless. Struck by the spell, Harry’s back arched, throwing his arm wide. His wand, holly and phoenix feather, eleven inches, flew from his slack fingers. The instant the tumbling wood struck the glowing barrier it collapsed the field…

…and Harry James Potter, the Boy Who Lived, fell to the ground, dead.

2

Back to Privet Drive

Harry woke from his nightmare, screaming at the top of his lungs.

“Dammit Boy, stop that racket this instant!” Vernon Dursley’s voice boomed through the door.

Harry went limp, eyes staring blearily up at the ceiling. His head hurt so badly it felt it had been split open with an axe, like in one of Dudley’s video games. “Am I dying?” he whispered aloud. He wondered if he’d had a stroke, like they talked about on his Aunt’s favourite hospital shows. He didn’t feel like one side of his body had gone numb. In fact, both sides of his head ached abominably.

He lay flat on the bed and tried to slow his breathing. As he closed his eyes, images began to flash again. He saw people fighting and dying. He saw red eyes glowing at him from the darkness, hate burning like a fire. He didn’t recall ever seeing a show on the telly about people fighting with wands, so he wondered if the dream had come because of his trip to Diagon Alley with Hagrid.

He smiled as he thought about the immense, rough-spoken man, the first adult wizard Harry had ever met, and really his first real friend. Even as he pictured the man’s beetle-black eyes and bristling beard, he also saw the man’s face gone slack and pale, the eyes staring glassily into infinity. Harry’s stomach contracted into a small hard ball as he realized he was seeing Hagrid dead. The boy shivered and clutched as his thin, ragged pillow.

“It’s just a nightmare,” he whispered to himself, “a really, really horrid nightmare.”

Maybe if he kept repeating that, he’d start to believe it.

Nightmares or not, Harry was up early cooking breakfast before Uncle Vernon went off to work. It was hard to focus though. He kept seeing images from his dream, most of which were quite disturbing. He almost dropped the frying pan as his Aunt swept into the kitchen to see why breakfast wasn’t ready yet.

“Be careful, you stupid boy!” she snarled. “You’re just as careless as your worthless parents!”

A cold draft seemed to blow straight through Harry’s chest, freezing the air in his lungs. He set the pan aside and spun around. Petunia Dursley was used to dealing with her unwanted nephew; she was used to sullen obedience, grudging respect, and general avoidance. She was not, however, used to cold rage.

“My parents were not worthless. My father was a star Quidditch player and my mother was one of the best Charms witches of her generation. If you weren’t so bloody jealous of her and her relationship with my father, you wouldn’t feel the need to make up petty lies.”

The blood could not have drained from Petunia Dursley’s face any faster if she’d had her throat cut.

Harry blinked as she turned and left the kitchen at close to a run. What had possessed him to say such a thing? He didn’t know his parents at all. Hagrid told him his mother and father had been Head Girl and Boy at Hogwarts, but no details beyond that. And that last part… he knew from what she’d said in the shack by the sea that his Aunt had been jealous of her sister’s talents. But she said nothing about being jealous of Lily’s husband, his father.

And yet Harry’s words had stopped her in her tracks.

He shook his head as he put the bacon back on the burner until it sizzled properly. He brought the food out to the dining room and served everyone. Aunt Petunia was white-faced and silent, while Uncle Vernon glared at him and Dudley just looked confused. Harry slid the remaining bacon and eggs onto his plate and ate quickly in the uncomfortable silence. He got the washing up done in record time as well and retreated to his room. On the way, Harry filched a couple of aspirins from the lavatory medicine cabinet and washed them down with tap water. Once he was back in his room, he checked his owl’s cage and made sure her water dish was full.

Harry sat on his bed, face in his hands, and elbows on his knees. As he took a deep breath, he remembered sitting in a chair in a similar fashion while arguing… with a portrait? The memory felt recent, like it was from something he’d done this summer, but parts of it were all wrong. He had a ton of aches and pains. But Harry couldn’t recall ever getting hurt that badly, even by Dudley’s gang at school.

Giving up trying to figure it out, Harry lay back down on the bed and closed his eyes. The headache was fading now, and if his Aunt continued to avoid him, he might get a chance to rest.

When Harry awoke that afternoon, his headache was lessened, but his nightmares had been, if anything, even worse. When he stumbled downstairs, his Aunt was sitting quietly in the living room. She didn’t look at him as he told her he was feeling ill and wouldn’t be down for supper, but just nodded her head.

Skipping supper was no hardship that evening, as his appetite was nonexistent. He couldn’t recall ever feeling so sluggish and weak, except perhaps the time his Uncle struck him in the kitchen and he hit his head on the oven as he fell. This was different though. “Is this magic?” he whispered in the darkened room. It was still hard to think of the place as his bedroom, his place was the cupboard under the stairs. Taking a shaky breath, Harry settled back down onto the pillow and let the darkness claim him.

What happened next was like no dream he could ever recall.

Harry found himself sitting in the spare bedroom again. The chair was pulled away from the desk and a strange man was sitting in it. He was very thin, and looked incredibly tired and haggard. Lank black hair fell across his face and his eyes were shadowed. He stared at Harry, shock etched onto his features, and then wearily scrubbed at his eyes.

“I should have expected this,” the man said finally. “Too much natural resistance for this to have gone smoothly. Anyone who can throw off the Imperius at fourteen would not make this easy.” His face twisted into a grimace, “Maybe it’s better this way, rather than forced.”

Harry tried not to stare as the odd-looking man talked to himself. He was used to strange dreams that didn’t make a lot of sense at the time, like flying motorcycles and flashes of green light. But he’d never had a dream figure that ignored him to talk to itself.

The man glanced at Harry and let out a sigh. “I’m not explaining this very well then, am I? Look, Harry, have you met Hagrid yet?”

The boy nodded eyes wide.

“Good, then I didn’t botch that part. You’re getting ready to head off to school, right?”

Harry nodded again.

“Right then. You’re going to love Hogwarts, and it will become a home away from home for you. More home than you ever had here with the Dursleys.” The man’s voice went hard and Harry’s mouth dropped open. His Aunt and Uncle were usually brilliant at keeping up appearances in front of the neighbours. How did this man know what went on? Harry felt his face grow hot with shame.

“None of that,” the man said firmly. “It’s got nothing to do with you and everything to do with them. They’ve earned themselves a special place in hell for what they’ve done to you.”

Harry took a shaky breath and tried to make himself accept the man’s words.

“Don’t worry about it. It’ll take time and someone a lot more persuasive than I am to make you believe. Anyway, you’re going to enjoy your time at Hogwarts, and the friends you make there, but things will not always be good.”

Harry just looked at the man calmly as he appeared to gather his thoughts.

“There’s quite a bit that’s going to happen, and some of it is very bad. The man that killed your parents is going to come back, and he’s going to kill a lot of people. Some… some of the people he kills will be your friends, people you’ve come to… come to love.”

Harry felt the blood drain from his face. He didn’t know you could go into shock in the middle of a nightmare. “W-why are you telling me this?” he whispered. “How do you know all of this?”

The man looked at Harry for a long moment, and he realized the sunken eyes were a dim, murky green. Finally, his visitor pushed back the hair on his forehead to reveal a very familiar scar in the shape of a lightning bolt.

Harry stared at the man for a long moment. He opened his mouth and said the first thing that popped into his mind. “But how? If you’re me, why aren’t you wearing glasses?”

The man smiled for the first time, a slow, sad grin that made Harry’s stomach seem to twist painfully. “Hermione— uh, one of my, or maybe our, friends you’re going to meet at school, developed a vision charm that corrects for nearsightedness. She got tired of my glasses getting knocked off at inconvenient times.”

Harry noticed the man was blinking rapidly and his eyes were a little shinier than they had been. “It doesn’t turn out very well, does it?” he asked.

“No, I’m sorry to say it doesn’t. I won in the end, but everything was destroyed and everyone I cared about… died. Afterwards, I realized that there was nothing left for me, so I used some really advanced magic to take my… spirit… out of my body and send it back to this time. I can give you my knowledge of what is going on, what is going to happen. Hopefully, we can make a difference.”

“You say ‘we’,” Harry asked cautiously.

His older self nodded. “The original plan was for our spirits to merge, which means our consciousnesses would meld as well. You will stop being just you, and I will stop being just me. We will become more of an us, I think.” The man fell silent for a moment, and then continued in a softer voice. “I don’t want to deceive you, Harry, if you agree you will not be the same Harry Potter you were. A lot of my memories are… not very pleasant.”

The boy looked up at the man, eyes growing damp as well. “Will I really have friends at this new school?”

The man nodded and took a shaky breath. “Oh Harry, you are going to have great friends. You are going to have so many people love you that you won’t be able to believe it.”

The boy stood up from the bed. “Then I am not letting anything happen to them. Not if I can stop it.” He stuck out his hand.

The man whispered as he took the boy’s hand, “Somehow I knew you were going to say that.” The man disappeared as an unseen breeze blew through the room.

Harry awoke with his skin burning like it was on fire. He bit back his cries as the pain faded. When he was sure he could move again, he sat up and swung his feet to the floor. He looked around at Dudley’s abandoned storage room. It was the most beautiful thing he’d seen for years. He looked over at the Snowy Owl that was still staring at him. “I bloody did it, Hedwig!” he whispered fiercely. “It bloody well worked!” The owl didn’t react to her name, and Harry reviewed his recent memories in confusion. “Oh, sorry girl,” he said as he got up and opened the cage door. He stroked her soft head feathers, something his future self hadn’t gotten to do for too many years. “How do you like the name Hedwig, girl? It’s a pretty name for a pretty owl.” The owl bobbed her head and rubbed her beak across Harry’s knuckles. He gave her an owl treat and she hooted softly at him.

Harry sighed happily and looked up at the paper pinned to the wall that counted down the days until he left for Hogwarts. He still had nearly two weeks. The battered clock on the desk told Harry it was a little after two in the morning. Harry stood thinking for a moment before pulling on his battered trainers and sliding his wand under his over-sized shirt. Finally, his vault key and money bag went into his pocket. Harry slipped out of the house with the stealth he learned at a young age from trying to avoid his relatives.

Harry stood on the darkened kerb, the moon just beginning to peek around the clouds, and held his wand up. He stared at it for a moment, surprised to see smooth wood, unblemished by the scorch marks and nicks his memory showed him. He jumped as the Knight Bus appeared with a loud bang.

“Leaky Cauldron,” Harry said coolly as he paid his fare. A slightly younger Stan Shunpike than he remembered from his third year took his money. Harry avoided the young man’s eyes and made his way to a sliding bed before anyone noticed his scar.

Once he got off on Charing Cross road, Harry walked into the tavern and cut through to the back wall with purposeful strides. He avoided meeting anyone’s eye as he cut through the pub. He had his wand out and was tapping the bricks before he heard a voice behind him. “Hey Tom, who’s the lad?”

This late Diagon Alley was quite different. Many of the shops were closed, though a few stayed open. The streets were almost deserted, and the few figures that were still abroad were wrapped in dark cloaks. Harry felt horribly exposed in his ill-fitting Muggle clothes, but he kept his wand tightly clenched in his fist and marched down the centre of the lane. He didn’t really want to be interrupted, so he summoned up the scowl he first developed as Quidditch Captain for the Gryffindor team. He just hoped it didn’t look completely laughable on an eleven year old.

When he arrived at the large white marble building, he was relieved to see that his deductions were correct. Gringotts was open for business, though only a few workers were on duty. Goblins, commonly living underground, were a lot more flexible about their sleeping schedules than humans. Also, the fact that some of their customers had an aversion to daylight almost guaranteed they would stay open late, if not all night long.

Harry walked up to the nearest available goblin and nodded politely. “I’d like to visit my vault, and ask a few questions about my account.”

The goblin looked at him curiously, but gestured for Harry to follow. After another rollercoaster journey through the tunnels, Harry unlocked his vault with the key Hagrid had given him. This time he scooped out a larger pile of galleons. He knew this vault would be refilled by the family vault if it ever became depleted. The Potter Family vault would be inaccessible to him until he was seventeen, the age of majority in the Wizarding world. He hadn’t even been aware of its existence until the owl from Gringotts reached him the day after his birthday. Harry never stopped being frustrated by the things that had been kept secret from him, but this time it would be different.

The only complication lay in finding a way to use his foreknowledge without revealing too much of what he knew. If the ministry knew he had knowledge of the future, Fudge would have him locked away and drinking Veritaserum until they drained him dry. Merlin only knew what Fudge would do with the information. Albus had also cautioned him about changing the past too far too quickly. If the course of events deviated too far from his memories, then his foreknowledge would become useless. Harry knew he had to use his memories with care, but he didn’t want to be paralyzed with indecision either. As they rode the cart up to the surface, Harry decided to be as subtle as possible and see what results that obtained.

Once they were back in the lobby and he’d exchanged some galleons for pounds, Harry turned to his guide. “Did my parents leave anything besides money? Any papers, journals? I have so little to remember them by,” he added wistfully.

The goblin did not appear to be comfortable dealing with emotional humans. “I believe there is a family vault, and some investments, but by the terms of your inheritance I’m afraid you will not be able to access them until you are of age.”

“Really?” Harry asked, feigning surprise. “Would it be possible to speak to the account manager?”

“Why would you wish to do that?” the goblin asked suspiciously.

Harry shrugged nonchalantly, though later he imagined the gesture looked somewhat odd coming from a child. “I have a few general questions about how it is being handled. I also have to consider whether I may want to move my assets once I am old enough,” he replied coolly.

The goblin’s eyes widened. It wasn’t often that a junior employee got the opportunity to receive the blame for a multi-million galleon account being lost to one of Gringotts’ overseas competitors. “I will see if Goldfarb is available,” he said quickly and scurried off.

Within minutes Harry was escorted into a comfortable conference room with an extremely fat goblin who wore a plaid waistcoat and had a tiny pair of gold-rimmed spectacles perched on the bridge of his bulbous nose. “Mr. Potter,” the goblin rumbled, inclining his head without smiling.

“Master Goldfarb, may your gold always flow,” Harry replied with a slight bow. He’d interceded between the American military forces and a group of surviving Gringotts employees after the ‘liberation’ of Diagon Alley. While he helped them salvage what they could from the destroyed underground vaults, Harry had picked up a smattering of Goblin language and customs.

Goldfarb’s eyes widened for an instant, surprised at hearing a formal greeting from a wizard, let alone such a young one. “How may I assist you today?” he said politely, eyeing the youngster.

“I was only recently made aware of my family vaults, and the fact that you manage my family’s investments.”

“That is correct,” Goldfarb replied carefully, obviously wondering where this was going.

“Have you any means of investing in Muggle businesses?”

The goblin blinked. “Er, yes, we have done so on certain occasions. It is not usually done, however.”

Harry pondered his options for a moment. “I will be frank with you, Guardian of My Vaults,” he said, using a formal Goblin title that denoted great respect and trust. Goldfarb inhaled and straightened in his chair at that. “I live with my uncle, a Muggle who hates my kind. He obtains his livelihood from a Muggle manufacturing company named Grunnings. I would consider it a personal favour if my entrusted portfolio were to include a controlling interest in this company.”

“You wish him dismissed from his post for revenge?” Goldfarb asked, but it wasn’t really a question.

But Harry shook his head, making the goblin raise a gnarled eyebrow. “I wish leverage, not vengeance. There have been… incidents. I want a way to end those.” Harry looked thoughtful for a moment. “If they… continued… and something happened to me, my uncle’s family constitutes my sole remaining relatives. Were they to gain control of my assets they would immediately withdraw them and place them in a Muggle institution.”

Goldfarb said nothing for a moment as his nostrils dilated. “As your account manager, it is my duty to promote a balanced investment strategy. I have noticed that your holdings in the Muggle sphere are rather sparse,” the goblin said in a formal voice. “You will receive notification by owl once we have acquired a controlling interest,” he added quietly.

Harry nodded and immediately got up from the table, a gesture of respect implying that he didn’t wish to waste any more of Goldfarb’s time.

Harry stepped out into the darkened street and looked around. The figures wandering around this late didn’t appear to be paying him any special attention, but he still felt like someone was watching him. He quickly made his way to a disreputable-looking second-hand clothing store near the entrance to Knockturn Alley. It was still open, and he was able to pay more than he should have for a shortened black hooded cloak. He felt a little more confident now, as he made his way back to the Leaky Cauldron. It wasn’t immediately obvious how young he was — and a short figure in a cloak could be anything from a dwarf to a goblin. No sane person wanted to accost a goblin in a deserted street in the middle of the night.

Harry wore the cloak all the way back to Privet Drive. He took it off and rolled it up under his arm as the Knight Bus stopped in front of number four. He nodded as he pushed by Stan and scrambled to the kerb. The cuckoo clocks on the bus mostly agreed that it was somewhere around half past four, and he was knackered. Harry stuck his wand inside the rolled up cloak and slowly let himself into the darkened house. He was almost betrayed by a creaky floorboard, but remembered it just in time.

The boy stretched out on his lumpy mattress with a sigh. He had to get up and cook in little more than an hour, but he’d slept most of the previous day. He slowly closed his eyes and dropped off for a few minutes.

The fire burned unnaturally bright, and even at this distance the skin on Harry’s forehead was hot and tight. He and Hermione had hold of Ron’s arms, digging their heels in as they tried to hold back the larger man.

“Let me go!” he screamed.

Hermione was sobbing incoherently as well. Harry finally found his voice and got his friend’s attention. “I’m sorry, Ron. We’re too late. She-she’s gone.” His voice trailed off into a whisper as Ron’s knees buckled and he collapsed onto the dirt path.

“Mum!” he sobbed as tears rolled down his face. Hermione knelt in front of him and hugged his face to her chest, comforting him.

Harry looked away and watched The Burrow burn.

Harry sat up so quickly he nearly fell off the bed. He grabbed the marred headboard to steady himself as his head continued spinning. I did not need that! he thought as he crossed his arms over his contorting stomach. I do not need to be throwing up right now either. Get it together, Potter.

He imagined Snape sneering at him for his weakness and an icy chill ran through his veins. The boy reminded himself that he needed to figure out what he was going to do about the potions master. As he pondered his options, he was ashamed to admit that cold-blooded murder was not immediately eliminated from the list. At least that damn mind-raper won’t be picking through my thoughts and memories this time around.

He still kicked himself sometimes about the implications he had not realized when he discovered that Snape was a master Legilimens. All those times he’d taunted Harry about being a glory seeker, all those times he’d blamed Harry when Draco sabotaged someone’s cauldron… he’d been able to see into Harry’s mind. He knew Harry didn’t crave attention and fame. He knew Harry wasn’t responsible for all those sabotaged potions. He knew… and still he punished Harry and made his life a living hell whenever possible. At that point he should have realized there was no way someone so evil and vindictive could have been truly working against Voldemort. He should have killed him on the spot. There would have been trouble, more than he’d ever had to deal with before, but Dumbledore wouldn’t have been killed. With the headmaster alive, Voldemort would never have dared to attack the school. A life sentence in Azkaban would have been well worth it.

Harry shook his head violently, whipping away the cobwebs of sleep and memories. He got up and put another tick on his sheet of paper. He had less than two weeks to plan what he needed to do. His face resolute, the boy marched down to the kitchen to start preparing breakfast.

Between meals and chores, Harry made it a practice to absent himself from the Dursleys’ house at every opportunity. Not that Aunt Petunia minded. Since his outburst, she tended to avoid him as much as possible. Reading his mother’s journals from the Potter Family vault after he turned seventeen had paid unexpected dividends.

So each morning he’d walk toward the play park and as soon as he was out of sight, call the Knight Bus. Harry made several shopping trips to Diagon Alley and other parts of London. He took great pains to make sure he wore the hooded cloak when visiting the Alley. He didn’t want random “Harry Potter Sightings” to be reported in The Daily Prophet and start people asking questions.

During his excursions to Muggle London, Harry was tempted to buy some clothes that actually fit, but he refrained. He wanted people to believe him when he finally told them about the Dursleys, so he didn’t want to do anything that would suggest he was being well treated in any way. Instead he purchased books on psychology, martial arts, and fencing. The latter two would be useful as references, and to supply cover for any skills or knowledge he might accidentally let slip. The psychology books were the most important. He needed to change how things happened this time. He couldn’t very well say to eleven year old Ron and Hermione, “you two will become lovers before you turn twenty, so stop arguing and be nice to each other.” There was also the matter of what to do about Ginny.

They talked a lot during the brief period of time they’d had after they’d gotten together. She told him she’d never really given up on him. The fact that she’d waited more than five years for him to get his act together both disturbed and amazed him. There was no way in hell he would be taking her for granted this time, but he also needed to help her with her shyness around him. What she told him about the aftermath of her time in the Chamber of Secrets also haunted him. He just didn’t know whether he needed to be there for her, or try to prevent it altogether. How far could he alter events without making them unrecognizable?

Thinking about meeting Hermione and the Weasleys on September first both elated and terrified him. He couldn’t wait to see them alive again, but at the same time he was worried he’d muck it all up.

Eventually, the last mark on the paper was ticked off. The morning he was to leave for Hogwarts, Vernon, Petunia, and Dudley piled into the car and left. They were taking Dudley to London for some elective surgery to remove the pig tail Hagrid transfigured onto Harry’s spoiled cousin. They left without a word about Harry’s departure, which was fine with him. Harry remembered that he had to mention needing a ride to King’s Cross the first time around.

Once they were gone Harry dragged his trunk down the stairs. With the extra books and his smaller size, it was quite a chore. He opened it up and pulled out a sack from a Muggle luggage store. After propping up the end of the trunk opposite the pull handle, he clipped a pair of rollers onto the bottom edge and tightened the screws. “This isn’t nearly as good as a shrinking charm,” he said aloud, his voice echoing in the empty house, “but it’ll do for now.” With that he ran back upstairs to get Hedwig’s cage and checked to make sure he hadn’t missed anything.

If the ever-dreaded neighbours had anything to say about Harry pulling a trunk, complete with caged owl on top, out to the kerb, they didn’t choose to express themselves.

The Knight Bus brought Harry to the train station by ten, a good hour before he had to leave. He chose to wait on the Muggle side of the nine and three quarters barrier, figuring that asking how to get through was just as good a way to introduce himself to his second family as any other. After a few minutes of staring up at the clock and fidgeting, Harry became bored. He hopped off his trunk and pulled out one of his Muggle psychology books to re-read. Try as he might, he couldn’t pay attention to the words.

He was terrified.

Meeting the Weasleys was the best thing that ever happened to him, but beginnings were such delicate things. One wrong word, one wrong move…might result in a bad first impression. Losing his friends wasn’t nearly as bad as watching them die, but what he did over the next few hours could make or break him. Added to that was the fact that he was going to deliberately try to change some things. He wanted to shore up the foundations some of his relationships were built on, but he wasn’t sure if he was doing the right thing. Would this backfire and make things worse? Did he even have the right to do this? Was he just manipulating the people he claimed to love?

Harry took a deep breath and closed his eyes. His Occlumency exercises were good practice for getting his emotions under control again. As his heartbeat began to slow, Harry tried to sort out his concerns in a logical fashion. The Weasleys had always considered him family, especially since the start of his second year. They did that the first time around, when Harry had no prior knowledge of the future. This time around, he would just be… extra considerate. He’d be a better friend, that’s all. He knew someday he would have to tell them of his journey back, and how things turned out the first time. To be honest, he was dreading that conversation. Until that happened, he’d just have to try and do the best he could with what was available. Harry nodded to himself and opened his eyes. A line of red-headed people was starting to enter the train station. He stowed his book back in the trunk and began to work his way toward the gap between platforms nine and ten.

Harry hung back as the Weasley matriarch directed her older boys through the barrier. Just hearing her voice again was music to his ears. He had to swallow twice before he could speak and Ron was already heading toward the barrier.

“E-excuse me,” he said, damning his voice for shaking. “I… was wondering how you get through…?”

Molly, peering worriedly after Ron’s progress, hadn’t heard him at first. However, a soft voice answered him. “I can show you,” it said. He turned and stepping around her mother was Ginny Weasley.

Harry had wondered how he’d react to seeing her again for the first time. By ‘react’, however, he hadn’t anticipated massive cardiac arrest. His heart gave such a thump he was amazed he hadn’t deafened everyone in the station. Her face was rounder, with a few traces of baby fat, but he could still see the lines of the beauty she’d become. He could feel the trunk handle quivering in his hand and struggled to get his emotions back under control. Hadn’t he been practising Occlumency just a few minutes ago? He grumbled as he felt the blood rushing to his face.

At least her cheeks were a little pink as well, Harry noted. “Er, sure.” He swallowed. “I’d really appreciate that,” he said in a clearer voice.

“Follow me,” she said, taking his free hand and leading him through the crowd. It was an innocent gesture, but it took all of Harry’s willpower not to squeeze it like he never wanted to let go.

When they drew near the metal barrier she turned back toward him. “My brothers all told me about this before. You just run toward the wall like it’s not there. It helps if you close your eyes first.”

Harry made a show of nodding thoughtfully. “Okay, you’re the expert here,” he acquiesced.

Her face grew a little pinker at the comment, but she turned and walked quickly toward the barrier. Harry didn’t follow her advice, but instead watched her as she walked through the wall. He followed her through, and smiled as he saw the Hogwarts Express.

Harry turned toward his guide, just in time to see her mother emerge from the wall behind them, a small smile on her face. “Well, you were right,” he said, smiling. “I owe you one. By the way, I’m Harry. Are you coming to Hogwarts as well?”

That was evidently the wrong question. She looked down. “I’m Ginny. I’d like to come, but I’m too young yet. Mum says next year.”

“Well, it’s good to meet you, Ginny,” he replied, but her eyes stayed downcast and he could see her face getting pinker. Harry racked his brain for a way to keep this going. He saw Ron and the twins heading their way when it came to him. “Could I possibly trouble you for another favour?” he asked quietly.

She looked up at him, puzzled.

“Well,” Harry began with a sheepish expression on his face. “I have this owl now, but no one to write to. You see, I was raised by Muggles, and not terribly nice ones. They said I’m not to allow Hedwig anywhere near their house. Anyway, I have a lot of questions about how they do things in Wizarding houses, things most of the other students have been around since they were born. You don’t, er, suppose I could write you and ask you a few questions, you know if something comes up? I don’t fancy looking like a berk in front of everyone in my classes, and you obviously know all about stuff that everyone takes for granted…” He looked away, a little uncomfortable.

“If-if you think that would help, I don’t mind,” she said shyly.

“That would be brilliant,” Harry said, smiling. “If you want, I’ll tell you all about what goes on in my classes, so you’ll know what to expect.”

“I’d like that, Harry,” she said.

He smiled at her again. This was going better than he expected. “Well, I hate to cut this short, but I’d better get my stuff on board.”

She nodded and started to turn toward her mother.

“Don’t worry though,” Harry said smiling, “I’ve already got half a dozen questions for you.”

Ginny pinked up again, but she was still smiling as she went back to Molly.

Harry worked his way down the train, knowing it was full almost all the way to the back. He smiled seeing Neville looking for Trevor. That was another friend he didn’t want to see waiting five years to come into his own. Eventually Harry made his way to the last compartment, and began trying to stow his possessions. Hedwig’s cage wasn’t a problem, but Harry’s trunk was even heavier this time. I really need to build up my strength, was his exasperated observation, I’m getting really tired of being a bloody weed.

As if on cue, one of the twins appeared like last time and they helped him get his trunk into the compartment. When they were done, one of them peered at the scar on his forehead and let out a low whistle.

“Blimey,” the other one said, “’e looks like—”

“I think he is,” the other one said.

“What?” Harry asked stupidly.

“You’re Harry Potter!”

“Yeah, I guess I am. Wait a minute,” Harry said, narrowing his eyes. “There’s two of you.”

“Really?”

“I hadn’t noticed, mate.”

Harry took a step back and made a horrified face. “Y-you’re not the infamous Weasley twins are you?”

Fred and George looked at each other in confusion.

“They warned me about you in my Hogwarts letter,” Harry continued in an accusing tone. “Where is that slip of parchment? Never mind, I remember what it said. ‘Notorious pranksters, approach with caution, do not touch, eat or drink anything they have been near!’” Harry resolutely clasped his hands behind his back and edged away from the confused red-heads.

“Oi, brother of mine, I think—”

“—our reputation has begun to get—”

“—a bit out of hand. Especially if the headmaster is—”

“—including warnings about us—”

“—in official school correspondence.”

“Too right, brother of mine.”

“Unless Mister Potter is having us on.”

“There is that.”

Both of them turned and stared at Harry.

“Would I kid a Weasley?” Harry asked innocently.

“Brother of mine,” the one on the left began.

“We have been had,” finished the one on Harry’s right.

“Good one, Harry!” they both said in unison. The one on the right stuck out his right hand, while the one on the left stuck out his left hand. Harry didn’t miss a beat and shook both simultaneously. The twins smiled at each other and exited the compartment.

Harry settled down next to the window and listened to the Weasleys begin to make their goodbyes. He smiled when Fred and George immediately revealed who he was, even before Percy got there. This time Ginny didn’t ask to get on the train to take a look at him, which made him smile even wider.

Ron evidently used the confusion to escape his mother’s ministrations, and boarded the compartment while she lectured his brothers about not asking poor Harry what You Know Who looked like.

“Mind if I sit here?” his future best friend asked.

“Not at all,” Harry replied with a smile. He still had a smudge of black on the end of his nose. “I’m Harry.”

“I’m Ron.” The boy peered at him for a second, and Harry waited for Ron to ask to see his scar. “Why did you want to talk to my sister?”

Things are already starting to happen differently, Harry noted as he stumbled over his prepared answer. He wondered about the open window behind him. The conversation outside seemed to have dropped off. “Well, er, she was really nice and helped me get through the barrier.”

Ron frowned slightly. “Everybody knows how to get onto the platform,” he scoffed.

Harry didn’t comment on how Molly seemed to feel he still needed watching to make sure he got through okay. “Well, I didn’t,” he said, fighting the urge to snap at the boy. Ron had always been a bit thick at times. “And she was kind enough to offer to show me how.” Harry thought about the open window again and added in a louder voice. “Besides, she’s awfully pretty.” Harry swore he heard a quick gasp that was almost submerged in the crowd noise.

Ron stared at Harry with something akin to horror. “You’re daft, you know?”

“Do you know you’ve got something on your nose?” Harry replied, smiling.

Percy showed up at this point and Harry and Ron smiled at each other as the twins proceeded to heckle their older brother mercilessly. Ron kept surreptitiously peering at him until Harry simply lifted up his fringe so Ron could see his scar. The boy flushed a little but still leaned forward to look. Harry was tempted to use his Legilimency to see what he was thinking, but he drew the line at using it on his friends. During the war, he only used it on enemies, potential hostiles, and to communicate with allies who also possessed the skill. Harry was tempted, but knew that he needed to set some limits and stick to them.

As the train set off the twins leaned out the windows to wave goodbye. Harry leaned out the next window, ostensibly to look around.

“Don’t cry, Ginny, we’ll send you loads of owls.”

“We’ll send you a Hogwarts toilet seat.”

“George!”

“We’ll get Harry to autograph it.”

“Fred!”

“We’re only joking, Mum.”

Ginny was laughing and running along the platform as the train picked up speed. Harry raised his hand and waved to her, and he saw her wave back before the train rounded the corner. Harry smiled as he settled down in his seat again. He wouldn’t be able to see her for almost a year now, but at least he had built a good start. He sighed and wondered how many letters he’d end up writing this year.

Ron was still looking at him funny.

“I’m really glad to be getting out of town,” Harry explained.

“I heard you were sent to live with some Muggle relatives. What are they like?”

Harry sighed. “Not too bad, except for the fact that they hated my parents and wish I’d died with them.”

Ron made a choking sound.

Harry shrugged. “They can’t stand the whole idea of magic, and thought if they beat me often enough, I’d decide to be normal,” he said bitterly.

“That’s awful,” Ron said in barely more than a whisper. At one time the look of pity in his eyes would have angered Harry, but he’d grown past that. He also hoped that giving Ron as unvarnished a look as possible into the life of the Boy Who Lived would kill any jealousy issues before they even got started.

Ron tried to cheer Harry up by describing the downsides to being the youngest son in a family full of brilliant wizards. As he listened to the boy’s litany, Harry wondered if he could do something about Ron’s sense of inferiority compared to his brothers. That was something even more delicate, but Harry didn’t really want to wait until fifth or sixth year for him to finally get over it. Ron needed to find his own identity and get comfortable with it. He settled for commiserating about not having money, and told Ron stories about the awful hand-me-downs he’d gotten from Dudley over the years.

When Ron pulled Scabbers out of his jacket, Harry jerked back with a hiss. Sitting asleep in Ron’s hand was the bastard who’d betrayed his parents to Voldemort. It took a moment before Harry could get his hands to stop shaking. It would be so easy to kill him now, but Merlin knew what it would do to their time line.

Ron flinched back, cradling his pet protectively against his chest. Harry noticed his reaction and started apologizing. “Sorry about that Ron, you just, kind of startled me. I’ve had a couple of bad experiences with rats, wild ones you know. It just took me by surprise. My aunt and uncle, they, well, never mind.”

Ron looked apologetic. “Sorry, I just didn’t think, I—”

Harry held up his hand. “Nobody got hurt, so I think we should stop apologizing to each other.”

Ron smiled, a little sheepishly, and they got past an awkward moment.

When the woman with the snack cart came by, Harry was hit by an inspiration as he again purchased a wide variety of sweets. Ron’s ears went pink and he muttered about having brought sandwiches. Harry looked at him out of the corner of his eye and asked what kind.

Ron unwrapped the package and made a face. “Corned beef,” he sighed.

“Really?” Harry asked happily. “That’s my favourite!” He looked down at the sweets on the seat next to him and frowned. “I don’t suppose you’d be willing to take some of this junk for one your sandwiches, would you?”

Ron looked at Harry like he’d gone mental.

“Damn, I suppose not,” Harry sighed, grinning ruefully. “Can’t blame a bloke for trying, can you?”

Wide-eyed, Ron handed him a sandwich. Harry gleefully shoved a handful of pastries and cakes toward his friend, and then dug into the sandwich with obvious relish. He was glad he’d bought a bottle of pumpkin juice, because it was a bit dry. On the other hand, he’d gotten out of the habit of eating a lot of sweets after everything had gone to hell in the future, and Molly Weasley’s cooking was something he’d loved, even if it was just a leftover sandwich.

Harry ended up trading the majority of his goodies for three of Ron’s sandwiches, and acted like he’d still gotten the far better deal. Ron held onto the last sandwich and chewed it slowly, staring at Harry all the while.

“I suppose it makes sense, with as many boys to feed as your Mum has, she’d have to be a fantastic cook,” Harry said thoughtfully. “I don’t know what she does differently, but her corned beef tastes a lot better than mine.”

“You know how to cook?” Ron asked, a little incredulously.

Harry shrugged. “My aunt and uncle make me do most of the cooking and cleaning. It’s not like I had much choice. I think that’s a big part of the reason why they didn’t want me to know about Hogwarts. My cousin won’t do any chores, so they’re going to be stuck while I’m away.” Harry smiled a little vindictively while Ron shook his head.

Soon they were both full and just nibbling. Ron explained about the Chocolate Frog cards and Harry stuck the Dumbledore card he’d been given into a pocket. He might need to drop that clue about Nicolas Flamel at some point in the future.

They were sampling the Bertie Bott’s Every Flavour Beans when Neville stuck his head into the compartment, asking if they’d seen his toad. The boy looked depressed when they said they hadn’t, so Harry spoke up. “I think there is a charm you can learn to summon things. That might help out next time he goes on walkabout.”

Neville brightened a bit at that, and then left to resume his search. Ron was just getting ready to try and turn Scabbers yellow, a colour which Harry felt to be highly appropriate for the rat, when the door opened again and a very familiar bushy-haired girl asked if they’d seen Neville’s toad.

Having already seen two of his oldest friends that day, Harry was better able to control his reactions this time. It was probably just as well that he’d run into Hermione last. She tended to pick up on things other people missed.

After Ron’s spell failed to turn Scabbers yellow, Harry decided to try and smooth out some first impressions.

“Are you sure that’s a real spell?” Hermione asked. “Well, it’s not very good is it? I’ve—”

“Ron,” Harry interjected, “did you get that spell from Fred or George?”

“George,” Ron answered with dawning comprehension.

“Your brother was just winding you up, mate,” Harry confirmed.

“Well, that wasn’t very nice of him, was it? Trying to make his brother look foolish is just mean,” the bossy girl fumed.

At least she’s being bossy on Ron’s behalf this time, Harry thought with a laugh. He watched Ron’s eyes get wide as Hermione went off on a rant about how hard she was working to learn magic, and George’s joke was just like all the myths that surround magic in Muggle society and make it harder for someone new to the art to understand what was really going on. She concluded with “—and that’s really a sore point for me as nobody in my family is magic at all. My name’s Hermione Granger, by the way. And you are?”

“Ron Weasley.”

“Harry Potter.”

“Are you really?” she asked in a delighted tone. “I read about you in Modern Magical History, The Rise and Fall of the Dark Arts, and Great Wizarding Events of the Twentieth Century.”

“Don’t believe everything you read,” Harry practically growled. He did end up reading all those books eventually in the future, and each one of them was laughably wrong on the major points.

Hermione blinked. “Why ever not?” she asked, sounding almost appalled.

“Books still have to be written by people, Hermione,” Harry said gently. “They say that history books are written by the victors. The only person that was there that night and is still alive is sitting right here, and I sure haven’t given any interviews, mainly because I’m not even sure what happened. So how could they honestly claim to know?”

Hermione looked a little stunned as she drank this all in. One of the less endearing traits she was starting to develop was the habit of depending on her books first and foremost for everything. Hopefully the seed Harry planted today would help her to recognize that blind spot before it came back to bite her too many times.

“Well, that is something to think about. Are you hoping to get sorted into Ravenclaw, Harry? I’m hoping for Gryffindor, that’s where they say Professor Dumbledore was sorted, but Ravenclaw wouldn’t be too bad I suppose.”

Harry shook his head. “My Mum and Dad were both Gryffindors, so that’s where I’ll go. Ron too.”

“How did you know that Harry?”

Damn, I got to watch myself, Harry stopped himself from wincing just in time. “Ron, everyone’s heard of the Weasleys: Red hair, lots of boys, and too damn brave to end up anywhere but Gryffindor.”

Ron ducked his head to cough, but Harry noted his ears had turned a delicate shade of fuchsia.

“Well, I don’t have any family traditions to guide me here,” Hermione fretted.

“I heard someone say that if you really want to go into a particular house, and make your desire clear during the sorting process, it will almost always send you to that house.” Let them think I heard it from a parent today, Harry mused, rather than coming out of my own mouth a life time ago.

The girl looked thoughtful for a moment, then thanked them and left to continue searching for Neville’s toad.

“I’m not sure I’m too crazy about her being in the same house with us, Harry,” Ron said slowly, staring at the closed door.

“I am. I think she’ll be right handy when we’re revising.”

“You’re already talking about homework? Harry, we’re not even to Hogsmeade yet!”

“Ron, I have to take it pretty seriously. If you flunk out, you go back home to your mother’s cooking. I’m not so lucky; if I flunk out I go back to hell with the Dursleys.”

Ron made a face at Harry’s remark about how lucky he was. “She still seems kind of mental to me,” he said stubbornly.

“You mean when she was getting mad about George tricking you with that fake spell? Ron, she was getting mad on your behalf you know.” Harry stopped and cracked an evil smirk. “Maybe she fancies you?” he asked.

Ron choked and coughed. “Harry, that’s not funny,” he gasped.

“No funnier than you harassing me about talking to your sister.”

Ron let out a quiet snort. “You’re an odd duck, Harry.”

You have no idea, old friend, Harry thought sadly. There was still such a long way to go.

3

Making Waves

Harry relaxed a bit as he and Ron talked about safer topics: Charlie and Bill’s careers, the attempted break-in at Gringotts, and, inevitably, Quidditch. Hearing his friend talk about their favourite sport was like coming home again after a long journey, and Harry didn’t have to feign a happy smile.

He was caught completely off guard when Draco Malfoy, along with his bodyguards Crabbe and Goyle, entered the compartment.

Mentally kicking himself for dropping his guard, Harry had tremendous difficulty controlling his rage. The blond ferret before him directly contributed to Dumbledore’s death. There was no proof one way or the other whether Draco participated in the Hogwarts Massacre, but the cruelty of some of the wounds inflicted on Ginny’s body made Harry wonder. It was all he could do to stop himself from pulling out his wand and obliterating the Death Eater in training.

“Is it true?” the boy asked, eyeing Harry. “They’re saying all down the train that Harry Potter is in this compartment.”

“That would be me,” Harry replied in a low voice.

“This is Crabbe and Goyle,” Draco said, gesturing at the two hulking boys. “My name’s Malfoy, Draco Malfoy.”

As Ron coughed, Harry growled, “I know who you are.”

Draco glared at Ron. “I can see you’ve been hanging out with the wrong sort. Some Wizarding families are better than others, and you don’t want to make friends with the wrong sort. I can help you there,” he said coolly, extending his hand.

Harry just glared. “The wrong sort? You mean like former Death Eaters who bribed their way out of Azkaban? You didn’t want to help me when we were in Madam Malkin’s, but now that you know my name everything’s changed. I’ll make my own friends, thanks.”

Draco’s eyes widened like he’d been slapped and an angry flush rose from the collar of his robes. “You’d better watch what you say, Potter, or you’ll end up like your parents. I can see how hanging around with a Weasley would degrade your manners though. They’re a poor excuse for family, and I do mean poor.”

Ron sprang to his feet as Harry’s fist crashed into Draco’s jaw. Crabbe and Goyle just stared in shock as Draco fell backwards into the corridor. The two hulking boys reached for Harry but Goyle let out an explosive breath as Ron charged into him, driving the top of his head into the larger boy’s stomach and knocking them both to the ground.

Crabbe’s meaty hand engulfed Harry’s shoulder, spinning him around. Harry went with the motion and locked his hands around the boy’s wrist before he could even begin to throw a punch. Still turning, Harry crouched down as the boy’s arm was stretched across his shoulders. A moment later, Harry jerked forward and the larger boy was pulled off his feet and landed in the middle of the compartment with a loud thud.

He spun toward Goyle just as the enormous boy was trying to pin Ron underneath his bulk. He stiffened in agony when Harry kicked him hard in the lower back, right over the kidney.

“Let him up before I break your skull,” Harry hissed. Goyle flinched again and unwrapped his hands from around Ron’s neck.

“Should have known you’d fight like a filthy Muggle, Potter,” Draco snarled from the doorway. He was standing again, but clutched at his jaw with one hand. The other hand held a wand.

“If you want to escalate things to that level, go ahead,” Harry said in a soft voice. His wand was still in his trunk, but he didn’t really care. “I’ll even give you the first shot.” He stared directly into the pale boy’s eyes. “Just remember that you have a choice to make of what to do with your life. And also remember that I was a baby when I destroyed your father’s master. Choose wisely, Draco.”

Draco’s eyes were wide as Crabbe and Goyle dragged themselves out of the compartment. He stood there, unmoving, as the door slid shut again.

Harry turned and helped Ron to his feet. The red-headed boy was rubbing at his bruised neck as he sat down again. “Blimey, Harry, where’d you learn to do that?”

“Read it in a book about Muggle martial arts. I can loan it to you if you like.” Harry neglected to mention some of the combat training his older self had received from the Order of the Phoenix. Ron had been his sparring partner for years. This time around, he’d like to get a head start on training like that if he could.

Ron nodded eagerly as Hermione pushed the compartment door open again. “What’s been going on in here? You weren’t fighting with those boys, were you?” she asked. “You’ll be in trouble before you even get to the school!”

“Hermione,” Harry said in a long-suffering tone that made him feel nostalgic for some reason, “we didn’t start it. Draco Malfoy came into our compartment and insulted both our families. He started it, and we finished it, all right?”

“Seriously,” Ron added. “My dad’s told me about the Malfoys. They supported You-Know-Who during the war, and then turned around and said they’d been bewitched. Dad said that Malfoy’s father didn’t need an excuse to go over to the Dark Side.” Ron frowned for a moment. “Hermione, be careful around Draco. You said your parents were Muggles, and the Malfoys think people like you shouldn’t be allowed at Hogwarts.”

“That’s perfectly ridiculous,” Hermione said crossly, glaring at Ron.

Ron looked down. “That’s what my dad says too.” He coughed. “I mean, he thinks the Malfoys are ridiculous for saying that.” His face was getting redder by the minute.

“My Mum was Muggle-born,” Harry said, trying to help Ron out of the hole he’d dug, “and she was Head Girl when she finished school.”

“Really?” Hermione gasped as her eyes widened.

She looked so surprised that Harry frowned. Then it dawned on him. He and Hermione had talked about many things, but her drive to excel in her studies was such a part of her nature that he never questioned it. He knew it stung her when Malfoy and others would call her a Mudblood, but Harry wondered if she drove herself so hard because she felt she had something to prove.

“Well, I was raised by Muggles, so I’m practically Muggle-born too.” Harry smiled. “We ought to all study together and pick Ron’s brain.”

Ron looked alarmed when Harry mentioned brain-picking, but reddened when he noticed Hermione eyeing him speculatively. “I don’t know that much, really,” he said. “Mum won’t let me practise at home, not even cleaning charms or anything.”

“Ron, it’s not the spells, it’s the little details, like how do you heat water for tea? Is it a spell, or do you have magical appliances to cook with?” Hermione reassured him. “Think of it more like… one of those Muggle Studies classes I’ve read the second year students can take, only in reverse.”

“Ginny said she’d help me too,” Harry said quietly. “We can compare notes as well.” He knew he wouldn’t be able to hide his letter writing from his dorm-mates, so best to get it out in the open now.

Ron looked at Harry, frowning, but he didn’t say anything.

“Goodness,” Hermione said. “I forgot. The conductor said we’d be getting there soon. You’d better get into your robes!”

“Yes Ma’am,” Harry said, chuckling. Somehow Hermione’s bossiness didn’t bother him nearly as much this time around.

Harry couldn’t resist breaking into a huge grin when Hagrid asked him how he was doing. “He rescued me from the Dursleys and told me I was a wizard!” he explained to Ron. He wasn’t going to keep any secrets he didn’t have to. Harry already felt guilty enough about the way he was manipulating things. He was deep in his thoughts as they made their way down to the lake. Remember the things Ron told you after Hermione died. He missed her so badly, his only regret was that they took so long to realize how they felt. There’s no way he could have loved her so much in the future and not feel anything for her in this timeline. I’m just going to… help things along a little bit. When everything is settled, I can always tell them everything and give them the option of hexing me. Maybe I am playing God a little, but I can’t just do nothing and let things happen. I wouldn’t be able to live with myself. Besides, we’re going to need every advantage if we want to stop that ghoul before he starts killing everyone.

Harry’s thoughts cut off as they rounded the last bend and saw Hogwarts, perched on the mountain above the lake, lights glimmering from every window. His heart climbed into his throat and he felt like crying. Seeing the old castle, unburned and whole, was like finding another long-lost friend. Harry heard the sound of water drops pattering on broken stones, echoing out of his memory. He vowed that he would never let that happen again. Not to the first place he’d ever felt at home.

He was silent as he boarded the boat with Ron, Hermione, and Neville. The chubby boy looked nervous and afraid, nothing like the confident and grim-faced young man he’d left in charge of the DA. I as good as killed him, Harry thought to himself, I owe him too. “Longbottom…” he whispered.

Neville looked up from his frightened contemplation of the black waters of the lake.

“Your parents are Aurors, aren’t they?”

“Er, yes, well, they were…” Neville muttered, his voice trailing off. “I live with my gran now.”

Harry hated to remind Neville of his parents in St. Mungo’s, but he needed to forge a connection here. “Sorry, Neville, someone… I think someone mentioned that your parents were friends of my parents.”

Neville looked up, startled. “Gran says they were pretty popular.”

“Well, I don’t have any magical relatives, so I’m glad I got to meet you, Neville. Any idea where you’ll get sorted?”

“Not-not really,” Neville stammered. “I’m amazed I even got a letter.”

“Well, the three of us are hoping for Gryffindor. I hope you get sorted there too.”

“I’m not that brave,” the round-faced boy whispered miserably. “I’m even terrified I’m going to fall into the lake.”

“But you’re still here,” Harry reminded him. “Being brave isn’t not being afraid. Being brave is being afraid and going ahead and doing what you have to do.”

Neville looked thoughtful, but didn’t disagree. Harry eased back in his seat and looked around. Ron was gazing out across the lake at the cave they were approaching, but Hermione was looking at Harry and frowning slightly. Harry began examining the cliff face they were approaching.

Everything after that proceeded as anticipated. Minerva McGonagall was the same as he remembered. A good heart, but scary as hell – he missed her nonetheless. At least this time around he’d try to do a better job in her transfiguration class.

He stood nervously with the other first year students, not wanting to join in the speculation about exactly how they’d be sorted into their houses. He didn’t trust himself not to reassure his new friends, and Hermione was standing right next to him, mumbling spells under her breath. If she was getting suspicious of him, the last thing Harry needed to do was draw her attention again.

Finally, they were led into the Great Hall, where the Hat was ready with this year’s new song. One by one, they were called to be sorted. Harry closed his eyes for a moment and made sure his Occlumency shields were up.

When his name was called, Harry ignored the cries from the older students. That was getting bloody old the first time around, he mused disgustedly. He sat on the stool and pulled the Sorting Hat over his head with some trepidation.

“Well, well, well, what do we have here?” a small voice asked in his ear. “I can sense you’ve already been sorted, but that’s impossible because I’d remember sorting the last of the Potters.”

I imagine you would, Harry thought sardonically.

“Yes, yes. So how did you… interesting.”

Harry strengthened his mental barriers as much as he could, but whatever the Sorting Hat was doing wasn’t interacting with his Occlumency at all.

“It isn’t often I run into something I haven’t seen before, Mr. Potter. I see another Hogwarts, and another Hat. One you were forced to destroy.”

Sorry, but I didn’t have time to do it any other way. I had to do it quickly before Voldemort realized it was a trap, Harry admitted. He still had some lingering guilt about destroying the hat in his original timeline, even though what he just said was the truth.

“No, I see the other Hogwarts was gone, and so its purpose had fled as well. Your plan is an audacious one; you seek to meddle with the workings of Fate itself.”

Well, I had literally nothing left to lose, Harry thought bitterly.

“True. I wish you well in this endeavour. Never fear, I will keep your secrets. The more who know the greater the risk.”

Thank you. Er, would it be possible to ask for one small favour?

“What favour is that?”

Well, Hermione was already sorted into Gryffindor, and I know you’ll put Ron and his sister there as well. But there is a new student next year named Luna Lovegood. She’ll be sorted into Ravenclaw, but she’ll have a pretty bad time of it. She’ll become a good friend, but I think the harassment from her own house was not a good thing for her. Could you possibly put her in Gryffindor where I can keep an eye on her?

“I see what you remember. I will allow this, unless she is completely opposed to your house, which I doubt will be the case. Matchmaking is at worst the most minor of sins, Mr. Potter, but are you prepared to deal with the consequences of your meddling?”

It’s what I came here to do.

“Very well. Though I must congratulate you on a plan worthy of the most cunning Slytherin, I had best send you on to your future friends in GRYFFINDOR!”

Harry slumped as the Sorting Hat shouted the last word, and the table under the red and gold banner erupted in applause. He swept the hat off his head and placed it gently on the stool. He gave it a gentle pat on the brim as if to say thanks and ran over to the all too familiar table.

He shook Percy’s hand with enthusiasm and laughed at the twins’ cheers. He barely caught his breath before his eyes strayed to the High Table. He smiled faintly at the familiar sight of his professors, and tried not to think about the broken bodies pulled from a shattered Hogwarts. He swallowed convulsively when he saw the headmaster’s brilliant blue eyes twinkling through his half-moon glasses. Harry frantically shoved all his strength into reinforcing his Occlumency shields again, and that had the desired calming effect.

Harry wrenched his gaze away just in time to hear Ron sorted into Gryffindor. He abruptly stood up and started clapping, making his palms sting as he gave vent to his emotions. The twins joined him in standing a moment later, and surprisingly, so did Percy. Another moment later Hermione and Neville, who was only now recovering from the shock of being sorted into Gryffindor, stood as well, clapping and cheering. Soon the rest of the table joined in as well.

Ron’s face was almost purple by the time Percy shook his hand in an overly formal manner, but he was beaming when his brother showed him to his seat.

Harry hadn’t been to a Hogwarts feast in almost fifteen years. After Dumbledore’s typical abbreviated speech, he dug in with enthusiasm. He was determined not to be a scrawny little runt forever this time around. He was so happy to be there that he was hoping he didn’t accidentally levitate the whole table. Harry actively concentrated on his happiness. He didn’t want to look around at his classmates, most of whom would meet terrible deaths. If he was going to do what he needed to do, he had to find a way to deal with his grief. He’d been alone for much of his early life, and the last year in his old life he’d been totally bereft of friends. This would be easier if he had someone he could talk to… someone to talk about what was really going on. His short conversation with the Sorting Hat made that abundantly clear. He’d just have to wait.

And maybe write a lot of letters.

As everyone grew full and dessert was served, Harry helped himself to a generous serving of treacle tart and listened to the buzz of half-remembered conversations around him. When he glanced up at the High Table and saw Professor Snape glaring at him past Professor Quirrell’s turban, Harry felt a subtle probing at his Occlumency shields. It faded after a few seconds and he continued eating his dessert without being interrupted by a burst of pain from his scar.

Things were looking up for Harry Potter.

From the partially burned sign by the street, the building used to be a Muggle orphanage. Now it was a charnel house, reeking of wood smoke and burnt flesh. The three of them flew over on their brooms as soon as they saw the Dark Mark glowing balefully in the evening sky over Manchester.

Hermione, with Ron’s help, overcame her nervousness about flying, and they tore across the night sky as fast as their brooms could go. For all the good it did them, they could have walked.

The Death Eaters were long gone by the time they got there, Apparating away to safe houses and pureblood mansions alike. They left nothing alive.

Still forms littered the lawn. A few of the more quick-witted children had tried to escape through windows or fire exits. Some appeared to have jumped. All had been cut down by curses, Death Eaters probably laughing at their efforts to escape the flames.

Harry, Ron, and Hermione stood, rooted in shock and horror. The memories of the Hogwarts Massacre were still fresh, but this was even worse. At least someone had been able to fight back before. These children, some as young as four or five, were completely helpless. Wizards and witches drunk on the power of Dark Magic tortured and murdered them for no purpose other than satisfying their own sadistic urges.

Ron and Hermione clung to each other, and Harry could hear one or both of them sobbing quietly. He stood there numbly until his eyes were drawn to a flash of red.

A breeze generated by the roaring flames stirred the hair of a little girl, no more than ten or eleven. Bright red hair spread out like a fan on the ground around her head, and glassy eyes stared up into infinity. Harry had a sudden urge to close them, but couldn’t move his feet. He knew those eyes would prove to be brown. She looked just like Ginny had, all those years ago, lying on the cold stone floor in the Chamber of Secrets. But this girl wouldn’t revive when he killed Tom Riddle’s diary. She was dead forever, just like his Ginny…

Harry threw back his head and screamed. He brought up his wand in both hands, holding it almost like a sword. He didn’t even remember shouting an incantation before a massive bolt of lightning erupted from the end of his wand. Harry was blown backward off his feet, the tip of his wand smoking, as the Dark Mark was wiped from the sky.

Harry woke up with Ron shaking his shoulder hard enough to make his teeth rattle. He blinked and sat up. Neville, Dean, and Seamus were all gathered around his bed as well. Harry blinked for a moment before he realized he’d had a nightmare, and evidently woke everyone with his screaming. “Oh hell, I’m sorry, guys,” he said miserably.

“Do you always have nightmares like that?” Ron asked in a quiet voice.

“Some-sometimes,” Harry admitted shakily. “I’ve had them on and off for a while.” Like over thirteen years.

“Is it because of You Know Who?” Dean asked quickly.

Ron shot him a furious glare, but Harry answered. “Yeah, it is.”

I’m going to need to ‘learn’ silencing charms first thing, Harry noted grimly. After reassuring Ron several times that he was okay, and that he didn’t need the school nurse, the other boys eventually returned to their beds.

After a while, Harry got up and padded out to the common room. Fortunately, everyone else appeared to be asleep, preparing for the first day of the new term. Harry looked around at a room that had been such a fixture in his life at Hogwarts. He had to hurry through here last night, claiming to be tired to hide his reaction.

His eyes began to prickle, so Harry walked over to one of the deep-set windows and looked out across the darkened grounds. I had no idea it would be this hard, Harry mused. It’s just so… difficult… to see all the things I lost, and not show any emotion whatsoever. Merlin, this is going to be a long year. He grimaced and leaned his forehead against the cold glass. After a moment he crept up to his dormitory and retrieved parchment and a quill from his trunk. There was little chance of sleep for him the rest of this night, so he sat down at the table nearest the fire and began to write.

‘Dear Ginny,’ he began.

Harry chronicled the train ride, the sorting ceremony, and most of the feast before dawn began to creep over the mountains. The steady scratching of quill on parchment was like a balm for his nerves. By the time he heard people stirring in the dormitories, he felt oddly calm, like he’d been drained of his excess emotions. He blotted the half-full page and placed it on the stack with the rest. Somehow writing it down helped almost as much as talking about it, with the added bonus that he could choose his words with care. He had to remind himself more than once that this was a much younger Ginny than he remembered, one who barely knew him – though he planned to change that as quickly as possible. For now, he would do his best to get to know her again, and let her see the real Harry Potter. If that didn’t get her completely past her initial shyness, well, he’d cross that bridge when he got to it.

Harry folded the stack of parchment and carried it upstairs with him. His roommates were just starting to awaken, so he quickly shoved the partially completed letter into his bag and went to take a shower.

The first week of classes was the same maelstrom of confusion he remembered. While Harry knew his way around a lot better than the last time, he also had to be careful he didn’t display a suspicious degree of familiarity with the castle. Harry reacted to his teachers’ introductions much the same as he did before, with one exception. Flitwick falling off his chair during the roll call still brought an embarrassed smile to his face, one that Ron shared this time. He was able to meet McGonagall’s eyes a little better this time around, but Quirrell was as nervous and distant as before. Harry sighed, but he knew there was nothing really to be done for the Defence professor. His fate had been sealed in Albania when Voldemort possessed his body.

Snape was another matter entirely. Harry checked his Occlumency barrier for the fifth time Friday morning as they descended into the dungeon where the potions lab was located. At least the note from Hagrid asking him to tea that afternoon gave him something to look forward to. He stayed silent as he set his things on the table and prepared his parchment for taking notes. He looked up without flinching when the potions master swept into the room.

As before, the man started in on him during roll call. “Ah yes, Harry Potter. Our new – celebrity.”

This time, Harry ignored Malfoy and his cronies. He locked gazes with the man as soon as he looked up at the class. Those black eyes were as cold and dark as he remembered, but this time he could detect the subtle thrust of Legilimency, probing at his shields. Harry maintained his barriers, but allowed a patina of uncertainty and doubt to creep through. Those were emotions he had in abundance, and would be less suspicious than a total lack of presence. The Occlumency books he’d read after Sirius’ death in the Department of Mysteries claimed that some people were born with a natural gift for the art, and were almost impossible to read beyond basic emotional reactions.

A crease appeared between the professor’s eyebrows as he held forth on the intricacies of potion making. It was his only reaction to being blocked out of Harry’s mind. For his own part, Harry had to struggle to remain impassive. Knowledge that his father’s nemesis had been rifling through his mind from day one angered the boy beyond belief. He snapped out of his quiet fuming when the man fired a question at him.

“Potter! What would I get if I added powdered root of asphodel to an infusion of wormwood?”

“Draught of Living Death, sir,” Harry fired back with no hesitation. The silence in the class was palpable. Even Snape blinked. Harry remembered five years of the hateful man’s potion classes, a much better year with Slughorn, and he’d even gone through his books again in the last week of August, just for this moment.

“Where would I find a bezoar?” the man snapped. He also stepped up his Legilimency, battering at Harry’s shields.

“Inside the stomach of a goat,” Harry replied evenly. He tried not to cringe at the memory of Ron almost dying from the poisoned mead.

“What is the difference between monkshood and wolfsbane?”

“Nothing sir, they are the same plant. Muggle botanists call it aconite.”

“What is the most popular use of armadillo bile?”

“That would be the Wit-Sharpening potion,” Harry replied frowning. That was a potion on the fourth year syllabus.

“Frozen ashwinder eggs?”

“Er, love potions, professor.”

“Powdered moonstone and syrup of hellebore, Potter. What potion uses both ingredients?”

“That would be the Draught of Peace, sir.” He wouldn’t forget botching that one in his fifth year, not any time soon. Snape was trying to trip him up with much more advanced material than Harry could possibly know. The fact that the boy still knew the answers must be driving the man mad. Harry knew he was being a little indiscreet, but he couldn’t help himself.

“Pomegranate juice?”

“Strengthening solution, sir.”

“When must fluxweed be gathered to be useful for potion making?”

“During the full moon, sir,” Harry replied. Snape’s face was darkening and the class had gone utterly silent, save for the scratch-scratch of Hermione’s quill as she quickly scribbled notes.

“What are the uses of ginger root, Mr. Potter?”

“I believe it’s also used in the Wit-Sharpening potion. Oh, and it’s good in Chinese stir-fry.” That got a quiet cough from Dean Thomas, who Harry remembered was Muggle-born.

That got a furious glare from Professor Snape, who continued to fire questions at Harry for more than fifteen minutes. Harry had a steadily worsening tension headache, but managed to answer each question in turn. Finally, the professor appeared to have grown tired of his game.

“What are jobberknoll feathers used for?”

“I believe that would be memory potions, sir.”

“Like the one you took before this class, Potter?” the professor snapped. “How else do you explain your encyclopaedic knowledge of potion ingredients? Decided to show off in front of your peers? Grab a little limelight?”

“Not at all,” Harry responded coolly. “I just read a bit ahead after I got my books.” He paused for a moment. “It’s not like this is really hard, is it? You just get the ingredients together and follow the instructions.” He shrugged. “Just like cooking, isn’t it?” he asked innocently.

Harry had to hold himself rigid to keep from wincing, both at the look on Snape’s face and the sudden furious thrust of the man’s Legilimency. Harry’s barriers still held, which no doubt infuriated the man even more.

“Of all the insufferable—” Snape exploded. “Damn Potters! Out! All of you! And one hundred points from Gryffindor for your bloody cheek, Potter!”

Nobody questioned this; the students just grabbed their bags and ran, most of the Slytherins as well. When they got back to the Gryffindor common room, most of the first years were pale with shock. Their class had lost a hundred points during the first week, and they did not want to face the older students when word got out.

Harry was gratified that no one directly blamed him for that fiasco, but he was furious at Snape all over again. He angrily pitched his bag into one of the squashy chairs and began to pace, hands clasped behind his back and cursing like a sailor under his breath. He jerked and spun around when someone touched him on the shoulder.

Hermione flinched back. Behind her, Ron and Neville watched him apprehensively.

Harry took a deep breath and blew it out. “Sorry,” he said.

The bushy-haired girl waved that off. “How did you know all those things?” she asked impatiently.

Harry blinked. Trust Hermione to be more concerned with this, rather than the house points. “Well, after I bought my books, I was stuck at home with the Muggles and had nothing to do, so I read a lot. Potions was the easiest thing to study, since I wouldn’t be tempted to do underage magic.”

She brightened at that. “So you spent your summer studying?”

“A good bit of it, yes. Not like I had much choice, but I wanted to make a good start. Look where that got me…”

“Don’t worry about it,” Ron said. “Fred and George told me that Snape hates all the Gryffindors. He takes points from them all the time for no good reason. All my brothers hate the greasy git,” he continued, looking thoughtful, “except maybe Percy. He gets along with all the professors.”

“I doubt any of your brothers lost a hundred house points in one go,” Harry said dubiously.

“Maybe not,” Ron agreed. “But I think you just gave Fred and George a new goal.”

Hermione made an exasperated sound while Harry shook his head. He sank down on one of the couches and held his aching head. Just sitting there letting Snape pound on his mind without retaliating was more exhausting than he thought it would be. He looked up when Neville sat down next to him.

“Harry,” the boy said, a little hesitantly, “are you all right?”

“I’m fine, Nev,” he replied, and cursed himself for slipping and using his friend’s nickname, one that wouldn’t be coined for several years yet.

Neville looked at him a little funny, but then got a very determined expression on his face. Harry felt his stomach flip over when he saw the boy set his jaw and frown, seeing the ghost of the friend who stood beside him in the Department of Mysteries.

“Harry, he had no business docking you points for answering his questions, let alone taking so many. I’ve heard so many stories about the potions teacher at Hogwarts that I was a little afraid about taking his class. Now I see he’s just nothing more than a childish bully. As far as I’m concerned he can dock all the points he wants, it doesn’t stop him from being a sorry excuse for a wizard,” Neville declared.

“Neville!” Hermione exclaimed.

“You were there, Hermione,” Ron said.

“Yes, well,” Hermione dithered, “but you still shouldn’t talk about a professor that way.”

“That is correct, Miss Granger,” Professor McGonagall said as she entered the common room. “Now would someone like to explain why Professor Snape just entered the staff lounge on the brink of an apoplectic fit?”

Harry honestly expected everyone to point McGonagall his way and groaned silently. His head was pounding like it wanted to burst. Instead, Ron, Neville, and even Hermione moved toward their Head of House, all talking over each other and denouncing Snape’s behaviour. Harry felt a warm glow in the pit of his stomach as his friends rushed to his defence.

“Students, please! One at a time,” Professor McGonagall finally said. The three of them looked at each other and Hermione spoke up again, giving a quick summary of how Snape threw them all out of his classroom and docked Harry one hundred points. “Is this true, Mr. Potter?” the stern professor asked when she was done.

He nodded slowly, still rubbing at his temples. “And something is giving me an awful headache, worse than I can recall ever having.”

Harry didn’t miss the flash of concern in his Head of House’s eyes. “The headmaster requests your presence in his office. If your headache persists, I will accompany you to the infirmary for a pain-relieving potion.”

Harry sighed and followed her through the portrait hole.

When they arrived at the headmaster’s office, Snape was already waiting with Dumbledore. As he and McGonagall sat down, Harry could feel mental fingers probing at his shields. The ‘touch’ was much softer than Snape’s battering ram approach to Legilimency, and Harry guessed it was probably Professor Dumbledore’s curiosity getting the better of him. He winced, clapping his hands to the sides of his head, and the fingers immediately vanished. Harry looked around blearily. “Er, sorry,” he muttered, “I have a really bad headache.” He didn’t miss the glance the headmaster shot at the potions teacher.

“That’s all right, Harry,” the old man said in a soothing voice. “Did that perhaps contribute to the disruption that occurred during Professor Snape’s class this morning?”

“No sir,” Harry said firmly, ignoring the easy way out the headmaster had offered him. “My headache didn’t start until part way through the lesson, when, er, Professor Snape started in on me.” He ignored the venomous glare the potions master shot at him. Instead, Harry stared into Dumbledore’s twinkling blue eyes and wished he could tell his former mentor everything. He felt a feather-light touch on his shields and twitched in his chair, blinking.

“Headmaster, the behaviour of this spoiled Potter brat is outrageous! He should never—”

“Severus,” Dumbledore said softly. “Harry, would you care to explain what happened during the class?”

“Yes, sir, I’d like to do that. Do you have one of those Pensieve things? I heard two of the older students talking about how they use them to take testimony for wizarding courts.”

“I believe I can lay my hands on one, but wouldn’t it be simpler to just tell us what happened?”

Harry nodded. “I suppose so, but I thought it would save time. You see, I plan on filing a formal complaint with the Hogwarts Board of Governors, so—”

Harry did not get to complete his sentence. He felt the battering ram again, coming from Snape’s direction, slamming furiously into his Occlumency shields. Harry stiffened, arching his back. He reinforced his shields to full opacity as he slumped back in his chair, eyes rolled up in his head, apparently unconscious.

“Severus!” Dumbledore barked. Harry, relying on hearing alone now, had to stop himself from jumping. He’d never heard Albus speak so sharply before.

“This brat is hiding something from us, headmaster, and I intend to find out exactly what it is!”

“Albus, this is outrageous,” Minerva exclaimed. “I will not have one of my students attacked by a professor! What did you do to him, Severus?”

Harry was surprised to hear Minerva defend him so vehemently after only knowing him for a week.

“Minerva,” Dumbledore’s voice took on a soothing tone. “What just happened was not Severus’ intent.”

“Then what, pray tell, just happened?”

“Mr. Potter, it appears, is a natural Occlumens. Although untrained, he instinctively shields his thoughts and memories. It is a very rare talent, though perhaps it is a consequence of what happened to him that night. He apparently reacted to our colleague using his Legilimency in a very unfortunate manner.”

“Using his Legilimency?” Minerva hissed. “Severus Snape, you’ve been invading the minds of students? Of my students?” Professor McGonagall’s voice rose into a shriek that raised the hairs on the back of Harry’s neck.

He almost felt sorry for Snivellus. Almost.

“There is another possibility, headmaster,” Snape said coldly, ignoring the other professor. “The Dark Lord was a skilled Occlumens as well as Legilimens. It is… conceivable… that he took refuge within Potter’s body when the curse rebounded back. That would explain the boy having shields neither one of us could penetrate.”

“I don’t think Tom Riddle would be content to live quietly in a Muggle household for the past ten years, Severus,” Dumbledore stated calmly. “I also highly doubt he would consent to being sorted into Gryffindor.”

Harry had to suppress the urge to laugh and give himself away.

“If it will make you feel better though…” Harry heard sounds of movement. “Old friend, were you able to see into the boy’s mind when you sorted him?” Dumbledore asked the Sorting Hat.

“Oh yes,” the Sorting Hat replied in a smug voice.

Harry’s blood ran cold.

“Occlumency, or any other kind of mental barrier, means nothing to me once someone willingly places me upon their head.”

“Excellent! That is as I thought it would be,” Dumbledore sounded pleased. “And I take it there were no invading mental presences?” he asked.

“Oh no, no invaders at all. Nothing between his ears but Harry James Potter.”

Harry was pretty sure he hadn’t imagined the smug undertone in the Sorting Hat’s answer.

I definitely need to find a way to extract the Horcrux without destroying the hat. If they thought I might be Voldemort in disguise, there would be no way I would be allowed to go free until after they’d gone through my memories with a fine toothed comb. I owe it a big one.

“Now, if you two are quite finished with accusing my student of being a Dark Lord, I’d like to know what happened in that class that gave Severus the right to deduct one hundred house points.”

Harry never knew his Head of House had such a sarcastic sense of humour, but he loved her for it. He let out a low groan and tried to sit up.

“Harry,” Dumbledore said in a concerned voice. “It might be best if you went and visited Madam Pomfrey. You clearly aren’t feeling well, and we can always continue this discussion later.”

Harry allowed himself to be hustled out of the Headmaster’s office. Snape’s eyes still bored into him, but he kept his Legilimency in check. Harry decided to let the issue of the formal complaint drop for right now. McGonagall’s unexpected vehemence in his defence made him want to alter his approach. She slowed her usual brisk pace to match Harry’s.

The second floor main corridor was deserted, as most of the students were still in their classes. Harry cleared his throat. “Professor McGonagall?”

She looked over at him, her lips still pressed into a thin line. “Yes, Mr. Potter?”

“Thanks for going with me, er, up there. It was good to have someone on my side.”

She looked down at him, a little curiously. “Staff members do not take sides, Mr. Potter. You are my responsibility as a member of Gryffindor.”

Harry nodded thoughtfully. “Professor Snape knew my father, didn’t he?”

Professor McGonagall stopped dead in her tracks and stared at him. “How did you know that, Mr. Potter?”

“Well, when Professor Snape was screaming at me, he said ‘Damn Potters’, and I don’t have any brothers and sisters, so that would almost have to mean my dad, right?”

“That’s very observant of you,” she said quietly. “I suppose since he brought it up himself, it’s his own fault. Yes, he knew your father. They both attended Hogwarts in the same year, but they did not get along well at all. It isn’t very appropriate, but I suppose some animosity has carried forward because of that. You would do well to rise above it as best you can.”

“I suppose I should,” Harry said thoughtfully. “I don’t think you are overly fond of Professor Snape either, are you?”

“Mr. Potter, my personal likes and dislikes are none of your business. Now, we should be getting you to the infirmary.”

“I’m sorry, professor, but I just wanted to ask your advice on a decision I need to make.”

She looked at Harry curiously, but did not speak.

“Professor Dumbledore obviously doesn’t want me to present a complaint to the Board of Governors. I think an account of what happened this morning would raise some serious questions about whether that man should be allowed in a classroom. The question is will it create more problems than it solves if I get him sacked?”

McGonagall’s face broke into a concerned frown. “What, exactly, in your own words, did he do?”

Harry sighed. “Well, after a smart remark about me being famous, he started firing questions at me, asking about all kinds of potions ingredients. Every question I answered just made him angrier. Finally after a while he blew up and accused me of using a memory potion. When I explained that I’d read ahead during the summer, and it was a lot like my aunt’s cookbooks, he just exploded again. He screamed at me, ordered everyone out of the potions laboratory, and docked Gryffindor one hundred points.”

The transfiguration teacher couldn’t hide the appalled expression on her face.

Harry shook his head. “The man is a professional educator, and yet he lost it – completely lost it – in front of a room full of eleven year olds. That doesn’t sound right to me.”

Minerva sighed. “No, I suppose it doesn’t. Mr. Potter. Harry. I don’t agree with what he did, but I’m not sure he can be easily replaced. There are not many Potions masters who are willing to teach younger students who are not apprenticed directly to them. Professor Snape does have a lot to teach, at least to those who can deal with his… personal issues. It would cause a major disruption for many students, some of whom are preparing to take their O.W.L. and N.E.W.T. examinations, if he was to be fired at the beginning of the term and no immediate replacement was available.”

Harry frowned. “I don’t want to hurt other students. I’m just worried about how much damage a man like that can do if he’s left where he is.”

“If you wish, I can make some inquiries and see if there is someone available to replace him.”

“I’d appreciate that, professor,” Harry said, cracking his first genuine smile of the morning.

“Good. Now let’s get you to the infirmary so you can join your classmates in time for lunch.”

Harry thought back to his career counselling appointment in his fifth year, when Professor McGonagall backed him to the hilt against Umbridge. Although from the beginning she’d presented this stiff, formal image, he realized now that she really had been on his side all along.

He just hadn’t figured it out.

12

Doing the Mungo Shuffle

When Harry awoke, he was asked to drink several potions in quick succession. The fact that he could now safely drink normal restorative potions would accelerate his recovery, Healer Stanhope informed him cheerfully.

Helpful or not, the potions also put him out like a lamp.

When he awoke again, he had visitors. He also had a wide variety of sensations passing through his body. Not the least of these was the needles-poking-through-my-flesh feeling he associated with Skele-Gro potions. That was currently running through his forearm, several ribs, and just a hint was emanating from the back of his neck. The muscles of his stomach and abdomen were extremely tender and even breathing seemed to stretch them intolerably. At least that bulky poultice was off his neck. While still bandaged, he could turn his head a little now.

It was when he was testing this that he saw his visitors. Mr. and Mrs. Weasley were sitting next to the bed. Mrs. Weasley had a copy of Witch Weekly in her hands while Mr. Weasley was dozing with his head propped up on one hand.

Mrs. Weasley looked up and her eyes widened. “Arthur,” she whispered, nudging her husband. “Hello, Harry,” she said brightly. “You’re looking a lot better. This is my husband, Arthur.”

Harry felt a little odd, being introduced to a man he’d grown so close to before he died. Fortunately, his emotions wouldn’t be that obvious surrounded by a sea of discomfort. “Hello,” he rasped, and grimaced.

Mrs. Weasley began fussing with the water glass, but this time Harry was able to use his right hand, though there was a bandage wrapped around his forearm. After a sip, he made a face. The inside of his mouth tasted like an old boot. “I guess they had some doxy antivenin,” he said.

Mrs. Weasley smiled. “You’re at St. Mungo’s, so I imagine so. One of the healers recognized the bite marks right off.”

Harry nodded. He’d been worried the wound sat untreated too long. “I wish I knew who sent them,” he muttered.

Mrs. Weasley frowned and Mr. Weasley excused himself. “Arthur is going to go fetch the Auror, dear. We agreed when they let us sit with you that we’d let them know first thing when you woke up.”

The door reopened after a moment and Mr. Weasley was followed by a tall black man that Harry immediately recognized.

“Hello, Mr. Potter,” he said in his deep voice, “I’m Kingsley Shacklebolt, I’m here to ask you some questions about your injuries, if you’re feeling up to it.”

Harry nodded and smiled. Kingsley had taught him more about duelling than most of his Defence teachers.

He’d also forgotten how perceptive the Auror was when the man frowned. “Have we met before, Mr. Potter?” he asked.

Harry’s smile widened in embarrassment. He needed to redirect the man’s curiosity. “Sorry. You, er, remind me of this Muggle actor…”

Kingsley smiled. “Ah, Samuel L. Jackson. Don’t worry, I consider it a compliment. He’s not a bad looking bloke.” He glanced over at the Weasleys. “If you’ll excuse us?” he asked.

As Mrs. Weasley rose from her chair, Harry spoke up. “You, er, can stay, if you like. Ron and the twins got in trouble for rescuing me; it’s only fair you know why.”

“Are you sure, Harry?” she asked.

Harry nodded and they all sat down.

“All right, Harry,” Kingsley began, taking out his little book. “Start where you feel most comfortable.”

Harry took a deep breath and told them pretty much everything that happened on his birthday, with the exception of his conversation with Dobby. He only indicated that an un-named house elf admitted he’d been holding Harry’s mail, but Harry persuaded the rogue elf to finally give it over.

“Someone sent you a box of doxies for your birthday?” Molly was outraged, but subsided when Kingsley looked at her.

Harry nodded. “I managed to kill two, but not before being bitten. Hedwig got one, but the last one was just about to blind her, so I had to use my wand to kill it.”

Kingsley nodded thoughtfully, but just waited for Harry to continue.

Talking about Vernon’s reaction was harder. He was angry at himself for letting things get that far, but he supposed it just appeared that he was angry at his uncle instead. He also let them think he was simply afraid to raise his wand against his uncle. The real reasons were a bit more complicated. By the time he was done describing Ron and the twins’ arrival he was glaring down at his blanket. The room was dead silent, and he realized that Mrs. Weasley was holding his hand.

After a long moment, Kingsley spoke up. “Mr. Potter, when my report is complete, I will be forwarding a copy to the Surrey Area Child Protection Committee with a recommendation for immediate prosecution. There will likely be a closed hearing at the Ministry scheduled after you are released to determine your legal status within the Wizarding world. I will also see Mrs. Hopkirk about having this warning removed from your record. The self-defence clause more than covers this.”

“Sir, will the Weasleys get in trouble for the, well, you know?”

“Ronald’s use of magic was in preventing further injury. I’ve already seen to that. As for the means of transportation,” at this he paused and grinned at Mr. Weasley, whose ears were turning red. “I’m afraid that’s out of my jurisdiction. In any event, my report focuses on what happened before they got there. I will go start the paperwork, but I believe these two would like to talk to you.” With that, the tall Auror stood up, nodded once to Harry, and left the room with a determined stride.

Harry looked over at the Weasleys, who were both suddenly hesitant. “Harry, dear,” Molly began. “We were wondering if you’d mind coming to stay with us for a bit. At least until your hearing; Ron and Ginny and the rest are very worried about you, and I know they’d like to see you.”

“We almost had to have them forcibly removed from the waiting area while you were unconscious. And we had to lock up the Floo powder,” Arthur said with a rueful smile.

“I, well, I’d like that,” Harry said quietly. “I just don’t want to be an imposition. I mean, I can always get a room at the Leaky Cauldron, you know.”

“You will do no such thing!” Molly gasped, outraged. Harry jumped a little in surprise, but she squeezed his hand in reassurance. “You’re just barely twelve years old, Harry. You can’t live by yourself, who’d watch out for you?”

Mr. Weasley spoke up. “Molly does have a point, Harry. The law will not allow you to live alone at your age without a legal guardian.”

Harry frowned but nodded. “I’d like that,” he said quietly.

Mrs. Weasley gave her husband a look.

Mr. Weasley cleared his throat. “Well, while we’re on the subject. Harry, would you object if we applied to become your legal guardians?”

Harry was quite certain his heart just stopped.

Misinterpreting Harry’s expression, Mr. Weasley began speaking very quickly. “It would only be until you were seventeen, you know, legal age. If there’s anyone else you’d prefer, we understand though.”

Harry was shaking his head. “No, there isn’t. I just don’t… I mean, you don’t have to do this.”

“No, Harry, we don’t.” Mr. Weasley agreed. “I think Professor Dumbledore will likely have some alternatives lined up by the date of the hearing. That would probably mean you could live at Hogwarts year round if you wanted.”

“Harry,” Mrs. Weasley said, “we’re asking because we want you to come live with us.”

Objectively, Harry realized he shouldn’t have been too surprised, not when they were sitting there waiting for him to wake up. Subjectively, he couldn’t believe it. Somewhere inside of him was a thirty year old Harry thinking how much easier it would be to protect them at The Burrow, and how much studying he could get done over the summers if he didn’t have to hide his books. Somewhere inside of him was an eleven year old Harry who was amazed that someone actually wanted him. All of this was wrapped up inside a newly-twelve-year-old Harry who realized he’d never been this happy before. He opened his mouth and closed it and suddenly he was being hugged by Mrs. Weasley.

Harry could remember that happening before, when he was racked with guilt following the Tri-Wizard tournament. He’d been about to go spare then, and he wasn’t far from that now. He tried to calm his breathing, which was starting to hitch. When he relaxed, Mrs. Weasley let go and sat back in her chair, dabbing at her eyes.

Harry steeled himself for what he needed to say. “I’d like that,” he said in a small voice, “but I’m afraid there are a couple of conditions.” The Weasleys stared at him, and Harry saw a ghost of a frown on Mrs. Weasley’s face. “I – I mean. Well, my parents left me some money, for school and, and other things.”

Molly shook her head. “That’s your money, dear.”

“I, well – you already have a family. I wouldn’t feel right if I didn’t… help out some.”

Mrs. Weasley opened her mouth, but her husband put his hand on her arm and shook his head.

“Harry, that’s very nice of you to offer,” Mr. Weasley said. “But we didn’t even know about your inheritance when we made our decision to ask you. You really don’t have to do this.”

“I know that, Mr. Weasley,” Harry replied, working to keep his voice even. “That’s why I want to.”

Eventually, Harry wore them down. Hospital beds do have some uses after all.

Mrs. Weasley got a little emotional toward the end. “Harry, we didn’t offer this to get at your money,” she said bluntly.

“I know,” Harry said. “The Dursleys never had a clue about it. They thought I got my school books from Public Relief.”

Mrs. Weasley bit her lip but subsided. “What was your other condition, Harry?” Mr. Weasley asked.

“Well,” Harry began. This was probably the tougher one. What he was saying would constitute a direct threat to their family, and he didn’t think they’d react well to that at all. “You know what happened when I was a baby.”

They both nodded, not looking like they knew where this was going.

“From what I understand,” Harry continued. “There are quite a few people who’d like to see me dead.” Mrs. Weasley flinched. “From what Professor Dumbledore has implied, there were special protections placed around my aunt and uncle’s house to keep it safe. My presence will put your family in danger, specifically from Voldemort and his allies.”

Mrs. Weasley twitched again at the name, but Mr. Weasley just met Harry’s gaze calmly. “Harry, the Weasleys were not quiet in our opposition to Voldemort in the last war. If he and his kind were to return to power, we’d be in just as much danger.”

Harry nodded. “That may be true, but my being at The Burrow would definitely move it up their priority list. I’d like to see about upgrading the security at The Burrow at my expense. I can talk to Goldfarb, who manages the Potter Trust at Gringotts, and see whether he can legally justify withdrawing money for that purpose.”

Mr. Weasley nodded. “If it would make you feel safer, Harry.”

“It would,” Harry agreed. And make me feel better that you are all safer.

“This is only for new wards and such, correct?” Mrs. Weasley asked.

“Or any additions of a defensive nature,” Harry temporized.

Mr. Weasley gave Harry a piercing look. Mrs. Weasley was shaking her head in resignation so Harry gave him a quick wink. Mr. Weasley looked a little dubious, but patted his wife on the arm. “Come on, Molly. We’ve tired the boy out enough.” As his wife collected her things and headed out the door, Mr. Weasley took Harry’s hand.

“I’m sorry, Harry,” he said in a quiet undertone.

“For what, sir?”

“If I’d listened to Ron and Ginny, we’d have been out there days earlier,” he said, chagrined.

“You didn’t know,” Harry said. “Nothing too bad happened until last Friday.”

“You’re being uncommonly generous.”

“It’s over now, and maybe I won’t ever have to see them again. Anyway, I’m just glad I’ve got a home to look forward to.” He smiled shyly at his best friend’s father.

The man chuckled. “You haven’t even seen The Burrow before, have you?”

“No, but it’s the people that make the home, don’t they? And I know most of the Weasleys already.” Harry’s grin was infectious now. Arthur Weasley smiled back, though his eyes were a little wide. He followed his wife out the door, but not before giving Harry an odd look.

It took Harry a moment to realize that he’d just repeated one of Arthur Weasley’s favourite sayings back to him.

After a relatively peaceful night, which made Harry ever so grateful for the dreamless sleep potions they finally gave him, he awoke to find Healer Stanhope taking the bandage off his right arm. The doxy bite had been left untreated for days, and the poison had done enough damage to leave a frightful scar. It looked like a shallow spoonful of flesh had been removed from his forearm, which is pretty much what happened.

“The tissue had gone necrotic, so we had to excise a good bit to ensure no further necrosis or putrefaction occurred.”

“I understand what all those words mean, you know,” Harry complained, turning a little green.

“Oh? Pity, that. I usually skate by using technical terms when people want to know what happened. Most of them don’t really, not in any detail. They just feel like they should ask,” the grey-haired healer confided.

Harry ignored that. He peered at the fierce-looking scar. The edges of it were raised and angry, like puffy little hedge rows on his skin.

“Lads your age usually like to have a good scar or two. Builds character, you know. And you get to make up stories about how you got them!”

Harry looked up at the healer and quirked an eyebrow. “I’d rather have a lot of stories no one believes.” He rolled his eyes upward to indicate the infamous lightning-shaped scar on his forehead.

Healer Stanhope reddened when he made the connection. “Yes, well. Quite. Skele-Gro aches all gone?”

Harry nodded slowly, pleased that his neck had stopped hurting.

“Feeling back in all your extremities?”

This time Harry grimaced. He still had pins and needles in his left hand and foot, along with spots of numbness.

Stanhope didn’t ask for elaboration. Instead he pulled out his wand and ran it over Harry’s left side. “I see – still a bit of mending to be done; you’ll be with us for a couple more days, Mr. Boy Who Lived.”

Harry started when he heard his famous sobriquet.

“Ah yes, I should warn you that your identity did eventually slip out after the Aurors left. Security has had to throw out four reporters already. They haven’t had this much fun since Celestina Warbeck was checked in for acute laryngitis.”

Harry made a disgusted face.

“Don’t worry,” Stanhope said, his voice serious now. “We take patient confidentiality very seriously here. The orderly that said they saw you on the patient roster was sacked on the spot. No one knows any details, which is what’s driving those vultures absolutely mad.”

Harry let out a sigh of relief. “Will the nerves completely recover? And how long will it take?”

“A couple of days more on the nerve-restoring potions. After that you may have some intermittent weakness for a couple of months. You should be fine in plenty of time for Quidditch.”

Harry jumped. “How did you—”

“I was sorted into Gryffindor, and I still keep up with the cup scores. I even played chaser back in the day.”

“Wow, did they have balls back then? Or were they still using rocks for Bludgers?” Harry asked sarcastically.

Healer Stanhope blinked and chuckled. “I supposed I have been winding you up a bit, haven’t I?”

Privately, Harry thought the healer’s eyes were a little too calculating. Was he testing me to see if I was traumatized or still had a sense of humour? he wondered.

“Anyway,” the healer continued. “I wanted to discuss some of your test results, since you are awake and sufficiently aware to mock my age and experience. First, I have a question. Have you experienced any unusual bursts of magic recently? Or at all?”

“Well,” Harry said carefully. “I have had a couple of bits of accidental magic over the past year.”

“Really, these happened after you started attending Hogwarts?”

Harry nodded.

“Well, I suppose that would account for… anyway. To explain before you jump up and throttle me. When you were admitted, we did a Magical Resonance Imaging test – standard procedure for people with head and neck wounds. What the test does is create a diagnostic image of a person’s magical energy. Quite useful for seeing if any central nervous system damage has impacted their ability to use magic. Your test, Mr. Potter, showed no damage. It did, however show that you had a second locus linked to your own. This secondary corpus magi was significantly larger and better defined, but it was slowly being integrated into the primary corpus that is linked to you.”

“Weird,” Harry said in a wondering tone. “How rare is that, anyway?”

“You are the first and only case we’ve seen of it since the MaRI was developed.”

“That’s really peculiar,” Harry said carefully. “What does it mean though?” Is this from the merger?

“As you get older, you may experience some increases in magical power. Those bursts of accidental magic are probably indicative of that. I wonder what could cause such a thing though… Have you been exposed to any unusual magical… energies…”

The healer’s voice trailed off as Harry sighed at him. Finally, he raised his hand and tapped the scar above his right eyebrow.

“Ah, yes, that would definitely constitute exposure to, er, well.” Stanhope looked sheepish. “I must say, Mr. Potter, you shouldn’t be that surprised if I forget. It’s not like you go about beating everyone over the head with your celebrity status.”

Harry just grinned. He wished Snape could hear him say that, the git.

“Anyway, thank you for satisfying my professional curiosity. I believe you have some visitors.” The healer walked over to the door and let himself out.

A moment later, Ron stuck his head in the door. “You awake, Harry?”

“Yeah, I am!” Harry said brightly.

Ron stepped carefully into the room, looking around. He was wearing threadbare but comfortable looking trousers with a Chudley Cannons tee-shirt. To Harry’s surprise, Ginny followed him through the door. Harry thought she was looking very pretty in a flower-print sun dress with her hair streaming down her back.

“Mum’s down getting a cuppa from the lunch counter. The healer saw us in the hall and said we could go on in.”

“I’m glad he did, Ron. It’s getting sort of boring now.” Harry cracked a lop-sided smile. “That’s two I owe you. When are you going to get tired of saving my arse?”

Ron looked down and scuffed his shoe, but his ears had already gone red. “The twins drove the car.”

“Who convinced them to go?”

“Well, I did a little, but it was Ginny that really got to them.” Ron glanced sidelong at his little sister, who’d frozen in place and suddenly gone pink. “She wouldn’t leave them alone once her letters stopped being answered.”

“Right, which reminds me, did one of the twins grab my mail?”

“Fred did. But why didn’t you send any responses back with Errol?”

“Some barmy house elf was nicking the letters before I even saw them. He was trying to talk me out of going back to Hogwarts and thought that if I didn’t get any letters I’d think no one cared.” He glanced at Ginny. “As if that would happen.”

She wrung her hands together, but he thought her down-turned face was smiling a little.

“Anyway,” Harry continued. “I convinced the elf that I was going back no matter what, so he eventually returned my mail. Unfortunately, I had a birthday gift on top of the stack. When I opened it, four doxies flew out and began playing merry-hell with me and Hedwig. We killed all of them, but I had to use my wand to get one off of Hedwig. When the owl from the Ministry came, it disrupted this dinner party my uncle was throwing downstairs and his guests left. When he came upstairs he was blazing angry and had just discovered I couldn’t use magic to stop him.”

“I would have hexed him anyway,” Ron snarled.

“In retrospect, I should have. I just didn’t think it would get as bad as it did.”

“He’s hit you before?” Ginny gasped. She was staring at him now, her embarrassment forgotten in her shock.

“Not like this,” Harry said quickly. “Maybe once or twice, not like he really meant it.”

“That’s rubbish,” Ron spat. Harry couldn’t help but smile at his friend’s sentiments.

“Look, it’s over, and I don’t think I’ll have to deal with them again. You can’t imagine what a relief that is.” Harry couldn’t help but smile thinking about The Burrow. He didn’t think he had a single bad memory that took place in the Weasleys’ haven.

Ron grunted. “Who do you think gave you the doxies, Harry?”

“I’m not completely sure, but I have my suspicions. Did the twins grab the box?”

Ron shook his head. “That Auror already asked. Sorry, it was really confusing in there, not to mention dark.”

“Whoa, Ron, back it up. You three were brilliant in there. The healer says you were incredibly smart to use a spell to levitate me, by the way. There were some loose bone fragments that could have sliced into things if you’d banged me around too much.”

Ron looked a little green, but nodded weakly.

“I wish Mum hadn’t caught Fred and George,” Ginny hissed. Her eyes had gone a little red to match her face.

“What did she catch them doing?” Harry asked curiously.

“They were trying to send a package to your relatives via Muggle post,” Mrs. Weasley said angrily as she walked through the doorway. “One with enough explosives and fireworks in it to get them both sent to Azkaban.”

“They deserve worse,” Ginny said darkly, ignoring the look her mother gave her.

Was she always this vicious where I was concerned? Harry wondered. “Your Mum’s right. I don’t want anyone getting revenge on my relatives… unless I’m personally involved in the planning and execution.”

Mrs. Weasley had been smiling at Harry until that last bit. “Harry!” she remonstrated him, “You really shouldn’t worry about such things.”

“I know,” Harry agreed. “At least until I’m seventeen and I can do it legally.”

She shook her head as Ron stifled a bark of laughter. Looking at her children, Mrs. Weasley asked, “And why did you not stay out in the hallway like I told you to?”

“Mrs. Weasley, the healer sent them on in when he finished examining me,” Harry said quickly, wanting to keep his friends out of trouble.

With that, they all settled into chairs and began talking. Mostly, Harry and Ron told stories from their first year at Hogwarts. Carefully edited stories, that is.

After a couple of hours, Mrs. Weasley looked at the clock on the wall. “Oh dear, I need to head back and fix lunch for Percy and the twins, provided they haven’t killed each other.” She shook her head. “Ron, Ginny, come on.”

“I’m not very hungry Mum, is it okay if I stay?” Ginny asked in a small voice.

Her mother gave her a long look, but finally nodded. Ron got up to follow his mother and his stomach gave an audible growl. Both Harry and Ginny had to suppress a snicker, but he never broke his stride as he walked to the door.

He stopped halfway out the door and dug into his pocket. He pulled out something rolled up and tossed it toward Harry’s bed. “You almost forgot this,” Ron said as he let the door shut behind him.

Bedridden or not, there wasn’t much chance a true Seeker would fail to catch something thrown directly at his face. It was the scarf Ginny had made for him. Harry slowly unrolled it and looked over at the youngest Weasley.

Her eyes had gone wide, but she stood her ground.

“I g-guess you really like the colour,” she said.

“Yeah,” Harry said. “I do.”

He couldn’t help but stare at her, even as his sense of caution warned him to change the subject immediately. Lying in that stifling room, he didn’t think he’d ever get to see her again, and that’s when he truly began to hate his aunt and uncle.

Ginny looked back at him for a moment, and then picked up the Daily Prophet her mother had left in one of the chairs. “It’s nearly impossible to read one of these things one-handed, you know. Would you like it if I read to you?”

Harry nodded.

And so she sat in the chair, paper folded in her lap, and began reading the stories to him. At first, Harry couldn’t care less about the stories, and just lay there listening to her voice. After a while, though, she started to insert her own commentary into the stories. Looking down at the paper, she didn’t seem to be quite as nervous, and it was almost like reading one of her letters, only out-loud.

Soon Harry began to add his own comments under his breath. She read an article about “prominent purebloods” opposed to the recent spate of Ministry raids looking for cursed Muggle items. Harry responded by coughing and saying “Malfoy” simultaneously every time the “prominent purebloods” were referenced. By the third time Ginny was snorting. By the fifth time she laughed out loud. By the end of the article she had cracked up and nearly fallen out of the chair.

Harry thought her laughter sounded musical, though he figured he was probably just being sappy. Still, it was good to hear her laugh. He’d heard little of it, probably because of the Chamber. Now if that isn’t a downer of a thought, Potter you morbid tosser, he grimaced. Watching Ginny slowly regain her composure, he smiled even as he made a vow. Screw the bloody continuity. I’ll take that Diary and shove it up Lucius’ arse first thing. No. Wait… better hold onto it. It is a Horcrux after all. Still, I’m going to keep that ruddy thing away from her this time.

By the time Ginny’s mother returned, the girl’s voice was a little hoarse and Harry’s sides hurt from laughing too much. He was fairly certain he saw Mrs. Weasley’s shadow under the door several minutes before it opened.

“Ginny, it’s time to come home. Dinner will be ready soon and I need you to set the table.”

Ginny looked rebellious for a moment, but just sighed in resignation.

“Dear, you’ve been here all day. Visiting hours are almost over and I’m sure Harry is exhausted.”

“I’m fine, Mrs. Weasley, but I think Ginny’s probably pretty hungry. She’s been chewing on her hair.”

Ginny jumped and pulled the stray lock of fire-coloured hair out of her mouth. She gave Harry a betrayed glare, but he just tried to look innocent, and failed miserably. She gave up the glare as a bad job and began giggling again.

Mrs. Weasley sighed, but she still had a smile on her face. “Come on dear. There will be visiting hours tomorrow as well.” She began to lead her slightly less resistant daughter from the room.

“Don’t forget your letters, Ginny,” Harry called out when they reached the door.

“I won’t Harry, but I don’t see why you’d want to read them now,” she said, looking downward again.

Harry tried to shrug and winced. “I just like knowing what you were thinking when you wrote it. There’s a little piece of you in there, you know.”

He hadn’t meant it to be embarrassing, but his words made her flush like a tomato all over again. “Bye Harry,” she whispered as they left the room.

Harry awoke the next morning when an orderly cast a cleansing charm on him. At least it’s less embarrassing than a sponge bath, he thought groggily. He smiled at the young woman after yawning widely. He scratched his head for a moment before he realized he was using his left hand with no difficulty. The numbness was gone.

After a moment of groping on the nightstand, Harry found his glasses and put them on. The enchanted windows showed it was daylight outside, at least mid-morning. I don’t think they gave me a dreamless sleep potion last night, Harry mused. Apparently he still managed to sleep through the night without dreaming.

After downing another round of potions, Harry drained the water glass in one drink. Not only was he thirsty, but the mingled aftertaste from his medicinal potions was impressively foul. However, when the orderly asked him if he was hungry, Harry found himself nodding.

Every hospital should have some house elves, Harry reflected as he chewed on a nicely crisped strip of bacon. He was finishing a surprisingly well-cooked breakfast when the door opened.

Ron and Ginny walked in, carrying handfuls of unopened letters. The twins followed them, with Mrs. Weasley bringing up the rear. Of course, the twins started in on him immediately.

“Ickle Harrikins!”

“Imagine meeting you here!”

“One might think—”

“—you were a bit under the weather.”

“Fred! George! Mind your manners!” Mrs. Weasley scolded. “You said you’d be on your best behaviour if we let you come this time.”

“But this is—”

“—our best behaviour!”

Ron spoke up as he peered around. “They have a point, Mum. Nothing’s exploded yet.”

Ginny looked over at Harry, rolling her eyes. He smiled back at her.

“We were just telling ickle Ronnie—”

“Hey! I’m not any shorter than you lot,” Ron objected.

“Ah, but you’re shorter in all the ways that matter:”

“Wit, sense, pocket change, and dare I say it—”

“Only if you want both your mouths washed out. And I’ll use the lye soap this time.” Mrs. Weasley’s eyes were narrowed, but Harry didn’t think she was completely serious.

“Saved by the mum, Ronnikins!”

“As we were saying—”

“—before that rude interruption,”

“—we should have continued—”

“—our classes with that old bat Trelawney,”

“—as we seem to have—”

“—that inner eye she natters on about.”

“Shocked we were,”

“Very shocked indeed!”

“When Mum and Dad—”

“—called a family meeting last night!”

“And we hadn’t even set anything on fire yet!”

“Quite surprising it was!”

“Could have coshed me with a feather.”

“A small one at that.”

“When we found it was true—”

“—and we actually had found a black-haired Weasley!”

Harry looked at Fred and George for a moment before snorting. “Did you rehearse that?” he finally asked. Ron and Ginny were grinning and stifling laughter.

“No, but we did—”

“—practise this bit—”

“—if you will remember—”

“—at the Sorting Feast—”

“—last autumn!”

With that, the twins linked elbows and began dancing a jig, singing, “We got Potter! We got Potter!” Harry was roaring with laughter, even before Ron and Ginny joined in. Mrs. Weasley tried to shush them, glancing at the door. Finally she pulled out her wand and cast silencing charms on her children.

“Honestly, I don’t know what’s got into you! This is a hospital! There are sick people here and healers trying to do their jobs,” Molly said as she frowned at Harry, who was holding his stomach and lying back on the pillows, red-faced. “I’m sorry Harry, I had no idea they had something like this planned.” She seemed actually distressed.

“N-no, it’s okay,” Harry said. “It actually was funny. Muggles have this saying: ‘Laughter is the best medicine.’ So, I think I just got a dose big enough to bring me back from the dead.”

Mrs. Weasley’s face went pale all of a sudden and Harry felt ashamed. He was just trying to let her know that the twins’ little skit actually made him feel better… not remind her of how badly he’d been hurt.

Wiping at her eyes, Mrs. Weasley let out a sigh and raised her wand again and cancelled the charms. “You are far too forgiving, Harry. Now, if the rest of you do not stay quiet I will send you home.”

“Right Mum,” one twin said, rubbing his ear theatrically.

“We get the message,” the other one elaborated.

“We brought your mail, Harry,” Ron announced, stepping forward. “We saw Ginny gathering up some of your letters and figured you’d rather have the whole lot.”

Harry glanced at Ginny, who was beginning to turn pink again. “Thanks,” he said, trying to meet Ginny’s eyes, but she wouldn’t look up.

“We sorted it a bit,” Ron said. “I have the letters from Hogwarts and from students. Ginny’s still carrying her letters,” he added frowning. “And the twins have everything else.”

“For a firstie, you sure get a lot of mail. George and I have stuff from half the shops on Diagon Alley, including Gringotts,” Fred said coolly.

“Fred, don’t pry into Harry’s affairs,” Mrs. Weasley scolded.

“There’s a letter from Gringotts?” Harry asked, sitting up. “Let’s see it.”

George frowned and began digging through a stack of letters. “Here it is,” he said, handing Harry an envelope of creamy white vellum with an elaborate Gringotts seal on the flap.

Harry broke the seal and pulled out a short note.

Mr. Potter,

The diversification we discussed has been completed. Please contact us at your earliest convenience when you wish action taken.

Goldfarb

Harry looked up with a wicked grin.

Ron was giving him an odd look. “What’s that all about?” he asked, nodding at the letter.

“Well, it means my preparations are complete,” Harry said with a smirk. He glanced over at Ginny, who was looking interested again. He thought the twins had likely teased her about the letters that morning, so he figured it wouldn’t hurt to get her some payback. “You’re right, Ginny. Blowing up someone’s mailbox is very amateurish.” He sighed and clucked his tongue. “Now, getting them sacked is another matter entirely.”

Ginny looked up, confused. But after a moment, she caught his intent and gave her brothers a very superior look.

“Harry?” Mrs. Weasley spoke up. “What are you up to?”

“Well, I had the Goblin who manages my parents’ trust buy up some shares in the company where my uncle works,” Harry explained. “I know Mr. Shacklebolt said he’d try to get him prosecuted, but if that doesn’t work, and he tries to do anything at the hearing, he’ll lose his job.”

“I’d rather transfigure him into something nasty,” Ron said darkly.

“Or set him on fire,” Ginny added.

“This will be worse,” Harry replied before Mrs. Weasley could object. “He’s always on about how he hates magic. This,” he held up the letter, “was done with no magic at all. I’m beating him at his own game this time.”

Fred let out a low whistle. “George, I think we’re at risk—”

“—of being supplanted as pranksters supreme!” his twin agreed.

“Should have seen this coming—”

“—after him smuggling that dragon—”

“—not to mention trashing—”

“—the Divination Tower as a diversion!”

“What are you talking about? Harry would do no such thing! Would you, Harry?” Mrs. Weasley turned an outraged expression toward Harry, who felt a sudden urge to sink into the bed. Mrs. Weasley raised an eyebrow at Harry as the silence wore on. She didn’t even notice Ginny kicking Fred in the shin, making him hop about on one foot.

“Well, it’s a long story, Mrs. Weasley,” Harry said apologetically. “Hagrid had this dragon egg he won in a card game, and when it got too big for him we helped some friends of Charlie’s transport Norbert down to the preserve in Romania.”

Mrs. Weasley’s eyes had gone wide. “Harry, that’s illegal! Do you know how much trouble you could have got into?” She rounded on Ron. “I suppose you were helping him, weren’t you? Tell me the truth, Ronald Bilius Weasley, or so help me…” She didn’t notice Ginny get George, either.

“No, I didn’t,” Ron said disgustedly. “Stupid thing bit my hand so Neville had to help with the crate.” He paled as his mother looked even angrier. “Mum, we had to! Hagrid is Harry’s friend. Besides,” he added innocently, “didn’t Hagrid help when you and dad were almost caught at the Astronomy Tower?”

Molly Weasley stopped dead in her tracks, mouth open in mid-tirade. Her face went from pale with anger to red as a tomato in seconds. “Yes, I see. Well, don’t let it happen again. All right Harry? Ron?” she said tonelessly.

Harry and Ron looked at each other and nodded vigorously.

“Good,” Mrs. Weasley said. “Now that’s settled, I’ll go see the healer about when you can come home, Harry.” She smiled faintly and left the room.

“Oi! Ginny—” George said the instant the door shut. He was still rubbing his shin.

“What the bloody hell—” Fred continued, tapping his leg with his fingertips and frowning.

“Was that for?”

Ginny still had her fists planted on her hips. “I would never have expected you two, of all people, to go all Percy on Harry!” she snapped, still outraged.

“Well, we had to make sure—” Fred began.

“—Harry could handle a Weasley chewing out—”

“—while he still had the protection of a hospital bed.”

Ginny sniffed. “I think you’re just afraid of the competition, to sink to such a low.”

“Never see little Gin-Gin lose her rag like that, do we, brother of mine?” Fred asked his twin in an arch tone.

“Truly, oh brother of mine. I think someone may not be quite as happy as the rest of us at having Harry as a brother,” George replied in a conspiratorial murmur.

Ginny had a stricken look on her face and Harry felt a sudden flash of anger. “That’s enough, you two,” he snapped. Harry had given the twins orders before, when he’d assumed temporary command of the disintegrating Order of the Phoenix. He’d slipped into his ‘voice of command’ without really meaning to. It didn’t work so well with a twelve-year-old’s voice, but it had the desired effect.

“Sorry, Gin,” they muttered in unison.

As Molly Weasley tried to locate Healer Stanhope, she steadily regained her composure. Harry and Ron had never mentioned anything about smuggling a dragon out of Hogwarts! She couldn’t believe they’d even tried to do something so outrageous, let alone got away with it.

She heaved a tired sigh. She’d hoped that once the twins were safely graduated she could stop worrying so much. But it appeared that Ron was just as trouble-prone as his brothers. She’d been horrified when he mentioned the incident at the Astronomy tower. Fortunately, he appeared not to understand exactly what had happened – only that Hagrid had helped her and Arthur out of a jam. Thinking about the start of that night gave her a warm glow. It was the first time Arthur admitted he loved her, and after that they lost all track of time. If Hagrid hadn’t hidden them from Filch… She shook her head and asked one of the white-robed witches where she could find Healer Stanhope.

As Molly waited outside the ward where she was told the healer was conducting his rounds, she realized something was bothering her. Ginny was not at all surprised by the twins’ revelation. She regretted for a moment her decision not to read any of her daughter’s correspondence. On the other hand, she knew Ginny would not take it well if she found out. She knew being the only girl in a house full of boys meant that privacy was at a premium. Her relationship with her daughter was not as close as she’d like it to be… they were too different in some very basic ways. However, she didn’t envy Arthur’s closeness to ‘his little girl’. In some ways, she wondered if her Ginevra was just playing a role with her father as well.

Molly sighed. Perhaps she wasn’t as close to her youngest as she wanted to be. That didn’t mean she couldn’t try to bridge that distance. She had an entire summer before her last baby started at Hogwarts.

“Ah, Mrs. Weasley,” Healer Stanhope said as he walked through the doorway.

Molly gathered herself and smiled. “Healer Stanhope, I have to say you do incredible work. Harry looks like a different person.”

The grey-haired man waved his hands dismissively. “Yes, well, when you work with a healthy young man with magic that strong… well, any old duffer can look like a champion.”

“Does that mean he can be released soon?”

“Like to take him home, would you?” the healer asked, but his eyes were kindly.

“Well, I’m sure he might rest better there. I’d like him to be able to forget… everything,” Molly said quietly.

Stanhope looked her in the eye and for a moment his genial affability fell away like an old cloak. “I think we need to talk about that,” he said firmly. His hand on her elbow was light as he guided her to a small meeting room. As she took the offered seat, she felt a quiver of dread. Is Harry not going to be all right? she wondered. He said the poor boy is healthy… She hadn’t got to see that much of Harry Potter, but what she did know wrung her heart. She didn’t want to see him go through anything else.

“Normally, this is something I would discuss only with an immediate family member. However, I understand you and your husband are to become Harry’s guardians?” Stanhope said as he sat down.

“Yes, we talked to Harry and my husband has already filed the paperwork.”

“I understand you were there when the Auror took his deposition.” It was not a question.

Molly nodded. Thinking about what she heard still made her feel sick.

“Despite what Harry may have said, I don’t believe this is the first time something like this has happened to him,” Stanhope said in a steely voice.

“I don’t think Harry would lie to us and his friends,” Molly replied.

“I’m not sure it’s as simple as a matter of truthfulness,” Stanhope said with a sigh. “The boy shows signs of a severe mental disturbance. Last night was the first night since he was admitted that he didn’t have to have a dreamless sleep potion. We don’t like to administer them if we can help it, but he would have such violent nightmares each night that we had little choice.”

“Couldn’t they have been caused by what happened on his birthday?”

Stanhope leaned back in his chair. “When a boy suffering from broken bones tries to sit up in bed, that’s not a normal dream. Do you know if he’s suffered from nightmares before this?”

Molly sat thinking for a few minutes. “I believe my son mentioned that he didn’t sleep well when he was at Hogwarts.”

The healer nodded slowly. “I think he’s been through a lot more than he lets on… and it’s left its mark on the boy. He acts in some ways like the older Aurors, the ones that were hurt badly in the last war. A lot of them saw things, or had things done to them, that they never recovered from. Do you remember the Longbottoms?” he asked.

Molly nodded. “Their son is classmates with Harry and Ron.”

“Not all of the old veterans are as bad off as Frank and Alice, but many have problems like Harry. Some are just a bit jumpy, others will go weeks before they get an uninterrupted night’s sleep. A lot of them never fully recover,” The healer said as he looked Molly square in the eyes. “I think you should probably discuss this with your husband as well.”

Molly inhaled sharply, but her voice came out in a whisper. “We are not going to abandon that boy now,” she practically hissed.

“Good. But you both need to make an informed decision. It’s entirely possible that Harry has gone through things so horrible that he’s repressed the memories. Him getting better may or may not require that he remember. If he does, you will have a very powerful young wizard going through an intense emotional trauma. Are you ready to deal with that as well?”

“We will do whatever needs to be done,” Molly said earnestly. “That poor boy has gone through so much, only to be left with people who treated him worse than dirt. It is high time he got to live with people that care about him. Otherwise I’m afraid of what will become of him.”

Stanhope nodded slowly. “I hope you and your family are in this for the long haul. I’m not a specialist in mental injuries, but I don’t care to think about what another disappointment could do to him.”

“If by some freak occurrence my husband and I were both to falter, I doubt our children would ever let us get away with it. My youngest four are very close to Harry.”

“Good,” Stanhope said, smiling slightly. It was his first change of expression since they’d sat down. “I think he needs as many friends as he can get.”

Author notes

16

A Visit to Sunny Azkaban

Mrs. Weasley Flooed back to The Burrow while Harry and Mr. Weasley returned to the Department of Magical Law Enforcement to fill out the approximately three stone of paperwork needed to formalize the guardianship. While they worked, Harry explained what he knew about the Fidelius charm that was supposed to protect the Potter home in Godric’s Hollow. By the time Harry signed the last form in triplicate, it was well past lunch time. As they turned everything in, Mr. Weasley also inquired about the visitor schedule for Azkaban Wizarding prison.

It turned out there weren’t visiting hours, per se. The crimes committed by most of the inmates were such that few people were inclined to visit them. However, through prior arrangement with the warden, interviews with prisoners could be arranged. As one of the supposed victims of Sirius Black’s betrayal, Harry had more than sufficient grounds to request a visit. Mr. Weasley sent a message to the Warden requesting a meeting at their earliest convenience. He’d been shocked and dismayed at the implications of what Harry had told him.

By the time they were ready to leave the Ministry, Harry’s stomach was growling audibly, bringing a rueful grin to Mr. Weasley’s lips. “Best get you home, Harry, or Molly will have my head for starving you.”

When Harry followed Mr. Weasley out of the fireplace at The Burrow, his ears were assaulted by an avalanche of noise.

“We got Potter! We got Potter!” The twins were doing a re-enactment of their jig from the sorting feast of last fall. This time Ron and Ginny had linked arms and joined in as well. Percy was making a face at all the racket. Mrs. Weasley looked torn between wanting to shush them and wanting to join in as well.

Harry felt like he’d just won another Quidditch Cup when the dancing broke up and he was suddenly engulfed in a Weasley group hug. He hadn’t realized how worried his friends had been about the hearing, but now he saw Ginny’s eyes were quite red and Ron looked a little choked up as well. For once, the twins weren’t taking the mickey out of them about it either.

Harry didn’t really remember what Mrs. Weasley fixed for lunch that day. He vaguely remembered her kicking them out of the kitchen when he and Ginny went to clear the table. He ended up dragging her out with them to the paddock when her brothers suggested Quidditch.

She sat at the foot of an apple tree, watching them play two on two Quidditch. After the twins got him and Ron down by quite a few goals, Harry landed next to Ginny, rolling his shoulder theatrically and grimacing.

“I think I popped something. Want to have a go?” he asked her in a loud voice, holding out the Nimbus 2000.

Ginny stared at the broom like it was a snake about to bite her.

Ignoring Ron’s protests, Harry took another step closer and lowered his voice. “Here’s a chance to show them you aren’t really ‘ickle Gin-Gin’…” He wondered if his smile could get any wider without splitting his lips.

“Harry, she’s going to wreck your broom! Mum is going to kill you if—” Ron’s words were cut off as Ginny rocketed into the air, making him flinch back and almost lose control of the rickety Cleansweep Four he was riding.

Ginny cut into a tight loop and shot between the twins, grabbing the Quaffle they were idly tossing back and forth. She didn’t decelerate before the ball was through their goal. Taking in the dumbfounded looks on her brothers’ faces, she made an exasperated sound. “What’s the matter? Haven’t you ever seen a girl on a broom before?”

“Better answer that one carefully,” Harry called out from the ground. “Angelina would probably be highly interested in your answer. After she removed the Quaffle from your nose.”

Ginny let out a laugh and the game resumed. Harry stretched out on the warm grass and enjoyed the show. Ginny’s agility and speed on Harry’s broomstick was just about unstoppable. Before long, Ron simply fell back and concentrated on guarding the younger siblings’ goal, while his sister quite literally flew rings around the twins. By early evening, Fred and George had been gleefully trounced in three straight sets. Harry couldn’t ever remember enjoying just watching Quidditch quite so much.

When Ginny and her brothers came in for a landing, she frowned at Harry. “Sorry, I hogged your broom all afternoon,” she whispered guiltily as they walked back to The Burrow. “I sort of lost track of how long we’d been up there.”

“Don’t be sorry,” Harry replied with a grin. “I’d rather watch you play than try being a chaser myself. I’m rubbish at passing.”

She gave him a long look as they neared the back door. “Thanks Harry,” she said with a shy smile of her own.

After dinner, the five of them retired to the sitting room to work on their Occlumency. Mrs. Weasley had wondered what they were up to at first, but was satisfied with their assurances that it was for school, and it wouldn’t violate the underage magic laws, since no wands were involved. If she was really concerned, Harry was prepared to let her know why they were studying Occlumency. He almost anticipated the fit she’d throw when she found out what Professor Snape had been doing to her children.

That night, Harry was pleasantly surprised to get almost nine hours of sleep. He awoke feeling almost hyperactive from being completely rested.

Thursday they settled back into their routine of martial arts alternated with Occlumency. Harry noticed a slight decrease in the random emotional emissions from the twins. It seemed the meditation exercises were starting to help them not broadcast their feelings quite so loudly. Ginny and Ron didn’t show any noticeable differences, which set Harry to thinking.

In all his reading, there was no mention of teaching Occlumency to students as young as eleven or twelve. It might be impossible for children that young to learn to defend their minds from intrusion. It was also possible that children were naturally more open, and might just take longer. These complications didn’t really alter Harry’s plans. It did, however, make him realize that it would likely take longer than he thought to come clean with his friends.

During a break after lunch, Harry wrote a note and gave it to Hedwig to deliver. It was short and to the point. He offered both a carrot and a stick to the message’s recipient, along with instructions on how to get the former and not the latter. Harry knew he was potentially playing with fire here, but he hoped his assessment of the personality in question was accurate.

When Mr. Weasley came home that evening, he told Harry that he’d gotten a reply from Azkaban, and the two of them would be allowed to visit the facility Friday morning at ten a.m. Mrs. Weasley gave Harry a worried look, but didn’t say anything.

After his confrontation with Dumbledore, Harry explained to his guardians about his dreams and the implications of Sirius Black’s innocence. While she was horrified at the thought of an innocent person being sentenced to life at the Wizarding prison, Mrs. Weasley was less than happy with the idea of Harry going there, even for a visit. It took some fast talking for Harry to reassure her. He’d also had to resort to bringing up details. He really hoped no one asked where he got some of that information. While it was no secret that Sirius was Harry’s godfather, he couldn’t point to a single person as being the one who told him. Thus far, he’d mostly skated on this issue – when he brought something up, his audience usually just assumed someone else spilled the beans. Fortunately, people like Dumbledore were more concerned with what Harry knew (and how to prevent him from finding out more); they seldom got around to asking how Harry knew what he did. On the other hand, he couldn’t count on that blind spot in the Headmaster’s thinking lasting forever. Professor Dumbledore wasn’t a stupid man. Harry may not have agreed with how the head of the Order of the Phoenix conducted the war against Voldemort, but he also recognized the staggering depths of the man’s knowledge.

Harry decided to go to bed a little early. Ron followed him upstairs and asked him if he was all right.

“Sure Ron,” he replied, a little confused. “Why do you ask?”

“Well,” Ron looked away, “you’ve been awfully quiet since dinner.”

“Just a lot to think about; I wonder what my godfather is going to be like. He’s been in Azkaban a terribly long time. I have no idea what to expect when I see him.”

Ron nodded slowly. “That’s got to be a lot to take in. You don’t have to deal with it all yourself though.”

Harry nodded, though he realized with some sadness that the worst of his issues he couldn’t share with anyone yet. “Ron, when did you get so sensitive?”

Predictably, his friend’s ears darkened. “Sod off, Harry,” he muttered.

“Actually, I wasn’t being sarcastic – for once. I bet Hermione will be impressed.” Harry couldn’t resist that last bit, wondering how far back that whole thing got started. The slightly panicked look on Ron’s face lasted less than a second, but that was more than enough to give Harry a healthy surprise. Damn, I had no bloody idea it was going on this long… or did I jump-start it a bit this time around?

“You’re bleedin’ hilarious, Harry,” Ron replied coolly. “Anyway, if you want to talk about something besides trying to embarrass me, you know where I am.”

Harry sighed. “I do appreciate that Ron. I mean, you’re as good a friend as a bloke could ask for, you know that, right?”

Ron nodded silently and they both began getting ready for bed. Harry knew he’d need his wits about him when he went to meet Sirius, so after completing his Occlumency exercises, he tried to focus his mind on happier memories.

He awoke the following morning before seven. He hadn’t had a nightmare about Sirius falling through the Veil in a long time. It made him nostalgic, in a sick sort of way. Of course, he’d been having that one since before he turned sixteen, so he supposed he’d worn off a lot of the sharp edges. Ginny throwing a wobbly at him for blaming himself needlessly hadn’t hurt.

Harry was starting to prepare breakfast when Mrs. Weasley came down the stairs. Her lips pursed in annoyance at seeing Harry running her stove, but then she frowned.

“Odd to wake up and find someone else cooking breakfast,” she said calmly. “Hasn’t happened to me since I lived at home with my parents. Of course, Arthur pitches in when I’m sick, or when I’m in my last month, but the poor dear is a bit hopeless in the kitchen.”

Harry made a face. “Sorry if I intruded. I just thought I’d go ahead and get things started.”

“That’s all right dear,” she smiled, but it didn’t quite reach her eyes. “Ron mentioned once that you have trouble sleeping at times.” She paused and looked at him closely. “Nightmares?”

Harry sighed and nodded. “Once I’m up, I’m up. I figure if I’m already awake, I might as well help with breakfast. It’s kind of calming, really.”

“I know, that’s why I enjoy it,” Molly said with a small smile. “You know Arthur and I are here any time you want to talk.”

“I appreciate that, Mrs. Weasley.”

She smiled a little. “You know, you don’t have to be so formal. Fosterlings usually call their guardians by their given names. I’ve discussed it with my husband, and we’d prefer if you called us Molly and Arthur.”

“I’ll try to do that, Mrs., er, Molly.”

“Good,” she said briskly. “Now, if you want, I can show you a few tricks that can make cooking on this old dear a bit less of a chore.”

Harry shifted slightly to the side so Molly could join him at the stove. “I’d like that,” he said with a shy smile.

By the time Ron and Ginny followed their father down the stairs, there was a meal of truly epic proportions waiting for them. Harry couldn’t help but be impressed by what he’d already learned that morning. He recalled that Mrs. Weasley had home-schooled all her children before they attended Hogwarts, and done a cracking good job of it from what he could tell. She was an obviously gifted teacher.

Mr. Weasley had to go to the Ministry to check on a few things before he was to come back and collect Harry for the trip to Azkaban. Harry, Ron, and Ginny took a quick run while the Twins were just beginning to stir. Harry was obviously preoccupied, and after Ron knocked him down for the third time, Ginny offered to take his place sparring with her brother.

Harry shook his head ruefully and stepped back. She was right; the thought of seeing Sirius again was crowding out his other thoughts. Ron made the rather significant error of patronizing his little sister as they sparred. He was larger, had more reach, and had been practising months longer. That, however, did not stop her from ducking under his arm and landing a quick punch at his unprotected stomach. It was surely an accident that her punch landed, well, lower than she probably intended.

After Ron was able to stand again, he took Ginny a bit more seriously. Harry watched and helped them catch when their stances got sloppy or their technique faltered. He tried not to think about Ginny’s last fight, during the Hogwarts Massacre. Unbidden, the images of her broken and battered body flooded his mind and he had to turn away from his friends. He began practising kicks and punches at random, snapping his blows as fast and as hard as he could. He battered imaginary enemies, trying to drain away his own emotions. Finally, he called a halt and led them on another run to cool down. Normally, he ran last in line, so he could keep an eye on his friends. This time he led, not wanting to see them, not wanting them to see his face. He set a fairly brutal pace, and by the time they returned to The Burrow, his heart stopped pounding and the sweat pouring down his face disguised his tears.

After he showered and dressed, Harry felt cleansed, almost as if he’d been hollowed out and allowed to drain. It was almost pleasant, that sense of detachment.

At half past nine, Arthur Flooed back from the Ministry. Harry was sitting at the scrubbed wood table in the kitchen, and stood up as the tall red-headed man stepped out of the fireplace. “Ah, all ready, Harry?”

Harry nodded. “Thanks, Mr. W- er, Arthur.”

“Ah, good. Molly said she’d talk to you about that. It’ll probably be easiest to just Apparate to the docks. I’ve been there a couple of times, so I can take you along.” He stood close to Harry and gripped his shoulders tightly. “Ready?” he asked.

Harry nodded and then felt a jerking motion as his vision went blurry. He blinked and saw a battered dock set into a rocky shoreline. The sharp tang of the sea burned in his nostrils. Arthur released him once it was clear he could stand. They walked across the damp stones to a small shack. As they drew closer the view in front of them suddenly wavered and changed.

The shack was now a concrete blockhouse, looking very sturdy with narrow slits for windows. Next to the entrance stood two alert looking wizards that Harry assumed were Aurors. Their wands were out and pointed at them. Harry clasped his hands together nervously. This also brought his fingers in contact with the butt of his wand. If they started casting, Harry was braced to knock Mr. Weasley down as he drew and returned fire…

Harry took a deep breath. His reflexes could get them into a lot of trouble here.

“Arthur Weasley,” his guardian announced calmly, “escorting Harry Potter for a prisoner visit.” The Aurors immediately lowered their wands and Harry relaxed.

Mr. Weasley must have been able to sense his tension. As they approached he spoke in a low tone. “Security is very tight here, which is quite understandable. Everything should be fine though. I don’t fancy being an Auror having to explain how he accidentally stunned Harry Potter.”

Harry snorted, but the man’s words did make him relax a bit. As they walked out onto the concrete dock that replaced the rickety wooden one, Harry could see a ferry boat moored at the end of it.

A weathered looking man with long grey hair let them into the cabin, which was scarcely warmer than the outside. At least it’s out of the wind, Harry reflected as he shivered a bit under his plain black robe. It sure as hell doesn’t feel like August out here.

In truth, Harry didn’t know if the weather was unusual. He’d never visited Azkaban before. It was said to be destroyed shortly after the Hogwarts Massacre. At that point the news reporting was starting to break down. Evidently Voldemort decided to liberate the few Death Eaters incarcerated there and eliminate the place as a symbol of justice and Ministry power. As the Dark Lord massed his forces, the Azkaban garrison nearly deserted. Instead, Alastor “Mad Eye” Moody, the legendary retired Auror, showed up at the dock after disabling the Death Eater sentries. No one survived to tell the world what he said to the frightened guards, but it is known that they held the fortress against Voldemort’s forces for twenty-two days. In the end, the Dark Lord’s forces won, but gained nothing for it. Every structure on the island had been levelled in the fierce fighting, and rumour had it that Moody himself executed all of Voldemort’s men before he could free them. After that it was said that one way a prisoner of the Death Eaters could earn a swift death instead of lingering torture was to yell “Constant Vigilance!” at their captors.

Brooding about the future at least kept Harry too distracted to get sea-sick. They docked at a concrete quay identical to the one they’d just left. A path led from the foot of the docks to an enormous metal door set in the base of a cliff. A small slit opened and Arthur had to identify them again. Harry was increasingly distracted by the chill in the air. He also felt an unpleasantly familiar stirring in the back of his mind. The Dementors can’t be affecting me all the way out here… can they? He stiffened his Occlumency shields as much as he could, but it didn’t seem to help.

The massive door retracted into a slot cut in the stone and they entered a rough-hewn tunnel bored out of solid rock. Torches set in wrought iron sconces every dozen paces provided minimal light. Harry followed numbly, trying not to hear the cloying whispers lingering just below the threshold of comprehension. Sirius described escaping through bars, so the prisoners were probably kept in above-ground cells. Perhaps these underground passages shielded him from the worst of the Dementors’ powers. He shuddered to think of what it must be like in the prison itself. They passed stout wooden doors, bound with iron strips, set flush against the walls. Eventually, their guide stopped in front of one and opened it.

Harry stepped into a better-lit room. This one was easily thirty feet on a side, though the low ceiling made it appear smaller. Stationed in each corner was an Auror, their impassive faces showing nothing.

In the centre of the room was a large wooden table. On the near side was a pair of empty chairs. On the far side was a single chair, occupied.

Sirius Black sat rigidly, his wrists bound in manacles connected to chains that wound through the reinforced frame of his chair. He was just as gaunt and corpse-like as Harry remembered from the Shrieking Shack. Long filthy matted hair hung down to the arms of his chair and glittering dark grey eyes glared emotionlessly ahead.

When the door closed behind them, those bottomless eyes flickered toward the intruders. Harry met his gaze evenly and saw those eyes widen a tiny bit. Harry reached out gently with his Legilimency, but Sirius was so tightly contained that he might as well have been a porcelain statue as a man.

His eyes, however, bored relentlessly into Harry’s. Arthur carefully led him to the table, and he sat down without breaking eye contact.

When Sirius spoke, his voice was so gravelly from disuse that his words were almost indecipherable. “You look just like your father did at your age… except…” he swallowed.

“Except for the eyes, I know,” Harry said softly.

Sirius nodded slowly. If his skin were less sallow, Harry imagined it would have gone pale.

“I, er, I remember that night—bits and pieces of it anyway. I know Peter was the secret-keeper, not you.” Harry’s words tumbled out of his mouth. The look on his Godfather’s face was more than he could bear. The two statements he made were, technically, both true.

Sirius’ eyebrows rose until they were obscured under his matted hair. “You… know? What happened?”

Harry nodded. “Most of it; I’ve been working on Dumbledore, trying to get you freed. The ministry is being difficult though. Part of it is those Muggles who were killed when you confronted Peter. Did they ever check your wand to see if you did that spell?”

Sirius shook his head. “It would be hard to do that since they snapped it moments after I was taken into custody.”

Harry snarled. “Idiots,” he muttered. This was going to make it even harder to prove his innocence; they had no business punishing him before he was even tried.

Sirius blinked. “You sound a lot more like your mother,” he whispered.

“Did she ever express a desire to hex the entire Ministry?” Harry growled. He glanced over at Arthur, who seemed to be a little amused. “Sorry,” he muttered.

“Quite all right, Harry, sometimes I feel like hexing them myself,” Arthur agreed affably.

Harry noticed Sirius studying Arthur curiously. “This is Arthur Weasley,” he said. “He and his wife agreed to be my guardians. Their youngest children go to Hogwarts with me, but we’re all living at The Burrow. It’s out near Ottery St. Catchpole in Devon.”

Sirius looked at him, confused. Privately, Harry preferred any expression over that deadened look he’d had when they entered the room. “I was staying with my Aunt Petunia and her family, but that didn’t, well, it wasn’t working out.” He didn’t want to tell Sirius too much and just add to his godfather’s burdens. Honestly, he was also a little afraid of the man’s reaction. He didn’t want this interview to end prematurely.

“I’ve seen you before, at a… meeting,” Sirius whispered. He seemed to be studying Arthur’s face. When Harry glanced at his guardian he was surprised to see how angry the man was. He wondered for a moment if he was angry at Sirius, but when Arthur simply nodded Harry made the connection to his downplaying of the situation at the Dursleys. Damn, Harry thought in wonder, Arthur never gets mad like that. It gave him a warm glow, even as he felt a little twinge of fear. I don’t want him getting hurt trying to protect me.

“Harry’s a good boy. My son couldn’t stop talking about him when he returned from Hogwarts. Molly and I will take good care of him.” Arthur spoke calmly but firmly. Something seemed to pass between the two men and Sirius relaxed visibly.

Harry wasn’t quite sure what to make of all that. “I’ve told Professor Dumbledore,” he said suddenly. “He said he’s been trying to get you out of here, but the people in the Ministry don’t want to listen. I gave him a bit of an earful when I heard that,” Harry admitted ruefully. Arthur actually chuckled out loud. “I’m not happy with you being stuck in here,” he continued, “and I’m going to make things quite difficult for people.”

Sirius blinked and looked at Arthur.

“Yes, he talks like that quite often. He rather reminds me of Professor McGonagall when she gets angry. If there is anything we can do to help him, rest assured we will do so.”

Sirius swallowed. Harry caught his eyes and they bored into his again. This time he could dimly feel a morass of thickly clotted emotions swirling from his godfather. He hoped that giving the man hope wouldn’t prove to be cruel. “I, er, I think it would probably help if we could find Peter. If he’s still alive, capturing him would wreck the Ministry’s case, wouldn’t it?”

“If he’s still alive,” Sirius said slowly. His struggle not to give in to hope was as obvious as it was heart-rending.

Harry nodded thoughtfully. “If you, well, can you tell us how he got away when everyone thought you’d killed him?”

Sirius took a deep breath. The man’s skin was stretched tight over his bones. Harry hated himself for not finding a way to get here even quicker. If Dumbledore had been a little more… Harry let the thought trail off. There really wasn’t another way that could have worked, aside from going public. And if that failed, then Sirius would likely be stuck in here forever.

“I suppose it doesn’t really matter anyway. Peter was an unregistered Animagus. He took the form of a rat, appropriately enough. I was in a hurry when I found him… as far as Dumbledore knew, I was the secret keeper for Lily’s Fidelius charm. Only I could have betrayed them. It was only a matter of time before the Aurors sought me out. I found him on a street crowded with Muggles, so I had to get close before I could stun him. I couldn’t have cared less about the Statute of Secrecy, but I wanted to get a clear shot. He spotted me at the last minute. He didn’t pull out a wand, just a knife. I wondered if he’d lost his wand when he cut off his finger and dropped it to the ground… His behaviour was so bizarre I began to wonder if he’d been put under the Imperius. I suppose I didn’t want to believe he’d willingly betrayed you. Then he dropped the knife and screamed at me for betraying James and Lily. He must have had his wand in his back pocket, because as I struggled through the crowd there was an explosion behind him that threw people to the ground like rag dolls. It blasted a hole all the way down to the sewers. He transformed and dropped through it before I could even speak.”

Sirius’ shoulders began to slump, as if telling his tale had extracted all the rigidity from his bones. He looked so tired and old that Harry could barely stand it.

“So we may be looking for a rat that’s missing a toe… off the left forepaw?” he asked slowly.

Sirius shook his head. “The right,” he corrected.

“Any other distinguishing marks?” Arthur asked quickly.

Sirius shook his head. “Just a common gray rat, a little on the fat side. It’s going to be almost impossible to find him.”

Harry smothered a grin as he noticed Arthur’s startled expression. “Well, at least we know what to look for. Are you allowed to receive post?”

Sirius shook his head. “I wouldn’t know. I doubt owls could get past the Dementors.”

Harry frowned. “Is there anyone you would like me to contact?”

Sirius just frowned at him curiously.

Harry sighed. “I told you I believe you are innocent. Is there anyone out there you would like me to talk to? Family? Friends?” He regretted the way his godfather flinched at the mention of family, but he had to ask.

“There is one,” he said slowly. “I don’t know if he’s alive or where he lives now. Remus Lupin was a friend of mine and your parents’ friend as well. He… he should know the truth. If an owl cannot reach him, I imagine Arthur would know someone in the Ministry who can locate him.”

“Why is that?” Arthur asked.

“He… well, he has a medical condition that is monitored by the Ministry,” he replied evasively.

“He thought you were the secret-keeper as well?” Harry asked.

Sirius sighed and tried to rub his eyes, but the chains on his arms would not allow it. Harry resisted a sudden impulse to rip them off his godfather. “At the time, there were rumours of a spy helping Voldemort. We thought it might have been him, so… we didn’t tell him.”

“And the spy turned out to be Pettigrew?” Arthur asked. The sympathy in his voice was palpable.

Sirius nodded and dropped his gaze. “It was all done so stupidly, really. I as good as killed your parents, Harry. I came up with the brilliant notion of secretly switching my role to Peter. Everyone knew how close James and I were, so I’d be the perfect decoy. Instead, I told James to trust the man who betrayed him.”

“Rubbish!” Harry snapped. “You are as much to blame as my father, which is to say not at all. There’s a rather large difference between being tricked and being a betrayer.”

Sirius’ head lifted suddenly and he stared at Harry.

Harry mentally kicked himself. It’s getting harder and harder to keep acting like a twelve year old… even a precocious one. “I’ve read a lot of books about Voldemort’s rise,” he explained. “He tricked a lot of people, didn’t he?”

“You have no idea, Harry,” Sirius whispered. “I only saw him once, thank Merlin, but he’s… well. It’s hard to describe.”

Maybe this is an opportunity to act a little childish and make up for earlier, Harry mused. “Well, I do have an idea. He snuck into Hogwarts last year trying to steal something. He possessed one of the Professors,” he said airily.

His godfather stared at him in shock. “How do you know this?” he asked.

“I, er, sort of killed his host.”

Sirius looked from Harry to Arthur, eyes widening. Mr. Weasley glanced sidelong at Harry and shook his head. “Ron told me about it. Harry stumbled across Professor Quirrell as he was trying to slip past the outer defences. Harry triggered it while he was in the middle.”

Harry shrugged. “He tried to grab me after he was hurt. Whatever my Mum did that night finished him off when he laid hands on me.” He was purposefully trying to act blasé about the whole incident. Hopefully a little premeditated immaturity would set their minds at ease.

“I should hope that will not be necessary in the future,” Arthur said crisply.

Harry shrugged. “From what that dark tosser said, I think I’m supposed to be the one who kicks his arse.”

Arthur sighed, and just for an instant Harry thought he saw Sirius’ lips twitch. He’d give almost anything to make the man smile. He’d spent twelve years in Azkaban, another year on the run, and then a final year under house arrest at Twelve Grimmauld Place… only to be murdered by his cousin trying to save Harry from his own stupidity. Between his rotten family and everything else, the poor bastard never got a break. Well, this time he’s got me and it’s going to be different. I don’t care what I have to do, he’s going to get out of here and live the life he deserves, Harry silently vowed.

“I don’t want you seeking him out,” the two men said, almost in unison. They looked at each other sharply and Harry almost laughed out loud.

“I promise I won’t,” Harry replied seriously. “I’m trying to learn as much as I can, as quickly as I can, so when he does come back, I’ll be ready for him.”

Arthur looked at Harry intently and the boy could almost feel him putting pieces together. His guardian nodded almost imperceptibly.

“So, you’ve finished your first year at Hogwarts?” Sirius asked, changing the subject.

Harry nodded gratefully. “This has probably been the best year of my life,” he said in a wondering tone. “I made some good friends, I learned more than I’d thought possible, and I even got to play Quidditch.”

“You play? For the house team?” Sirius leaned forward in his chair, and his eyes seemed almost lively. He’s as bad as Ron, Harry thought with amusement.

Harry nodded. “Yeah, it was brilliant. I wasn’t so crazy about the green and silver uniforms, but…” he let his voice trail off as Sirius’ mouth fell open. “I’m joking, I was sorted into Gryffindor.” He smiled slyly. “You should have seen the look on your face though.”

Sirius stared at him and Harry began to wonder if he’d miscalculated. A constricted grunting sound came from Sirius’ direction. As his godfather’s eyes widened, it erupted into a rusty chuckle. Harry felt his eyes prickle as he heard his godfather laugh for what had to be the first time in eleven years.

They talked for almost two hours. Fortunately, Arthur seemed to be as interested in getting to know Sirius as vice-versa. When the Aurors began to shift uncomfortably and try to catch their eyes, Harry and his guardian reluctantly got up from their chairs.

On a sudden impulse, Harry leaned across the table and gripped Sirius’ hand. Out of the corner of his eye, he saw the Aurors tense, but they didn’t intervene. “I’m going to raise bloody hell until they let you out of here, Sirius. I mean that.”

Sirius’ fingers were almost painfully tight around Harry’s. Then he let go convulsively and leaned back in his chair, closing his eyes.

Harry turned, glaring at the Aurors, thinking one of them had done something. None of them, however, had their wands out. A couple of them actually looked disturbed at what they’d overheard. He supposed that made sense; they knew better than anyone what it was like in the actual cells. The idea that an innocent man had been sentenced to that would have to be especially horrifying.

Arthur led a reluctant Harry from the visiting room. Neither of them spoke as they walked out to the docks and boarded the ferry. When they’d finally walked past the camouflage charms, Arthur broke the silence.

“Harry, I don’t want to head back to The Burrow immediately. I’m going to take us to the Ministry and place a few calls. Do you mind? I think your godfather’s description has made me a little paranoid, but better safe than sorry.”

Harry shook his head. He already had an idea of what was going on. Better to let Arthur run the show here. He knew he could trust the man to do the right thing, no matter what.

They Apparated to the Ministry, and Arthur checked them in and led Harry to the Misuse of Muggle Artefacts office. The office was large, but only contained a couple of desks, both unoccupied. The room had its own Floo fireplace, but the majority of the space was given over to large shelves and storage bins. The shelves contained all manner of odd items, most of which resembled junk or charity sale items.

Harry looked through these curiously as Arthur placed a series of Floo calls. He froze as he moved a tea set and saw a vaguely familiar shape of black metal and moulded plastic. It appeared to be a Glock 19, from the engraved logo near the muzzle. The war-mages in the American expeditionary force sometime carried side-arms like this. The soldiers usually had larger forty five calibre pistols, but the officers seemed to prefer the smaller nine millimetre design. While nowhere near as versatile as a wand, pistols had their advantages – like being much faster to use.

Harry jumped when Arthur’s voice came from directly behind him. “Ah, you stumbled onto one of our more interesting finds. This was seized from an Italian hit-wizard captured by the Aurors a fortnight ago.” He picked up the pistol awkwardly. “These Muggle wands… fire-legs? No, fire-arms, that’s it. They are quite odd. Anyway, this chap was a nasty piece of work. Had several Dark artefacts, a poisoned dagger and this little thing. We could tell it had several permanent charms placed on it: a self-cleaning enchantment and some sort of conjuration in the handle here.” He shrugged and lifted the pistol. Harry instinctively cringed back. “Too bad it appears to have ruined it. The spells seem to have frozen the workings.” He held it up, the muzzle dangerously close to his head, and pushed awkwardly on the trigger a few times. “See?”

Harry swallowed and nodded weakly. Arthur hadn’t slipped his finger completely through the trigger guard, so he wasn’t depressing the safety trigger. The warnings General Hastings’ men had given him were screaming through his mind. There is no such thing as an unloaded gun! Never point a weapon at something you don’t want dead!

“Well, it was an interesting idea that fellow had, even if it didn’t work. I might have another look at it tomorrow, though everything on this shelf is due to be destroyed. Mostly rubbish, but we can’t let it fall into the wrong hands.” He winked at Harry and smiled as he put the pistol back on the shelf.

Harry nodded weakly as the fireplace roared. When Arthur turned toward the green flames, Harry snatched the pistol off the shelf and shoved it into his robes, making sure nothing snagged on the trigger and the muzzle was pointed away from him. This was complicated by how hard his hands were shaking. Merlin’s balls! It’s a miracle he hasn’t blown his bloody brains out with that thing! He was distracted from his terror when Kingsley Shacklebolt stepped out of the fireplace.

“Hello,” Arthur said brightly, “I see you got my message. I appreciate you coming on short notice.”

The tall Auror smiled. “I don’t think you’d call me out for a wild snitch chase. Now what was this about capturing a fugitive?”

Arthur glanced apologetically at Harry. “Er, Harry, when your godfather described that rat, it seemed awfully familiar.”

Harry hoped the look of dawning comprehension on his face was convincing. “Scabbers?” he gasped.

Arthur nodded, looking uneasy. “I imagine he befriended Percy because he wanted to stay with us, a Wizarding family where he could overhear any news. The idea of that traitor living under my roof makes me physically ill.”

Kinglsey looked confused. “Traitor?”

“We’ve just been to see Sirius Black in Azkaban. The man is innocent.”

“Arthur, what are you talking about?”

“Harry here,” Arthur smiled, “remembers some of the events that led up to him receiving that scar. His parents’ voices… they mentioned Peter being their secret keeper, not Sirius. When Black confronted Pettigrew that day, Peter cut off a finger and blasted the street. Peter then transformed into a rat and fled into the sewers. Pettigrew is an unregistered Animagus, and his form sounds very similar to a rat that’s been living with my family for the last eleven years.”

The Kingsley Shacklebolt Harry remembered was famous for being completely unflappable. He showed no emotion when he stepped out the front door of Grimmauld Place to face Voldemort himself. His sacrifice gave Remus, Tonks, and the rest of the Order members time to flee. This Kingsley was several years younger and unseasoned by war; he was gobsmacked. “This isn’t some joke?” he asked weakly.

“I wouldn’t joke about such a thing,” Arthur replied.

“Why did you call me for this? Surely…” Kingsley’s voice trailed off.

“You were very helpful when Harry was hurt. And you, er…” Arthur’s voice trailed off. Harry remembered then that Shacklebolt had neglected to mention the illegally enchanted car Arthur’s sons used to rescue Harry from the Dursleys.

“I see,” Kingsley said gravely. “Well then, let’s go see about this rat. I think we should be careful not to alarm it beforehand…”

Harry’s recent Floo trips improved his landings. He only fell to one knee when they returned to The Burrow. Mrs. Weasley was just cleaning up from the midday meal. “Auror Shacklebolt!” she exclaimed with a smile. “Can I get you a cuppa?”

“Not right now, Molly,” Arthur said in a loud voice. He looked over at Ron, who was helping stack dishes along with Ginny. “Is Scabbers upstairs?”

“Yeah, in my room,” he answered, but frowned, “Why Dad?”

Arthur nodded to Kingsley. “Top of the stairs,” he said, then turned back to his son. “There’s a nasty bit of magical distemper going around, affecting rats and some other types of pets,” he explained in that loud voice again. “Kingsley is with the Department for the Regulation and Control of Magical Creatures. I asked him to check Scabbers and make sure he isn’t infected.”

Molly spun toward her husband when he misidentified Kingsley. Arthur gave her a very significant look and she said nothing. Harry couldn’t help but notice that she folded her dish towel so her hands were very close to the wand protruding from the pocket of her apron. Harry wasn’t sure if Ron and Ginny were carrying their wands, so he edged closer to his friends. He followed Arthur’s gaze and moved his eyes to watch the bottom of the stairs as well.

As they fell quiet, they couldn’t hear any voices upstairs. However, the distinctive crackle of a stunning spell broke the silence. A moment later, Kingsley was marching down the stairs carrying Scabbers’ cage. Inside, the rat was stretched out, unconscious.

Ron looked furious, but Harry grabbed his arm before he could interfere.

“Any trouble?” Arthur asked quickly.

“No. Your story was a good cover. He didn’t suspect a thing until I had my wand on him.” Kingsley replied.

“What are you doing with Scabbers?” Ron asked in an alarmed tone.

“Ronald,” Arthur said, “We need to test him for something a bit more serious. Auror Shacklebolt, do you know the charm?”

“I believe I remember. It doesn’t see a lot of use but they cover it in Auror training, just in case.” He closed his eyes for a moment, lips moving slowly. “That’s it. Animus Revalo!” A flash of white light enveloped the rat, and suddenly it began to glow bright red. Kingsley nodded. “That’s it, he tested positive.”

“Harry?” Ron asked. His friend looked worried and confused.

“Scabbers isn’t really a rat,” Harry said slowly. “He’s an Animagus, a wizard transformed into a rat.”

Ron’s eyes went wide. “Why on earth would someone masquerade as a rat?”

Harry sighed. “Because he betrayed my parents to Voldemort and framed my godfather for it,” he said quietly. He turned and walked out the back door as he heard the roar of the Floo and Kingsley’s voice calling for the Department of Magical Law Enforcement.

It was nearing dinner time when Ginny found him sitting cross-legged under a tree in the orchard. He’d been thinking about a lot of things. The murder of his parents, the knowledge that Wormtail had actually been captured this time, worry about how that would impact things, hope that Sirius would be freed soon. His thoughts spun in tighter and tighter circles, and he barely noticed when she thumped down next to him.

Even though it was covered by jeans and robes, he still jumped when she put her hand on his knee. “Are you all right in there, Harry?” she asked quietly.

“Mostly,” he said. He remembered when Ginny made him promise to never tell her again that he was ‘fine’. Of course, this isn’t the same Ginny, is it? he thought hollowly.

“Really?” she asked with surprise. “If I’d had a day like yours I’d be ready to hex something.”

Harry chuckled in spite of himself.

Ginny scowled at him. She began ticking off points on her fingers. “Let’s see. You get to see your godfather, who appears to be having a rough go of it, Dad thinks. You find out who really betrayed your parents and how they got away with it. You come back here and watch them actually catch the no-good toe-rag, which no doubt has you thinking about how you lost your parents. No,” she concluded dryly, “No good reason to be even slightly upset.”

Harry went very still. For an instant, he was fifteen years old in number twelve Grimmauld place and Ginny was telling him where to get off. He’d been so worried about being possessed by Voldemort he’d forgotten to even ask her what it felt like. His hand tightened around the one she’d laid on his knee. He didn’t even remember grasping it. His eyes were fixed on the ground.

Ginny gave his knee a squeeze before she pulled her hand back and stood up. Harry felt a stab of self-pity before he ruthlessly squelched it. I’m probably making her uncomfortable, he realized. I should have expected that… No one wants to see the Boy-Who-Lived acting weak, he concluded bitterly.

He let out a grunt when Ginny plopped down in his lap. She sat with her legs stretched out to his left, but twisted around until she was facing him. She wrapped her arms around his neck and pulled his head down to her shoulder. Harry froze again. The fabric of her blouse was warm on his forehead. He was glad the pistol had been shoved under his armpit when he sat down.

“Mum did this for Daddy when Uncle Bilius died,” Ginny murmured. “Harry, you’re supposed to be sad when people die. It would be weird if you didn’t.”

Harry shuddered, but managed not to cry. He didn’t know what to do with his arms until he wrapped them around her waist. She shifted, and he started to pull back but she tightened her arms around his neck. Her breath tickled his skin. For a moment, he allowed himself to forget.

He didn’t know how long they sat there before they heard Ron calling out that dinner was ready. Ginny sat up and Harry realized he’d almost dozed off. She stood up and he followed, wincing at the pins and needles sensation flooding his legs.

“Thanks Ginny,” he murmured as they walked back to The Burrow.

She smiled impishly at him. “What are friends for?” she asked.

He remembered another eleven year old girl putting her elbow in the butter dish. Things are changing, he thought with a sense of wonder. Another strange feeling began to flutter at the base of his stomach. It took him a moment to identify it.

For the first time in years, Harry Potter felt the faint stirrings of hope.

21

Sirius & A Quidditch Spectacle

That evening Neville received a hero’s welcome in the Gryffindor common room, which rather embarrassed him. Percy, however, proved to be the exception to the rule. The Weasley prefect seemed to revel in his role as the official killjoy and began berating Neville in front of everyone. This earned Percy some mutinous glares from his housemates, which he ignored.

As Harry watched his friend wilt under Percy’s tirade, he finally snapped. “Right!” he snarled as he jumped to his feet and grabbed a handful of Percy’s robes. “You and I need to have a little talk, right now!” With that he dragged the taller boy toward the portrait hole.

Percy was a good bit larger than Harry, but when he began to resist, Harry sank down into a deep front stance and continued driving forward. Between Harry’s lower centre of gravity and some unexpected leg strength, the prefect was yanked forward off balance. Out in the corridor, Harry brought them to an alcove and spun toward Percy, releasing his rumpled robes.

“All right,” Harry said coldly. “You don’t like me. That’s fine. Everyone is entitled to their opinion. But when you start taking it out on my friends, your licence to be an utter prat gets revoked. Do I make myself clear, Percival?”

“You don’t tell me how to do my job, Potter,” Percy snapped. “Longbottom committed assault in front of the entire school. That sort of conduct is unacceptable for anyone.”

Harry sighed disgustedly and shook his head. “Did you ever stop to ask why Neville lost his temper? Do you even care? Or has your self-righteous furore driven the last vestiges of logical thought from your head?”

Percy started to open his mouth, but stopped. He frowned and crossed his arms, glaring down at Harry, waiting.

“Let me tell you a little story, Percy, that started shortly after my parents were murdered,” Harry said in a flat voice. “A group of Death Eaters raided the Longbottom house. They were trying to find out about just what happened to Voldemort because they didn’t believe that he’d just disappeared. The Longbottoms were highly respected Aurors, and the Death Eaters reckoned that they knew what was really going on. They used the Cruciatus curse on the Longbottoms until they were driven completely out of their minds. They’ve been in Saint Mungo’s long term care ever since. Neville visits them every so often, but as far as anyone can tell, they don’t even know that he’s their son.”

Percy’s face had gone pale as he heard this, but his expression also grew puzzled. “What does this have to do with what happened today?”

“The Death Eaters, who were captured and sentenced to life in Azkaban,” Harry continued, “were led by Bellatrix Lestrange, Draco Malfoy’s aunt on his mother’s side. This morning, when Draco was taunting Luna, he decided to throw in a crack about Luna not being able to talk because she’d lost her mind. Only he was staring at Neville as he said it.” Harry nodded in satisfaction when he saw Percy’s shocked, angry expression. “Exactly – in your parents’ day, he could have legally challenged Draco to a death duel for making a comment like that.”

Percy took a deep breath. “I – I was not fully aware of the circumstances. Neville still needs to control his temper in the future, but I will admit that in this instance he was most seriously provoked.” There was an implied apology in his words.

Harry nodded. “I knew you wouldn’t have come down on him if you knew all the circumstances.” It was a rather backhanded compliment as well. He paused and then stuck out his hand.

Percy frowned for a moment, and then shook it. “I need to talk to Professor McGonagall. You’d better get back to the common room before curfew.”

Harry nodded and walked back to the Fat Lady’s portrait. When he returned, he found everyone still gathered in the common room, talking excitedly. The twins had set up a betting pool based on, among other things, how many times Harry was going to hex Percy. When Harry returned alone, money immediately began changing hands. He growled as soon as he understood what was going on. If Percy got wind of this, any progress they’d made would be lost and he’d become even more difficult to deal with.

As he walked over, he noticed the couch was full and began looking for an empty chair. Confrontations of any sort tended to leave him a little drained. It was possible that the non-violent types were even worse, since there was no physical release for his muscular tension. Luna appeared to notice Harry’s predicament because she stood up from her seat between Ginny and Neville.

“Hey,” Harry objected, “you don’t have to—” He shut his mouth when Luna smoothed her robes and then flopped down in Neville’s lap. “Never mind – Luna, thanks!” Harry suppressed a grin at the expression frozen on Neville’s face. As he sat down, Harry noticed Ginny was stifling a giggle as well.

Harry scratched his head and tried to organize his thoughts. “Look, Percy and I have come to a bit of an understanding. So let’s not do anything to muck it up, yeah?” He addressed that mainly toward the twins and Ron, but he noticed Ginny nodding as well, a small smile on her lips. He looked around and noticed most of the Gryffindors were drifting away to attend to their own schoolwork, now that the excitement seemed to be over. “Since we’re all here, we should also, er, practise our homework, you know.”

With that, they all pulled out a book, but soon their eyes were closed rather than open as they began their Occlumency exercises. Harry tested each of them, noting their progress. Ron was a bit steadier and even Ginny was beginning to show some resistance to him. Hermione was frowning and turning her head slightly from time to time, so it seemed like she was testing their friends as well.

Harry had given some thought to what he would do as his friends began to master Occlumency. He could tell them everything individually when their defences grew sure. But the people who were still somewhat open would likely feel excluded to some extent. While those feelings might motivate them to work harder, Harry was loath to do anything that would make his friends feel uncomfortable around himself or each other. There was also the likelihood that they would feel betrayed when they discovered the truth about him and his manipulations. Bad enough if they decided that they didn’t want anything to do with him after that, but to lose them one by one as he told them would be worse. It would also make it harder for them if half of them suddenly hated Harry and couldn’t tell the rest of them why.

Besides, it also delayed the inevitable and gave him a little more time with them. After all he’d been through, was a little more time so much to ask?

Harry shook his head to clear it of morbid thoughts. They’d still be alive, and that was why he’d come back, wasn’t it? Better Ginny married to Michael Corner or Dean Thomas than lying in that ruined courtyard, tortured to death because of his stupidity. Better to see Ron and Hermione married and making their own lives than dead following Harry on his fool’s crusade. Luna and Neville might even have a chance together in this timeline, provided he didn’t screw things up too badly. Even if he died taking Voldemort with him, he’d leave behind a much better and happier world. The important thing was making sure the prophecy was fulfilled with Voldemort’s destruction. Whatever happened after that would happen. His part would be done and he could rest.

Harry sighed and leaned his aching head forward on his palms as he planted his elbows on his knees. He knew his thoughts were spiralling downward out of control, but sometimes he just got so damn tired of it all. The wheels of fate could grind just as finely as those of justice.

He was about to get up and leave when Ginny put her hand on his shoulder. He jumped a little and turned toward her. She pulled her hand back, but her eyes were questioning. How did she know I was upset? Harry wondered, but he just shrugged and gave her a lop-sided smile. He settled back on the cushions as she closed her eyes again. Harry took a deep breath. Clearing his mind was seldom this hard.

The articles about Sirius continued, though they were starting to become less frequent. The Ministry was refusing to divulge any details, and requests by members of the press to interview either prisoner were denied ‘for security reasons’. The reporters were prowling for blood, but the Ministry was still stonewalling them.

Harry and Hermione researched the possibility of simply hiring a lawyer to file an appeal on Sirius’ behalf. They were a little shocked at how primitive the appellate system was in the magical world. They couldn’t find any clauses that guaranteed a convicted prisoner access to legal counsel. At one time, a wrongly convicted wizard could challenge his oppressor to a duel to obtain legal redress, but the repeal of the duelling code closed this avenue.

Hermione had to elbow Harry to break him out of a pleasant daydream involving challenging Fudge to a formal duel and kicking the spineless politician’s arse in exchange for Sirius’ freedom.

The Wizarding legal system seemed to assume that there was no way they could make an error and convict the wrong man. Of course, with all the magical means that existed to get at the truth, it would be difficult for them to get it wrong – provided the accused actually got a day in court. Apparently the de facto imprisonment of Sirius Black was a rather unusual precedent in Wizarding law. That made the powers that be even more culpable for his imprisonment. More importantly, they would likely go to even greater lengths to avoid admitting their error.

“It might be easier to start researching jail-breaks,” Harry finally said with a groan one afternoon.

He was a little shocked when Hermione looked thoughtful rather than immediately yelling that he wasn’t funny. “I’m starting to wonder if there is a legal means of doing this, if people in the Ministry are going to hold him completely incommunicado,” Hermione pondered.

“I’m worried that they have something else planned,” Harry muttered.

He thought he might be able to introduce some of what he’d overheard in a way that wouldn’t garner suspicion. “I’ve been thinking about other reasons people might want Sirius locked away. He’s now the last of the Blacks, and there is a considerable family fortune being held in trust while he’s in Azkaban. He has a cousin, Nymphadora, who’s an Auror, but her mother was formally disinherited before she died. His cousin Bellatrix is in Azkaban as well, but his other cousin Narcissa is Draco’s mum.”

Hermione’s eyes went wide. “So if he dies in prison, Narcissa and the Malfoys would receive the Black inheritance?”

Harry nodded. “They might be afraid to do anything overt to kill him, but between the cold and the Dementors, Azkaban is not a healthy place to be. If he died of something like that, it wouldn’t raise as many questions, would it?”

Hermione got a sick look on her face. “Harry, that’s horrible!”

“Would you honestly put it past people like Draco’s family to bribe the Ministry to guarantee they got his money?”

Hermione looked like she was on the verge of tears as she shook her head.

Harry felt like a heel for asking Hermione to waste her time on the fruitless search, so he and Ron got together with the twins a few nights before her birthday and sent the fourth year students off to Hogsmeade. Harry provided a small stack of galleons and Ron provided a dire threat that he would personally thrash the two of them if her gift was pranked in any way, shape or form. Neville was walking by and offered to help with the thrashing – his pounding of Malfoy had given the formerly shy boy a little bit of a swagger when he walked. That of course disappeared when Luna was around. She seemed to make him very nervous for some reason.

The twins winked mysteriously and disappeared soon afterward. Harry knew they were using the Marauder’s Map and the secret passage into Honeydukes, so he wasn’t really worried about them getting caught. He didn’t really want to loan them his invisibility cloak. He wasn’t sure he’d ever get it back and letting those pranksters know about it was like showing a pyromaniac where the napalm and matches were stored.

He and Ron were a little nervous as they waited for Fred and George to return. Sometimes their sense of the appropriate was a bit – off. When they waltzed into the common room, their grins made Harry’s stomach drop. One of them nonchalantly tossed a small box to Ron.

“There. Now let’s see if we’ve earned a beating, oh brother of mine,” Fred chirped.

“Perhaps we should step back so we’ll have a bit of a head start,” George said dramatically.

Harry’s fears proved unfounded as Ron fumbled the box open. Inside was a golden locket in the shape of a book. It opened to reveal a small mirror and a place to fix a photo. Harry had made a copy of the group shot Colin took of all of them and shrank it down until it fit into the opening.

“Does ickle Harrikins think we need to sleep with one eye open tonight?” Fred asked.

Harry smiled as Ron closed the locket and replaced it in the box. “No, you two have done quite well. I’m almost sorry I doubted you.”

“Always do the unexpected, Harry, that’s something George and I learned from the Marauders,” Fred said in sage-like voice.

“The Marauders?” Harry asked curiously.

“The marvellous, multi-talented pranksters of yesteryear, my good man,” George explained in a grand voice. “They attended Hogwarts long before us, but their legacy remains and Fred and I are proud to uphold their traditions of pranking excellence.”

“Do you know who they were?” Ron asked.

“No,” Fred said shaking his head. “Just their nicknames, Prongs, Padfoot, Moony, and Wormtail.”

Harry was tempted for a moment to just tell them that one of their heroes was locked up in Azkaban and then stand back. On the other hand, the Ministry might need that prison again some day.

Ginny and Luna made a card to go with the gift that all of them signed. Ron and Neville felt like they should have contributed more, until Harry pointed out the key role their dire threats played in keeping the twins from buying a locket that turned into a rubber chicken.

Of course, Harry wasn’t above manoeuvring things so that Ron was sitting next to Hermione in the common room when Harry nudged the boy and passed him the box with the card.

Ron looked horrified when she opened the locket and promptly burst into tears. He hesitantly patted her arm and assured her if she hated it they could get her something else – he was sure the twins had kept the receipt. Ron yelped when she suddenly grabbed him around the neck in a tight hug.

She let him go after a couple of minutes, sniffing and wiping at her eyes. “I’m sorry,” she said shakily. “You must think I’m mental.”

“No,” Luna said. “You’ve just never had friends before, have you?”

Hermione’s head snapped to the side and she stared at the blonde-haired girl.

Luna looked back at her, cocking her head to the side. Harry noticed her right hand was resting on Neville’s forearm. “It’s not hard to guess. I never had any friends before I came to Hogwarts either. Harry seems to have gathered a lot of interesting people together, hasn’t he?”

Harry blinked and swallowed. This Luna was a little more perceptive, or perhaps she was just more open with her perceptions. “Maybe I just recognize quality folk when I see them,” he replied in a swotty tone of voice. Everyone laughed at that and Harry felt his stomach unclench.

“Well, I do appreciate this – all of you,” Hermione said as she abruptly let go of Ron and flushed. “I – I did have a few friends at school – before – but they only seemed interested in having me help them with their homework.”

“And we know how you hate helping people with their homework,” Ron teased.

Hermione snorted and looked away. “I suppose you want to finish that transfiguration essay on your own then?” she asked tartly.

Ron shrugged. “I’ll muddle through.”

Hermione’s head snapped back around and she stared incredulously at Ron.

Ron looked her square in the eyes and responded in a very matter-of-fact tone. “If you have any doubts about whether we’re just being nice to get help, then I’d rather you didn’t help me.” It was one of the calmest and most mature things Harry could remember this version of Ron ever saying.

Hermione had a stricken look on her face. “Ron, I didn’t mean it, not seriously. I was just teasing you back.”

Ron shrugged and smiled faintly. “I know, but I didn’t want there to be any doubt either. You don’t have to buy our friendship, you know.”

Hermione just stared at him. Eventually Harry got a little uncomfortable and turned away, coughing discreetly.

After dinner the next day, Ginny cornered Harry in the hallway outside the Gryffindor common room.

“That was very nice what you did,” she said.

“What I did?”

“I know Ron couldn’t afford that locket,” Ginny said, slouching into a don’t-try-to-fool-me posture.

Harry shrugged, a little uncomfortable. “I supplied the galleons, Ron and Neville ‘persuaded’ the twins to go pick it up with no funny business.”

“But you organized this.”

“Well, she’s been spending a lot of time on legal research for Sirius,” Harry explained.

Ginny nodded. “And then you made sure Ron gave it to her.”

Harry grinned, a little sheepishly. Trust Ginny to pick up on that.

“Why are you trying to fix Hermione up with my brother, of all people?”

Harry’s heart skipped a beat. He wondered how transparent his manoeuvring was. How long until everyone else started noticing? How long until he was forced to answer some very uncomfortable questions. Harry fidgeted with the neck of his robes, trying not to imagine a noose. “Ron isn’t that bad,” he said, playing for time.

Ginny frowned up at him. “It’s not that, I mean, you two are the smartest out of us. I was just wondering why you didn’t – well—” she trailed off, embarrassed to state the obvious conclusion.

I can’t believe I’m having this conversation, Harry mused as his face burned hot and cold.

“Well I hear you and Luna are doing quite well,” he replied.

Why did I just say that? he wondered.

“I like Hermione just fine – as a friend – but we, er, both tend to worry. A lot, you know. Ron’s good for that.”

“Yeah, he never worries about anything except Quidditch,” Ginny agreed, rolling her eyes. She looked left and right down the corridor. “Well, we better get in there before people wonder what happened to us.” With that she grabbed Harry’s wrist and led him toward the Fat Lady’s portrait.

What the hell was that all about? Harry wondered, flustered, as she gave the password.

A week later, Sirius Black was in the news again. The Ministry reported that the man had somehow escaped from Azkaban, probably by resorting to the darkest of magic.

Harry sat, stunned, as he read the Daily Prophet.

“…This only shows that the man is truly guilty of the crimes he was charged with,” said a senior Ministry official, “and this will hopefully put those ridiculous rumours to rest.”

Harry read the rest of the article, which was basically a re-tread of the recent history of the case. The slant of the article was that as hopes for his release faded, the dark wizard grew desperate and broke out on his own by means of some heretofore unknown magic.

Harry stared down at his plate, lost in thought as the others read the story.

“Well, at least he’s out, right Harry?” Ron asked, breaking the uncomfortable silence.

“We only have their word for it,” Harry whispered.

Hermione frowned then gasped. “You think they ‘disappeared’ him?”

Harry nodded.

“They what?” Ron asked.

Hermione gave Harry a worried look before she answered. “I did a report on Latin America when I was in Muggle school,” Hermione explained. “People who disagree with the government tend to disappear – no records, no arrests, they just vanish in the middle of the night. Most of them are killed by their own government.”

“The Ministry wouldn’t do that!” Ron gasped, horrified.

“Ron,” Harry said wearily, “you said yourself Draco’s dad paid a lot of bribes and was able to stay out of Azkaban. How many people do you think he murdered as a Death Eater?”

“Harry,” Ron hissed, “Dad works there! They wouldn’t – they couldn’t…”

“I don’t think the whole government is corrupt, Ronald,” Hermione said patiently, “and I don’t think Harry is saying that either.”

“But I’m not going to trust blindly if I can help it,” Harry insisted. “I don’t think Mr. Weasley would disagree with that attitude either. Remember how suspicious he was about Auror Shacklebolt being sent to Italy?”

Ron nodded, but his face was still troubled.

“Harry, he might really have escaped too,” Hermione said. “We are making some assumptions here.”

“But why would he escape when people are finally asking questions about his case?” Neville asked.

“We don’t know that he’s even aware of that,” Harry said. “I haven’t been able to see him after that first meeting.” The first time around, it took the realization that Wormtail was travelling to Hogwarts with Harry to get Sirius to risk his soul and try to slip past the Dementors. And with the knowledge that Peter was an Animagus, the guards would be more suspicious of a large dog that suddenly appeared.

Harry walked through the rest of the day in a haze of fear, doubt, and worry. The worst part, of course, was his utter helplessness to do anything about the situation. What the hell was the use of travelling back to the past only to have to watch things get screwed up again in newer and more dramatic fashions? Sirius’ death in his previous life seemed to herald the beginning of the dark days. Was it going to happen even sooner this time? Had all his meddling only accelerated the process? Was the entire magical world in each time line little more than a pile of oil-soaked tinder, waiting for any excuse to catch fire?

Was fate some vindictive harridan that resented his meddling? Was she going to respond by making things go to hell even faster this time around? For the first time in a while, Harry began to entertain the possibility that he really might lose. He wondered if there was any way he could just take his friends and leave the country, maybe emigrate to the United States or Australia… some place they’d never heard of Voldemort or the damn Prophecy. Of course it would be almost impossible to persuade all the Weasleys to leave the country. Not to mention Hermione’s parents, Neville’s Gran, and Luna’s father. Could he leave Hagrid and the Hogwarts staff to their fates? Did the students outside of Gryffindor not deserve to escape their fate as well?

In short, Harry was well and truly trapped.

Damnation.

That night, Harry’s Occlumency exercises did little to quiet his mind. His dreams decided to play a medley of some of his subconscious’ greatest hits. He watched Cedric and Sirius die, and then Dumbledore. He watched Hermione step in front of a curse meant for Ron; he watched Ron do the same for himself. He watched Hogwarts burn and Ginny die, which was the cruellest of all; he hadn’t been there, to his eternal shame, and he couldn’t possibly have memories of that horror, but his subconscious decided to fill in the blanks. He saw her torn and battered body lying on the ground, writhing as Draco cursed her. The harsh glow from his wand cast his features in demonic relief as he lowered himself onto her…

Harry awoke to find himself in midair, having sprung from his bed. The canopy ripped loose and was flying across the room as the duvet burst into flames. Harry bit off his scream of rage as he realized he was beyond the silencing charms placed on his bed. He barely managed to tuck his shoulder under as he fell and rolled into a crouch in the middle of the room.

Harry rose shakily to his feet and grabbed his wand off the bedside table. A wave and a muttered charm restored the duvet, and another re-attached the torn canopy. His pyjamas were soaked with sweat and Harry felt like he’d just run a marathon. It took over half an hour under the hottest shower he could stand before the shaking in his hands even started to abate.

Hours later, Harry drove them mercilessly on the morning run. When he sparred with Ron, he nearly cracked his friend’s ribs when he was sloppy with a block. The boy glared at him as he tried to get his wind back.

“You trying to kill me, Harry?”

“You should take this seriously. It might save your life some day,” Harry growled.

Ron frowned. He expected Harry to joke back, not snap at him. “You want to tell me what’s bothering you?”

“I can’t, Ron, not until you learn how to maintain your Occlumency and not let it slip every time you get bored.” Harry’s voice sounded both weary and irritated at the same time.

Ron flinched back like he’d been slapped and Harry abruptly felt ashamed of himself.

“I’m sorry, mate. I had a very, very bad night. But I shouldn’t take it out on you.”

“Better me than the girls, Harry. I, at least, won’t hex you for it.” He cuffed Harry on the shoulder and they resumed sparring.

Ron’s remark reminded Harry of something though. He cut the martial arts practice short and led them back out to the lake at a quick jog.

Soon they were standing on the shore as Harry gathered a small pile of stones.

“All right. We’re going to work on some slightly more serious spells than you’ll see in Lockhart’s classroom. The cutting charm is called ‘Diffindo’, and you use it with a whipping motion like this,” he said as he demonstrated. “Visualize a very sharp wedge of force emanating from the end of your wand. Now, to start, we’re going to practise just casting it into the water near the shore. The merpeople are out in the deep water, so we won’t risk hurting anyone. Any questions?”

“Is this what you used to kill that troll?” Ron asked.

“Yeah. Its hide was pretty tough though. I had to wait for Neville to get it to open its mouth before I could really hurt it.” Harry replied as he noticed Hermione frowning.

Harry had to demonstrate the wand motion a couple of times for Ginny and Luna before they were confident they had it down.

After that, as Harry led the count, they practised casting the spell at the unresisting water. As the spells discharged into the surface of the lake, small plumes of water shot into the air. Harry noticed that his spells were creating noticeably larger splashes than the others, so he began focusing less and less when he cast.

Once they were all comfortable with the spell, Harry began tossing rocks into the air in front of them as he counted. At first, none of them could strike a small, moving target. But with practice, they improved. Ginny was the first to strike a glancing blow. Then Hermione pulverized the next, followed by Ron and Neville scoring a simultaneous hit. Luna squinted fiercely, but still had problems connecting as the others improved.

When Harry ran out of rocks, Ron and Neville helped him gather more. Hermione, however, was talking to Luna and pointing toward the Quidditch pitch. “Luna,” she asked, “how many of the goal hoops can you make out from here?”

Luna frowned at Hermione. “You can see the hoops?”

Hermione nodded and held up her fingers in front of Luna’s face. “I want you to watch my fingers and tell me when they start to get blurry.” She began to back away from the younger girl.

When she was about twenty feet away Luna spoke up. “All I can see now is the hand, not the individual fingers.” She held up her own hand. “You can see my fingers from there?”

“Quite easily,” Hermione replied. “It appears you are a little nearsighted.”

“Oh,” Luna said tonelessly. “I was hoping I could hold out for farsighted.”

“Well,” Hermione continued like she hadn’t heard anything, “that would explain why you were having so much trouble with the moving targets, but can still read fine.”

Hermione prevailed upon Harry to end the practice so they could have an early breakfast. After they showered and ate, Hermione dragged Luna off to Madam Pomfrey before the first class period began. At lunch time, Luna was sporting an elegant pair of silver wire-frame glasses that framed her pale blue eyes. The first year witch was frowning as she began eating.

“It may be a little uncomfortable at first, but Madam Pomfrey said that should pass,” Hermione reassured her.

“I think they look rather unattractive,” Luna said as she fiddled with the string of butterbeer corks around her neck.

“Harry’s got glasses and he looks all right,” Ginny quickly reassured her.

Luna stared across the table at Ginny, cocking her head. “Harry is a boy. It’s all right if he looks unattractive.”

Harry opened his mouth to say something but stopped, as he didn’t have a clue as to what he could say in response. Ginny surreptitiously patted his leg under the table. Harry turned toward her, thinking just how he could tell either girl that he didn’t care if his glasses made him look unattractive, but finally just gave it up as a bad job all around.

Luna turned toward Neville, who appeared to be doing his best to stay out of the whole discussion. “What do you think? Do these glasses look unattractive?”

Neville frowned and swallowed. “I think they look very nice on you, Luna,” he said sincerely.

“Oh,” Luna said. She shrugged. “That’s all right then.” She patted the nervous boy on the arm and began eating her lunch. “At least it might be easier to spot a crumple-horned Snorkack if father gets the chance to travel this summer.”

Harry appreciated the distraction his friends provided him from his worries, but his sleep grew increasingly disturbed. They added spell-casting drills to their daily routine and began getting up half an hour earlier. Harry showed them a variety of nasty curses and hexes, all of which were potentially lethal or capable of knocking someone down and keeping them down.

As they worked together, Harry became increasingly aware of the difference between spells he cast and those his friends cast. It was especially apparent when they were casting Reducto spells into the surface of the lake. His friends’ spells were throwing up geysers of white water at the point of impact. The largest of these was over six feet tall, but Harry was matching it even while he was withholding most of his power.

He was pondering Healer Stanhope’s words about his MaRI test results when he started counting out loud again. Their volleys set off another set of geysers each time he counted. Evidently Ron had been trying to say something because he suddenly grabbed Harry’s shoulder. Startled, Harry accidentally pushed all his magic down his arm into the outstretched wand.

The wood bucked hard in Harry’s grip and the light that flew toward the lake seemed to be almost a solid mass. There was a loud thump as a column of water two feet wide and over thirty feet tall exploded upward from the surface of the lake. Harry barely had time to close his eyes before they were drenched with cold, fishy-smelling water. Someone let out a squeal and he was sure he heard a fairly vile curse or two.

When he’d knuckled the muddy water out of his eyes, Harry saw stunned fish begin floating belly up in the agitated water. He turned toward Ron, who was blinking rapidly. Hermione looked shocked, but Ginny was red-faced from holding back either laughter or tears.

Ron finally found his voice. “I was going to ask if we were about done. I wanted to make sure I had time to take a shower before breakfast.”

“I think Harry saved you some time there,” Ginny said before she sank to her knees, laughing uproariously.

Harry nervously scanned the Daily Prophet each morning at breakfast, but the only word his daily ritual yielded about Sirius consisted of vague rumours and alleged appearances in the unlikeliest of places. Harry had yet to read a “Black Sighting” that didn’t sound like a complete hoax.

On the other hand, Molly wrote that Aurors had stopped by The Burrow several times, supposedly to interview her and Arthur. However, they seemed to be more interested in looking around the house than talking to anyone. Molly also saw several new faces in the village when she went to do her shopping.

Harry was also interviewed by several Ministry officials at the school, though Professor McGonagall insisted on attending these meetings in her capacity as his Head of House. Though he didn’t think it truly necessary, Harry was amused to observe the quelling effect his stern protector had on the Auror who was evidently assigned the role of ‘bad cop’. It certainly didn’t help when Minerva reminded the man that he’d gotten much lower marks in her classes than Harry.

After they left, Harry thanked her politely and informed her that if she ever wanted to hold a workshop on how to discreetly intimidate people that she could easily fill the Great Hall. Professor McGonagall’s thin lips did not curl when she raised an arched eyebrow, but she did say, “Indeed,” with a hint of warmth.

October brought damp and chilly weather, forcing them to bundle up for their morning exercises. Hermione found a water-repelling charm in the library that made her extremely popular with her classmates.

Harry was especially grateful for her discovery as he returned from Quidditch practice the first weekend of the month. The new brooms were the only bright spot in the day. Oliver’s enthusiasm was not dampened by the elements, and so he drove them mercilessly. Harry was secretly amused to note that they were practising just as hard as they had in his previous reality, when they hadn’t won the Quidditch Cup his first year.

He did try and talk his friends out of escorting him to and from practice, but Ron was having none of it. Ron was convinced that Draco and his cronies were just biding their time. Harry would have argued that he was going to extremes, but he knew that in the future that sort of thinking would be necessary, so he bit his tongue.

As they re-entered the castle, Harry saw Nearly Headless Nick drift by muttering to himself and the Boy Who Lived remembered the events that led to him attending the Gryffindor house ghost’s Deathday Party.

Having no great desire to smell a lot of rotting food, or obtain proof that Mr. Filch was a squib, Harry stopped dead in his tracks and quickly cleaned himself using the Scourgify charm. Harry nodded toward Mrs. Norris, who’d just rounded the corner, and directed his friends to clean themselves up before the cantankerous caretaker caught up with his cat. He directed a few cleansing charms at the water puddled on the floor as well.

When Argus rounded the corner, he found a lot of slightly damp students standing on a suspiciously clean section of flagstones. The bitter old man heartily disapproved of any sort of cleaning magic as effeminate and dishonest. Cleanliness should only be obtained by hard work, he claimed, and he didn’t hesitate to punish anyone he found using spells to speed things up. He really despised house elves, Harry knew, no matter that their efforts were the only thing that allowed Hogwarts to function as it did. Fortunately, the man’s lack of magical ability also made it difficult for him to punish anyone when the offence didn’t happen right in front of him. So he merely scowled as he brushed past them.

They all laughed about the close call during dinner that night. When asked what had tipped him off, Harry said he saw Mrs. Norris watching them enter the Great Hall out of the corner of his eye.

Ron growled. “That mangy beast tries to get everyone in trouble. I’d like to give her a good kick if she ever stopped moving close by.”

“Ronald!” Hermione sniffed. “I thought having your own cat would give you a little more empathy for other people’s pets.”

“Crookshanks can’t stand Mrs. Norris either, Hermione. He gets along fine with the village strays, but every time he sees her he starts snarling – probably because she’s Filch’s narsty ickle spy.”

Hermione just sighed and shook her head. It was hard to disagree since Crookshanks did go out of his way to warn Mrs. Norris from coming anywhere near the Gryffindor tower. The kneazle-cross was several times the size of the other cat, so the warnings were quite effective, making Ron’s familiar very popular with the twins and other housemates.

The Halloween Feast was quite spectacular. Hagrid’s pumpkins had grown enormous, and Professor Flitwick had proven to be quite an artist when it came to carving absolutely terrifying visages into the rinds. After a couple of first year Hufflepuff girls fainted dead away when a life-size giant’s head snapped at them, Harry concluded that animating the jack-o-lanterns had been just a bit over the top.

Of course, Harry wondered if the frightening decorations were the sole reason Luna was holding onto an even more nervous Neville’s arm.

The food was incredible, of course, but Harry found himself losing his appetite. Worrying about things he had no control over was a singularly useless occupation. Harry knew this. But he couldn’t stop himself from stewing about his godfather. He sat there staring at his plate for a few moments, and then jumped when a fork deposited a slab of rare roast beef on the plate, followed by a wedge of steak-and-kidney pie. He frowned at Ginny, who was matter-of-factly loading his plate with all of his favourite dishes.

“Starving yourself isn’t going to help anyone,” she whispered tersely. If the others even noticed what she was doing, they gave no indication of it.

“I know,” Harry said, sighing. “I’m just…”

“You’re worried about him. But Harry, you’re not Merlin. If you find a way to help him, I’m sure you will. But until then, you need to take care of yourself. If you run yourself into the ground, you might get the opportunity to help him, but be unable to act on it.” She said this very calmly as she cut up her steak.

“How did you get so smart?” Harry asked in an amused tone.

“I cheated.”

Harry blinked. “You cheated?”

“I wrote Mum. She’s rather good at lecturing people.” Ginny cocked her head and looked at him sidelong. “Would you rather hear it from me now, or get an overdose of it when we go home for holidays?”

“Er, from you.”

Ginny nodded and smiled. “Good answer, Potter.”

It’s rather frightening, he mused as he ate his dinner, how well she can read me. Was she always this perceptive? And was I just too incredibly stupid to notice?

The day of the match against Slytherin was damp and muggy, which Harry supposed was an improvement over the ‘pouring water out of a boot’ rain that had dominated the previous month.

Harry ate a modest breakfast before going out to get suited up. He wasn’t nearly as bad as he used to be, when he often couldn’t eat at all before a match, but he still felt vaguely nauseous when the adrenalin started to flow.

“All right, we’ve got an absolute parity of brooms,” Oliver told them during his pre-game pep-talk. He ignored the fact that Harry was still mounted on his Nimbus Two Thousand, since the Two Thousand and One wasn’t that big an improvement and he was intimately familiar with the quirks of the broom he’d flown for over a year. “We’ve trained harder than anyone,” Oliver continued, ignoring the grumbles that followed that statement. The fact of the matter was that he’d driven the team mercilessly since the day they received their new brooms. “And we want it worse than they do,” he growled and then turned toward Harry. “You made some big claims about beating Malfoy to the Snitch,” Wood growled. “Now you need to make good on them. Get the Snitch or die trying!”

“No pressure, Harry,” Fred said, winking. George rolled his eyes and made a face behind Oliver’s back.

Harry cracked his knuckles in an overly dramatic fashion that had the twins chuckling. “The Snitch isn’t in question. What I want to see is if I can make Draco piss himself before I catch it.”

Oliver stared at him for a long moment before echoing Harry’s feral grin. “Right. Good lad! Now let’s go, Lions!” he roared as he led them out onto the pitch.

Without Dobby’s rogue Bludger to distract him, Harry made sure Draco had a very long afternoon. The Slytherin seeker zipped around the pitch a few times, calling Harry ‘Scarhead’ and showing off his new broom. Harry supposed he also wanted to intimidate the Hufflepuff and Ravenclaw players they’d be facing later in the season. According to the grapevine, those houses were less than pleased about the Slytherins and Gryffindors receiving new brooms. Professor Flitwick was working toward cutting a similar endorsement deal with Comet, while Professor Sprout was lobbying the Board of Governors to have the Quidditch matches played on a standard set of brooms provided by the school itself. Harry didn’t really care what happened, as long as Slytherin didn’t have an overwhelming advantage.

Draco’s broom was only marginally faster than Harry’s, and the blond Seeker quite obviously couldn’t handle it well at full speed. Harry demonstrated this by diving just past the Slytherin player and then flipping over him in a quick barrel roll. Draco couldn’t stop himself from flinching back as the red-robed figure flashed past and around him. Harry hauled back on the shaft of his broom and kicked it into a standing stall so he could smirk at his furious counterpart.

“Already frightened, Malfoy? Money not doing you a lot of good up here, is it?” he sneered.

He supposed he was pushing things a little, but the vision of Draco torturing Ginny would not leave him alone. While it was technically possible that something like that had happened, it was more likely just his own fears and frustrations that were torturing him through his nightmares.

Harry’s expression suddenly became very keen and he spun his broom and pushed it over into a dive, flashing under Draco in an instant. The Slytherin Seeker didn’t hesitate and followed Harry in his sudden plummet. Harry waited until he was about to strike the turf before he hauled back on his broom with all his might, veering to the side as he pulled out of the suicidal dive. Blades of grass made a whirring sound as the toes of his shoes skimmed through them. Even sweeter sounds were the sudden thud and tumble as Draco hit the ground and bounced into the air.

“Oh, that’s got to sting!” Lee Jordan announced over the enchanted megaphone. “A picture perfect Wronski Feint by Potter and a wonderful example of why little rich boys shouldn’t try to buy their way onto the pitch by Malfoy. Er, sorry, Professor,” the boy concluded, though he didn’t really sound that sorry to Harry.

Ron later told him that Professor McGonagall didn’t look all that irate, either.

Draco shakily took to the air again and Harry began circling him in a distinctly predatory fashion. The circling also meant that Harry could look past the boy and search for the Snitch in every direction without being obvious.

After Angelina scored a goal, making it seventy to thirty, Harry saw a flash of gold near the Slytherin goals and took off after it immediately. Draco, wary of another feint, was slow to follow him. The roar of the crowd soon disabused him of that notion and he began pushing his broom for every scrap of speed to try and catch his nemesis.

Harry cursed as he dodged a Bludger from one of the Slytherin beaters. The Snitch passed behind the goal posts and disappeared again. Harry glanced behind him as he flattened his dive until he was just skimming above the turf. Draco was obviously pushing his broom for all it was worth in an attempt to catch up.

Pulling back sharply on the handle, Harry engaged the braking charms and let the uneven drag flip the broom over onto its back as it slewed sideways. Letting go with one hand and unhooking a foot, Harry splayed his limbs and dropped into a rough ‘Starfish and Stick’ – right in Draco’s flight path.

Draco didn’t even have time to yell as he jerked his speeding broom into a sharp turn to avoid Harry. Directly colliding with the opposing Seeker when not in pursuit of the Snitch could get Draco thrown out of the game if Madam Hooch were so inclined. Unfortunately, he couldn’t manage a completely flat turn. His right toe dug into the turf, and at the speed he was travelling – an instant later the Malfoy heir was tumbling across the pitch in a blur of silver and green robes.

Harry hauled himself back up onto his broom, just in time for a Bludger to glance off his hip and send him spinning. The Slytherin beaters were closing in with blood in their eyes. This made sense, because if the Snitch appeared while Draco was taking a dirt-nap, they had no prayer of winning.

The sensibility of their actions did nothing to deter Harry’s anger though. As soon as he got his broom back under control he shot up toward the Slytherin beaters, going almost as fast as the broom could go. The one on the right, Peregrine Derrick, was closing in on an arcing Bludger, bat poised to strike. Harry gritted his teeth and shot almost directly toward the thick-set boy. As the beater closed in on the Bludger and cocked his arm back to hammer it with his enchanted bat, Harry veered off at high speed.

Derrick got a nasty grin as he struck the iron ball with a resounding smack. He waited until Harry was right next to him to maximize the damage. When Harry saw the boy’s arm begin to move, he opened the broom up the rest of the way, gaining a tiny increase in speed.

This was enough to make the Bludger brush the back of Harry’s robes instead of staving in his ribcage. There was a nasty crunching sound a moment later though. Derrick’s partner, Bole, was directly in the path of the hard-struck Bludger, and it nailed the boy dead-centre in the chest. Bole flew backwards off his broom and plummeted toward the ground before someone caught him with a levitation charm.

There was a short time out while Bole floated to the ground. Harry could see Hermione had her wand out now, and was carefully lowering the boy toward an extremely sour-looking Severus Snape. Harry carefully repressed a smile. Would Snape be forced to give her house points for this?

After a short examination, the Potions Master stated that Bole had broken ribs and possibly a fractured sternum. Gilderoy Lockhart offered to help, using a charm he’d performed ‘dozens of times.’ Harry felt a touch of dread and tried to find a spot to land nearby. If the inept buffoon masquerading as a Defence Professor removed the bones in Bole’s chest, the boy could easily suffocate before they could get him to the castle.

Lockhart was brushing off the boy’s team-mates and rolling up his sleeves when he suddenly froze. Snape had placed the tip of his wand in the hollow underneath Lockhart’s jaw.

“My student will be attended to by an accredited healer or medi-wizard. You, Professor Lockhart, are neither of those and I will thank you to put away that wand.”

Lockhart froze in place, and then cautiously stepped back. Harry let out a relieved sigh. Snape removed his wand and gestured at the prone student. Bole’s body slowly lifted into the air and followed Professor Snape as he walked toward the castle. After they left, the Defence Professor blustered a bit about how the man was ‘obviously distraught’ over his student’s injury.

The game soon resumed, but Derrick’s confidence was shattered after knocking out his team-mate. Fred and George dominated the Bludgers and pretty much stifled the Slytherin Chasers while Katie, Alicia, and Angelina ran up the score. Draco was hurting from his two turfings and flinched every time Harry swerved towards him. Finally, Harry saw the Snitch near mid-field and began to slowly drift in that direction. Draco was still quartering the pitch and checking near the Gryffindor goal posts when the shout went up from the crowd.

Harry was barely ten feet away when someone in the stands noticed the Snitch hovering near the ground. Easing forward as Draco hauled his broom around in a desperate bank, Harry neatly plucked the Snitch out of the air. The final score was three hundred twenty to ninety in favour of the Gryffindor Lions.

As the pitch erupted in cheers and shouts, Harry was half afraid Oliver was going to kiss him as the team landed at mid-field. Fred and George hoisted Harry up onto their shoulders to spare him such a fate. Harry found his friends standing on the bleachers and waved to them. Ron’s face was nearly purple and Ginny’s wasn’t far off. Luna had an odd smile on her face while Neville’s eyes were fixed in a glassy stare pointed somewhere off in the distance. Hermione looked like she was about to pass out from laughing, and Harry abruptly decided to look away. He probably didn’t want to know.

He did notice that Marcus Flint was standing over a red-faced Draco Malfoy, shouting as he repeatedly jabbed a thick finger into the smaller boy’s chest. Harry imagined Draco was getting a sound reaming for his failure to deliver on pretty much everything he was supposed to do today. How very sad for him.

The agent-in-place carefully folded the letter he’d received. Among the veiled insults and threats were some very specific instructions. Things were not progressing as they should and he was to ascertain why.

As he lay back on his bed and stared up at the canopy, he pondered his options. He had a fair idea of the source of the difficulties, but direct action was out of the question at this time.

Or was it?

Setting this up would be difficult, but not completely impossible. It was rather like Wizarding chess. You had the pieces, you had the board, and you had an objective. Everything moved according to the game’s rigid mathematics. The trick was to set up the pieces on the board in such a way that achieving the objective wasn’t just possible, but inevitable.

Inevitable was good, since the consequences of failure didn’t really bear thinking about. Not if he wanted to maintain his sanity, anyway. Some games have higher stakes than anyone can imagine – both good and bad.

The first thing to do was to gather the pieces. His current helpers had proven themselves to not be up to the task, especially given the opposition they were facing. They’d failed him for the last time. That was another lesson he’d learned the hard way.

He would now need some very specialized allies to make his plan work, but he knew what inducements he could offer. There were some inducements that his unwitting ally would never refuse. And that was a valuable lesson. No matter how hard and controlled someone may be, there was always a key that would unlock them. Everyone wanted something – or someone.

The letter hadn’t specified a timeframe, but the boy knew that sooner was preferable to later. On the other hand, later was better than never, wasn’t it? The objective was visible, and the steps leading up to it were obvious. It was the beginning and intermediate phases that were hazy and ambiguous. Of course, that was the hazard when one planned things out in such a way.

He would need time to work out the earlier stages, and in all likelihood it would take considerable time to complete them as well.

That being the case, he needed to act soon to guarantee he had as much time as possible. In this case, too much was far better than not enough, wasn’t it? He fingered his wand and began planning the first of many, many steps.

Author notes

22

The Dueling Club

The post-Quidditch party in the Gryffindor tower was truly epic in scale. Fred and George somehow ‘acquired’ several cases of butterbeer, and used warming charms to serve it piping hot. Percy looked a little upset, but after a whispered conference with the twins, he accepted a mug and sat down near the fire.

Harry noticed he looked a little pale and nudged George. “What did you say to him?” he whispered.

“Old Perce started objecting to the butterbeer, so Fred and I said better this than Firewhisky,” George whispered back. “If he objected to this, next time we’d bring back a case of Ogden’s Finest and tell people it was his idea.”

“But who’d believe you?”

“If he takes away the butterbeer, we wouldn’t have any choice then would we? We could swear to that under Veritaserum, and then he’d be sunk,” George said with a wicked grin.

Harry coughed. “Where did you two get your paws on Veritaserum?”

Fred ambled over to join in the conversation. “We made it, mate.” He drained his mug of steaming butterbeer and opened a fresh bottle.

“You can make Veritaserum?” Harry was fairly sure his jaw had dropped open.

“Harry, my dear boy—” Fred chuckled.

“—and now adopted little brother—” George reminded him.

“Yes indeed, now Harry — what form do most of our pranks take?”

Harry closed his eyes and squeezed the bridge of his nose. “Liquids, powders, pastes, and assorted goops. You’ve been throwing your Potions exams, haven’t you?”

The twins shrugged in unison. “It’s not like Snape would give us a fair grade anyway,” Fred assured him.

“We just save him the trouble of deliberately failing us,” George added helpfully. “But we can brew just about anything in the textbook—”

“Provided we have the ingredients, of course,” Fred stipulated. “Most of our brews taste good as well.”

“You realize if Mum finds out, she’s going to kill the two of you. That’s a lot of blackmail material, right there,” Harry said with a crooked grin.

The twins looked at each other. “Won’t work Harry,” Fred informed him. “Not only are you far too decent a bloke to stoop to our level…”

“But even if you did tell her,” George agreed, “we’ll just mention that you slipped and called her ‘Mum’ and she’ll forget why she was mad.”

Harry shook his head and started laughing. Trust the twins to be highly skilled in a subject taught by the Professor they despise, he mused. Veritaserum is a N.E.W.T.-level potion.

He took his mug and walked over to one of the bay windows that opened onto the common room. He looked out across the darkening grounds and remembered joking with Sirius about being the Slytherin seeker. He scowled at the gathering gloom. It felt vaguely obscene that he was standing here, warm and safe with a mug of butterbeer, while Sirius might be dead or suffering goodness knows what.

He supposed he might be pushing people so hard on the training as some obscure form of penance. Still, he needed to make sure they were ready when Voldemort made his move. He could feel the difference in his own strength and endurance. He was also a little surprised at how strong his blasting curse had been when Ron startled him. No one confronted him about that, but he could tell it had been noted.

Harry saw Colin edging toward him with his camera. He’d toned it down a lot after Ron had a little talk with him, the contents of which Harry wasn’t sure he really wanted to know. Still, the first year would probably consider the Quidditch victory to be enough of a ‘special occasion’ to justify taking another picture. Harry downed the rest of his butterbeer, left the mug on a side table, and raced up the stairs to his dormitory.

Harry threw himself on his bed and stared up at the canopy. After a moment he unlocked his trunk and pulled out some of his recent correspondence. He sorted it by author and went through them again.

Remus Lupin had no idea where Sirius might be, or whether he even really escaped. The Black family home at number twelve Grimmauld Place was still abandoned. Owls with messages addressed to Sirius simply circled around in confusion, which could mean any one of half a dozen things.

Rita Skeeter hadn’t been able to interest her editor in a follow-up story unless she had new information to include. None of her contacts, voluntary or otherwise, in the Ministry knew anything useful. She also reminded him that he owed her an interview this summer, which Harry really wasn’t looking forward to. At least she’d have a vested interest in not smearing him this time around.

Mrs. Weasley reported that the new faces in the village were still there, and several suspicious looking people had been spotted near The Burrow. After one of these people triggered the outermost wards, the rest kept their distance. None of them wished to be stunned for the better part of a day. Harry was just glad the man had fallen backwards instead of forwards. If he’d been a little more stubborn about breaking through, the results might have been — messy.

Goldfarb at least had nothing but good news. After a short legal proceeding, the Dursleys lost their home. It seemed Vernon had taken out a second mortgage the previous year and his credit rating was rather shaky. With the loss of Vernon’s income, his arrest for fiscal malfeasance, and indirect pressure from Goldfarb’s agents, the holders of his note decided to immediately call it due. The icing on the cake was a newspaper clipping taken from the Surrey Advertiser. Petunia had been arrested for shoplifting at the grocers.

Harry cracked a nasty grin and wondered if he was an awful person for taking such delight in their misery. He shrugged. With all he was doing to save people he’d likely never meet, he figured karma owed him a little petty behaviour. Besides, he was just helping his so-called relatives pay their own karmic debts, right?

Harry set the letters aside and stretched out. There didn’t seem to be anything he could do now, but he nonetheless felt like he was forgetting something. He wished he could write down his plans and objectives so he could try to organize everything. But he couldn’t take the chance. Snape could demand he turn out his pockets any time he saw him. His seven-year plan for Destroying Voldemort and Saving the Wizarding World™ would be very interesting reading — and damn hard to explain if it fell into the wrong hands.

He tried to relax and let the normal post-game adrenalin fade. He’d taken an unwholesome glee in making Draco wish he’d never learned to fly a broom, but something about the smarmy bigot made Harry want to thrash him. The little ponce played a key role in Dumbledore’s death, even if he didn’t have the stones to cast the fatal spell. The death of the only wizard Voldemort ever feared made the Hogwarts Massacre inevitable.

Harry sighed. He’d tell the headmaster everything he knew, if he could just be sure the man would act appropriately. Surprisingly enough, the man’s portrait had counselled against immediately disclosing future events. Evidently the personality-imprint remembered some fleeting concerns he’d had about Harry when he first came to Hogwarts. It also knew the reason for his unwavering support of Severus Snape. It made sense when put in the right context. Harry acknowledged this freely. It still didn’t mean that the consequences were any less severe.

On the other hand, the conversation he’d overheard between the two of them gave him some hope. He doubted Dumbledore would have rebuked Snape like that in front of others, but the fact that he did so at all was encouraging. The headmaster also hadn’t tried his Legilimency on Harry since the previous year. He hoped that stopping Quirrell and his master from reaching the Stone last spring had earned him a little trust in Professor Dumbledore’s eyes.

The more he thought about his plans and his options, the more Harry Potter felt like Harry the lab rat, attempting to navigate a maze filled with deadly traps. He closed his eyes and tried to will his racing mind to rest. Surprisingly enough, it worked after a few minutes.

A couple of weeks later, the school was abuzz with what happened at the Ravenclaw Quidditch practice. Harry heard about it at lunch from Ron.

“Fred and George are friendly with some of their team’s supporters,” Ron told them in between bites of chicken. “I think they studied together for Charms… Anyway, they play Hufflepuff Saturday, you know?”

Harry nodded and took a sip of pumpkin juice.

Ron swallowed, ignoring the impatient look Hermione gave him. “Right, well, when they were practising yesterday, someone decided to take out their Seeker.”

Harry gulped. “What?”

“Cho Chang. Pretty Chinese third year girl, you’ve seen her around, right? She replaced Frobisher as Seeker when he graduated.”

Harry nodded dumbly. He hadn’t said anything to her, but it was sort of weird to see the girl he’d briefly had a crush on in his prior life. “What happened to her?”

“Someone blew her off her broom during practice. Nailed her with a stunning spell when she was pretty high up. She hit the ground hard and broke a lot of bones. They heard it was touch and go whether she’d make it. They’ve got her at St Mungo’s now, trying to repair a lot of broken bones and re-grow her spine.” Ron’s voice was subdued as he relayed the grim news. “They searched the woods where the spell came from, but didn’t find anything.”

“That explains a lot of what I’m seeing now,” Hermione said, frowning over her shoulder. Most of the Ravenclaw students were glaring at the Hufflepuffs, who looked confused and distinctly uncomfortable.

Ron frowned. “You don’t honestly think someone in Hufflepuff did it? If Ravenclaw was about to play Slytherin, I could see that. I’d line them all up and check their wands straight away. But the ‘Puffs? That’s mental.”

Neville shrugged. “But that’s who they are playing in a couple of days; no one else has anything to gain. Professor Sprout was really upset about it yesterday. If it was someone from her house, they better hope an Auror arrests them before she gets her hands on them.” He shuddered. “I never even thought of using a trowel like that before.”

Hermione gave him an odd look as she spoke up. “That also explains why Professor Flitwick changed his syllabus. He taught the Prior Incantato charm in all the classes attended by Hufflepuff students. He must have wanted to see if anyone’s wand would show a stunning spell.”

“That’s not how I’d want to get caught either,” Ginny said. “I heard a rumour that he was a duelling champion when he was younger.”

“I’d be more afraid of what the other Hufflepuffs would do,” Luna added in that detached, toneless manner that Harry recognized as her ‘thinking while I’m talking’ voice. “They prize loyalty, only now the rest of the school sees them as disloyal. They feel betrayed and angry now. If this was done by one of their own, that person has betrayed all of them by making the rest of the school treat them as traitors.”

Harry shook his head. “I doubt it was a Hufflepuff student,” Harry said. “It’s just too obvious. I think someone is just trying to stir up trouble.” Though he was outwardly calm, Harry found his thoughts were racing. He remembered Oliver telling him before their third year match that Cho previously had some trouble with injuries… but he knew he would have heard about it if someone had a near-fatal accident. Especially if it had obviously been no accident.

If this didn’t happen in the previous timeline, Harry knew it had something to do with him. Some change he had made this time around resulted in someone trying to murder Cho Chang. Or at least make sure she was in no shape to play. Try as he might, Harry could not reason out any connection between his changes and this incident. The fact that the perpetrator hadn’t been caught was even more unsettling.

Of course, after this, Ron was even more insistent on all five of them accompanying Harry to every Quidditch practice. Harry doubted someone had declared open season on Seekers, but he couldn’t dissuade Ron, or anyone else for that matter. “Better to be safe than sorry” had become Ron’s motto, and honestly Harry couldn’t disagree. He’d been operating under a similar strategy since the dream where he’d met his future self.

Harry also had to admit their presence was comforting when the lengthening shadows at the end of practice made the skin between his shoulder blades crawl. During the next practice he made a point never to hover and make himself an easy target. But if he did get stunned, the odds were very good that one of the five could levitate him before he hit the ground. Snape very grudgingly gave Hermione five house points for catching Bole after Derrick’s errant Bludger had knocked out the Slytherin beater. Hermione was very gracious when he announced this fact at their next Potions class, but Harry knew she’d remember the look on his face for a long time.

At the beginning of the practice, Oliver announced that the heads of house held a meeting regarding the incident with the Ravenclaw seeker. It was decided that since this was an overt act of sabotage, the Ravenclaw team would not be required to play this weekend. Fred and George looked a little outraged about that, given that usually teams were required to play whether they had injured players or not. Oliver told them off, saying Professor McGonagall said the healers weren’t sure whether Chang would ever ride a broom again.

Harry imagined Oliver had voiced the same objections to his Head of House and been told to shut it in a similar manner.

To make a long story short, Professors McGonagall and Snape agreed to a coin toss. McGonagall won, so Slytherin would be playing Hufflepuff this weekend. Ravenclaw would take their slot and play the Hufflepuffs in early May. Harry was a little relieved that they wouldn’t be playing again on such short notice. Oliver made a point of scouting the other teams as much as possible when they played, looking for strengths and weaknesses in their game. Technically, the Slytherin team was at a slight disadvantage. However, after their crushing defeat in the first match of the season, their prospects for the Quidditch Cup were remarkably dim.

That weekend, the Slytherin team played like they had something to prove. The Hufflepuffs were still demoralized from being ostracized by their classmates. The fact that a fair number of Ravenclaw students were cheering on the Slytherin team must have been rather disconcerting as well.

The results were not pretty. Derrick and Bole knocked one of the Hufflepuff chasers unconscious minutes into the game after their Dopplebeater Defence caromed the Bludger off the boy’s skull. Soon another Hufflepuff chaser was sporting a dislocated elbow and could barely fly. After that, the Slytherin chasers ran the Hufflepuff keeper ragged while Miles Bletchley, the Slytherin keeper, made a great show of lounging on his broom. The massacre only ended after Draco Malfoy on his Nimbus Two Thousand and One outran Cedric Diggory on his Cleansweep Seven to grab the Snitch. The final score was three hundred and twenty to forty in favour of the Slytherin team.

Harry’s stomach twisted to see Draco strutting off the field. He looked away and saw Cedric Diggory and the other Hufflepuffs limping toward the changing rooms. Harry spoke to his friends and they got up and began fighting their way through the crowd. The Hufflepuff captain, a seventh year Harry didn’t really know, had already left to take his injured chaser to Madam Pomfrey. But it was really Cedric that Harry wanted to see. Harry felt he owed the boy for inadvertently leading him to his death at Voldemort’s hand. More importantly, he remembered Cedric getting the other Hufflepuffs to lay off him after the first task of the Triwizard Tournament. Now it was time to return that favour.

“Diggory?” he called out.

Cedric stopped, wincing a little. But when he turned around he appeared confused. “Can I help you?” he asked politely. Despite the sweat and dirt, he still looked like he stepped off a recruiting poster.

Damn, he even looked like a movie star this far back, Harry mused ruefully. No wonder Cho went after him. He cleared his throat. “No one thinking clearly believes you lot had anything to do with Cho Chang. When they all calm down, they’re going to feel rather stupid,” he said rather loudly as he stuck out his hand to the startled Seeker.

Cedric shook his hand, frowning. “I — well, thanks Harry. That means a lot, coming from you. Especially after that mess over summer holiday. My parents, they didn’t say anything about it until afterward — I would have told them you’d rather stay with…” his voice trailed off and he nodded at Ron, whose expression had gone a trifle frosty.

Harry shrugged. “It’s water under the bridge as far as I’m concerned. It all worked out in the end. They were just there as Dumbledore’s back-up plan, I suppose. There were worse possible outcomes, you know.”

Cedric nodded thoughtfully. “I heard. I do appreciate you Gryffindors not thinking the worst of us as well — not that we’ll take it easy on you when we play, even if we are probably out of the running for the Cup.”

“We wouldn’t want it any other way,” Harry assured him.

As they made their way back to the Great Hall for dinner, Ron eyed Harry curiously. “What was that all about?” he finally asked.

Harry just smiled at him. “It was the right thing to do,” was all he would say. Hermione frowned as she tried to puzzle out his logic. Ginny nudged Harry with her elbow and nodded toward the bushy-haired witch. Harry gave her a small grin as they mounted the steps to the main entrance.

December couldn’t come soon enough for Harry and his friends. He was anticipating spending his first Christmas at The Burrow, while his friends were looking forward to a break from Snape over the winter holiday. Potions classes had slowly become a nightmare as the increasingly frustrated Legilimens took his anger out on them. Hermione and Neville could almost shut him out, and it would take him a while to get through their defences. Unfortunately, Snape picked up on Ginny and Luna’s friendship with the others, and began tormenting the Weasley girl during the first year Potions class. Luna, however, usually worked with Ginny, and sat as close to her as possible.

On one memorable occasion, they contrived to have Ginny drop her quill while Snape was ripping into her mind, and Luna bent over to pick it up at the same time as her friend. Luna’s head passed between Snape and Ginny before he realized what was happening. The results were quite gratifying as the Potions Professor stumbled and fell against his desk, gasping aloud. Slipping and accidentally entering Luna Lovegood’s mind was not a mistake anyone would want to make twice.

Nonetheless, his friends’ torment left Harry second-guessing himself. There were several types of Occlumency described in the book. He’d originally decided on the more straightforward version that used the person’s own magic to form a barrier against mental intrusion — mainly because that was the easiest to master. It did, however, have some disadvantages. It was very obvious to the Legilimens that they were being blocked — which led to Snape’s foul mood and constant abuse.

There were amulets that could be constructed or purchased that would also block mental intrusions. Unfortunately, Harry had no illusions about Snape abusing his authority as a Professor to confiscate or destroy any possessions of theirs. The man acted like he was incensed that mere students wouldn’t cede him access to their thoughts and memories as his right. And the man lambasted him as arrogant!

The more subtle Occlumency methods used misdirection to deflect probes away from sensitive memories. On the plus side, a skilful enough user could deceive a Legilimens without the invader even being aware of the resistance. Unfortunately, this method was much harder to master, and was less than effective if the user was upset or experiencing any sort of strong emotion. This was driven home to Harry when Snape tried to teach it to him during his disastrous fifth year at Hogwarts. Had Snape purposefully taught him the less effective version for himself at Voldemort’s orders? Or was it the only version he knew? The few times Harry had prodded the man’s mind, he’d felt some push back at the borders, but it might just have been the man’s natural resistance after spending so much time around Voldemort.

Harry stopped debating his choice of methodology when he realized that there was no chance of them mastering the harder method before Snape uncovered at least one memory of them practising or discussing Occlumency. At that point they would have been in for the same abuse anyway.

That logic reassured Harry that he’d made the right choice, but watching his friends go through the mental wringer during Potions class was something he’d never forget. He found himself going through his mental list of reasons why he couldn’t just murder Snape on the spot. Each time Harry found his reasons sounded a little less convincing. A couple of weeks away from the man might serve to curb his homicidal impulses.

It was with some satisfaction that Harry watched Professor McGonagall collecting the names of students who would be staying at Hogwarts over the holidays. It felt a little odd to remember that he had a home to go to now. Nice, but odd. He hoped they would be able to visit Diagon Alley for some Christmas shopping.

As the holidays approached, Harry wasn’t sure if Lockhart would be pushing to start the Duelling Club or not. The fraud’s classes with the Gryffindors had definitely become more than he bargained for. Led by Hermione, Harry and his friends mercilessly pressed him for details on his supposed conquests. By the end of what was supposed to be a session of boasting, the man was often stammering and sweating. If he arrived for class early, Harry sometimes saw the man reading through his own books, or worse, a standard reference, trying to prepare himself.

In desperation at how difficult this ‘easy teaching job’ had become, Lockhart fell back on the Standard Book of Spells. He started them practising the various curses and hexes on each other. Before long, Seamus, Dean, Lavender, and Parvati refused to work with Harry or his friends. They weren’t nasty about it, but their classmates knew the four of them had been practising a lot on their own. Whenever Lockhart told them to pair off, the two boys and two girls made sure they joined up. Harry really didn’t mind, because he knew Neville, Hermione, or Ron would give him a much better run for his money than the others.

All the same, Harry was very careful to keep his power reined in when casting indoors, especially at his friends. He didn’t want another wild surge to put someone in the hospital wing. It brought a lump to his throat when Ron agreed to face him the first time with no hesitation. Harry made a point of casting the jelly-legs jinx with as little power as he could. He was successful in that respect — Ron could actually force his legs to straighten up and stay rigid if he concentrated.

On the other hand, Harry felt it might be nice to face opponents he wouldn’t feel obligated to hold back against. So while their early mornings were filled with practising dodging and drilling on shield charms, Harry kept an eye on the notice board in the entry hall. Finally, on a gray Thursday that threatened snow, he noticed a parchment had been posted that already drew a small crowd.

“A duelling club?” Neville asked.

“I wonder who is sponsoring it?” Hermione asked.

“I know one way to find out,” Harry answered as he edged up to the board. “Eight o’clock tonight in the Great Hall.”

That evening the Great Hall was decked out just like Harry remembered, complete with a large golden stage. Harry hoped his smile didn’t become too feral as Professor Lockhart pranced out.

“Good evening, everyone. Gather round, gather round. Can everyone see me? Can everyone hear me? Excellent!” The man was practically preening in his dark plum robes. “Now Professor Dumbledore has granted me permission to start this duelling club to train you all in how to defend yourselves. I’ve had to do so no small number of times myself, and let me tell you — there’s nothing more important than knowing how to protect yourself. See my published works for details!”

Harry felt his nails digging into his palms as he restrained himself from cursing the man on the spot. His hypocrisy was galling, given what he’d told Harry about how improperly trained students wouldn’t survive to complain.

“Let me introduce my assistant, Professor Snape,” Lockhart announced, grinning. “He tells me he knows a little about duelling himself, and has agreed to help me with a short demonstration. Now, he’s being a good sport about this, so don’t worry, I won’t hurt him, never fear!”

Harry found himself looking forward to what he knew would happen next. Snape looked positively murderous.

Lockhart and Snape faced each other, bowing. Lockhart continued his narration, oblivious to the potion master’s disdain. “As you can see, we are holding our wands in the accepted combative position. On the count of three, we will cast our first spells. Never fear, neither of us will cast anything lethal!”

Ron mimed a disappointed sigh and Hermione muffled a snort.

On the count of three, both men raised their wands. Snape’s Expelliarmus struck first, the blast of red light blowing Lockhart off the stage and leaving him lying in a crumpled heap at the base of a wall.

The Slytherin students’ cheers broke off in confusion as Harry gave Snape a standing ovation. After a few nudges, his friends joined in as well. The Slytherin Head of House blinked twice, staring at Harry.

Although it was a close thing, Harry did respect Snape slightly more than Lockhart. The man was a complete bastard, but that was easier to stomach than the utter fraud teaching Defence. Besides, he’s probably going mad trying to figure out what I’m up to now, Harry reflected.

Snape must have been in an ill temper when he cursed Lockhart, because it took a couple of minutes before the man could climb to his feet again. Harry supposed that if it was Snape’s frustration about the Occlumency situation, then it was true what they said about silver linings.

Lockhart’s blather as he tried to laugh off his thrashing was less than convincing. That probably had something to do with the fact that he couldn’t stand up completely straight. Snape moved through the crowd and paired everyone off. True to form, Neville was set up with Justin Finch-Fletchley, Ron with Seamus (to the Irish boy’s noticeable dismay), Hermione with Millicent Bulstrode, and Harry, of course, with Draco Malfoy.

“Face your partners!” Lockhart called out, trying to regain some semblance of control.

Harry gave Draco the barest of nods. If he remembered correctly, the little bastard was going to jump the gun a little.

“Wands at the ready!” shouted Lockhart, getting into the theatricality of the moment again. “On the count of three, cast to disarm, only! One… Two… Three…”

Draco’s wand started moving on two, but Harry felt Snape’s eyes on him. He knew if he conjured a shield before ‘Three’, he would be called on it, no matter how Draco cheated. Instead he rolled his torso and ducked to the side, letting the Slytherin’s spell shoot past him. After the third count, he brought his wand up.

“Expelliarmus!” Let no one accuse me of breaking the rules here, Harry grumbled to himself as Draco tried to dodge his counterstroke. The spell clipped Draco in his left shoulder, spinning him around. The boy did, however, maintain hold of his wand.

Draco’s eyes lit with rage and he brought his wand up again. Harry braced himself and began the motions for a shield charm when Snape’s voice cut through the air like a whip. “Enough! Cease this instant!” he snarled in a venomous tone.

Harry raised the point of his wand, but didn’t take his eyes off Draco as Snape spoke to his student in a voice too quiet to hear. Peripherally, Harry was aware of Neville releasing Justin from a leg-locker curse as Ron handed Seamus his wand back. Hermione extended a hand to Millicent, helping the larger girl up from the floor. Bulstrode gave her a respectful nod as she rubbed at her right wrist and forearm.

The Great Hall was in chaos, with roughed up and afflicted students everywhere. Lockhart tried to sort things out, and finally suggested that they work on blocking unfriendly spells.

Of course, Snape’s voice rang out over the clamour and suggested Harry and Draco take the stage for the demonstration — something the Boy Who Lived had been anticipating with some glee.

Harry ignored Lockhart’s bumbling advice, instead focusing on Draco as Snape whispered something into the blond boy’s ear. Harry smiled as he stood on the stage in front of most of the school. He resisted the urge to twirl his wand in his fingers.

Lockhart counted off the start of the duel, this time counting down from three for some odd reason. Harry wondered idly if he’d been concussed by the wall.

Draco evidently wasn’t as eager to be caught cheating by the entire student body, so he refrained from casting until after Lockhart said “Go!” “Serpensortia!” the Slytherin yelled and a nasty great black snake flew out of the end of his wand.

The snake immediately began slithering toward Harry, who watched it coolly. Having absolutely no desire to be publicly identified as a Parselmouth, he waited until the snake reached the mid-point between himself and his leering opponent.

“Reducto!” Harry snarled and the snake exploded into fragments. A girl shrieked as she was covered in snake guts, but the fragments of the conjured snake almost instantly evaporated in puffs of black smoke.

“Furnunculus!” Draco called out, levelling his wand at Harry. A beam of sickly orange light leapt across the space between them.

“Protego!” Harry replied, angling his wand carefully and giving it a twist as he finished the incantation. A shimmering shield appeared in front of Harry, cocked at a slight angle. Draco’s spell struck it with a bang, and it rebounded off to one side of the stage. It hit Pansy Parkinson squarely between the eyes and she shrieked as huge pus-weeping boils covered her face.

Harry let the shield charm drop and smirked at Draco.

“Tarantallegra!” Draco spat.

“Protego!” Harry’s shield charm was cocked at a different angle this time. Draco’s spell shot back almost exactly the way it came, but clipped Gregory Goyle. Draco’s bristly-haired bodyguard abruptly began dancing a clumsy jig, trampling on several people’s feet before he tripped and fell out of sight.

A deflected stunning spell dropped Vincent Crabbe like a sack of potatoes, and Draco started to really lose it. Harry was mildly surprised when the pale boy began firing off curses he definitely hadn’t learned at Hogwarts. It was rather obvious that the boy had been practising over the summer as a column of flames spat from the end of his wand like a flamethrower. It was spread out enough that Harry’s shield charm just stopped it, rather than deflecting it. Not that Harry would necessarily risk killing someone in the crowd.

The cloud of flames did, however, obscure his vision for a moment. He wasn’t expecting it when the flames began to dissipate and Draco’s voice snarled, “Diffindo!” The cutting charm punched through the weakened shield as Harry instinctively threw himself to the side. Something tugged at the sleeve of his robes as a hot brand was dragged across the top of Harry’s left shoulder.

“Expelliarmus!” Harry barked as he rolled onto one knee. Draco ducked and used another cutting charm. This time Harry saw it coming and his shield charm held.

It was purely coincidental that the deflected spell parted Snape’s hair. The man’s eyes blazed with fury as a few strands fell to the floor. His wand came up and Harry knew that play time was over.

“Expelliarmus!” Harry called out as Draco began another spell. He knew that loud verbalizations were technically bad form, but he didn’t want there to be any question as to what he was casting.

Draco didn’t duck in time, and was hurled backward as his wand was torn from his grasp. He rolled off the edge of the stage into some Slytherin upperclassmen as his wand flew end over end across the stage. Harry switched his wand to his left hand, wincing as his shoulder began to complain. As slowly as the tumbling wand descended, it was easy for the Gryffindor Seeker to catch it in his right hand. He held Draco’s wand gingerly as he rose to his feet. He wondered what horrors it committed in the future as a low murmur broke out among the spectators.

“Hand that over, Potter,” Professor Snape demanded in a venomous tone. The man had already covered half the length of the stage, his eyes boring into Harry.

“I’d be doing him a favour if I snapped this,” Harry replied. “There are many with far less tolerance for arrogant Purebloods than I.”

Snape’s fury was almost palpable after Harry threw his own words back in his face. Harry tossed him Draco’s wand and jumped down off the stage. The jarring as he landed set his shoulder to aching again, but he wouldn’t give them the satisfaction of seeing him wince. He ignored the murmurs of the crowd as he strode away.

Of course, the minute they followed him out of the Great Hall, Harry’s friends insisted on dragging him to the hospital wing. Not that he was too reluctant; his shoulder ached abominably and the sleeve of his robes was soaked with blood.

Madam Pomfrey fussed over him with her wand and a foul-smelling salve. “Duelling Clubs! What sorts of idiocy will that fool come up with next?” she muttered, scowling.

Harry resisted the urge to shrug. “If you are referring to whom I think you are, he is. But he did call for disarming spells only. Draco just doesn’t like to follow rules.”

Ron and the others protested when they were asked to wait outside the treatment area. It would be curfew soon and they didn’t want to be shooed back to the Gryffindor tower without Harry. But as he sat there on a bed with his robes and shirt removed, Harry began to regret interceding with Madam Pomfrey. Ginny applied a great deal of concentration to casting Scourgify on Harry’s blood-stained robes.

“Mr. Malfoy’s conduct was reprehensible,” Professor McGonagall said briskly as she entered the infirmary. “But there are also questions about your actions as well, Mr. Potter,” she continued, ignoring the glares from five of her students.

“What sort of questions, Professor?” Harry asked blandly.

“While Mr. Malfoy displayed a — curious — knowledge of curses and hexes well above his grade level, his father has confirmed the boy received private tutoring over the summer. There are questions about your unexpected prowess as well. I would prefer to clear those up as soon as possible.”

“I’m not sure what you mean,” Harry said innocently. “I only used a shield charm and a disarming spell against him.”

“I believe it was more the — facility — with which you were able to use those spells,” McGonagall replied with some asperity.

“Professor McGonagall,” Hermione said hesitantly, “Harry, well, we’ve all been practising shield charms for over two weeks now. On our own.”

Surprised, McGonagall turned toward Hermione. She was about to say something when she was interrupted.

“That is correct, Minerva,” Dumbledore said, eyes twinkling merrily. “I’ve been watching their exercises with some curiosity now, but I daresay their efforts have paid off, at least in Harry’s case.”

Professor McGonagall turned toward the headmaster with a questioning look.

“Our colleague has — decided to retire to his quarters to recover his composure. He has had quite a trying day, from what I understand.” Dumbledore then turned his attention back toward Harry. “Although I won’t fault a student for making efforts to improve, I will admit I am curious as to why you six are going to such lengths.”

Harry wasn’t entirely sure if it was an honest question or not. He decided to simply take the bull by the horns. “We’re learning to defend ourselves because we’ve learned that Hogwarts isn’t the safest place to acquire an education.” Professor McGonagall’s lips grew even thinner as Dumbledore paused. Maybe he’s surprised at my bluntness? Harry wondered.

“Harry, I assure you that we will take any measure necessary to ensure the safety of our students,” the headmaster replied, his eyes no longer twinkling quite so merrily.

Harry just stared at the man for a long moment before laughing bitterly. He pulled on his bloody shirt and nodded thanks to Ginny as she handed him his robe.

Harry stalked toward the exit and the others followed him. Hermione turned back when Professor McGonagall touched her shoulder. The older witch frowned at the suppressed tears shining in the eyes of one of her favourite students. “Maybe it would be more believable, if it wasn’t a Professor that threatened to snap my wand for being an uppity Mudblood,” the girl hissed.

Professor McGonagall looked like she’d been slapped and turned to Dumbledore in consternation. His face grave, the headmaster idly waved his hand and the infirmary entrance closed right before Harry reached it. The Boy Who Lived turned back toward the Professors with an icy glare.

“Harry, I would prefer that we could discuss this in a civilized manner,” Dumbledore said quietly.

Harry slid his wand back up his sleeve and stiffly walked back toward the Professors. “I’m not sure we really have much to discuss. Professor Snape obviously sets the tone for his house: abusive, bullying, and murderous when given the opportunity.” He touched his shirt where the bloody fabric was torn away at the shoulder. “If I hadn’t dodged, Draco’s cutting charm would have gone through my neck. Instead of talking about that, I’ll bet Professor Snape was in your office complaining about the fact that I was able to deflect some non-lethal curses. Draco’s part in this whole mess is already being swept under the rug, isn’t it? Not to mention Voldemort himself sneaking into the school, and that prophecy he mentioned that you still won’t tell me about.” Harry took a deep breath. “Now, Professor, why was it that I should feel safe here?”

Dumbledore let out a low sigh. “Very well, Harry. I’d wanted to spare you this until you were older, but you deserve to know. Let us adjourn to my office and I will tell you what you want to know.”

“No,” was all Harry said.

Dumbledore looked at him again. “No?”

“No more secrets. These are my friends, and they deserve to know. They are likely going to be in danger just being around me. Secrets can kill…”

“Very well, Harry,” Dumbledore replied. “If that is your wish.” He gave a nod toward Madam Pomfrey and she quietly left the room.

Professor McGonagall started to leave, but Harry caught her eye and shook his head. “You may be in the middle the next time he tries to get me. You deserve to know as well.” The stern-looking woman stayed, though she looked distinctly uncomfortable.

Dumbledore paused, perhaps hoping that Harry would change his mind. With a resigned expression he closed his eyes and recited the words that had determined Harry’s fate. “The Prophecy was made shortly before you were born, Harry. The one with the power to vanquish the Dark Lord approaches … Born to those who have thrice defied him, born as the seventh month dies … And the Dark Lord will mark him as his equal, but he will have power the Dark Lord knows not … And either must die at the hand of the other for neither can live while the other survives …”

The silence that followed was deafening in its intensity. Harry broke it taking a shaky breath, one that wasn’t entirely feigned. After everything he had gone through, those simple words still had the power to chill his blood.

“My parents defied him three times?” Harry asked.

Dumbledore nodded. “They fought Voldemort and his Death Eaters on several occasions after they left Hogwarts.”

“My parents were Aurors,” Neville said in a shocked voice, “they must have fought him at least three times as well. My birthday was at the end of July… C-couldn’t this apply to me too?” Harry noticed Luna staring directly at the boy as he spoke.

“That would be possible,” Dumbledore agreed, “but Harry was the one Voldemort marked.” He slowly pointed toward Harry’s scar.

“So it’s him or me?” Harry asked.

“Eventually,” Dumbledore replied. “That is the only interpretation that makes sense to me.”

Harry nodded. “Good.”

The look on Dumbledore’s face was priceless.

Harry looked him squarely in the eye. Maybe it’s time to show a little more of who I really am. “The mad bastard’s tried to kill me twice. At least now I know why. The Prophecy doesn’t say he’s guaranteed to win, and I supposedly have some power he can’t comprehend.” He took a deep breath and his face hardened. “And since he killed my Mum and Dad, I’m glad I’m the one that gets to punch his ticket,” he growled. After a moment Harry sighed. “But thank you for telling me. I needed to know.”

Harry could feel his friends’ eyes on him, but it didn’t make him uncomfortable. He knew they had his back covered.

Professor Dumbledore gazed at him thoughtfully. “I’ll admit, Harry, this wasn’t the reaction I expected.”

“Given everything that’s happened, I’ve had to grow up rather quickly,” he said with a hint of bitterness.

Dumbledore went rather still, and the twinkling in his eyes faded. Dumbledore glanced at the others and Harry could see the skin around his eyes go tight. “Harry, I—”

Harry cut him off with a wave of his hand. “You thought you were doing the right thing. I can’t blame you for that — after all, we all make mistakes, don’t we?” he said the words calmly, but his eyes met Dumbledore’s the whole time. He waited for the feather-light touch of the headmaster’s Legilimency, but it never came. Point for you, old man, Harry mused.

“Indeed, Harry, you are — unusually mature,” Dumbledore replied. Harry couldn’t tell if he was hinting or not. “Rest assured that I will do everything in my power to ensure the Prophecy is resolved in your favour.”

“I appreciate that, Professor,” Harry replied sincerely. “I think the largest question in my mind is how he keeps coming back from the dead. I mean, from what I read, the Aurors concluded that the killing curse rebounded on him in 1981. And after I fought him last spring, his spirit seemed to remove itself from Professor Quirrell. What keeps him from passing on?”

“That is, indeed, the key issue, Harry. I’ve done some research on means of cheating death, but I don’t have any definitive answers as yet.”

Harry didn’t even have to look to know that Hermione’s eyes were lit up at the implied challenge. “Well, I suppose we should continue preparing then.”

“That would be for the best,” the headmaster agreed. “Now if you will forgive me, Professor Lockhart has been waiting for some time now.”

After he left, Professor McGonagall stepped into Madam Pomfrey’s office. She let the healer know she’d be escorting her students back to the Gryffindor tower.

As they were walking back, Harry broached another subject he’d been debating. “Professor McGonagall?”

“Yes, Mr. Potter?”

“I understand that a faculty sponsor is needed for any sort of official student organization.”

McGonagall gave him a sidelong look, but nodded. “That is correct. What kind did you want to start?”

“I was thinking about some sort of permanent duelling club.”

“Harry,” Ron asked curiously, “aren’t we already practising enough?”

“We are,” Harry agreed. “But don’t other people need to know how to defend themselves? Look what happened to Cho. Besides, it’s not like they’re going to learn anything useful from Lockhart.”

“Mr. Potter!” the Deputy Headmistress snapped.

“I know, I know. He is a Professor. But seriously, Ma’am, have you ever seen him successfully cast a spell?” Harry asked. “I know we haven’t.”

Professor McGonagall’s lips compressed into a line sharp enough to cut parchment. “What sort of activities would you propose?”

Harry spread his hands in a placating gesture. “Nothing too extreme. Maybe start off on Friday nights, work on basic hexes and jinxes. How to cast accurately. How to dodge. Things like that. I doubt too many older students will be interested, at least at first.”

“You might be surprised, Mr. Potter,” his Head of House responded with just a hint of amusement. “Word of your match with Mr. Malfoy has spread, no doubt growing more exaggerated with each re-telling.”

Harry rolled his eyes.

Ron started warming to the idea. “What should we call it then? The Duelling Club?”

Harry smiled. “That seems awfully plain. How about the ‘Duelling Association’ so we can call it the DA for short?” Take that, Fate!

The next day was Friday, with the last classes of the term. Harry was extremely grateful for this, as it seemed that Professor McGonagall’s words regarding rumours were quite accurate.

Their morning started off rather poorly. The blizzard had finally begun during the night, and the grounds were already ankle-deep in a white blanket, with more snow spiralling down from the iron-grey sky. After their morning run degenerated into a pratfall festival of slips, slides, and spills, Harry gave it up as a bad job.

He led them to a spot in the courtyard that was partially shielded from the growing drifts for martial arts practice. Unfortunately, without a warm-up run, they were too cold and stiff to do very much. They finally gave up and headed back inside.

Quitting early at least gave them time for an extra-long hot shower before breakfast. Harry half-boiled himself before all the feeling returned to his fingers and toes. When he went down to breakfast, he wore his Weasley jumper under his robes and had the scarf Ginny made him wrapped around his neck.

The moment he entered the Great Hall, the normal quiet conversations among the early-risers ended abruptly. Harry noticed that several people were openly staring at him. The sounds of urgent whispering soon filled the room as they made their way to the Gryffindor table. Harry fought the urge to duck his head.

Fred and George, he noticed, were watching this with great amusement.

“Honestly, I don’t see why you’re so surprised, Harry,” Hermione gently chided him, “You did put on quite a show last night.”

“Would you rather he acted like Draco?” Ginny asked tartly. “I suppose you might enjoy him strutting a bit, but I wouldn’t.”

Hermione stared at Ginny, obviously taken aback.

“One of the reasons Ginny likes Harry so much is because he’s so modest,” Luna said as she poured herself some juice. “Most wizards who could do what he did would get a very big head about it. Harry acts like he feels uncomfortable when he does something better than the rest of us. Especially you.” She took a sip, oblivious to the blush creeping up Ginny’s face as well as Harry’s. She frowned at Hermione, who was gaping like a fish. “Surely you notice how reluctant he is to discuss grades until he hears how you did. If he did better, you have to drag the paper out of his hands. It’s almost like he feels guilty because he has some unfair advantage.” She looked over at Harry and smiled faintly. “Don’t let that stop you from beating Draco when the opportunity arises. I rather enjoyed that last night, almost as much as I liked watching Neville.”

Harry dodged to the side as Neville sacrificed a mouthful of Pumpkin juice to the gods of the spit-take. He was just glad the food hadn’t appeared yet.

Luna turned and looked at Neville. “What?” she cocked her head and stared at the sputtering Longbottom.

“You’re doing that on purpose,” Ron accused the blonde girl.

“Doing what?” she asked innocently. That couldn’t have been a glint in her eye, could it? Harry wondered.

Unfortunately, Ron’s inquiry was fatally distracted by the arrival of breakfast. As they loaded their plates, Harry tried to relax and sit up straight. He’d put up with being the centre of attention before, and usually for far less pleasant reasons. He sighed and bit into a nice warm chipolata.

Ginny, however, was still quiet, and a little red-faced. He took hold of the trailing end of his scarf and brushed it against her arm. She turned toward him so suddenly he had to stop himself from flinching back. “Told you this would be right useful by the end of autumn,” he reminded her.

She nodded. “I know, I’m wearing two jumpers under my robes. Any more layers and I won’t be able to bend my elbows.”

Harry chuckled quietly. “Might be hard to take notes that way,” he said airily.

“What are you two talking about?” Ron asked from the other side of his sister.

“Harry agrees that I need to not wear too many clothes,” Ginny said, grinning.

“We’re talking about how cold this rock pile gets in the winter,” Harry corrected her, growling. “Do you really have to wind him up like that?” he asked. “I’m the one that has to go to class with him.”

“Not immediately,” Hermione corrected him. “Herbology was cancelled. The greenhouses are almost snowed under and Professor Sprout is worried about the mandrakes.”

“Yeah, she needs to get something warm to wrap them up,” Neville agreed, his embarrassment forgotten in the warm glow of herbology. “They’re used to a warmer climate than Scotland. I promised to help her this afternoon if she’s still at it.”

“I’ll help too, if you want,” Luna volunteered.

Neville looked at her, a little surprised.

“If I’m going to tease you, I should also be nice at times. That way you’ll be more confused,” she explained.

Neville sent Harry a pleading look.

Harry just shrugged helplessly. “I’m not smart enough to figure out girls. No one is.”

“I’m so glad,” Luna said, beaming. “Are you two glad as well?” she asked Ginny and Hermione.

Hermione just groaned and began massaging her temples. Ginny snorted, then began giggling quietly.

“Mental. All three of them.” Ron muttered. “Absolutely mental.” He jumped, grunting with pain. “What was that for?” he asked, scowling at Hermione.

“If you call me mental one more time, I’ll do more than kick your — shin,” the bushy-haired witch growled.

Ron blanched and then focused exclusively on his food.

Ginny smiled at Harry, who responded by shrugging, but wisely kept his mouth shut.

After they finished eating, the second-years escorted Luna and Ginny to charms, and then retired to their common room in the Gryffindor tower. Ron somehow talked Neville into a game of wizarding chess. Harry watched with some amusement, even though the outcome was practically preordained. The game was very popular with wizarding folk, but Ron could burn anyone out on it — like most of the Gryffindors.

For their last transfiguration class of the term, Professor McGonagall had them turning small metal spheres into Christmas ornaments. He remembered doing this the first time around. He managed to produce a shiny metallic green bauble with a hook that wasn’t too embarrassing. But in the aftermath of Justin’s petrifaction and the wild accusations that followed, he’d hung it on the smaller tree in the Gryffindor common room and forgotten about it. Between the whole Polyjuice fiasco and visiting Hermione in the hospital wing, he’d forgotten to retrieve it until after the tree was taken down.

Harry thought the ornament was lost forever, but it wasn’t. After they found Ginny’s body and Harry woke up at The Burrow — after he rationalized not ending his own life just yet, he’d gone to her room. He didn’t know why he did that to himself, but he wanted to feel closer to her, if only in his mind. The room hadn’t changed much over the years. Her bed and bureau were there, but her trunk was gone, crushed under the wreckage of the Gryffindor tower. The top of the bureau had a scattering of trinkets. A figurine he’d owled her for her last birthday. A dried flower pressed under glass. A silver hair-clip. And a metallic green ornament. One he’d made before he even noticed her, one that she saved from being discarded and put away as a keepsake of her horrible first year. Holding the worthless bauble like it was the most precious thing in the world, he sat on the foot of her bed, legs too weak to stand, and wept for all he’d lost, and all the time he’d wasted.

Harry blinked, swallowing to dull the prickle in the back of his throat. Ron was frowning at him as McGonagall passed out the spheres. Harry sniffed and coughed loudly to cover up.

“Don’t do that around Mum,” he warned in a low voice. “She hears you cough she’ll have your shirt off and a mustard pack on your chest in an instant.”

“Hmmm…” Harry murmured. “Then I’ll have to tell her I caught it from you and escape in the confusion.”

Ron glared at him. “You need to stop hanging around Fred and George.”

Professor McGonagall frowned at them as she handed them their spheres. They wisely decide to shut it at that point.

Harry glared at his ornament-to-be. He didn’t know what he wanted to make, but it definitely would not be metallic green. He knew they were starting with metal spheres, so whatever they made would be less likely to shatter if dropped or the transfiguration failed horribly. Harry’s Quidditch-obsessed mind immediately thought of another metallic sphere that was roughly the same size. He worked on visualizing exactly what he wanted, adding details and trying to make everything as clear as possible. When he was finally satisfied, he reached for his wand.

When the small puff of smoke cleared, the metal ball was replaced with a Golden Snitch ornament, complete with a hook protruding from the top, between the wings, so it could easily be hung from a tree.

“That’s brilliant, mate,” Ron said in an awed whisper. He hesitantly reached over and touched one of the delicately moulded wings with his fingertip. The limbs immediately blurred into motion and the Snitch ornament slowly rose up from Harry’s desk.

Harry quickly grabbed it before it could get away, but a shocked silence descended around him.

“What’s happening over here?” Professor McGonagall asked, walking toward him. She’d been circulating around the classroom, offering help to those struggling, and ensuring that the students already finished didn’t start acting up.

“P-Professor, Harry animated his ornament,” Hermione said in an awed tone.

Harry resisted the urge to hit himself in the forehead. Animating solid objects was a topic in his N.E.W.T.-level transfiguration seminar. Damn, I better just try to dumb it out.

“Mr. Potter, what did you do to your ornament?” McGonagall looked slightly impressed in spite of herself.

“Er, I’m not completely sure. I was trying to visualize a Snitch, and you know, I never see one when it isn’t flapping its wings like mad — it must have just — come out that way.” Harry tried to make himself sound as confused as possible. Crabbe and Goyle would be proud, he thought happily.

“I — see — Mr. Potter,” McGonagall said in a profoundly disapproving voice. She did not sound happy at the idea that Harry just bumbled into creating what originally appeared to be a nice bit of advanced transfiguration.

After she left, Hermione gave Harry a slightly disgusted look. Harry just shrugged sheepishly. At least this ornament is quite different, he reflected happily.

By dint of several warming charms, strategically placed Incendio spells, and no small amount of brute force, the six of them were able to beat a path from the courtyard to Hagrid’s hut that weekend. The groundskeeper and holder of the keys was a little surprised to see them so close to the end of term, but he quickly whipped up some hot tea (which was appreciated) and set out platters of rock cakes (which were politely ignored) and treacle fudge (which only Harry would eat, taking very, very small nibbles and chewing vigorously).

Harry knew the man would be lonely over the holidays, having no real family left, so he talked everyone into coming to see him. Honestly, though, it wasn’t that hard. The second years remembered the stories he’d told of their parents, or the tea and encouragement he’d given when Snape was being beastly. He’d also evidently hit it off with Ginny and Luna during their trip across the lake. He promised Luna he’d provide a breeding ground for Crumple-Horned Snorkacks if she and her father could bring back a breeding pair, so he was first rate in her book.

Harry, Ron, and Ginny clubbed up to get a new collar for Fang, made of dragon hide with metal fittings. Neville got him a new hat, since his old one was sporting an increasing number of holes and chew marks. Hermione gave him a book on Muggle veterinary treatments, since some of his charges were very sensitive to magic. Luna gave him a year’s subscription to The Quibbler, so he could stay on top of new species discoveries that seemed to happen unusually often these days.

Hagrid was clearly touched and surprised. In no time he was starting to sound congested. As they bid him goodbye, Harry whispered, “I look through that album almost every night.”

Hagrid’s hand on his shoulder nearly brought Harry to his knees.

After Monday breakfast they loaded up their trunks and made their way down to the snowy courtyard. Hermione became very popular with the shivering first year students, as she would cast a warming charm on anyone who asked her. Harry was glad Draco was staying at Hogwarts for the holidays, and wasn’t there to see Matt Harper, a Slytherin first year student, politely thanking Hermione. Can’t have anyone ruining their image as a house full of complete bastards, now can we? Harry reflected wryly.

Harry was in such a good mood that he just smiled and nodded when Colin Creevey asked to take another picture. Ginny was sitting on her trunk nearby, so Harry sat down next to her and posed. Colin fooled around with the camera for a moment, then snapped the picture. Harry smiled at Ginny, who looked slightly cross, then got up to see what Ron and Neville were arguing about.

The two of them were working out the details with Hermione on when they could get together and exchange gifts over the break. They finally agreed to try for some time between Boxing Day and New Year’s Eve.

Harry looked up in time to see Colin running from Ginny, who’d just pasted him in the back of the head with a snowball. The fleeing first year unfortunately ran right past Ron, who hooked an arm around the smaller boy.

“Is there some reason my sister is angry at you?” Ron asked in a falsely cheery tone.

“No! I don’t know! I mean — I said something, but I don’t understand why she got mad.” Colin looked back and forth between Ron and Harry. “I just took a picture of Harry and her sitting together and I told her you two make a good couple for portraiture. Your colours contrast well, and you two are roughly the same size…” his voice ran down as Harry’s face went pink. “I didn’t mean anything else,” he added quickly. Then he wriggled out of Ron’s grip and got into the line to board the next carriage. Ron just chuckled at his friend.

One by one, the thestral-drawn carriages arrived and ferried them to the train station. As soon as their trunks were stowed, they claimed the last compartment. The idling train was a bit cold, even with warming charms, as they were out of the sunlight now, and the metal walls and hard seats seemed to leach the warmth from their bodies. It wasn’t long before Luna was sitting on Neville’s lap again. From the redness of his face, it seemed her solution was warming him up as well. Harry wrapped his cloak over himself like a blanket, but soon realized that Ginny had left hers in her trunk when they boarded the train.

To his credit, Harry tried to offer it to her. She was noticeably smaller than he was, and logically would be more affected by the cold. Ginny sighed theatrically and got up. To his surprise, she sat down next to him and wrapped the trailing edge of the cloak around herself and leaned against him. Ron and Hermione had both kept their cloaks, but they were soon leaning against each other as well.

There must have been some problem with the boarding, because they sat there for a good half hour before the train finally jerked into motion. The warm air that finally wafted from the vents was very welcome, and soon Harry found himself drifting off to sleep.

Harry awoke when the train jolted as it slowed. He was quite warm for a change, though he wished the reason was a little different. Ginny was still curled up under his cloak, only now she was burrowed into his side, and his arm somehow ended up wrapped around her shoulders. He froze when he realized what a compromising position he was in. Thank Merlin everyone else is asleep as well, he thought as his panic ebbed.

As gently as possible, he attempted to extract himself. Unfortunately, Ginny had a firm grip on his robes, so he had no choice but to wake her. He tapped her on the shoulder, hoping and praying that she didn’t let out a yell. He was tempted to put a hand over her mouth, but didn’t want to risk panicking her. As it was, Ginny’s eyes snapped open and she flinched back from his side like he was on fire. She opened her mouth to speak, but Harry shushed her before she could wake the others.

Ron and Hermione were still leaning against each other. Ron was snoring lightly (for him), but Hermione didn’t seem to be disturbed by that. Luna was curled up on Neville’s lap, but for once he didn’t look petrified. Instead, he was faintly smiling, and more surprising, had both his arms wrapped around the blonde girl.

“I can see we’re almost there, but I still need to use the necessary,” Ginny whispered as she stood up.

“All right,” Harry said. “Give me a minute.” Ginny looked at him oddly as he stood up, wincing as his back popped and his muscles twitched. “What? I’m not letting you go off by yourself, no matter how close we are to King’s Cross.”

Ginny sighed and rolled her eyes.

“Do I need to repeat back the things you said to me when I complained to Ron?” Harry asked her, smirking.

“All right Harry, you’ve made your point,” she said as she reached for the compartment door. She tried to unlatch it, but it slid open at her touch.

“That’s odd,” Harry said, frowning.

“Maybe Ron didn’t get it completely latched,” Ginny speculated.

“No, I’m pretty sure I heard it engage,” Harry said. He looked back at his friends slumbering in the compartment. Nothing appeared to be out of place. He shrugged. “Let’s get going before they wake up.”

Author notes

24

Christmas at The Burrow

Working as rapidly as possible, Harry Obliviated and marinated Sirius’ other pursuers. The Animagus made his own contributions as well. Harry supposed making it look like Macnair lost control of his bladder added to the effect, but he thought Sirius enjoyed whizzing on the Death Eater a little too much.

When they were done, Harry quickly weighed his options. “Padfoot,” he said quietly, “I know you have a lot of questions. If you will follow me for right now, I’ll answer as many as I can when it’s safe.”

The large dog gazed at Harry for a moment, then nodded its head in a distinctly un-doglike manner.

Harry gave a quick glance left and right at the mouth of the alleyway. Seeing no one, he slid his wand back into his jacket.

“Come on boy,” Harry said in a jaunty voice as he stepped out onto the sidewalk, “I bet I can find you some dinner back home.”

Sirius made an encouraging sound somewhat close to a whine as they set out.

Harry wondered briefly how long it would take before the men he stunned were found. If it were long enough, they could possibly die from exposure. That wouldn’t be a tragedy as far as Harry was concerned – the only reason they were still alive was his desire to avoid stronger scrutiny. Of course, if their deaths looked to be completely accidental, then so be it.

The light was fading and the wind was picking up as they crossed the bridge over the River Otter. Harry looked left and right for any sign of Ron or Percy, but still found no sign of them.

Starting to worry even more, Harry set out for The Burrow at a brisk walk. Sirius paced him easily, warm inside his shaggy coat. Harry supposed the Grim look-alike would give anyone trying to accost them pause, so he picked up his pace to a slow jog.

By the time he reached the two-track lane that led to the Weasley residence, it was nearly dark. Harry knew Mrs. Weasley was probably getting frantic at this point, but his next actions required a certain degree of precision.

As they neared the outer edge of the wards, Harry called out for Sirius to wait. The large black dog paused, then cocked its head when Harry pulled out his wand again. Muttering the pass phrase under his breath, Harry tapped the end of his wand on the top of Sirius’ head. Harry’s wand vibrated as his Godfather was outlined in a flickering glow that disappeared just as suddenly.

“That’s so you can get through the wards without getting cooked,” Harry muttered.

Sirius shook his head like he had an itch in his ears, but stared as Harry nodded.

The moment they stepped onto the property, Harry made a beeline for Arthur’s shed. He opened the door and led Sirius inside, careful not to knock over any of his guardian’s projects.

“Will this be warm enough for now?” Harry asked the dog.

Sirius nodded in a distinctly human-like fashion.

“Good, I’m going to bring Arthur Weasley out here as soon as I get a chance to talk to him alone. He’s been prodding people at the Ministry about what really happened to you, and I think we can trust him. I’ll be back out here in a while.”

With that, Harry stepped back out into the chill evening air and headed for the garden and the house beyond it. He took deep breaths as he walked, trying to calm his trip hammer pulse. Sirius had been found, and he was safe, at least for right now.

Harry knew he had to tell the elder Weasleys. There was no way really to hide Sirius on the property without their help. It was the reactions of the younger Weasleys he worried about. Percy, with his attitude toward the Ministry or any other authority figure, was worrisome.

For that matter, the younger Weasleys were still subject to having their memories read by Snape. Given the Potions Master’s antipathy toward the Marauders, Harry had little doubt that he’d inform the Ministry at once of his discovery.

No sooner had Harry begun knocking on the door than it was snatched open.

Mrs. Weasley hauled him inside and shut the door all seemingly in one motion. “Harry!” she breathed. “Are you all right? We were starting to worry when Ron and Percy came back without you.”

Harry found himself engulfed in a Mrs. Weasley-sized hug. His arms partially trapped, Harry patted her awkwardly. “So they made it back already?”

Mrs. Weasley let him go, seemingly with some reluctance, and nodded. “Ron wanted to go back out and look for you, but it seemed smarter to give you a bit of time first, especially since the clock said you were all right.”

Harry turned toward the clock as she drew him into the kitchen. It was then that he noticed a hand had been added for him as well, and it was now pointing at ‘home’.

“You do need to be more careful when you cross the street though, Harry dear,” Mrs. Weasley continued. “Your hand changed to mortal peril for an instant.”

Harry nodded slowly. That must have been when Dawlish almost hit me. “How did I miss Ron and Percy?” he asked.

“We took a short-cut on the way back,” Ron said as he walked into the kitchen, a disgusted look on his face. “If it hadn’t been so cold, we wouldn’t have—”

“No harm done, Ron,” Harry said with a smile. It honestly would have been a lot harder to deal with Sirius, not to mention the Ministry flunkies, if he’d been with Ron and Percy at the time.

Ron frowned, but decided to let it drop, for which Harry was grateful. Harry hung his jacket up in the hallway and let Mrs. Weasley drag him back to the table for some hot chocolate. Before sitting down, he handed her the jar of marjoram with a flourish.

She frowned at the spice container for a moment, and Harry guessed she’d forgotten why she’d sent him to the village. He was touched that she’d been worried enough to forget about her cooking.

Ginny was sitting at the table as well, dicing up vegetables with a small knife. Harry didn’t miss the small sigh she let out when he entered the kitchen, so he gave her an especially bright smile. His younger half had never had anyone worry about him, and his older self had missed it as well. Sometimes it was all he could do to keep from collapsing into a blubbering heap. Reminding himself that Tom was still out there was usually more than enough, because that thought always filled him with a cold fury. He was damned if he’d let that bastard hurt them again.

Ginny abruptly looked down, focusing all her attention on her task as Harry took a deep breath. Maybe he wasn’t the only person struggling for some emotional equilibrium, and he wondered if that meant what he thought it might. His mind snapped back to the present as Mrs. Weasley placed a steaming mug in front of him.

“Drink that up, Harry,” she said, visibly fretting, “I would never have sent you, if I’d known it was going to get dark so quickly.”

Harry swallowed, letting the hot chocolate spread a column of warmth down his throat and into his stomach. “It was all right, I just jogged on the way home and stayed warm enough. I missed my workout this morning anyway.”

Mrs. Weasley began blinking rapidly, and Harry wondered what was wrong. Then he realized he’d used the word ‘home’ to describe The Burrow. A little embarrassed, he finished his hot chocolate, then set the cup in the sink, grabbed another knife and sat down beside Ginny.

The youngest Weasley was more than happy to split the vegetable preparation with him. As they set to work, she whispered, “Don’t mind Mum, she’s always like this around Christmas.”

Harry nodded and let his hands work while his mind wandered. He could hear Mr. Weasley and Ron talking in the sitting room. His guardian still hadn’t given up on that string of Muggle Christmas lights, but seemed content to while away the day working on them. Harry supposed he’d have a better chance to talk to him alone after dinner.

He decided to approach Mr. Weasley first for a couple of reasons. Molly was still a little turbulent, and Harry wasn’t sure how she’d react if she discovered he’d gotten into a fire fight with three adult wizards – no matter how easily he’d won. The other factor was his memories of the future at Twelve Grimmauld Place. Sirius seemed to get along a little better with Arthur than with his wife. Harry knew that he was one of the main bones of contention, and he wanted to play this as cautiously as possible.

So Harry sat there, chopping vegetables with Ginny until they were done. Molly shooed them out of the kitchen while she put the finishing touches on tomorrow’s dinner. Harry had come to realize how much she simply enjoyed cooking, so he let himself relax as Ginny led him out of the kitchen.

Ron had evidently talked Percy into a game of wizarding chess, something his older brother looked to be regretting. Of course, that regret might also have origins in the fact that Fred and George were watching with great interest, and making commentary like Quidditch announcers. Or at least Quidditch announcers like their friend Lee Jordan – unashamedly biased and funny as hell.

Percy was the most studious of the Weasley brothers, with the possible exception of Bill the Curse-Breaker. He was definitely the most academically inclined of those still living at home. As such, he was not used to losing in a primarily cerebral match-up with his youngest brother. That, combined with some smart remarks from the twins, had his ears turning an angry pink.

Ron, bent over his pieces, was oblivious to his brother’s growing frustration, but Harry noticed Ginny frowning and chewing at her lip. She evidently didn’t want a blow-up on Christmas Eve any more than Harry did.

Ron finally announced check-mate in that detached voice he used when Harry knew he was well into the game.

George whispered, “…and the crowd goes wild!” while Fred made faint cheering noises and tried not to crack up. Percy stood up abruptly, his face starting to flush.

Harry spoke up. “I think Percy set the record, didn’t he Ron?”

Ron straightened up, blinking and stretching. “How’s that?”

“You two must have been going at it at least forty minutes, right?” Harry clarified. “That’s the longest anyone in Gryffindor has lasted so far this year, isn’t it?”

Ron nodded slowly. “Hermione went thirty five minutes once, but she always took a while to make her moves.”

Harry bit back the first reply that came to mind. Instead he turned to Percy. “Congrats Percy, you’re just the latest in a long line of victims, but you made a better showing than I did.”

Percy blinked, but finally managed to master his emotions. “I did?”

Harry nodded. “Ron beats everyone at chess. It’s become almost silly. I’m just waiting for him to challenge Professor McGonagall or Dumbledore.”

Percy nodded slowly, and began to smile. But then he stiffened and gave Harry a piercing look.

Whatever the prefect wanted to say was interrupted by Mrs. Weasley announcing that dinner was ready.

As Ron had explained to Harry earlier, dinner on Christmas Eve at The Burrow was usually light fare – sandwiches and a hearty soup. This allowed Mrs. Weasley time to go all out for her Christmas Day feast.

When no one was looking, Harry slipped a dry sandwich into his pocket for later. He ignored the pointed look Crookshanks was giving him.

As he and Ginny cleared the table, Ron and the others began heading upstairs, obviously planning to make an early night of it. Harry smiled to himself. The sooner they went to sleep, the sooner Christmas morning would come.

Ginny seemed tired as well, but she was also looking at Harry a little oddly.

“You must be tired,” Harry suggested, “you were working half the day.” He yawned. “I’m going to sleep after I ask your dad something.”

Ginny frowned a little, but just nodded and went upstairs.

Molly was in the kitchen and Arthur was in the living room, regretfully rolling up the string of lights that never actually lit up, no matter what he tried.

“Are you taking those back out to the shed?” Harry asked.

Arthur nodded, obviously still pondering the mysteries of Muggle technology.

“I’ll go with you,” Harry suggested. “There’s something I need to ask you about.”

Mr. Weasley looked up then, no longer distracted. They both collected jackets from the front hall and walked out into the shadowed garden.

“I had a bit of trouble in the village,” Harry said as they approached the shed.

Arthur gave him a quick look, but said nothing.

“I’m all right,” Harry quickly assured him. “In fact, I’m better than all right. I found Sirius.”

Arthur Weasley stopped dead in his tracks and stared at Harry as the boy pulled the door open. A large black dog, curled up comfortably in the corner, raised its head sleepily.

Mr. Weasley glanced from Harry to the dog, and back again. At first he gazed at Harry with some concern in his eyes, but then they widened. “He’s an Animagus as well?” he asked.

Harry nodded, and then turned toward his Godfather. “You can show him. I trust him, and you should as well.” He pulled the sandwich from his pocket. “Besides, I think you’d rather eat this with hands anyway.”

Sirius’ outline blurred and suddenly a very thin man in ragged clothing was crouched on the floor of the shed. His hand shook as he took the sandwich from Harry.

Harry felt his eyes prickling. If anything, Sirius looked worse than the first time he’d seen him. Before he stopped to think, his wand was in his hand and a simple charm filled the shed with warm air. Another wave and a mug of steaming hot chocolate appeared in front of his Godfather.

Arthur’s eyes widened as he watched Harry casually violate the laws on underaged magic use. Not to mention the fact that his ward had just performed a dual conjuration on the spot.

“Don’t worry,” Harry said quietly. “The Ministry sensors can’t pick up a thing through those wards. I should have done this earlier.”

“It’s all right,” Sirius said, his voice rusty. “I was more tired than anything, and this shed is plenty warm enough when you have fur.” He took another sip of the hot chocolate and grimaced a little. “I think this is all I’d better eat for a while, anyway.”

Arthur nodded slowly, obviously troubled by the implications of Sirius’ appearance.

“I saw some men chasing him in the village,” Harry explained. “When I saw one pull out a wand, I knew they were up to no good. When I saw what they were chasing, the memory came back of a big black dog that looked after me when I was a baby and I put it all together.”

“But how did you get away from the Aurors?” Arthur asked worriedly.

“Only one of them was an Auror I recognized,” Sirius corrected. “And I didn’t do anything. Young Harry here came up behind them and stunned all three.”

Arthur stared at Harry, who was suddenly seized by a desire to sink into the floor. “How long before they come here looking for you?” he said turning back toward Sirius.

“Quite a while,” Sirius said affably. “Harry Obliviated them and left them soaked with alcohol in an alleyway. Even if they did eventually remember what happened, no one would believe it. James couldn’t have done better himself.”

The compliment caught Harry off guard and he coughed as his throat suddenly constricted.

“I see,” Arthur Weasley said. “Well, I am glad you seem to be all in one piece. We were getting a little worried when you disappeared.”

“You were not the only one,” Sirius agreed. “A few days after your visit I was moved into another cell block. I wasn’t concerned at first, but then I realized that they weren’t feeding me anymore. When it became clear this was deliberate, I decided to risk getting caught by the Dementors and snuck out as a dog.” He shivered. “The sea is damn cold this time of year. I almost didn’t make it.”

Arthur looked furious. “Did you recognize any of the men who moved you to your new cell?” he asked.

Sirius shook his head. “They were all new to me,” he sighed.

“Maybe you will get an opportunity to identify them later,” Arthur said in an encouraging tone of voice, “But I’m not sure I understand why Harry didn’t bring you into the house already.”

Harry let out a frustrated sigh. “Remember that book I showed you?”

Arthur nodded as his face turned grim.

“One of the few people Snape hates as much as me or my father is Sirius Black,” Harry said flatly. “If he picked up from Ron or Ginny that he was staying here, well, there would be Aurors here in minutes. You and Mrs. Weasley can avoid him until you’ve mastered what’s in that book.”

Arthur nodded. “That seems possible. But what about Dumbledore? You said he can do it as well.”

Sirius appeared to follow this conversation easily enough that Harry began to hope. “Professor Dumbledore knows that Sirius is innocent. Moreover, he knows that I know. If he gave Sirius up to the Ministry, he knows I’d likely leave Hogwarts forever and maybe even let him deal with Voldemort on his own.”

Both adults went silent at this.

“I don’t think it will come to that,” Harry reassured them. “He’s even cut back on the legilimency since he knows I can sense it. And I doubt it’ll be that easy to duck out of a prophecy.”

“You know about that?” Sirius asked quickly.

Harry nodded. “He finally told us last term.”

“Prophecy?” Arthur asked.

Harry sighed. “There was a prophecy made, right before I was born. It’s going to come down to me or Voldemort, ‘for neither can live while the other survives’.”

Arthur looked ill. “So there really isn’t any way out, is there? No way to avoid fighting him again.”

Harry shook his head. “I appear to be the only one who can stop him, at least permanently. Otherwise he will come back and start killing again.”

“And he told you this?” Arthur asked incredulously. “How could he do such a thing to a twelve year old boy?”

Harry grunted. “Maybe because I asked him to. Voldemort mentioned a prophecy in passing when I met him before, and I wanted Dumbledore to tell me. If it’s my destiny, then I have a right to know. If it’s up to me to take him out, then better I know as soon as possible so I can start preparing. I already knew I was a target, now I just know why.”

Arthur nodded, but his face was a little grey. “Doesn’t… doesn’t it bother you, to know what you have to do?” he finally asked in a sick voice.

Harry considered his response, noticing that Sirius was also watching him closely, his sandwich eaten and his hot chocolate drunk. “Mr. Weasley, do you remember when you and Mrs. Weasley heard about Fabian and Gideon?”

Arthur swallowed and nodded.

“Mrs. Weasley hasn’t been quite the same after that, has she?” Harry asked softly. “I saw her looking at her ornament,” he explained in little more than a whisper.

Mr. Weasley seemed to have found his voice again, for this time he answered aloud. “No, Harry, she hasn’t.”

“Voldemort has killed so many people, and blighted the lives of so many more…” Harry’s voice trailed off as he groped for the words. “It’s almost, a privilege, to know that I’m the one who gets to stop him. My parents, Ron’s uncles, Sirius’ brother.” Harry noticed his last addition garnered a sharp look from Sirius. “I’ve done a lot of reading about that bastard’s reign of terror. He has a lot to answer for.”

Mr. Weasley nodded slowly, his jaw tightening as his colour returned. Harry supposed he had just dropped a lot of nasty shocks on him. A less charitable person could interpret his reticence as manipulation, so Harry threw a bone to his conscience. “I’ll understand, you know, if learning this makes you feel differently about our living arrangements,” he said quietly. “You didn’t sign up for all of this, and you have your own family to look out for.”

Arthur Weasley frowned, and Harry thought he detected a flash of anger in his eyes. “Harry, I will decide what I need to look out for. When Molly and I signed those papers, you became a member of this family. Are you saying that you want to leave?”

Harry shook his head quickly.

“Good. Then let us never speak of that again. For that matter, I agree that the Dark Lord has a lot to answer for, and it could also be a privilege to help the one who is supposed to bring him to justice.” Arthur’s anger faded as he spoke, and Harry felt a little ashamed. He’d been feeling so guilty and so concerned about making sure of his welcome that he’d inadvertently insulted the man.

“Now,” Arthur continued, “I think our guest could do with a meal and a hot bath. I think I’ve got some clothes—”

“Er,” Harry spoke up. “Remember, we can’t let anyone in the house know he’s here. Percy is very sharp, and he hasn’t had any Occlumency training at all.” He didn’t miss Sirius’ eyes dart towards him when he mentioned Occlumency, and he began to entertain a small, frail hope.

“Right.” Arthur nodded, frowning. “I suppose we could rig up something out here then. It doesn’t seem very hospitable though… Molly would clout me if she knew I let you stay out here in the cold.”

Sirius chuckled again. “It seems to be quite warm in here right now,” he said, nodding toward Harry. “Honestly, this is better accommodations than I’m used to, if you know what I mean.”

Harry looked around the shed. “I’m sure we could rig up a tub or something if you wanted to get cleaned up… and there’s plenty of food in the house.”

Arthur clapped his hands together. “Let’s see to that and I’ll have a quick word with Molly. I will, however, need to tell her more when it’s prudent to do so.”

In short order, Sirius was looking remarkably better. His filthy prison clothes had been burned while he was soaking in a magically-expanded washtub. Using a wand he’d ‘acquired’ after his escape, Harry’s Godfather managed to trim his matted hair and beard. Now, sitting on a transfigured cot, dressed in some of Arthur’s old clothes that fit his wasted frame, he looked decades younger.

Arthur was a little concerned when Sirius politely declined more than another small sandwich, but Harry’s eyes narrowed. “They were starving you, weren’t they?”

Sirius nodded. “Long enough that it hurts if I eat too much.”

Arthur’s face purpled and Harry briefly felt sorry for the people responsible for his Godfather’s condition if his guardian ever got hold of them. Harry distracted himself from the darkening course of his thoughts by taking out his wand and reinforcing the warming charms on the shed.

“Harry,” Arthur asked after a moment. “I know the Ministry can’t tell you are using magic, but why did you insist on doing all the conjuring and spellwork in here?”

“Well, partially I wanted to feel useful, but mostly I wanted to clear my wand,” he admitted. “Prior Incantato will only show the most recent spells cast with a wand. As far as I know, no one should suspect me having anything to do with those stunned wizards, but I don’t want to risk someone checking my wand and seeing stunning spells and memory charms.”

Both men gave Harry a long look and he supposed he was displaying an unusual degree of caution. The problem was that for someone used to fighting Voldemort and his Death Eaters for well over a decade, the idea of ‘excessive caution’ was almost laughable.

Arthur looked from Harry to Sirius and back again. “Well, Molly and I have some things to attend to in the house. I’m sure you two have a lot to talk about.” He paused with his hand on the door. “Harry, do try to get some sleep tonight.”

Harry smiled at his guardian. “I will. And thank you. For everything.”

Arthur smiled back, and a lot of the evening’s awkwardness was banished. “You’re more than welcome. Merry Christmas to you both.” He opened the door and stepped out into the chill night.

Sirius broke the silence that descended after the door shut. “He’s a good man,” he said.

“The best,” Harry agreed.

Sirius looked at Harry for a long moment. “Lily hardly ever let me around you when I was a dog. She was worried I’d give you fleas or something.”

Harry sighed. “Just a moment.” It was inevitable that one of his invented early memories would eventually be found out. But there was a chance it wouldn’t be necessary. Locking eyes with his Godfather, Harry reached out with his Legilimency and felt for the mind behind those dark eyes.

Harry almost cheered aloud as the probe skittered off of a sphere of blackest obsidian. He dug in again, working from multiple angles, but his strongest efforts glanced off the hardened barrier without leaving a mark. Finally, he smiled in genuine relief. “You’re an Occlumens,” he said with a note of wonder in his voice.

“You’re a Legilimens?” Sirius asked.

Harry nodded. “It’s not natural, is it?”

“No,” Sirius shook his head. “They were worried some of my family members might try to get information out of me, even though I avoided them for the most part. There were a few who still sought me out, we weren’t sure why – either to try and convert me or because they wanted out as well.” He shrugged. “It would have been easier to just keep me ignorant of anything important, but James wouldn’t hear of it.”

“Who trained you?” Harry asked curiously.

“Dumbledore, after James talked him into it,” his Godfather answered.

Harry suppressed a surge of jealous anger. Dumbledore had also trained Sirius in the less subtle method that seemed to work better for Harry as well. He wondered how much misery could have been averted if Dumbledore had been willing to train him before. But the old man had his reasons for sending Snape instead, and he paid for it as well.

“It also helped, a little, in Azkaban,” Sirius added tonelessly. “It wouldn’t completely shut them out, the Dementors, but it did take the edge off.”

Harry swallowed. Sirius had also paid for his training, in ways unimaginable to others. “I’m sorry about that. I wish I knew how I could have gotten you out of there faster.”

Sirius looked at him, a little confused now.

Harry took a deep breath in and blew it out. “With Snape and… other people… running around using Legilimency on everyone, I’ve had to be careful what I shared with anyone else. You’re the first full Occlumens I’ve met here that I can trust.” He pulled out his wand. “Let’s get this out of the way first. I, Harry James Potter, solemnly swear on my magic and my life, that everything I am about to reveal to Sirius Black this evening will be true and factual, to the best of my knowledge.”

Sirius squinted against the glare that Harry’s oath invoked. “Is that really necessary?” he asked.

“I think so,” Harry said. “I’ve got some things to tell you, Padfoot old boy, that I doubt you’ll believe, even with the oath.”

Sirius chuckled. “You’re James’ son, all right. But you have to be the oddest twelve year old I’ve ever met.”

“That’s just it,” Harry corrected him. “I’m not. Or at least not just twelve years old.”

“What is that supposed to mean?” Sirius asked.

“Part of me is twelve year old Harry Potter, part of me is a bit older.”

Sirius’ eyes widened. “James?” he asked in a wondering tone.

Harry felt his stomach cramp into a ball when he realized where Sirius’ speculation had gone. Correcting that false hope would kill him, but Harry’s Oath didn’t leave him much choice.

“I’m sorry, Sirius, but no. The ages are close though, now that I think about it. My older part is the memories of an older version of myself.”

Sirius frowned in confusion, though the disappointment was also plain on his face. “How is that possible?” he finally asked. Harry’s oath made saying it was impossible an exercise in futility.

“The memories… along with the spirit, and maybe the magic, were sent back in time from the year 2010.”

Sirius’ mouth dropped open. “Twenty years? That’s impossible. A time turner can only do a few hours.”

“It wasn’t done with a time turner,” Harry corrected him. “I set up a temporal transit field with enough energy for a nineteen year jump.”

“But why just your memories, why not send all of you back?” Sirius asked, but the leery expression on his face told Harry he already half-expected the answer.

“The field can’t send back solid matter,” Harry explained, “unless you have nearly infinite energy to power it. As it was, I had to wrap the field around myself and then commit suicide so my spirit would get shunted through the field.”

“You what?!” Sirius roared, leaping up from his cot.

“Sit down!” Harry snapped.

“How the hell could you kill yourself?!” Sirius demanded, his face red and angry. “I never thought James’ son would take the coward’s way out.”

Harry knew Sirius didn’t have the full story yet. He knew the older man was probably reacting strongly because of something that had happened with someone else. But his last statement took Harry’s self control and smashed it to kindling.

“Coward’s way out? Coward’s way out? Damn you Sirius, I had won! I killed that son of a bitch. I ripped out Voldemort’s mind and blew his body into fragments. And then I looked around and realized that I didn’t have any reason left to live. Everyone I cared about was dead, starting with you, you careless idiot! How the hell you let Bellatrix kill you I will never understand!” Harry paused, and realized his chest was pumping like a bellows. “I bloody damn well won my effing war, and then I read about a way to travel back in time, and I came here, so I could do it all bloody over again, and maybe see if I could do a better job of it this time, so maybe Hogwarts would still be standing, and maybe the people I love could still be alive. So why don’t you tell me how that’s the coward’s way out?”

The look of utter horror on Sirius’ face made Harry feel even worse. He turned away and swiped at eyes he just now realized were leaking. He jumped when he felt a hand on his shoulder, and the next thing he knew Sirius had grabbed him in a rough embrace.

Harry held onto his Godfather for dear life. Merlin, how he’d missed the man, his father’s oldest and best friend. He also realized that this was the first person he’d ever been able to talk to about his whole ordeal. The bits and pieces he’d had to hold back from his friends had festered, like bits of dirt in a healing wound, and the pressure had built up more than he’d realized.

The next thing he knew, he was sitting next to Sirius on the cot, his Godfather’s arm across his shoulders.

“You’ve never been able to talk about this before, have you?” the older man asked.

Harry shook his head. “I’m teaching my friends Occlumency, but it’s hard for them. They don’t even know why, not really. One of them, Hermione, figured out on her own that Snape was using Legilimency, so she bought us a book on Occlumency. Everyone thinks I’m a natural Occlumens, because of the curse-scar, so they don’t question why Snape can’t get into my mind.”

“That greasy git never gets tired of making things hard for everyone else,” Sirius said in a disgusted voice.

Harry nodded. “So I have to be careful what I say to everyone, otherwise Snape might learn it second-hand.”

“I’m surprised you haven’t tried to do something about him directly,” Sirius observed.

“Well, I am trying to get him sacked,” Harry said, “but there aren’t a lot of accredited potions masters willing to teach at Hogwarts.”

Sirius frowned. “Watch out he doesn’t hear about that. He’s a pretty nasty piece of business when he wants to be.”

Harry nodded. “I know, I watched him murder Dumbledore.”

Sirius’ eyes bulged out. “He what?”

Harry sighed. “Maybe I’d just better start at the beginning.”

Sirius nodded, so that’s exactly what he did. He described the original timeline in as much detail as he could remember without using a Pensieve. Sirius sat and listened without saying a word… with a few exceptions.

“The Dursleys?” Sirius demanded at one point. “But Lily’s sister detested her…”

Harry nodded. “It wasn’t pleasant either time, less so this last one. But Dumbledore thought I’d be safer under the protection of the blood wards.” Sirius subsided a little at that, but Harry thought he was still likely to have a few words for the professor, and few of them polite.

Sirius nodded thoughtfully when Harry relayed the sequence of events that led to Voldemort’s resurrection. Harry was pretty sure he could hear the wheels turning already.

The battle at the Department of Mysteries also provoked an outburst from Harry’s Godfather. “Bellatrix? How the hell did she manage to kill me?”

Harry sighed. “You know they have this archway in the department of mysteries, have you heard of it?”

Sirius nodded. “Yes, they used it to execute criminals in the old days, didn’t they?”

“Yeah, well, you were duelling with your cousin, and you stopped to taunt her when you were standing in front of the archway… and she hit you with a stunner.” Harry swallowed. “You fell through.”

Sirius’ jaw dropped open. “That is the… the most ridiculous thing I’ve ever heard! Killed by a stunner? Because I stopped fighting to taunt her?”

Harry shrugged. He didn’t know why Sirius was acting so outraged, it was hardly his fault it happened. “Try not to do it again, all right?”

Sirius looked offended at that, then broke down laughing. “I’ll try to remember that, Harry.”

There wasn’t much cause for laughter after that. Sirius’ hand on his shoulder tightened as he choked out the words to describe the Hogwarts Massacre. When he finished describing the clean up of the bodies, Harry paused to collect himself – he was emotionally drained.

“She was the One, wasn’t she?” Sirius asked him in little more than a whisper.

Harry just nodded. He didn’t need Sirius to clarify who he was asking about.

“What is it with Potter men and red-heads?” Sirius mused. The arm across his shoulders tightened and Harry felt the lump in his throat soften a little.

Harry felt a little ashamed that he found it easier to describe the utter destruction of the British Wizarding culture that followed. He still found his chest tightening when he described the fates that found each of their friends. Sirius shuddered at Remus’ pain-filled end. “I’m glad he and Tonks got together, though I never would have pictured it.”

“He said once that she made him laugh, and he hadn’t laughed very much since he became the last of the Marauders.”

Sirius let out a sigh. “Well, she’ll have to find another reason, though I might help her a bit. There are still three Marauders around, and we better not let the number go any lower.”

“I don’t count Peter,” Harry said tightly.

“I’m not counting the little rat either,” Sirius agreed. “Remus, me, and you, Prongs the second.”

“Me?” Harry asked.

“You.” Sirius said firmly. “Your Patronus is still a stag, right?”

Harry nodded.

“Good. Your Animagus form, if you have one, is likely to be the same, but that’s enough by itself to justify the name. I imagine you gave Remus a good shock the first time he saw it… Anyway, what you’ve described to me sounds like the greatest prank in history, and more than sufficient grounds for your induction into the august ranks of the Marauders.”

“A prank?” Harry asked, his mind refusing to make the connection.

Sirius nodded. “You go back in time to screw with Voldemort’s plans, using all the knowledge you gained in nearly twenty years of fighting him. Once you are here in this time, you fool everyone, including Dumbledore, which I’m not sure James and I ever really managed to do. Wherever he is right now, your father has to be grinning like a maniac.”

Harry just stared at his Godfather, who was smiling broadly now. Nothing fazed the man. The news of his own demise. The destruction of the world. The deaths of his remaining friends. And here he was, smiling in appreciation of what he saw as an especially good prank. Harry felt himself smiling back.

“I imagine you are making a few changes this time around?” Sirius asked with a raised eyebrow.

Harry found himself describing his first year at Hogwarts in rather greater detail than he expected. Not unexpectedly, Harry found himself giving a play-by-play breakdown of the Quidditch matches, which Sirius relished. Harry’s foiling of Quirrell’s attempt at the Stone with a single stinging hex had the man laughing out loud again.

Sirius also reassured Harry when he wondered aloud at the ethics of how he was manipulating his friends. “Look Harry, do you honestly think that they are doing better this time than they did their second year, er, their first second year?”

Harry thought it over and slowly nodded. “Yes, I think they are.”

“Are they happier, better grades, better able to defend themselves?” Sirius prompted him.

Harry nodded again.

“Maybe you are just being a better friend than they realize?” Sirius suggested. “It’s odd, but you remind me a little of Lily in that. She was always trying to get people to do what was best for themselves and the people they cared about. I think she was responsible for half of the good relationships in our house. I’m not saying she was a match-maker or anything, but she was good at getting people to realize if they really cared about someone or not.” He smiled faintly. “Of course, her talent was completely useless where she and James were concerned. In that, you have a leg up on her, though I suppose you do have an unnatural advantage.”

Harry gave a weak laugh, but his voice was so shaky it sounded more like a hiccup. He just hoped Ginny, Ron, and the rest agreed with Sirius when they finally could be told the truth.

“I also think,” Sirius continued, “that you are letting the Dursleys off too lightly. But I can take care of that while I’m running a few errands.”

Harry frowned. Sirius’ voice was a little too deliberately light for that to not be significant. “Errands?” he asked.

“Well, you’ve got these Horcruxes to gather, but you’re a little young to be travelling alone, let alone Apparating all over creation. I, on the other hand, as a dashing escaped convict, can go wherever my feet lead me. And if the course of my evasions leads me through Little Hangleton, or near Twelve Grimmauld Place, or near any other hidey-holes… well, no one would suspect a thing, would they?”

Harry felt his stomach tighten, but didn’t voice his initial protests. Instead he thought it over as rationally as he could. He had been wondering when he’d get a chance to do all these things, and now Sirius was offering himself as a surrogate to gather the Horcruxes before Voldemort grew wary and moved them. “The Cup needs to be last,” Harry finally said. “There was some kind of charm on it that alerted him when we touched it. That led him to attacking the school. Also, be careful about that ring. Something around it destroyed Dumbledore’s hand when he removed it.”

Sirius nodded. “Tell me everything you can remember about them, and that little ceremony you described when Voldemort was resurrected. I may be up for a bit of grave robbing as well.”

It was close to three in the morning before Harry finally got to bed. He felt utterly drained, like an old husk. Sirius pumped him for every detail Harry could recall, and there were more than he suspected at first.

Confiding everything in his father’s best friend had also acted to drain Harry of his own doubts and ethical concerns. Sirius listened to him castigate himself for manipulating everyone around him, then told him he was being too hard on himself. Harry had no idea how freeing that could be.

He fell asleep the instant his head touched the pillow.

An instant later, Ron was shaking him awake. Harry blinked blearily at his friend.

“Every other day of the year, you’re awake before the sun, Harry. But on Christmas you want to sleep in?” Ron shook his head. “You’re barmy.”

Harry scrubbed at his eyes and sat up. The light filtering through the curtains was proof it was daylight, even though it felt like no time had elapsed. As he sat up it hit him. He hadn’t had any nightmares, even though he’d been asleep more than long enough for them to start.

Harry pondered this as he looked dully at the stocking full of brightly wrapped packages laid across the foot of his bed. He’d left his presents in Mrs. Weasley’s care, all wrapped and neatly labelled under the tree. He just wasn’t sure how she distributed them so neatly, and without waking anyone.

The first present was a book, oddly enough, from Percy. Wizarding Duelling Code was the title, and Harry set it aside for future reading… but not before noticing the bookmark placed in the section regarding ‘targeting of spectators’.

Charlie had evidently heard about the duel as well, because he sent Harry a pair of dragon hide duelling gloves. They were fingerless, with a metal plate sewn onto the back and small metal ridges over the knuckles. They were reputed to make one harder to disarm, but Harry was more impressed by how much damage they would do with a punch. He hoped Charlie enjoyed the Playwizard subscription that he’d clubbed up with Ron and the Twins to get him. Arranging to have an American wizarding periodical shipped to Romania once a month was a little more expensive than anyone anticipated.

Bill sent Harry a book as well, Wards: Construction and Disruption, along with a short note explaining that the eldest Weasley brother learned more about the basics of curse-breaking from that book than almost anything else he ever read. Harry chuckled to himself when he recognized the title. It was one the Ministry had placed on the restricted list, meaning only licensed professionals could purchase it. He wondered if Bill knew that… then he realized that was probably what had prompted his decision. I hope he’s enjoying his new job even more than tomb-raiding, Harry thought to himself with a smile.

Ron and Ginny’s names were on the next package. Inside, Harry found an adjustable leather wand holder. The instructions indicated that it could be attached to one’s belt, or strapped around the forearm. Harry looked up at Ron, who was smiling.

“We figured that one of these days you were going to wave your arm and have your wand come flying out of your sleeve,” Ron said. “Plus, we couldn’t see you wearing long-sleeve shirts all summer. Ginny couldn’t anyway…”

Harry was too happy to allow himself to be baited. “You going to put those pads to good use?” he asked.

Ron frowned. “I’d like to, but it’s a bit early, innit?”

Harry shrugged. “I talked to Oliver about starting up a reserve team again, and he seemed interested. If nothing else, you’ll get some serious practice before he graduates. I don’t see anyone else in Gryffindor stepping up to take his spot.”

Ron blinked and coughed. “Really? I mean, you don’t?”

“You’ve already got the eye,” Harry said nonchalantly, “and if you keep growing the way you are, you’ll have more than enough arm span to do the job.”

Ron was quietly thoughtful as Harry emptied out the stocking. Mrs. Weasley had knitted him another jumper in emerald green, which seemed to be his colour as much as maroon was Ron’s.

Under the jumper was a small box from Fred and George. Inside the box was a small container of chocolates labelled ‘veritamints – eat one and tell nothing but the truth for five minutes’ and a newspaper clipping.

It seemed that one Vernon Dursley, formerly of Surrey, had appeared at his scheduled labour board hearing to protest his dismissal from Grunnings. At some point he caused a disruption of the proceedings and not only had his petition dismissed, but was found to be in contempt, fined fifty pounds and spent the night in jail.

Harry laughed out loud as he read this, prompting Ron to ask what was so funny. When he explained, Ron was amused, but even more he was in awe of how his brothers managed to sabotage Vernon’s court appearance without getting caught leaving Hogwarts.

The last object in the toe of the stocking was a small box. Inside, Harry found a silver pocket watch with a note:

Dear Harry,

In the course of my ‘checking up on a few things’, I went through the crime scene materials from Godric’s Hollow. As you have no doubt been told, there wasn’t much left of your parents’ cottage after the fire, nor were their personal effects spared. However, one of the evidence bins did contain this watch, which had been ruined by the fire. There’s a rather good clock-maker on Diagon Alley who specializes in custom work. She was able to replace the mechanism and restore the exterior. I don’t know if this belonged to your father, your grandfather, or someone completely unrelated to you, but I thought you might like to have it.

Merry Christmas,

Arthur Weasley

Harry had some difficulty finishing the note. He ran his fingers over the cover of the watch, which was engraved with the image of a stag.

It was a while before Harry was able to shower and get dressed. As an early riser, he wasn’t so used to having to wait for the plumbing. Of course, he was very aware of how long he had to wait, because he was frequently looking at the silver pocket watch that he knew had been his father’s.

By the time he was done, Mrs. Weasley was already setting out the light lunch intended to tide everyone over until the planned Christmas feast. Harry found Fred and George at the bottom of the stair, talking intently as they passed a thick black soft-cover book back and forth between them.

“Hello gentlemen, I must say that your gift was highly appreciated, and Ron is losing his mind trying to figure out how you pulled it off,” Harry said in a grand tone. “I see that you have also found my gift to yourselves. Have I perchance altered your appreciation for fine Muggle literature?”

George was visibly biting his tongue, so Fred took up the gauntlet. “It might be slightly amusing,” he said in a bored tone. He shrugged. “We’ll let you know. We do appreciate those ingredients though. They should prove right useful for the coming term.”

Harry made a clucking sound and shook his head. “I suppose I lose the bet then. Here, I’ll take that back and use the money to get you some more asphodel, or—”

“Let’s not be hasty now,” Fred interrupted quickly, intercepting Harry’s hands with his raised palm. “We really should at least give it a chance, you know, to be fair and all.”

“That’s all right,” Harry said smoothly, reaching again for the book. “You don’t need to spare my feelings. Ginny and I won’t die of embarrassment. I’ll just take that worthless Muggle book back and…” He tugged on the book, but George refused to let go.

“He’s not buying it, o’ brother of mine,” George said, breaking his silence.

Fred let out a defeated sigh. “I suppose he isn’t.”

Harry smiled, feeling a trifle smug. “I had you the second you saw the title, didn’t I?”

Fred made a face, but George just nodded- a trifle morosely.

“Well, you’ve got until January twenty fifth before you can pull another prank,” Harry said, smiling. “Of course, it’ll take you almost that long to read 1001 Practical Jokes and Dirty Tricks.”

George nodded more cheerfully and Fred looked thoughtful. “You know, Harry, you could, er, not mention the terms of our bet. That way everyone would go spare over the next thirty days wondering what we’re up to. In a way, you’d be pranking the whole school.”

I’m already doing that, Harry thought to himself. He mulled it over for a minute, and then nodded. “All right, but only as long as you two behave yourselves.”

“Harry!” Fred said in a shocked voice. “When have you ever known us to misbehave?”

Christmas dinner was just as big a production as Harry expected. Mrs. Weasley’s kitchen table, magically expanded for the occasion, almost literally groaned under the weight of the dishes it supported.

Remus arrived by Floo at precisely five o’clock on the dot. From the way the man’s eyes bulged out, Harry didn’t think he’d ever seen anything like a Weasley Christmas either.

Harry felt momentarily bad for Sirius, stuck out in the shed. He’d taken it upon himself to slip out of the house and bring his Godfather some breakfast, only to find that Arthur had already beaten him to it. Harry tried to keep the man company as long as he could without raising suspicions, until finally Sirius himself sent him back inside.

“Harry, I’m warm, I have food to eat, and there are no Dementors around. This is the best Christmas I’ve had since 1980. I’m serious.”

“And I’m Harry. I still wish…”

“Hearing you make lame jokes about my name, something only James would stoop to, I might add, makes it even better. Now get back in that house before you make someone suspicious. You’ve got a new family waiting for you in there, and not many people get that precious a second chance.” Sirius’ voice softened for a moment. “Don’t blow it, Harry.”

And so Harry found himself taking Remus’ cloak and hanging it in the hallway. When he returned, he found Remus asking Arthur if there was any word on Sirius.

“Oh, er, yes. Well, no new word at the Ministry,” Arthur replied carefully.

“I imagine he’s doing well, wherever he is,” Harry added quietly.

Remus looked from Arthur to Harry and back again. “I… see. Well, I do hope he’s staying out of trouble.”

“That’s hardly likely,” Harry said, “unless he’d travelled as far away as America.”

Remus’ eyes widened and Harry felt like a heel. While nothing he said was a literal lie, he still hated to mislead the man. Unfortunately, if he still ended up teaching at Hogwarts next year, he’d be in close proximity to Severus Snape, especially during the disorienting after-effects of his ‘monthly problem’. Harry didn’t want to let him worry needlessly, but he also knew that being too direct would put Sirius’ neck in a noose.

“Perhaps,” Remus said carefully, “some of us have more to be grateful for during this holiday season than they realize.”

“Perhaps,” Arthur agreed.

Following tradition, the Weasley children were seated around the table in order of their ages. This left Harry between Ron and Ginny, which he did not mind in the slightest. She wore the copper butterfly hairclip he gave her above her left ear, and it flashed with glints of candlelight.

The meal which followed set even Hogwarts’ best to second place in Harry’s reckoning. Mrs. Weasley, and Ginny as her mother reminded everyone, had outdone themselves. The enormous goose that Arthur carved was as flavourful as it was juicy, and one bite of the chestnut stuffing convinced Harry that it was worth any number of long walks into Ottery Saint Catchpole.

Lingering over pudding, Mrs. Weasley asked Remus how he was doing.

“Quite well,” he replied, “in fact, I understand that the Defence Against the Dark Arts position may be opening up after this year, so I’ve owled my curriculum vitae to Professor Dumbledore with an inquiry.”

Percy gave Remus a long look after hearing that. Harry couldn’t tell if it was disbelief that the shabby-looking man was applying, or respect that he was qualified enough to think he even had a chance of becoming a Professor.

“Well, I think you’d be brilliant,” Harry said.

“It’s not like he’s got a tough record to beat,” Fred added.

“Not with the ‘great fake’ and ‘what’s that in the back of my head’ as predecessors,” George agreed.

“We’ll keep Hermione off your case,” Ron volunteered.

“From what I’ve heard, I think she’d be a delightful student,” Remus said with a laugh.

“I’ll bet you used to nag your schoolmates about studying, didn’t you?” Ron asked warily.

“Well, sometimes,” Remus agreed. “James and Sirius weren’t always the most focused of…” His voice trailed off as he looked from Ron to Harry, who was having difficulty keeping a straight face.

“There’s at least one in every generation,” Harry said with a smile at his friend.

“I suppose there must be,” Ron said gloomily. “Now I just know he’s going to replace Lockhart this autumn.”

Harry smiled at his father’s friend. “I’m sure you and Hermione will get along splendidly.”

“I’m just not so sure about the rest of us surviving next year,” Ron said.

“Be nice,” Harry chided his friend.

“All right,” Ron agreed. “But remember we’ve only just gotten her calmed down a bit. If he encourages her too much, we’ll be back to the beginning of first year again.”

“Ron,” Harry asked airily. “Have you ever known Hermione needing to learn the same lesson twice?”

Ron frowned. “Good point.”

“Besides,” Harry continued, “if you keep working with her on her flying, that’s less time for her to get worked up about her revising, right?”

Ron nodded, and Harry turned back to Remus, who was frowning in confusion. “We have a friend,” he explained, “who is just a bit mad about her grades.”

“Just a bit,” George added.

“Like Hagrid’s just a bit large,” Fred chimed in.

“Boys!” Mrs. Weasley said in a warning tone.

“Anyway,” Harry continued, “she’s picking Lockhart to pieces every class, pointing out inconsistencies in his books and asking questions about them. We’re just saying we’re sure you two will hit it off.”

“Which is good,” Ron added, “because she’s scary brilliant.”

Remus smiled faintly. “I’m sure we will.”

With that, the dinner conversation moved on to lighter topics. Mr. and Mrs. Weasley told about their first Christmas together with baby Bill. Remus relayed a time he and his classmates had all been stranded at Hogwarts over Christmas by a nasty blizzard and a collapse in the Floo network.

All in all, it was a very enjoyable dinner. All too soon, they were clearing the plates, and Remus was thanking his hosts.

As he shook Harry’s hand, Remus said, “I hope a certain reprobate is having a good Christmas, wherever he is.”

“I’m fairly certain that’s exactly what he’s doing,” Harry replied, looking the werewolf directly in the eye.

Remus gave that faint smile again, one that almost seemed to be a trademark of his. “We’ll have to get together and discuss our sources of information some day,” he said with no small amount of irony.

“Some day,” Harry agreed, deadpan.

After their guest left, Harry and Ginny began clearing the table with help from her brothers. With the extra hands Mrs. Weasley drafted, the table was cleared and the dishes washed in no time. This proved to be providential, because the short sleep the previous night, and the excitement of the day, left Harry stumbling over his own feet.

Harry was lurking in the kitchen, wondering if too many people were still awake for him to bring Sirius a snack, when Arthur walked in with his jacket still on from outside. The man started, but relaxed when he seemed to recognize Harry. From under his jacket, Arthur produced a bottle and plate that he quickly placed in the sink.

“I see we had the same thought,” Harry observed.

Arthur nodded. “Makes me sick to think someone in the Ministry gave orders for him to be deliberately starved.”

“It is a disturbing thought,” Harry agreed. He felt a little sick as well, watching the anguish on his guardian’s face. “By the way, I never got to thank you for the watch. Sirius said he gave it to my father when he got married.”

“Really?” Arthur asked with a pleased smile.

“Yes,” Harry confirmed. “It was actually a present for both of them, because my mum used to get after him about being late all the time.” Harry was annoyed to find his voice getting constricted as he repeated Sirius’ words.

“I… well…” Arthur seemed to be getting a little choked up as well. “I’m glad you liked it, Harry. I had a watch like that once. I passed it on to Bill for his seventeenth birthday. It just… felt right that you should have your father’s watch as well.”

Harry Potter stood there, on the evening of Christmas, with his father’s watch in his hand, staring at another man who’d become much the same to him in a very short period of time. “Mr. Weasley, don’t take this the wrong way, but if it weren’t for people like you and your family… well, I’d probably be in Australia, or America, or some other place where Voldemort would never find me.”

27

All Hell Breaks Loose

Harry slowly became aware. It was a very gradual process, hampered by the fact that he seemed to be floating in absolute darkness. Of course, ‘floating’ was his best guess, because he couldn’t feel his body either.

He wondered if he was dead, and was mildly surprised by how little that thought seemed to upset him. He’d made a good effort, but perhaps Fate wasn’t to be denied. She seemed determined to extract her due from the Wizarding world in general and Harry Potter in particular. Part of him wanted to rage against the unfairness of it all, but his emotions seemed to just drain away, leaving him a peaceful, but empty, husk.

Harry felt his awareness fade again, but then he was reminded of what roused him. There were voices, faint but discernable. He focused on them as a drowning man might cling to a rope.

“Merlin, I can hardly stand to see him lying there like that,” a male voice said quietly. Harry struggled to recognize it as his mind groped through a tangle of new and old memories.

Neville?

“He wouldn’t be here if we’d been where we were supposed to be,” another, slightly deeper, voice growled.

“Ron, you can’t blame yourself. You didn’t have any choice after Professor Snape made you leave,” replied a very precise feminine voice.

“I haven’t forgotten that, Hermione,” Ron’s voice snarled. “That greasy git set Harry up, I know it. He’s hated him since the first day of classes, and now he’s finally tried to kill him… and damn near succeeded.”

“He looked very unhappy when I saw him bringing potions to Madam Pomfrey,” another voice added tonelessly. “His face was very pale, and when she said she wasn’t sure Harry would wake up, he looked quite ill.”

“Luna!” Hermione gasped. “Don’t say that in front of him!”

“Why?” Luna’s voice asked. “If he can hear me, then he’s probably going to wake up anyway. If he can’t, then it doesn’t matter does it?”

Harry found that he didn’t really care that much. There was another voice that should have been there, but it was missing. A thread of anxiety began to pierce the peaceful shroud dragging him back into the darkness. Then it faded.

She’d been increasingly cold and distant since the New Year, so it shouldn’t surprise him if Ginny wasn’t there. Harry felt the almost comforting chill soak into his awareness, numbing it, urging him to rest again.

“Ron, you can stop looking daggers at Luna,” Neville said. “We’re all worried about Ginny too.”

Ginny?

“The entire staff is looking for her,” Hermione said quietly. “They’ll find her, Ron. And then we’ll all get detention for not staying in the tower,” she fretted.

“I don’t care,” Ron snapped. “I told Percy someone might take advantage of this to go after Harry. If I knew who had my sister, I’d go after them, but I don’t. At least I can do something useful here.”

“I think Professor Dumbledore knows we are here,” Luna said quietly. “He was looking right at you two when the announcement was made.”

“Her skeleton will lie in the Chamber forever,” Hermione recited, not responding to Luna’s words. “What Chamber is that referring to?”

Harry felt fear twist inside him. How could this be happening again?

“I’m not sure, but I think it’s some sort of secret,” Neville said. “All the teachers are looking for it now.”

“But who would kidnap Ginny?” Ron asked, his voice getting rough.

“Professor McGonagall insisted on questioning the Slytherins,” Hermione said. “I heard that she and Professor Snape argued quite loudly about it in the Staff Room. But now Draco and all his friends are still confined to the Slytherin Dungeons, and she’s out looking with the rest of the staff.” She sniffed softly.

“Ginny hasn’t been herself lately,” Luna said suddenly.

“She has been awfully quiet, especially since Harry was hurt,” Neville agreed.

“I know,” Ron said miserably. “She was so worried about him. Madam Pomfrey kicked her out of here half a dozen times in the last month. But she didn’t really talk much. All she did was mope around and write in that bloody diary Harry got her.”

Diary? No!

Harry felt his nonexistent body convulse with horror and then rage at his helplessness.

Then he heard a crash and tinkle of breaking glass.

The darkness exploded with blinding light as Harry Potter opened his eyes. He squinted as he painfully sat up and winced when Hermione let out a piercing scream. He felt hands grip his shoulders, steadying him.

Harry was released just as suddenly, but was still blinking and trying to get his eyes to focus. He almost flinched back when something touched his face, but recognized the smooth plastic. He held still as a red-headed blur slid his glasses onto his face.

That helped a lot, as he blinked, and finally reached under the lenses to wipe away some gunk that had accumulated while he was unconscious. With a little more blinking, the room was mostly in focus. He tried to speak, but all that came out was a dry croak. Harry looked over at the nightstand, but the top of it was covered with a tangle of broken glass, soaked in a multi-coloured mixture of liquids. He coughed and tried to swing his legs off the bed as Neville darted over to the infirmary’s sink.

Neville returned with a glass of water, earning a nod of thanks from Harry as the cool water soothed his dry throat. “Wand,” he said to Ron as he held out his hand.

Ron pulled Harry’s wand out of his robes, but Hermione looked on rather dubiously. “Harry,” she said carefully, “shouldn’t you be staying in bed? You were hurt rather badly. Madam Pomfrey said her salves would keep your muscles from deteriorating too much, but you fractured your skull and you’ve been in a coma for over a month…” Her voice trailed off when she met Harry’s eyes.

Harry straightened his back, then looked down at the hospital pyjamas and grimaced. He shook the pillow out of its pillowcase and let both fall to the floor. He transfigured them into a pair of trainers and pulled them on over his bare feet. He stood up carefully, but everything seemed to be working more or less correctly. He was sore, but functional – though anxiety seemed to be gnawing at the pit of his stomach. “How long ago did Ginny disappear?” he asked, dreading the answer.

“Luna saw her about four hours ago, coming out of Charms,” Ron said quickly.

Harry took a deep breath; all other things being equal, she was probably still alive. “I know where she is,” he finally said, “and I’m going to get her.”

“Not alone you aren’t,” Ron retorted.

Harry gave his oldest friend a weary smile that made the taller boy flinch back. “No, I don’t suppose I am.”

“How do you know where she is?” Hermione asked, clearly confused.

“It’s a long story,” Harry said as he quickly stood up. “How’s your Occlumency?”

Hermione’s eyes widened a bit, and Harry knew she was starting to fill in the gaps. “Let’s move,” he said, “we need to get to Ginny as quickly as possible.” Harry led his friends out of the hospital wing, his legs steadying with every stride. The doors opened before Harry could even reach for them, but he had more important things to think about right then.

Harry hoped that with the staff searching and the students confined to their dormitories, he’d be able to avoid encounters with the curious. Apparently, that wasn’t to be. No sooner did they round the corner in the corridor leading to Madam Pomfrey’s domain, than they encountered three adults.

Gilderoy Lockhart, resplendent in mauve robes with a matching tri-corner hat, was leading Rita Skeeter and her photographer, Bozo, towards the infirmary.

“Harry?” Lockhart gasped, stopping suddenly as he saw them.

“Ah, Mr. Potter, so good to see you awake again,” Rita said, her eyes glittering. “Mr. Lockhart was good enough to escort us to see you. Many people are very concerned about you after your accident.”

“Professor Lockhart,” Hermione asked suddenly, “why aren’t you helping search for Ginny?”

“Oh, er, um,” Lockhart sputtered for a moment, “you see, I already had this appointment set up, and it would be rude to just…”

“Is there some problem?” Rita asked, and Harry thought he even detected a note of concern in her voice. He must have hit his head pretty hard.

“Nothing serious,” Lockhart said quickly. “A silly little girl ran away and has everyone looking for her. I’m sure she’ll be found soon, never you worry. Now Harry,” he added in an avuncular tone, ignoring the murderous glare Ron was giving him, “I was just telling Rita what good friends we’ve become over the course of this year. Why don’t the three of us all go back to my quarters and we can talk about what fun we’ve had?” he asked with an imploring look. “I’ll even forget to mention your friends being out of bounds,” he added.

“Sorry,” Harry said coolly, “one of my friends is in danger and I don’t have time to waste on useless frauds.” He could see Rita’s Quick Quotes Quill moving feverishly behind the Defence Professor.

Lockhart’s eyes widened and he evidently heard the scratch of quill on parchment as well. He spun around with his wand in his hand. “Obliviate!” and Rita and Bozo were both slumping to the floor with glassy-looking eyes.

The overdressed charlatan whirled back toward the mostly stunned students, but Harry’s wand was already out. The Boy Who Lived held it out sideways, clenched in a fist shaking with rage. “Protego Maximus!” he roared as Lockhart finished his spell.

A semi-translucent wall of light spread out from Harry’s fist, expanding until it reached the floor, walls, and ceiling with a loud crunch. Beyond it, he could see Lockhart snapping his wand forward to erase their memories as well. This was one spell the man could perform with great skill, having never been caught once over the course of his entire career. If the bastard succeeded, Ginny’s life would probably be extinguished before they even remembered she was in danger. Harry panicked and reinforced his shield with everything he could put into it. The stones around them groaned and a suit of armour flew to pieces.

There was a bright flash of light, visible even through the shield, and Lockhart was violently thrown backward. Harry held for a moment, and then let the shield drop. He stepped forward, but kept his wand on the professor the entire time. Gilderoy Lockhart lay perfectly still on the hard flagstones, his head turned to one side. His eyes were staring glassily into space, the only signs of life the slow rise and fall of his chest and a thin line of drool creeping down from the corner of his mouth.

“What did you do to him?” Ron asked quietly.

“I think I reflected back a memory charm strong enough to wipe all five of us at once,” Harry said. “Hermione, now we know why he’s never been caught before. He probably let someone else do the dirty work, Obliviated them, and then took all the credit.”

But the bushy-haired witch wasn’t paying much attention. She was staring at the floor. Where Harry’s panic-driven shield had touched the millennia-old stones, a groove three inches wide and at least an inch deep had been gouged. She looked up at Harry, her eyes wide. “What did you do?” she asked.

“I panicked and threw up the strongest shield charm I could think of,” Harry replied truthfully. “We need to hurry, Ginny could be dying,” he added in an agonized voice.

Hermione visibly gathered herself and nodded.

Harry took one last look at the mind-wiped professor. He wasn’t even babbling as he remembered from before. Harry supposed it made sense. Rather than a back-fire from a broken wand, he’d evidently thrown a memory charm strong enough to affect five people, only to have it reflected back in his face. He suspected the man was catatonic now. Fate can have him, Harry decided as he set off down the corridor again. Rita and Bozo would be found soon enough.

There were no more encounters before they reached Moaning Myrtle’s bathroom.

“You’re not supposed to be in here!” the ghost wailed as soon as Harry pushed the door open.

“Sorry, it’s an emergency,” Hermione explained, though she was eyeing Harry rather oddly.

“Oh, you’re looking for that other girl,” Myrtle replied with a knowing smile.

Ron made a strangled noise but Hermione beat him to the punch. “You know where she is?” she asked, outraged, “and you didn’t tell anyone?”

“If she doesn’t make it, I’ll make you wish the Bloody Baron was after you instead,” Harry snarled. “Now get out of the way!”

Myrtle backed away slowly, but Harry had had enough. He quickly stepped forward, ignoring the biting chill as his shoulder passed through the ghost’s body. Stopping in front of the marked taps, he hissed, “Open!”

He turned back to his friends as the taps glowed and the sink descended into the floor. “Yes,” he said, “I know I just spoke in Parseltongue. It was a little gift from Tom when I got this ruddy scar. That’s how they kept this hidden for so long and why none of the staff could find it.” He picked up a bar of soap from the next sink over and transfigured it into a long coil of rope, but he watched his friends out of the corner of his eye, gauging their reactions.

Hermione’s eyes were dancing with questions, but she was visibly restraining herself. Ron nodded, but his eyes were worried. Neville just took a deep breath and helped tie the rope to the thick pipes below the working sink. Luna looked as though she’d been told the house elves were serving roast beef for supper – mildly interested, but not really surprised.

“This is going to be really dangerous; if any of you want to back out now, I’ll not think ill of you,” Harry said quietly once the rope was anchored. He wasn’t sure Fawkes would come, since they hadn’t been introduced yet, and he wasn’t feeling overwhelmingly loyal to Dumbledore at the moment. Better to have another way back out of there.

“Harry! She’s my sister!” Ron said, outraged. The others nodded.

“All right,” Harry acquiesced. “But you need to do exactly what I say when we get down there. Agreed?” Another chorus of nods.

The inside of the pipe was just as foul and slimy as Harry remembered. It would have been better if they’d had their brooms, but any delays while the Diary was sucking away Ginny’s life could be fatal. He had to stop that immediately. The pipe finally levelled out and deposited them on the floor of a damp tunnel. Hermione instantly had her wand out and illuminated the humid darkness.

Harry was on his feet in an instant. As they advanced, their feet began to crunch on rat skeletons. “There’s a basilisk down here,” he whispered, “so keep your eyes down. If it attacks, we use massed blind fire in its direction, physically damaging curses only, it’s too big to stun. Just like one of our covering fire exercises, right?”

“A basilisk?” Neville gasped.

“Yes, and if you meet its gaze, it’ll kill you on the spot,” Harry said, turning toward the boy. “What part of ‘really dangerous’ did you not understand?”

Neville’s eyes flickered toward Luna and Harry noticed the girl’s eyes hardening behind her wire-rimmed spectacles. “We’re all here to save Ginny,” she said. “We’ll have time for long overdue conversations afterward.”

Harry nodded and led them to the end of the tunnel, a wall with two carved serpents. He hissed, “Open,” again in Parseltongue, and the serpents parted, splitting the wall with them.

The five Gryffindors then entered the Chamber of Secrets.

The elaborately carved pillars, dim greenish illumination, and echoing footsteps all combined to creep Harry out just as much as last time. He knew what to expect, but that didn’t seem to matter to his racing heart. He was also dreading finding Ginny. He hoped she was still alive… no, she had to be. But he could be wrong. He wasn’t sure what another failure would mean, because his mind shied away from even admitting it was possible. His wand shook in his hand. All his hesitancy, all his doubts, seemed so stupid now.

Harry resisted the urge to break into a run. If things were repeating from last time, Ginny would be on the floor at the base of the statue, on the far side of the chamber. But they needed to stay together; otherwise the Basilisk might pick them off one by one. He must have been insane to let them come down here with him.

Nevertheless, when the statue swam out of the gloom, Ginny’s tiny form sprawled at its feet, Ron let out a sob and broke into a run. The rest of them picked up the pace as well, their footsteps echoing off the ancient stones. As Ron struggled to rouse his sister, Harry’s eyes flickered down to the Diary tucked under her hands. His stomach contracted into a small, icy ball, and his wand trembled in his hand as he looked around.

This time, Harry saw the hateful spectre materialize out of thin air. The tall, handsome, dark-haired boy was slightly blurred around the edges, but his gloating smile was all too visible. Harry felt the blood surge in his veins as rage threatened to overcome his reason. This bastard had hurt Ginny, again, and he’d let it happen, again.

“She won’t wake, you know,” the boy observed in a pleasant voice, making the others look up.

“Why not?” Ron demanded.

Tom ignored the question, merely shaking his head. “Is this the best Albus Dumbledore could do? A handful of children? Even if one of them is the famous Boy Who Lived.”

“How do you know that?” Harry asked carefully. He never told the Diary that much about himself when he tested it.

“Oh, I know a great deal about many things now. Some of them, I got from her,” he continued, nodding at Ginny’s silent form. “But she was surprisingly resistant. It took over a month before I could take control, and even then she was strong enough that I knew I wouldn’t be able to suppress her memories afterward.” The boy frowned petulantly. “I was so hoping to have a bit of fun with her first. The daughter of the Mudblood-lover murdering Mudbloods when she’s away at school, that would be a nice bit of irony, wouldn’t it?”

Ron’s wand was up in an instant, but the stunning spell merely passed through Tom’s chest with no effect. Hermione gasped.

“You can’t hurt me, you know,” the older boy said with a superior smile.

“He’s right,” Harry agreed, “he’s just a shade of a memory, generated by a Horcrux.”

That cracked the shade’s composure. “How…?”

“I know a great deal about many things,” Harry said mockingly. “Like how a half-blood orphan grew up with so much hate that he threw away his humanity to become a madman bent on killing Muggle-borns and Muggles like his father.”

Naturally, Hermione put it all together first. “Voldemort?” she asked.

“This ponce is Voldemort?” Ron asked incredulously.

“This is a memory of him when he was Head Boy,” Harry corrected, watching the spectre’s edges become blurry as it struggled to control itself. He decided to twist the knife a bit further. “At least he’s somewhat presentable. Later, he looked like something that escaped from one of Snape’s preserving jars.”

“That’s pretty bad, Harry,” Neville said with a shudder.

“Don’t blame Harry,” Luna added, patting Neville’s shoulder comfortingly. “It’s not his fault this silly boy wanted his outsides to look like his insides.”

Harry struggled to keep his voice light. Part of him wanted to rage at Riddle and part of him was horrified to see Ginny in this place again. He ruthlessly suppressed both of them – he needed to stick to the very rough plan he’d made. “It’s okay, Tom, you never seemed to have much imagination – but we all have our limitations. Don’t worry everyone: he can’t touch us, so let’s concentrate on breaking his hold on Ginny and waking her up. Then Tom can go back to sleep.”

“I may not be able to touch you,” Tom grated, “but I know what can! Speak to me, Slytherin, Greatest of the Hogwarts Four!” he continued in Parseltongue.

Everyone turned as the sound of grinding stones filled the chamber. The mouth of the massive statue opened, revealing a large dark hole. “Wands out!” Harry snapped. “Gather around Ginny, sight on that hole, and then look down. The Basilisk will come out of there, so don’t look up until it’s over.” He purposefully placed himself in the gathering around Ginny so that he was closest to the statue.

His wand trembled in his hand as his ears strained to hear the first hiss. There was a thud as something huge struck the floor. “Kill them!” Tom commanded in Parseltongue.

“Fire!” Harry snapped. It felt odd, casting spells blindly, but he kept his eyes fixed on the floor. His first Reducto was apparently a lucky hit, because it was followed by an explosive hiss like a damaged boiler. He kept on with that, pushing his magic to do as much damage as possible, hoping a hit would force the king of serpents back a pace or two. He needed to buy as much time as possible for them to kill the thing, otherwise what its fangs didn’t bite, its sheer bulk would crush.

But from the sounds of shattering stone, they were apparently missing as much as they hit. The hissed exclamations from the basilisk seemed to draw closer and closer. Harry finally felt something rear up above him, and he could see a faint shadow stretching toward him in the gloom. He risked raising his eyes a little and in his peripheral vision he saw the giant snake’s bright green underbelly, scarred and damaged from spells. It was rearing back to strike. Even if Harry dodged, it would probably crush Ginny.

Tom apparently realized that as well. “Not her!” he screamed in Parseltongue.

Before the snake could even register the command, Harry screamed, “Diffindo!” aiming his wand at the exact centre of the cracked belly scales. The cutting charm punched through the snake’s underside in a splash of dark blood. The lower section began to thrash wildly, while the upper portion toppled over to the side. Blood poured onto the stones from the massive rent, and Harry knew from its disorganized motions that the spine was severed.

He stepped to the side and glanced at Tom Riddle, who in turn stared incredulously at the dying basilisk. Harry couldn’t help but note that his outline was even sharper than before. He then turned to his friends, relieved to see that they’d followed his instructions, and were in fact still looking down at the floor. “Grab Ginny and move back!” he said. Ron and Neville picked her up, while Hermione diverted the tide of ichor with a wave of her wand.

Harry let out a sigh of relief and started to follow them when he heard the nearby scrape of scales on stone. Acting on instinct, he threw himself to the side, but a stunning impact on his back sent him tumbling across the floor. He thudded against Neville, almost knocking him over. Winded and sore, he looked up without thinking, right into the eyes of the basilisk… which were already glazing over in death.

“It doesn’t matter,” Tom Riddle snarled defiantly. “She’s almost gone now, and when she expires, I’ll be completely here and then I can kill you all. Slowly.”

Harry climbed shakily to his feet as Hermione worked on Ginny, first with Finite Incantatem and then an Awakening Charm, neither of which had any effect. He limped over to the dead basilisk’s head, ignoring the gasps behind him. “Tom,” he said slowly, “there’s always a way to kill vermin. Accio Diary!” He winced as the Diary flew to his left hand. Adrenalin does funny things, and he hadn’t realized he’d scraped it during his tumble.

The basilisk’s mouth was slightly open as the muscles relaxed in death. Harry jammed the diary onto one of the sabre-like fangs, right through the bloody hand-print he’d left on the cover.

“No!” Tom’s shade screamed, reaching out toward Harry, even as he doubled over.

“This makes five times now,” Harry said softly. The spectre’s eyes widened with shock and fear. Harry gave the bottom of the basilisk’s jaw a roundhouse kick, snapping it shut and driving a pair of fangs into the book. Black ink poured out of the monster’s mouth.

Tom’s voice rose into an agonized shriek as he writhed and twisted into nothingness.

Harry let out a sigh and turned back to the basilisk. He carefully pried the jaws apart and retrieved the shredded diary. He limped wearily over to his friends, even as Ginny’s eyes fluttered open. She sat up, coughing and confused, while the strength slowly bled out of Harry’s legs.

“Harry?” she asked, sounding bewildered and a little scared.

That single word shattered Harry’s control and he knelt on the stones next to this girl he’d nearly lost again. He didn’t even remember picking her up, he just realized that he had his arms around her, his ear pressed against her chest, holding her as tightly as he could. The sound of her heartbeat calmed him, but he still found himself babbling. “Oh Ginny, I’m so sorry. This is my fault, this is all my fault. I screwed it up again. You could have died again. I…” The feel of her arms wrapping tightly around his neck made him pause, and he inhaled convulsively.

Slowly, he became aware of what he was doing and loosened his arms. Ginny sat back down, but her hands lingered on his forearms. “You’re awake,” she said.

Harry nodded.

“That Diary wasn’t from you, was it?” she asked.

Harry hesitated, but still nodded. “I had it locked up in my trunk. How did you get it?” He noticed Ron and Neville exchange a quick look.

“It came by owl post a couple of days after you were hurt. The paper inside said it was a gift you’d ordered for me.” Her face coloured, losing some of its unnatural pallor. “I am such an idiot,” she whispered.

“No more than me, maybe less, even,” Harry disagreed. “You were tricked, that’s all. And Voldemort’s fooled a lot of people over the years.”

“Voldemort?” Ginny gasped.

“Tom Riddle grew up to become Lord Voldemort,” Harry explained. “He left a piece of his soul behind in that diary. That’s one of the things that kept him alive after his curse rebounded on him.”

“Harry?” Hermione asked hesitantly, “How do you know this?”

Harry let out a long sigh. Ginny’s hand squeezed his forearm, helping him come to a decision. “Your Occlumency was almost there before I was attacked. How is it now?”

“I can’t get through to anyone anymore,” Hermione said. “But you should try as well to make sure,” she added hesitantly.

Harry nodded and closed his eyes. He reached out and tested everyone’s defences, but none of them yielded in the slightest, not even Ginny. He supposed that was because she didn’t trust him anymore, but he deserved no better.

He let go of Ginny completely and sat down. “Might as well make yourselves comfortable,” he said, “this might take a while. At least we’re in an appropriate place,” he added.

“Speak for yourself, Harry,” Ron said with a grimace.

“This place is called the Chamber of Secrets,” Harry announced, “and if there is any place we won’t be overheard, this is it.”

“Until someone finds the rope, Harry,” Neville reminded him.

“Right,” Harry agreed. “Once there was a boy named Harry Potter. When he was eleven years old, he discovered he was a wizard, and he came to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry to ‘learn the family business’, as it were.”

Everyone was giving him some strange looks, but Harry ignored them and forged ahead. “Things went well and Harry made some good friends. But then, at the end of his fourth year, Voldemort’s minions captured Harry and used some of his blood to resurrect the Dark Lord. People began to die. Students, his godfather, Dumbledore… eventually the Wizarding world was consumed in one massive war.”

Most of them were looking at Harry blankly, or in outright disbelief. Hermione, however, was frowning until she let out a little gasp. “We all died, didn’t we?” she asked in a small voice.

Harry nodded slowly, not trusting his voice to respond. “In the end, Harry won, but it was awful. He found a way to send his… memories… back in time to his younger self. To stop it from happening again.”

“But Harry!” Hermione objected, “that’s taking an awful risk. Maybe he, or you, won’t win this time.”

“I don’t see how it could have ended any worse, even if Voldemort won,” Harry said tightly.

Ron’s face had gone so pale that his freckles stood out like beacons. “All of us – we all died?” he repeated numbly.

“Harry?” Hermione asked carefully, “If it’s possible to send memories back in time like that, why hasn’t it been done before? Why didn’t the Ministry use that to stop it from happening?”

“Well, one, because I came up with it, with Dumbledore’s help, of course,” he replied. “I never studied Arithmancy before then.”

“I thought you said he died?” Neville asked, shaking himself out of his stupor.

“His portrait,” Harry clarified. “It was about the only thing to survive Hogwarts when it fell.”

“Hogwarts fell?” Hermione gasped, but then caught herself with a visible effort. She fixed Harry with a piercing glare she must have learned from Professor McGonagall. “What else are you leaving out? Why are you the only person to send their memories back? Surely others would have helped.”

Harry took a deep breath. He knew Hermione would drag out all the details, and he needed to stop hiding things if he wanted to ever have friends again. “You can’t send anything physical back in time by this method – the best you can do is send back something carrying human memories. The easiest way to do that is to separate the soul from the body.”

“You bloody killed yourself?” Ron demanded, outraged. Hermione and Neville looked ill, while Ginny just stared at him, her mouth hanging open. Luna merely nodded, looking thoughtful.

“Sort of,” Harry admitted. “The future me arrived in the middle of my dreams one night after my eleventh birthday. He said he didn’t have anything left to live for. Once we… merged… I could see what he meant.”

“Those ruddy nightmares,” Ron breathed.

Harry nodded. “Most of them are memories from my future self, replaying as I sleep. I think it was even worse for him. I’m slowly building up memories and experiences to counter those. The five of you are not exactly like the people he remembers, and that helps, in a way.”

“We’re different?” Hermione asked carefully, “In what ways?”

Harry braced himself. Better to just get it out in the open now and let them hate him. Better to not have it hanging over his head. “Well, first time around, we weren’t immediately friends. I didn’t really get to know Ginny, Neville, or Luna until my fifth year.” Ginny’s eyes snapped up to meet his and it was all he could do not to flinch away. “Luna, you were originally sorted into Ravenclaw, but you really hated it there because you were being harassed by the Ravenclaws. I asked the Sorting Hat to help. Ron I met on the train, but Hermione, you weren’t really friends with Ron or me until after the Troll in the bathroom incident.”

“That’s how you bloody knew something was going to happen that day!” Ron exclaimed.

Harry nodded. “Quirrell released it to cover an attempt to steal the Stone. There was no reason to expect that not to happen again.”

“And when you got him at the end of the year…” Neville continued.

“Yeah, I knew what he was up to. But instead of the three of us fighting through the obstacles the staff set up to protect the stone, I went alone and ambushed him as he was sneaking past Hagrid’s three-headed dog. Fluffy did all the work. I’m sorry I lied to you all, but I couldn’t explain without Snape finding out, and honestly I only needed to cast one stinging charm to do him in.” Harry took another deep breath. “I also didn’t want to risk any of you getting hurt,” he admitted in a small voice.

As he expected, Ron’s face was growing thunderous.

Hermione laid her hand on his arm and he visibly collected himself. “Harry,” she said quietly, “you’ve been deceiving us since we first met, haven’t you?”

Harry tried not to flinch as her words struck home. “I suppose I have,” he admitted. “I knew some of what was going to happen, or rather, what might happen, and I acted on that knowledge. First time around we didn’t study martial arts. We never really studied defence or duelling all that seriously until fifth year. I wanted you all to be ready, to be prepared for what’s coming. I don’t want to lose you all again,” he concluded.

“But we’re not even the same people, are we?” Ginny asked.

“Perhaps not,” Harry said. “Maybe I’ve tried not to repeat mistakes I’ve made. Maybe I’ve tried to be a better friend, to be more understanding. Hermione needed someone to support her when she wanted us to take our studies seriously. I didn’t before, and that was a mistake. If we’d known more magic, maybe we’d have survived longer. Ron, the first time through I was embarrassed about my problems, and I shut you out. And then I was stupid enough to feel betrayed when you didn’t understand me or became jealous. Neville, Luna, I had no idea what great people you were until I grew up a little and got to know you both. I just didn’t waste time with my second chance.”

He looked at Ginny, and his tongue stuck to the roof of his mouth. He knew what he wanted to say, but it wouldn’t be fair to lay it all on her right now. If she asked him directly, though…

“What about me?” she asked.

“I ignored you for five years. If I thought of you at all, it was just as Ron’s little sister; until the day you laid into me during your fourth year when I was being a spectacular prat. I made sure not to make those mistakes this time around.”

Harry took a breath to continue, but realized that he’d run out of things to say. A lot of his arguments sounded like tedious self-justification anyway. “You’re right, Hermione, you’re right, I’ve been lying to you since the first day,” he said, his voice becoming rough. Hot tears burned in his eyes as he realized this was turning into his worst-case scenario. “But what would you have done in my place? I don’t expect you all to like it, but please keep doing the training, at least among yourselves, so you can stay—”

His words were cut off when Ginny slammed into him so hard he almost fell over backward. Her arms wrapped around his ribs, her face pressed up against his filthy hospital wing pyjamas. She was murmuring something that sounded like ‘you stupid prat.’ He felt a steadying hand on his left shoulder and looked up to see Luna. She knelt down and slid her arm around his back. Neville joined her, his arms going around Luna and Ginny. Then Hermione was on his right, tears streaming down her face as she buried her face on his right shoulder. Ron joined them a moment later, gingerly wrapping his arms around Hermione and his sister.

Maybe I am a bastard, Harry thought, maybe I’ve manipulated them as badly as Dumbledore ever manipulated me. Maybe I don’t deserve their forgiveness. But they didn’t seem to care. They held onto him like they were afraid he’d be torn away from them. He realized the front of his filthy pyjama top was damp from Ginny’s tears, and then he realized he was crying as well. Wait a minute, I don’t cry. I never have, not since… But I have them back, don’t I? All the way back. All of his friends were back and suddenly, he didn’t care. He let out a sob and held them tighter. He was shaking like a leaf, but he didn’t care.

Afterwards, Harry couldn’t ever exactly recall how long they’d huddled together. He knew enough time had elapsed for the worst of his tremors to pass, as well as for his legs to grow sore from the hard stone. His breathing was back to normal when Ron gave a start.

“Do you think they’ve contacted Mum and Dad?” he asked.

Harry felt Ginny, who was still hugging him, stiffen. “I’m in so much trouble,” she said in a muffled voice.

“No, you’re not,” Harry said firmly. “Older and wiser people than us have been tricked by Voldemort, including Professor Dumbledore’s predecessor.” The arms around him loosened as his friends stood up.

“Mum’s going to kill me,” Ginny insisted, looking up at him now. Her eyes were bright red from crying and her face was a dirty mess from the front of his pyjamas.

Harry smiled down at her. “Maybe, but only if she hugs you to death by accident,” he allowed.

“We’re still going to be in trouble for coming down here instead of staying in our common area,” Hermione fretted.

Harry shrugged as Ginny stood up, weaving a little until Ron steadied her. “We’ll just tell Professor Dumbledore ‘we had a choice between doing what was right and what was easy’.” His legs were so numb that Ron and Neville both had to help Harry to his feet.

“That sounds like a quote,” Hermione remarked thoughtfully, “who said that?”

“He did,” Harry replied, but then shook his head suddenly, “or rather, he will.”

“That’s going to get right confusing after a while,” Ron observed with a smile. Neville chuckled.

Harry laughed out loud. He felt so relieved he was almost euphoric. Well, he had hit his head pretty hard, according to Hermione. “You should look at it from my perspective,” he said with a smile.

“What does it look like from your end of time?” Luna asked suddenly.

Harry sobered a little, looking around. Hermione’s light spell cast strange, flickering shadows across the pillars and the ancient statue. “Okay, I’ll tell you anything you want to know, anything at all. But I think we should make sure we never discuss certain things where anyone else can hear. And I’ll answer any questions you might have, but you may want to think about whether you really want to know the answers or not. I won’t keep something back for your own good,” Harry vowed, his eyes hardening as he spoke the last four words, “but there are some things you might not want to know right now.”

Hermione looked thoughtful, and Harry thought her eyes might have flickered toward Ron for a moment.

Ron, however, had no hesitations. “Do the Cannons ever win the League Cup?” he asked quickly.

“Not even close,” Harry answered instantly. He’d been expecting that question.

“Damn…” Ron said in an anguished voice, “I see what you mean now about not wanting to know.”

“At least Quidditch games are sufficiently random that they don’t repeat exactly like before,” Harry reassured his friend.

“But Chudley will always be awful,” Neville said with a smile, earning a glare from their number one fan.

“Anything else for right now?” Harry asked.

“I think,” Hermione said carefully, her eyes roving from person to person, “we should all think about this, a little, before we ask our questions. If Mr. and Mrs. Weasley know about Ginny, they are probably frantic by now – and maybe the professors know that we’re missing as well.”

Harry and the others nodded. “You’re right,” he said, “let’s get moving.” He could still feel the tension bleeding off as they walked, but his legs grew steadier. He could hardly believe they let him off the hook like that. They were better friends than he deserved. He felt someone’s eyes on him and turned to the left, only to see Luna shaking her head. He frowned at the girl, one eyebrow raised questioningly.

“You don’t seem to like yourself very much, do you?” she asked softly, her wire-frames glinting slightly in the light thrown off by Hermione’s Lumos spell.

Harry tripped, and barely caught himself before he fell. You’d think I’d be used to this by now, he thought wryly. “I’ve had to do some things I’m not very proud of,” he said quietly.

“But for good reasons?” she asked.

“The road to hell is paved with good intentions,” Harry said thickly. He didn’t turn around, but he could feel eyes on his back.

“I thought it went to Bristol,” Luna said absently, “or was it Gloucester?” She frowned, pursing her lips. “Anyway,” she continued, “how can we be angry with you, if you did it for us because you loved us?”

“Er…” Harry didn’t really have an answer for that one. A set of tiny fingers wrapped around his right hand, and he felt a flush of shame. Ginny had just been through a horrendous experience, nearly dying, and now here she was trying to comfort him. Pathetic, that’s what it was. “I’m fine,” he said quickly, “I’m just a little disoriented, I think.”

They accepted that, but Ginny didn’t let go of his hand, so he wasn’t sure she believed his explanation. Eager to change the subject, he came to a stop as soon as they passed the split wall that marked the edge of the Chamber. “Close!” he hissed in Parseltongue. The wall slid slowly shut behind them, until the carved snakes met in the middle again.

“Why did you seal it up again?” Neville asked.

“Because there’s a dead Basilisk in there, probably the largest one seen this millennium. An apothecary will pay good money for just a bit of skin or some blood, so it’s worth a fortune,” Harry replied.

“But Harry, it’s been living in the school all this time,” Hermione protested.

“Yes, but we killed it,” Harry reminded her. “You won’t find many wizards willing to face one of those things, no matter what the reward.” He felt Ginny’s fingers tighten around his hand and he silently cursed his wagging tongue. He turned to the girl, who was looking horribly guilt-ridden. “It’s not your fault,” he reminded her. “That Diary was designed to do just what it did. You had no reason to suspect otherwise, and from what it said, you resisted it even harder this time… Tom knew he couldn’t control you enough to suppress your memories of what happened. Now, what I want to know is how that ruddy book got out of my trunk.”

“Er, Harry,” Ron spoke up as they continued walking toward the pipe, “someone broke into your trunk the day you fell. When we got back from the match, we saw that before anyone told us you’d been hurt. We thought you were still in detention at the time…” he frowned as his voice trailed off.

“I didn’t fall, I was stunned from behind by Draco,” Harry corrected, but he wondered.

He remembered going stiff as a board as the stunner knocked him out. Had someone else been there with a wand? That other spell practically guaranteed that he fell over backward instead of just slumping to the ground.

“I can’t believe I was unconscious a whole month,” he groaned.

“Longer,” Hermione corrected him. “Harry, you had a very bad skull fracture. Madam Pomfrey wasn’t sure… she wasn’t sure you’d make it,” she continued in a tight voice.

Neville nodded, adding, “She wanted to send you to Saint Mungo’s once you were stabilized, but Professor Dumbledore wouldn’t allow it. He said it wasn’t safe.”

“He may have been right about that,” Harry replied slowly. He didn’t fancy being in such an insecure location when he was helpless. At least if Professor Dumbledore was keeping him at Hogwarts for safety reasons, then he was probably also limiting who could get to him in the hospital wing. At least, he hoped that was the case. He noticed Ron was still looking a little queasy. “Is there more bad news?” he asked.

“Your cloak,” Ron said quickly. “It was gone from your trunk. We thought that was why someone broke in, we had no idea about the diary…” the red-headed boy’s voice trailed off.

Harry felt the muscles along his jaw tighten. That cloak was one of the few things he’d had of his father’s. “Anything else missing?” he asked in a low voice.

Neville shook his head. “Not that we could tell,” the round-faced boy replied.

Harry frowned. He’d need to make a thorough inventory when he had the chance. He wondered if the gun had been taken, or if the thief even recognized what it was. “Let’s get up that pipe as quickly as we can,” he said.

When they finally reached the large pipe leading up to Moaning Myrtle’s bathroom, it didn’t look very inviting. The slime and muck that coated the insides of the pipe made it far too slippery to climb. Regretting the absence of Fawkes even more, Harry suggested they cast lightening charms on themselves and try climbing the rope with their hands. With their weight reduced to less than a stone apiece, climbing hand over hand was indeed possible.

Harry urged them to hurry. He was fairly sure his transfigured rope would last a while, but it was better not to take any chances. Ron argued a bit about Harry going up last, but Harry insisted. Once his friend was a good way up the pipe, Harry cast one last nervous glance behind him at the tunnel and started up the rope.

He’d hoped he could steady himself with his feet as he climbed, letting them just slide along the slimy pipe. After the pipe narrowed a bit, Harry found himself dropping to his knees, grimacing as the cold slime soaked through the thin pyjamas and coated his skin. Despite the weight reducing charm, Harry’s shoulders began to burn, and he was forcibly reminded that he’d been confined to a bed for more than a month. Harry found himself questioning if he’d be able to make it when he felt the rope moving on its own and he was pulled up the pipe even faster. In short order, he found himself sitting on the floor of the bathroom, rubbing the soreness out of his shoulders and thinking ruefully of how much his next sparring session was going to suck.

“Are you all right?” Ginny asked in a concerned voice.

Harry nodded. “A bit wobbly. I just need to get back into shape again, that’s all.” He looked up at her and tried to smile. It must not have been one of his better performances, because she still looked a bit dubious. Harry took a deep breath and climbed to his feet. He grimaced. Every one of them was smeared with slime, front as well as back now. “Cleaning charms all around?” he asked.

Hermione nodded quickly, pulling out her wand. “Scourgify!” she said, waving it at Ron. A section of his robes was suddenly slime-free. He promptly returned the favour, and soon all of them were casting at each other. In moments, they weren’t exactly clean, but they were somewhat presentable. Dripping slime on the floors would no doubt earn a detention with Filch, though as far as rule-breaking went, Harry knew that would have been the least of their offences that day.

Not wishing to delay the inevitable any longer, Harry led them out into the corridor. There was no sign of anyone, staff or students, so he led his friends directly to Dumbledore’s office. If the Headmaster hadn’t been sacked, as happened the first time around, then that’s where the search would probably be coordinated from. And if Harry was wrong, Fawkes might know where Dumbledore was.

The empty corridors seemed to echo rather ominously. Harry suppressed a shudder as memories of the ruined and blasted but equally silent halls of another Hogwarts from another time intruded. This is not that place, he reminded himself as a rising tide of despair threatened to engulf him, and it never will be. He found his eyes wandering over toward Ginny, and he felt his heart lighten. She’s still here, he reminded himself, it’s not going to happen this time…

The gargoyle was in place, guarding the door to the Headmaster’s office. Harry was about to start listing off all the Muggle sweets he knew when he had a sudden idea. “You can communicate with the Headmaster, right?” he asked the unmoving stone. “Let him know we are out here, and I bet he says to let us in.”

Ron and Neville both looked at Harry like he’d gone mad. But a moment later the gargoyle moved aside. Harry gave them a quick smirk, but as he rode the moving spiral staircase up into the office he braced himself.

“The Board of Governors had heard about this disappearance, and, combined with the unfortunate incident last month, they are a bit concerned about how the school is being run,” a smooth voice said. Harry recognized it as belonging to Lucius Malfoy, and found his fingers tightening around his wand. “Your flat refusal to send the boy to Saint Mungo’s has struck many as an ill-concealed desire to maintain control over your little celebrity,” the man continued, “even if it should delay his recovery.”

“Now see here!” a voice interrupted, one Harry recognized as that of his legal guardian, Arthur Weasley, “Professor Dumbledore explained his reasons to our satisfaction. Harry’s getting the best care possible right here.”

“Ah, yes, and I am sure the Ministry will be fascinated when it is informed of your complicity in the Headmaster’s actions. There are many who believe the outcome of that hearing was wrongly decided, and are looking for any reason to re-address the issue.” The elder Malfoy’s voice dripped with malice.

Now at the top of the stairway, Harry opened the polished oak door and sauntered into the room. “You know, it’s truly heart warming to hear that so many people are concerned with my well-being,” he said in a casual drawl.

Seated near the fireplace were a distraught-looking Mr. and Mrs. Weasley. Professor McGonagall was standing near them. Professor Dumbledore was sitting at his desk, with Professor Snape beside him, while Lucius Malfoy stood in front of it, his face pale with ill-concealed anger. Dobby, wrapped in heavy bandages, cowered at his feet. With the addition of Harry and his friends, the room should have become a little crowded. There was still space, however, and Harry wondered if it automatically expanded to accommodate however many people had business with the Headmaster.

“Harry?” Mrs. Weasley gasped, then, “Ginny!” she cried as her daughter entered the office. She was out of her chair in a flash, jostling Lucius Malfoy roughly aside as she swept both Harry and Ginny into a fierce hug. Arthur was just a step behind her and Ron was nearly strangled as well.

“But… how did you…?” Professor McGonagall, not one usually at a loss for words, was nearly speechless.

“That’s a very good question, isn’t it?” Snape observed in an insinuating tone.

“I daresay we might all be interested in that,” Dumbledore said, “but perhaps we should first let Madam Pomfrey make sure their ordeals have done them no lasting harm.” His twinkling eyes shifted toward Mr. Malfoy as he finished.

Harry understood the Headmaster’s point, but the tale he’d constructed would work just as well on the former Death-Eaters. “I had some very interesting dreams while I was unconscious, after Mr. Malfoy’s son attacked me,” he said calmly.

“You dare accuse my son!” Lucius snapped angrily. “I’ll have you expelled.”

“I recognized his voice from when he cast the stunning spell,” Harry replied calmly. Then his eyes narrowed. “From the back of course, as he’s too cowardly to try it from the front.” He decided not to mention the possible other spell, as it might muddy the waters.

“We’ve only your word for it,” Snape observed coolly. “Draco has several friends who he was studying with at the time of the attack.”

“It’s interesting that you’d already checked his alibi,” Arthur Weasley observed. His voice was even, but his ears and neck were a dangerous shade of red.

“Of course he would,” Lucius replied, running a thumb over the head of his cane. Knowing about the hidden dagger, Harry knew the man was probably fantasizing about stabbing his nemesis. “It’s obvious that someone like you would seek to take advantage of the situation after this clumsy boy managed to fall down the stairs.”

“Mr. Potter was indeed struck by a stunning spell,” McGonagall corrected him, “and it interfered with his treatment until we realized this and neutralized it. But what I’d like to know is the circumstances that prompted Mr. Potter to return to the dungeons.”

“Return?” Harry asked, confused. “I was just leaving after my detention.”

McGonagall and Dumbledore exchanged a quick glance. Harry turned toward Hermione. “Do you know what they’re talking about?” he asked her.

Hermione nodded. “I was there when they questioned the Fat Lady. She said several hours after you left for your detention, you returned for a few minutes and then left again.”

Harry shook his head. “That wasn’t me. I never made it back to Gryffindor Tower.”

Hermione’s eyes widened as Harry’s implications seemed to sink in. For that matter, Harry’s brain seemed to be moving at a hundred miles an hour as he began to fill in the missing pieces. He looked up and locked eyes with Professor Dumbledore. Those blue orbs twinkled as hard as ever, but Harry didn’t feel the distinctive touch of the man’s Legilimency on his shields. Then quite deliberately, he looked off into the distance over Harry’s left shoulder.

Harry turned, acting as though lost in thought, as Lucius Malfoy again threatened to have Arthur sacked for daring to accuse a Malfoy. There was no one standing to the right of the door. Not that he could see anyway.

Harry always wondered how Professor Dumbledore could see through invisibility cloaks. It couldn’t be that easy, could it? he wondered. Then he reached out with his Legilimency and sensed a consciousness – right there, radiating equal portions of frustration and glee. An instant later his wand was up and he was casting a banishing charm.

He was rewarded with a thud and groan as some thing was slammed against the wall. Harry cut his eyes down toward the cowering Dobby and gave the house elf a quick wink and nodded toward a rippling motion in the air as something was pinned against the wall.

The air seemed to fold back on itself and suddenly Draco Malfoy’s head appeared and the hood of a cloak slid down as he struggled. Dobby rushed to the boy’s side, mincing from foot to foot and wringing his hands.

“Mr. Malfoy!” McGonagall exclaimed.

“You should learn to breathe a bit more quietly when you’re excited, Draco. I believe you have my property,” Harry snarled. He raised his wand until it was pointed directly at the boy’s face. “It’s a little harder to be brave when you aren’t stunning someone from behind, isn’t it? Now drop the cloak before I get creative.”

Thrashing and cursing, Draco managed to pull the cloak off and threw it to the floor… right on top of Dobby.

The house elf promptly disappeared under the cloak.

“So, thief,” Harry said scornfully. “I suppose you found some way to look like me to get access to my room. According to Hogwarts, A History, the doorway portraits can see through simple glamours. So that leaves what…?”

“Polyjuice potion,” Hermione blurted out.

Harry nodded slowly. “If you had it brewed already, you just had to cut off a bit of my hair and add it to the brew.”

“But Harry,” Hermione objected, “Polyjuice isn’t part of the regular Potions curriculum; it was just mentioned in passing, but I think the only book that has it is in the Restricted Section of the library.”

“One you should be quite familiar with,” Professor Snape observed in an acid tone.

“You’re right, Hermione,” Harry said, slowly turning, “Draco had to have help to brew something that complex… not to mention the fact that someone had to tell him the password to get past the Fat Lady.” His eyes came to rest on Professor Snape, whose expression grew murderous.

Professor Dumbledore’s eyes lost a good bit of their twinkle as he turned toward his Potions master. “Severus?” he asked quietly.

Snape let out a sigh and visibly gathered himself. “Very well. Draco approached me about a matter of some concern to both of us. From some… incidents… that occurred during the previous year, it was thought that Potter had somehow acquired an illicit means of moving around the grounds.”

Harry wondered how much Snape knew about the events surrounding Norbert’s evacuation. He’d even stunned and Obliviated the professor at one point to keep Hagrid’s secret safe. He supposed Snape might have reconstructed his afternoon to a certain point, and then reasoned out the rest. On the other hand, smuggling Norbert to the roof would have been impossible without the cloak. Harry was sure Neville’s memories had included them using it. So Snape probably knew Harry had it.

McGonagall’s fingers were twitching at Snape’s words, and Harry wondered what would have happened if she’d had a wand in her hand. Dumbledore’s face was very grave, and he looked every one of his years at that moment. “Severus,” he said slowly, “Harry’s possession of the cloak was known to me. His father left it with me, and I passed it on to him. With the… circumstances… surrounding him, I felt that he would be safer if he had the means to move invisibly, or to escape if it came down to that.”

Snape’s face grew even paler as his features twisted into a mask of outrage. “You knew he had it?” he spat.

“Yes, Severus,” Professor Dumbledore answered wearily, “and if you had shared your suspicions with me, this whole series of events could have been avoided.”

Neville let out a small sigh, reminding Harry that he’d never told his friends that the cloak had been given to him by Professor Dumbledore. They’d probably been worried that he’d get in trouble for simply owning it, present or not.

Professor McGonagall peered at the visibly fidgeting Draco, and then back at her colleague. “He didn’t tell you he found it, did he?” she asked with a wintry smile.

Snape drew himself up coldly. “No. He said he was unable to find anything incriminating when he searched Potter’s trunk.” His gaze swept the room, his eyes narrowing when they reached Draco and his father.

“You talk as though this was just a room inspection,” Molly half-shouted. “Harry almost died when that… that murderous little thug attacked him!”

“Draco was instructed to use a simple stunning spell,” Snape corrected her coldly. “Potter would, at the most, have sustained a bruise or two, were he not clumsy enough to manage falling down the stairs as well.”

“That happens when you get hit with a stunner when you’re halfway up a flight of stairs,” Harry explained, acerbically. “Funny how this whole plot was concocted with the sole aim of getting Draco into my trunk. The cloak, of course, was just a red herring.”

“A what?” Ron whispered.

“The real objective,” Harry continued, tossing the mangled diary onto the Headmaster’s desk, “was this.”

Harry watched Lucius Malfoy’s face out of the corner of his eye, and was rewarded to see his eyes narrow in fury when they saw the sodden mass of paper. “Your old master really isn’t going to be happy with you,” Harry chided him.

“What is that?” Arthur Weasley asked curiously. Harry couldn’t help but notice his right hand was hovering suspiciously close to his pocket.

“That’s the diary Mr. Malfoy slipped into Ginny’s cauldron when he ran into us at Flourish and Blotts. I was a little suspicious, so I took it out when I brought her books upstairs. It is, or rather, it was a diary that wrote back to you as you wrote in it, rather like an instant pen pal. I had a little talk with it after we arrived at Hogwarts and decided I didn’t quite trust it. It claimed to be a former Hogwarts student, but it never would give me a straight answer about anything.”

“Who did it claim to be?” Dumbledore asked in a subdued voice as he examined the torn pages, each as blank as the others.

“Tom Marvolo Riddle, that’s the ‘TMR’ on the cover. Funny how that’s an anagram of ‘I am Lord Voldemort’, isn’t it? After that, I decided to keep it under wraps until I’d sussed out a means of destroying it. It turned out to be fireproof, but basilisk venom seems to have done the trick.”

“How did you acquire basilisk venom?” Professor Snape snapped.

“From the basilisk, of course,” Harry replied blandly.

“Harry,” Professor Dumbledore said reprovingly.

“Yes, Professor,” Harry replied meekly. “The chamber contained a rather large basilisk. The, er, essence of Tom Riddle contained in the Diary was able to speak to it and ordered it to attack us. We ended up having to kill it.”

“How on earth did you manage to kill a basilisk?” Professor McGonagall demanded. “You should have died you the moment you saw it.”

“We knew approximately where it was coming from,” Harry answered, “so we kept our eyes down and blind-fired an awful lot of curses in its general direction. A sixty-foot snake is kind of hard to miss.” He noticed several of the adults flinch at his casual mention of the snake’s size, but there were other questions as well.

“But how did Ginny even get that Diary?” Molly asked.

“I got an owl,” Ginny said in a very small voice, “a couple of days after Harry… fell. It was carrying a package wrapped in paper and had a note that said Harry had ordered it for me from Flourish and Blotts. I was so worried, it was nice to have someone, er, something to talk to about… things,” she concluded miserably. “Today, I was writing about how worried I was and… suddenly everything went dark and I heard a voice say that if I was so concerned about Harry, it would send me to be with him. When I woke up again, I was on the floor, and everyone was around me and Harry was p-picking me up…” Her voice broke as she shuddered and Molly was hugging her again and smoothing the hair back off her forehead.

Harry wondered for a moment if it might have been better for her to go to the hospital wing, but then he realized that seeing the cause of her anguish confronted could be just as therapeutic.

“Were you disappointed to hear no news of attacks or strange happenings at Hogwarts?” Harry asked Lucius in a taunting voice. “Decided to get your son to see if he could get things back on track?”

“You can’t prove any of these ridiculous accusations,” Lucius said in a tight voice.

“I don’t have to,” Harry said lightly. “When your old master finds out what you did and how you failed, he’ll do things to you I can’t even imagine.”

“You are a delusional child!” Lucius snarled. “I am not going to stand here and listen to any more of this drivel,” he exclaimed. “I am leaving to make a full report to the Board regarding this insane asylum masquerading as an institution of learning.”

“Mr. Malfoy,” Dumbledore said as the man strode from the Headmaster’s office. Seemingly in spite of himself, Lucius stopped a step short of the door. “Please take your son with you when you leave.”

Draco’s eyes bulged comically and Harry had to concentrate on keeping his face neutral. Ron didn’t bother; he looked as if Christmas had come early this year.

“What is the meaning of this?” Lucius asked in a dangerous tone.

“Mr. Malfoy, your son has been implicated in the attempted murders of two fellow students,” Professor McGonagall reminded him, in a voice as chill as the polar breeze, “Surely you do not think he could possibly be allowed to stay at Hogwarts?”

Harry’s eyes sought out Snape, who for once was not defending his favourite student. Harry supposed being manipulated and lied to had silenced Draco Malfoy’s strongest advocate on the Hogwarts staff.

“This is an outrage!” Lucius snarled.

“Yes, it is,” Arthur agreed, surprising everyone. “He should be facing trial, not expulsion. Shall I call for the Aurors?” he asked the Headmaster in a firm voice.

“You have no proof to back up any of Potter’s web of lies!” Lucius shot back. “Bring this to trial and my solicitor will make a mockery of you. Then I’ll ruin all of you… those who aren’t ruined already, that is.”

“While Mr. Malfoy is correct in that most of this information has been revealed by Mr. Potter, I do have the means to confirm a good deal of it,” the Headmaster explained, his eyes twinkling once again. Harry supposed he’d sifted through Draco’s memories while they were talking, though it was hard to be sure when he’d done it. “It’s unfortunate that this other evidence is not admissible in court, but it’s more than sufficient to settle this matter to my satisfaction. You are both free to go, as long as young Mr. Malfoy vacates the grounds immediately. We will have his school things delivered to your estate.” The old man’s voice dropped in pitch and Harry saw a glimpse of the Dumbledore he’d seen at the Department of Mysteries.

Lucius had evidently seen it as well, for he dropped his hand onto Draco’s shoulder. “Fine, we’re leaving this disgrace of a school. Come, Dobby.” He looked around. “Dobby? Come!”

The air beside Draco’s feet twisted and Dobby slipped into view as he carefully folded the invisibility cloak that had covered him. He ran his thin fingers reverently over the shimmering fabric. “Got a cloak,” he said, his tiny voice quavering with disbelief. “Young master dropped it, and Dobby caught it, and Dobby – Dobby is free.”

Lucius stared at the smiling house elf, and then he spun toward Harry. “You’ve lost me my servant, boy!” he roared, reaching forward.

And stopped.

Because an inch from the end of his nose was the end of Harry’s wand, rock steady even with his arm at full extension. Five other wands were out as well, as a handful of children silently threatened to hex him and his son if they made another move. Behind them, Harry imagined the adults were reacting as well, but the immediate threat was already visible.

“You shall not harm Harry Potter!” Dobby said in a firm voice.

“You got that right,” Ron said.

“You’ll meet the same sticky end as your parents one day, Harry Potter,” Lucius whispered, glaring down at the Boy Who Lived. “They were meddlesome fools as well.”

“They died saving people they loved,” Harry replied, his green eyes boring into the Death-Eater’s cold grey orbs. “There are far worse ways to die. You’re probably going to discover one or two.”

“We’ll see who dies well, boy,” Lucius breathed, then spun on his heel and threw open the door.

Draco favoured them with one last dark look as he followed his father. “Be seeing you, Potter,” he sneered.

“Only if your luck runs out, Draco,” Harry said firmly.

The room was oddly quiet for a moment after the two left. Harry found his hand was shaking slightly as he lowered his wand. He jumped when he felt something tug on the leg of his pyjamas. He looked down and saw Dobby, holding the folded cloak.

“Mister Harry Potter, sir? Dobby hears that cloak belonged to Harry Potter’s father. Dobby mustn’t keep it,” the tiny figure said, holding out the cloak.

“Thank you, Dobby. But will this affect your being free? I mean, you won’t have to go back to the Malfoys, right?” Harry asked. He was pretty sure it was the symbolic act that was important, not retaining possession of the item of clothing, but he wanted to be sure.

“Oh no, sir. Dobby is free,” the elf reassured him, holding out the folded cloak again. “But Dobby cannot believe that Harry Potter is so concerned about a lowly house elf.”

“So, er, what do you plan to do now that you are free?” Harry asked, taking the shimmering fabric and tucking it under his arm.

“Dobby doesn’t know, Harry Potter, sir,” Dobby admitted. “Dobby didn’t think he would ever be free, even after Harry Potter said he would find a way. Dobby is very sorry Dobby doubted Harry Potter!” With an anguished look, the elf began wringing one of his floppy ears with both hands.

“Dobby! Stop that!” Harry snapped. “You’re a free elf; you don’t have to punish yourself anymore!”

“Dobby is sorry, Harry Potter, sir, but Dobby should have remembered that Harry Potter is a Great Wizard and Great Wizards do Great Things and even if freeing Dobby isn’t really a Great Thing, Harry Potter said he would do it and Dobby shouldn’t have doubted Harry Potter!” Dobby said, amazing Harry with his lung capacity.

“It’s okay, Dobby,” Harry said, kneeling down so he was closer to eye level with the diminutive creature. “I wasn’t sure I’d get the chance, but I’m glad you were paying attention when the time came. Now, what do you like doing?”

“Dobby is a house elf, and house elves like to work. But Dobby isn’t liking being owned, Harry Potter sir. Being owned means maybe having a family like the Dark Bad Wizard Malfoys and not being able to get away!”

“I can understand that,” Harry agreed, “I wouldn’t want to be stuck with them either. Can a free elf work for wages?”

“Dobby doesn’t know, Harry Potter sir. Dobby hasn’t ever known a free elf. Would a wizarding family be willing to pay wages to a free house elf?” Dobby asked in a voice filled with wonder.

“I don’t know,” Harry said slowly, “but I know I would. If you can’t find a proper family to work for, come see me and we’ll work something out.”

“Harry Potter is too kind, sir. Dobby can’t impose on Harry Potter like that—” Dobby objected, shaking his head violently.

“Yes, you can,” Harry insisted, leaning forward and lowering his voice. “You came to warn me, at great personal risk. Even if I suspected some of it already, you still took the chance. I like having people around that I know I can count on. So will you at least think about it?”

Dobby nodded, too choked up to speak. He bowed very low, then snapped his fingers and disappeared.

Harry straightened up, to find Professor Dumbledore’s eyes on him again, twinkling madly. “That was a very noble thing you did, Harry,” the Headmaster said in an approving tone.

Harry shrugged. “The Chinese have a saying: When you save someone’s life, you are responsible for what they do with it. I didn’t free him from the Malfoys just to see him starve or have someone else take advantage of him.”

“Well said, Mr. Potter,” Professor McGonagall said with a nod. Professor Snape merely looked bored and irritated at the same time.

“Ah, I don’t suppose,” Professor Dumbledore said with a slight smile, “you’d have any idea what happened to poor Professor Lockhart, would you? We found him, quite unconscious, near the hospital wing, along with a reporter and a photographer, neither of whom had permission to be on the grounds.”

Harry swallowed. “Er, I think they were invited by Professor Lockhart, based on some remarks he made. He was taking them to the infirmary to photograph me when we ran into them.”

Molly inhaled sharply, and McGonagall’s scowl was just as fierce.

“And how did he come to be in his current condition?” Dumbledore asked soberly, though Harry swore he saw a hint of a smile under that bloody beard of his.

“Well, he wanted us to abandon searching for Ginny so I could go back to his quarters with him and that reporter, and tell them what a brilliant teacher he is,” Harry replied rolling his eyes. “I said that I didn’t have time to waste on a complete fraud. He Obliviated Ms. Skeeter and her photographer as soon as they heard it. He was about to do the same to us when I threw up a shield.”

Professor McGonagall frowned. “A shield created those marks on the stones? What shield charm did you use?” she asked.

“Um, Protego Maximus,” Harry answered. “I was in a bit of a panic, so I pushed it as hard as I could.”

“Mr. Potter!” Professor McGonagall exclaimed, “How on earth did you learn a N.E.W.T.-level defensive spell?”

“I read it in the seventh year Defence Against the Dark Arts textbook,” Harry replied truthfully. In the future, Hermione had insisted the three of them continue training and learning spells to aid them in their hunt for the remaining Horcruxes. “It’s not like those aren’t for sale to anyone with the galleons,” he added. “At the time, I just wanted to see what the most powerful shield I could cast would do. It worked pretty well today, but it reflected Professor Lockhart’s spell right back in his face when he cast it.”

“I see,” Professor Dumbledore murmured. “Well,” he continued in a louder voice, “Ms. Skeeter and her assistant are recovering nicely, though they don’t recall anything that happened since they entered Hogwarts today. Professor Lockhart was a bit harder hit, and he will probably require some time at St. Mungo’s before he recovers.”

“I’m sorry to hear that, sir,” Harry said with a straight face. He thought he heard Ron mutter something quite different beside him.

Dumbledore nodded slowly, the rosy late afternoon light from the window seeming to strike sparks in his silvery beard. “Well, you’ve had a long day, Harry. All of you, actually… and you’ve done no small service to the school. I’ll be discussing the disposition of house points with your Head of House. In the meantime, Arthur, Molly? Could you please escort these brave students to the fearsome hospital wing? I’ll alert Madam Pomfrey, as I expect she will want to have a few words with them. There will be time for us to talk more, later.”

Harry allowed himself to be hustled from the Headmaster’s office with a sigh of relief that almost set his knees to trembling. As he passed through the door, he darted one last look back and saw Professor Snape, his features shadowed against the light from the window, the reddish glow making his skin appear even more sallow in contrast. His eyes were hooded, but the muscles along his jaw stood out in sharp relief.

Mr. and Mrs. Weasley were still a bit shaky as they led Harry and his friends to the hospital wing. Molly kept straightening Ginny’s hair or brushing at her robes. Harry supposed she was just trying to reassure herself that her daughter was safe. He was a little surprised when she squeezed his shoulder as well.

“Harry, it’s so good to see you back on your feet again,” she said. “We were so worried, first with you hurt, and then Ginny disappearing, and now… we’ve got you both back.” Her voice cracked a bit at the end, and Arthur wrapped an arm around her shoulder.

Harry glanced over at Ron, who was grinning at his parents. He supposed he should have expected this reaction from the elder Weasleys.

Madam Pomfrey, however, reacted exactly as Harry expected when they arrived. Ginny was immediately put to bed, while Harry and the others were checked. Harry, in particular, was closely examined. However, she did not order him back to bed, saying that he needed to continue moving around more than anything. She said he needed to counteract any muscle atrophy that occurred while he was unconscious. After a strict warning to report back if he had any headaches or blurred vision, Harry was pronounced conditionally free to return to the Gryffindor tower, after he changed out of the much-abused hospital pyjamas and into the clothes that had been brought down. Noting the traces of slime and muck on all of their clothing, she also required everyone who’d been down in the Chamber to drink a wide-spectrum cure-all potion, just in case.

Arthur escorted most of them to the Gryffindor common room, while Molly stayed in the infirmary to tuck her daughter in. No sooner did Hermione give the Fat Lady the password than an excited gabble of voices spilled over from behind the portrait. Fred and George were in the front, along with Percy, who appeared both relieved and annoyed at the same time.

“Ginny’s all right,” Arthur reassured his sons. Percy let out a sigh, but Fred and George didn’t appear too surprised, to Harry’s jaundiced eye. The other students appeared relieved as well, and a shout went up when they saw Harry.

In spite of himself, Harry cringed a bit at the cheering that erupted, which made it easier for the twins to pull him aside. Fred explained that with the altered Quidditch schedule, Gryffindor was playing the last match against Ravenclaw in a week.

“And if you can play,” George added, “that changes the complexion of the whole thing!”

“You know, Ginny could replace me at Seeker fairly easily,” Harry admitted.

Fred shook his head. “She stopped attending practices after you were hurt. I think Oliver would have cut her from the reserves if Angelina hadn’t threatened to brain him.”

Harry frowned. She must have already been affected by the Diary, he mused. “Well, I’ll see if I can get back in shape by then,” he replied, “but I can’t promise anything where Madam Pomfrey is concerned.”

George waved that off. “We know you’ll try as hard as you can. More importantly, where did Ginny go?” he asked in an urgent tone.

Fred gave his brother a rather annoyed look, but explained. “We, er, have a means of locating people who are in the castle, Harry. The exact mechanism isn’t that important,” he added quickly, “but we tried to locate Ginny with it, and it said she wasn’t anywhere on the grounds. That meant she was either outside Hogwarts, or, er…”

“Dead,” George added in a tense whisper. “When we saw you moving around, we were going to go and find you, but Percy was being a pain. While we were waiting for him to drop his guard, we saw you all enter a bathroom and then disappear!”

“Ignoring the question of why you lot were all in the ladies’ privy,” Fred added with a smirk, “We’re rather curious as to what happened. Especially since we saw all of you reappear in that same lav, only with Ginny this time!”

Harry knew they were talking about the Marauder’s Map. Come to think of it, it never occurred to him to wonder why they didn’t use it to locate Ginny the first time around, but this explained it. “There’s a secret chamber,” Harry explained in a low voice. “It’s not on any of the maps I’ve seen of Hogwarts. Maybe whatever you are using couldn’t reach down there?” He knew for a fact that the Chamber of Secrets wasn’t on the Marauder’s Map, but he didn’t want to explain how he knew about that. Not right at this moment, anyway.

George nodded slowly, but Fred peered at Harry shrewdly. “There’s more you aren’t telling,” he said slowly.

Harry nodded. “This isn’t a good time or place,” he agreed. “How’s your Occlumency?” he asked.

“Getting there,” Fred replied. “Snape’s getting rather hacked off about it too.”

Harry smiled. “Well, when you’re all the way there, you’ll get the full story, yeah?”

George elbowed his brother. “We’re not getting any prezzies before we well and truly earn them, oh brother of mine!”

Ron was entertaining their housemates with a very general explanation of what happened.

“You had dreams about what was happening when you were knocked out?” Seamus Finnegan asked Harry incredulously.

“Sort of,” Harry said. “Not exactly, but it’s kind of hard to describe.”

“C’mon, mate,” Dean Thomas interrupted, nudging Seamus, “Harry’s always had weird dreams. I’m just glad you’re back on your feet!”

“I am too,” Harry agreed, warmed by his dorm-mate’s sincerity.

“Ginny’s all right,” Hermione reassured Lavender, Parvati, and several of the younger Gryffindor girls. “Madam Pomfrey just wanted to keep her overnight to be safe.”

“But who kidnapped her?” Colin demanded, looking uncharacteristically angry.

“Voldemort,” Luna answered, in the offhand manner that occasionally drove her friends barking mad. Of course, the room immediately went deadly silent, except for a few horrified gasps.

Harry reluctantly spoke up. Better to address this now than let the rumour mill run wild. “Someone sent Ginny a book when I was unconscious, claiming I’d ordered it for her. It contained memories from when Voldemort was a student at Hogwarts named Tom Riddle. Over time, those memories were able to take control of her body and then take her somewhere isolated so it could kill her in order to steal her life. She fought it a lot harder than it expected, and she held on long enough for us to get to her and destroy it,” Harry said in a flat voice. Then he took a deep breath and his eyes hardened, “I don’t want this bandied about with the other houses, and I don’t want anyone badgering Ginny about it when Madam Pomfrey releases her. She’s had a rough time of it, and anyone making things harder for her will answer to me.”

“And after that, Fred and I will do things to them that Harry’s too nice to think of,” George added.

“If anyone has any questions about what happened,” Percy said in a loud voice, “they are to direct them to myself or Professor McGonagall. Is that understood?” The scowl on the prefect’s face was uncharacteristically fierce, and Harry silently commended the older boy. Ron stared at Percy, clearly surprised, while Arthur smiled at his often-prickly son.

Eventually, everyone settled down and drifted back to their rooms to get ready for dinner. Percy announced that the curfew would be lifted soon and the Great Hall opened for the evening meal. After a final word with Harry and each of his sons, Arthur left to be with his wife and daughter in the hospital wing.

By the time they filed into the Great Hall for dinner, the nervous energy that had sustained Harry since he awoke in the hospital wing was exhausted. And so was he. Harry found he could barely summon up the energy to chew his steak and kidney pie, and he was actually beginning to doze in his seat between dinner and pudding when Professor Dumbledore announced that Gryffindor had been awarded two hundred points for the incidents that occurred earlier that day – after a good bit had been deducted for being out of bounds, leaving the hospital wing without being formally discharged, and a host of minor offences.

Harry was a little dazed at this news; he hadn’t thought they’d break even, after the punishments had been assessed. The more distant relationship he’d been establishing with this Dumbledore couldn’t have helped, either. But if Harry was shocked by that news, it was nothing compared to what came next.

“I also have the sad duty to report that Professor Snape is leaving Hogwarts to pursue opportunities abroad. While he will be sorely missed, Professor Sinistra will be temporarily serving as head of the Slytherin House, while I myself will attempt to take his place in the Potions lab. Fortunately, as it is only two weeks until exams, that should not unduly affect the O.W.L. and N.E.W.T. preparations,” Dumbledore announced.

The Headmaster seemed somewhat taken aback by the reaction to this news. The Slytherin table, of course, seemed somewhat shocked and upset. The other three tables, however, erupted into a standing ovation. Soon students were standing on their seats and cheering at the tops of their lungs. Professor Dumbledore looked around, somewhat bemused, but Harry noticed him darting a quick glance in Professor McGonagall’s direction, who responded with what could only be described as a smug “I told you so” expression.

As the applause continued for several minutes, with no sign of diminishing, the Slytherin students began to mutter and exchange dark looks. Fortunately, Professor Dumbledore raised his hands for silence before things got out of hand. “I’m pleased to note how excited Professor Snape’s students are that he will have a chance to devote his talents to new research opportunities. I’m sure we will hear great things from him in the future,” he concluded with a perfectly straight face. His act seemed to confuse the Slytherins and defuse a potentially nasty situation.

“Where is Draco?” a voice called out from the Slytherin table, one that sounded like Pansy Parkinson.

“I would ask you to direct any further questions about this or any other events to your heads of house,” Dumbledore announced, and with a wave of his hands, the dinner dishes were replaced with a rather elaborate selection of desserts. Harry supposed it was simply good tactics to immediately distract the students with large amounts of sugar, but he could barely pick at his treacle tart.

Ron, on the other hand, appeared to be having the best day of his life. The red-headed boy was exerting a visible effort to keep himself from crowing over the dismissal of his most hated professor. Finally, he could bite his tongue no longer. “I can’t believe they actually sacked him!” he whispered to Harry. “You’re going to be a hero when people find out!”

“Let’s keep that to ourselves,” Harry cautioned him in a similarly low voice. “I’d rather not have the entire Slytherin house out for my blood.”

“Don’t they already hate you? And us?” Ron asked.

Harry shook his head. “The upper forms, not so much, which is a good thing. And with Draco gone, some of the younger ones might mellow as well.”

“I think you’re being too optimistic,” Neville muttered, leaning forward across the remains of his custard.

“It means fewer people I’ll have to kill later on,” Harry said with a sigh. “So I hope not.”

Ron swallowed and made a face. “Sorry, Harry, you’re right.”

Harry gave Ron a crooked smile. “I might not be above a little private gloating among friends though,” he admitted.

Ron chuckled as he took another bite of his pie. He began coughing and choking until Hermione handed him a glass of water. Harry thumped his friend’s back until he swallowed and took a deep breath.

“Thanks, mate,” Ron said hoarsely. “Don’t want to kick it before I can attend my first Snape-less Potions class!”

The rest of them laughed a bit, but Hermione just rolled her eyes. “Honestly, Ron!” she said, but her voice sounded more amused than annoyed.

By the time they returned to their dormitories, Harry could barely stand. He checked the damaged trunk, and let out a heartfelt sigh of relief. The Glock was still where he’d left it, under some of his first year books, wrapped in one of Vernon’s old socks. After re-packing it, Harry collapsed onto his bed, still half-dressed, and pulled the curtains shut. Sleep overcame him with the drone of conversation still filling his ears.

Ginny hated the hospital at Hogwarts – it wasn’t anything against Madam Pomfrey or her establishment – she had similar feelings about St. Mungo’s, or any other hospital. Throughout the year she’d done her best to avoid it. She’d been there in the autumn to repair a bad scrape from a sparring mishap with Hermione, and after the Christmas holidays to borrow some emergency supplies when her monthly visitor caught her unawares, but she’d avoided an overnight stay. But after being near death in the Chamber of Secrets, she had an impressive collection of scrapes and bruises, meriting what she dreaded the most: an overnight stay “for observation”, after her mum finished fussing over her. She hated the scratchy sheets on the beds, she hated the potions and she hated the smells of disinfectant and poultices and brewing potions, but most of all she hated the fact that she wasn’t free to go until Madam Pomfrey released her. She’d tried to sneak out in the first light of morning, but the doors wouldn’t open, and her wand was presumably locked up somewhere else for safe keeping. She briefly considered picking the locks, since Fred and George had taught her how while Harry was at St. Mungo’s the previous summer, but she didn’t have anything shaped remotely like a lock pick, and nothing in the hospital wing looked promising. So she waited, and fumed, and fidgeted, and fell into a fitful sleep as she leaned back on her bed, waiting for Madam Pomfrey to perform her Saturday morning rounds.

“Good morning, Miss Weasley, how are we feeling today?” Madam Pomfrey asked, nodding her head in a way that made the tip of her Medi-witch’s cap jiggle.

“I don’t know how we are feeling, but I’m feeling ready to get out of here,” Ginny replied, trying to put on a pleasant smile. She wasn’t sure if she was succeeding or not.

“Well, we’ll see,” Madam Pomfrey replied noncommittally, humming under her breath as she ran a number of tests, stopping every so often to write some notes into a mercifully thin medical file. When she was done, she nodded her head and walked away with said file, returning in a trice with a basket containing fresh clothes – fetched by one of the Prefects, no doubt. Lying on top of the small pile of clothes was her wand. “You’re free to go, Miss Weasley. Do try to stay out of here between now and the end-of-term feast, hmm?” she said, breaking into a smile at last.

“Yes, Madam Pomfrey,” Ginny replied, stripping off her pyjamas, never so glad in her life to see her camisole and pants. Supposing that the toothbrush on the nightstand was intended for her use, she finished her morning ablutions, promising her hair a good brushing when she got back to her room, but deciding that that level of hygiene would wait.

She needed to find Harry.

Harry, however, was not to be found. Although she thought she knew the most likely places (Harry was, after all, a creature of habit), she kept drawing a blank. For once, she wished it was not a Saturday, because she at least knew his class timetable. She stayed in the Great Hall long enough to chew through a hastily assembled bacon, egg and tomato sandwich on toast, while she formulated her search. Without looking desperate, she asked everyone she thought might have a clue if they’d seen her rescuer, but those students who weren’t shying away from her confessed that they, too, hadn’t seen Harry that morning. She considered going back to her room for a good cry, more out of frustration than anything else, when she ran into Luna.

“You’re looking for Harry, aren’t you?” Luna asked, in a rather direct manner.

“Do you know where he is?” Ginny asked eagerly.

Luna looked thoughtful for a moment and then shook her head. “No, but if I was Harry, I’d go somewhere where I thought no-one would find me while I wondered whether or not any of my friends still liked me,” she said, looking out the window at nothing at all.

“But we all said that it didn’t make a difference, now that we knew the truth!” Ginny exclaimed.

“Maybe he wants to hear it again, personally,” Luna replied. “That, or perhaps he accidentally inhaled a Bibbering Gimble-chock. It produces much the same behaviour according to my dad – he wrote an article about it last year in the double-length August edition.”

“So where would he be?” Ginny asked, not wanting to get into any discussions involving animals mentioned in the Quibbler.

“Oh, the Owlery’s a good place,” Luna suggested.

“Been there.”

“Then that leaves the Quidditch pitch, or the bridge overlooking the lake,” Luna said conclusively.

“Thanks, Luna, you’re a life-saver,” Ginny gushed, running towards the door closest to the pitch.

Harry was mildly surprised that he awoke with no nightmares. He was shocked when he stuck his head out of the bed-curtains and saw the sun already lightening the sky beyond his window. He tried to process the idea of getting nearly twelve hours of uninterrupted sleep while he composed his to-do list for the day. If yesterday was a Friday, then this has to be Saturday, right?

And then the events of the previous day caught up with him and his eyes snapped open. His stomach clenched at the thought of Ginny in the Chamber of Secrets again, despite his best efforts to prevent it. Was Fate that adamant about having her way? He and Ron didn’t use Polyjuice to infiltrate the Slytherins, so instead Draco used it to infiltrate Gryffindor. Was that just a coincidence as well? Was there any such thing as a coincidence anymore?

Harry ground his teeth in frustration. Then he remembered what happened immediately afterward. He’d actually told them… everything. And they’d understood – or at least said they did – and forgiven him. He was still having trouble getting his mind around that. The one he expected to be the angriest was Ginny, but she’d been the first to reassure him. He still had a mild bruise from where her hands had been when she squeezed him.

But she didn’t really know, did she? Harry asked himself. He levered himself off the bed, his sore muscles protesting, and lurched toward the showers. The hot water soothed his muscles, but not his doubts. After drying off, he looked out the window at the morning sky and dressed for flying.

Skipping breakfast, Harry slipped out of the castle with no one the wiser, and was soon back in the air – one of the few places he really felt comfortable anymore. His stay in the hospital wing had indeed left him rusty, so he began slowly, gently circling the pitch. After a while, he began to work the kinks out and began to fly a bit less conservatively. In seemingly no time, he was tearing up and down the pitch, diving and rolling, and engaged in aerobatics designed to give a bat indigestion.

Still, as good as the flying made him feel physically, emotionally he wasn’t getting any better. He’d avoided answering Ginny’s questions, the ones she couldn’t directly ask in front of the others. It was fairly despicable of him to use his friends, and Ginny’s residual shyness, to keep her from putting him on the spot. His only defence was that he didn’t realize what he was doing at the time, but now he did. She deserved to know. Harry couldn’t face himself in the mirror if he continued to conceal things, no matter how embarrassing or painful.

Harry was resolved to return to the castle and face the music, when he noticed a lone figure sitting on the stands. It was rather small, but topped with a mane of fiery red hair that Harry could pick out of a crowd of thousands. Instead of landing on the pitch, he descended toward the stands, landing next to Ginny. He dismounted and sat down a few feet away, holding his broom carefully in his lap.

“Nice weather for flying,” she said in a slightly strained voice.

“Yeah,” Harry nodded. “The match against Ravenclaw is in a week. I’m not sure if I can be ready in time.”

“Playing against Cho Chang?” she asked.

“I think so,” Harry said, nodding. “I need to be at my best against her; she’s a pretty good flyer.”

“Very pretty in general,” Ginny observed coolly.

Harry glanced at her out of the corner of his eye as he nodded agreement. Her eyebrows twitched a little – perhaps because she thought Harry was still looking out at the pitch. “She and Cedric make a good couple,” he added.

Ginny frowned at Harry and he turned in his seat so he was facing her. “If you saw anything after the DA meeting, she gave me a peck on the cheek because of what I said to Cedric when everyone was accusing Hufflepuff.”

The redheaded girl blushed lightly as she stared down at her hands. “Then you two never…?”

“In the future?” Harry asked, but continued without waiting for the answer. “Yeah, we went out once. It was a complete disaster,” he added with a grimace.

Ginny let out the giggle she’d failed to completely swallow. “I’m sorry,” she said quickly. “It’s just, that look on your face…”

Harry shrugged. “I’ll admit it’s a bit funnier in hind-sight.” He tried to remain blasé, but he knew what was coming next. She’d ask if they ever had a relationship, he’d tell the truth, and she’d hopefully just tell him he was more of a brother to her now. If she felt betrayed by his actions, she’d be hurt and angry. Harry wasn’t sure if either of them could stand being together at The Burrow if that happened.

He clenched his hands on his broomstick to keep them from shaking.

“I didn’t see you in the Great Hall at breakfast,” she said, suddenly changing the subject, to Harry’s vast relief.

“I didn’t much feel like eating,” Harry admitted.

“Well,” Ginny said, bouncing to her feet, “I didn’t have much to eat either, and they should be starting lunch soon. If you get any thinner, Mum won’t let me and Ron hear the end of it when we go home for the holidays.”

“All right,” Harry agreed. It still made him smile when Ginny fussed at him like that. In at least one way, she was truly her mother’s daughter.

They began walking back to the castle, side by side, Harry’s Nimbus balanced on his shoulder. He enjoyed the warm sunshine and the comfortable silence when the latter was broken by Ginny’s voice.

“Harry?” she asked, her voice little more than a whisper. She was looking down at the grass as they walked.

“Yeah?” he answered. It was easier, he supposed, if they weren’t looking at each other.

“We were more than friends, weren’t we? In the future, that is,” she asked, her voice catching a little at the end.

“Yeah,” he answered, steeling himself for her reaction.

She was silent for a maddening length of time. “Good,” she said quietly.

The two of them, witch and wizard, walked back to the castle together. Maybe Fate wasn’t such a bitch after all.

28

Conversations & Confrontations

Luna gave them a knowing look when Harry and Ginny came in from outdoors and sat down for lunch in the Great Hall. Even though Ginny’s cheeks were a little pink and her eyes were red, she managed to give her friend a small smile.

As they finished a quick meal, Ginny murmured to Harry that she had a few more questions. Harry just nodded and stood up. As they left the Great Hall, Ginny noticed Luna’s eyes following them, a small smile on her lips. When they reached the seventh floor, Ginny peered curiously at Harry as he checked to make sure no one was around a seemingly deserted corridor. Then he frowned and paced back and forth in front of a tapestry of a wizard being chased by trolls in tutus.

The third time he walked past the strange tapestry, she was about to ask him what he was doing when a door suddenly appeared on the opposite wall. Harry smiled as he pulled the door open. “We won’t be overheard in here,” he said.

Inside was a small cosy-looking room with two overstuffed chairs pulled up before a banked fire that warmed the oddly cool air. Harry closed the door behind her as she walked in, and she jumped a little when it disappeared into the wall.

“The elves call this the ‘Come and Go Room’,” Harry explained as they sat down. “We used it for a Defence Club to train people when the Ministry didn’t want anyone knowing proper Defence Against the Dark Arts. They sent this awful woman when Dumbledore couldn’t find a Defence teacher and she pretty much tried to take over the school. So we held classes in here.”

“But if she was the Defence teacher, who taught the class?” Ginny asked, “Professor McGonagall? I know Professor Flitwick was a duellist when he was younger…” Her voice trailed off as Harry’s face began to resemble a tomato. “You taught it?”

Harry shrugged and looked like he wanted to sink down into his chair. “Hermione organized the whole thing,” he said. “She sort of put me up to it.”

Ginny snorted in a way her mother would not have approved of. “Harry, you’ve been teaching us practically since day one. I shouldn’t be surprised you’ve had previous experience.”

Harry sighed. “I just wish it wasn’t always a life and death thing,” he said wearily. “It’d be nice, for just once, to teach something, to learn something for fun, and not because we want to see our thirtieth birthdays.” Harry stared into the fire as his voice trailed off, and Ginny’s stomach contracted as he seemed to age before her eyes. It wasn’t like he suddenly grew wrinkles or grey hair, but his eyes looked so tired it tore at her heart. She wondered what he saw when the nightmares came, the nights when he ended up cooking breakfast for Mum the next day because he couldn’t get back to sleep. She wanted to know, but hesitated. Would her questions open old wounds?

He’d looked so… lost… down in the chamber, when he’d told them his secret. She’d just woken from what she hoped was a horrible dream, her body wrenched out of her control and spirited away to be sacrificed to Dark Magic, but Harry looked even worse than she felt. He only spoke a handful of words, but each one seemed to exact a physical toll from him as he revealed the truth. He’d spent his life fighting the most powerful Dark Lord to arise for centuries, kept on going after everyone else was killed, and avenged them all in the end… and he told them like it was a shameful thing.

And she realized why he was ashamed. His destiny didn’t matter. His victory didn’t matter. Not to him. As far as Harry was concerned, he’d failed because he hadn’t saved them all. She remembered waking from a nightmare of her own last night when she was in the hospital wing. The sensation as Tom tore her body away and shoved her awareness down into the inky depths was not one she’d forget any time soon. As she laid there in the dark, wishing desperately for her wand so she could have a bit of light, she tried to think about something else, anything else.

Not surprisingly, Harry immediately came to mind. She’d been thinking a lot about him, even before he’d been hurt. But instead of worrying about his injuries, or the impossibility of competing with the perfect Cho Chang, this time her mind seized on one incontrovertible fact.

Harry had killed himself to come back and save them. Even if she’d completely misread things before, and he only saw her as an annoying little sister, he’d thrown away his victory, his freedom from that awful Prophecy, to save her and everyone she loved, her family, her friends, practically everyone she knew. That realization was both humbling and heart-breaking. It also gave her something to think about as sleep slowly reclaimed her.

His oblique confirmation of her hopes today did nothing more than strengthen Ginny’s resolve to do whatever it took to help him. She remembered something her mother said once… “A sorrow shared is a sorrow divided”.

“Harry,” she said quietly, startling him out of his reverie. He looked over at her, blinking, and she could see him retreating inside himself again. She frowned. She didn’t want him to feel like he had to maintain his façade with her, but she also didn’t want him to feel like she was prying. She swallowed and stared into his eyes. She finally blurted out, “What do you dream about at night?”

Harry swallowed and the light seemed to go out of his eyes for a moment. “I see you, sometimes.”

“Me?” she asked.

He nodded. “You were dead. Your body lying in the courtyard,” he said in a choked whisper. “While we were out looking for the places Voldemort had hidden pieces of his soul, he and his Death Eaters attacked the school. They killed everyone. We found Neville and Luna first… the DA tried to help, but they couldn’t stop him, no one could. Then we found you in the corner. You were all torn and bloody and it looked like someone had been at you and…” his voice broke and he turned away.

Ginny stared at his clasped hands, the tendons standing out under the pale skin, as she tried to sort herself out. She felt like someone had dumped a bucket of ice water down her back. Harry wasn’t just talking about the possibility of dying, he’d seen it and his anguish was palpable. She couldn’t help shuddering at the picture his words had painted in her mind.

The youngest Weasley took stock of herself and wondered what she wanted to do… what she could do. She could let things stay as they were, and wait for Harry to gather himself. She could thank him for his honesty and then let him change the subject. She could let things go back to the way they had been and pretend that none of this had ever happened.

To put it bluntly, she could be a coward.

She was scared spitless, for the second time in two days, but she wasn’t a coward.

Ginny made no sound as she stood up from her chair and stepped in front of Harry. He was working so hard at mastering his emotions that he jumped when she laid her hand on his shoulder. The knotted muscles under her fingers were trembling with tension, and his eyes were two wet red holes in his face. She felt like her body was moving of its own accord, giving her an uncomfortable reminder of the previous day, when she leaned forward and lightly bussed his forehead.

The next thing she knew, she was sitting crosswise in his lap with both his arms wrapped around her. Her own arms were wrapped around his head and neck, cradling the side of his head against her chest. This might have been horribly awkward if she’d been a bit older, or maybe not. Harry was shaking so hard she wondered if her weight was the only thing holding him in the chair.

Harry wasn’t the only one that needed some calming either. It was one thing to know that you’d died in some possible future. It was quite another to hear a boy you quite possibly liked break down crying when he described finding your ravaged and lifeless corpse.

Even as she tried to comfort Harry, Ginny wondered what she could do. She couldn’t imagine what it would feel like, having lost everyone she cared about, only to see them all again years later. It would be like a dream come true… except it didn’t change what he’d seen, what he’d experienced in that nightmarish future. A future only he knew about. A future he couldn’t talk about for almost two years. Put that way, she wondered that he hadn’t gone quite mad.

She remembered how upset he’d been after Peter Pettigrew had been captured. She’d thought it was the reminder of his parents’ death that had sent him stumbling into the orchard, but now she knew better. Still, she’d been able to help him, at least a little, that day.

So she ran her fingers through his hair again, concentrating on the hair above his ear, and along the back of his head, to remind him she was there. Then she asked him for the rest.

Surprisingly enough, he told her.

It went slowly at first. Harry waking up at The Burrow and contemplating suicide had been almost more than she could stand to hear. But she tightened her arm around his neck, holding him so close his voice was muffled by her robes. Then she asked him what happened next.

It hurt, hearing of how each Weasley died. They’d gone out heroically, for the most part, but she didn’t really care about that. Each new name, when it came out of Harry’s mouth, pierced her in a different way. She might even have found herself resenting Harry on some level, if his own pain hadn’t been so evident in his broken whisper and shaking arms.

There were other names, people she didn’t know, but whose loss had torn Harry as well. She’d only met Mister Lupin a couple of times at The Burrow, but Harry seemed to have been much closer to the man in the future. There were other names that she filed away to think about later. Oddly enough, it became easier as Harry talked about the horrific devastation of the latter stages of the war. Most of the people they cared about were in the forefront of the resistance to Voldemort, and thus were among the first to fall. Not that it wasn’t disturbing to hear about British Wizarding society being destroyed, and the American Ministry having to send a relief force to salvage what was left.

The end was surprisingly hard. Hermione and Ron ending up together was hardly surprising, not with the way they alternated between squabbling and staring at each other. In a weird way, she envied them a little. They’d had years together, from what Harry said, and had been with him almost to the end. But his description of Hermione’s death still wrung new tears out of her. The older girl was occasionally exasperating, especially the way she tended to tell everyone else what was best for them. Her mutely asking Ron to look after Harry was just so… Hermione. And as they both cried a little, Ginny didn’t think she’d ever get as frustrated with the bushy-haired witch again.

Finally, she caught her breath and voiced the last, hardest question. “Ron?” she asked.

Harry’s arms tightened around her waist. “We ran into a trap,” he said dully. “Voldemort had the last piece of his soul bound to an object called a horcrux. He used to have six, but we’d destroyed the rest. He couldn’t die as long as it existed, so he was keeping it with him. We’d chased down a rumour on where he and his little toadies were holed up, based on intelligence from a Death Eater the Americans captured. Only it was a huge trap, set for us.”

Ginny could hear the guilt in his voice, and tightened her arms a little.

“We knew it as soon as we felt the anti-apparition wards go up,” he continued after a shaky breath, “even before the Death Eaters arrived. We fought our way out of there. Ron was like a bloody lion, you should have seen it…” his voice trailed off and he audibly swallowed. “We sent them running back to re-group, but I’d taken a hit. A curse got me in the leg, and I was bleeding pretty badly. We were fleeing through a block of burned-out row houses when I had to stop. Ron was half-carrying me by that point. We’d both picked up some medical charms from Hermione. He got the bleeding stopped, but the muscle was going to take a while to heal. That was when we heard the reinforcements show up.”

Harry took another deep breath. His arms weren’t shaking anymore and he was sitting very still. “I tried to stand up. I really did. But my leg wouldn’t take any weight. That was when Ron petrified me. He slid me under a broken table and pulled my cloak out of the backpack. When he spread it over me, the only thing he said was ‘I’m keeping my promise to Hermione.’ Then he used a charm I’d never seen before… I think Hermione worked it out at some point. All I knew is that suddenly he looked like me. Then he said goodbye.”

“I didn’t see exactly what happened,” Harry continued. “I heard some shouting in the distance after a while; then the sound of curses. I know when he died though… that’s when the Petrificatus Totalus wore off. I limped along in the direction he’d gone, hoping I was wrong and it had just worn off on its own. By then the anti-apparition ward was down and the Death Eaters were long gone. I supposed they thought I’d sent Ron out as a decoy. That’s something Tom would do. I was limping so badly it took forever to get there, but I knew I was heading in the right direction when I started to find blood. I knew not all of it was his, and there were swatches of torn and charred black fabric around as well. I found Ron near an intersection. They paid a heavy price to bring him down. The bodies were missing, but from the remnants it looked like he’d taken out at least a dozen there before they got him. He was so torn up… if not for his hair I might not have recognized him. I hoped they’d been angry enough to mutilate him after he’d died, so he hadn’t been forced to endure all those wounds while he was still alive. I kept looking down at him, knowing that should have been me lying there instead.” Harry lifted his head and looked at Ginny; his eyes looked almost… bewildered. “It should have been me,” he insisted.

“It shouldn’t have been anyone,” she said softly.

Harry blinked and nodded – slowly at first, and then faster. “You’re right,” he said hoarsely. “Now you know,” he said. “I’m sorry.”

“Don’t be,” Ginny replied. She knew she probably looked as bad as he did. “I did ask, after all.” She looked at the distraught boy and cocked her head. “Thank you,” she added.

“For what?” Harry asked, puzzled.

“For telling me everything,” she answered. “Have you talked about this with anyone?”

Harry shrugged. “Some with Sirius; he got out, you know, out of Azkaban. He arrived at The Burrow over Christmas. He already knew Occlumency, with his family and all. But I told him the general shape of things to come, not all the… details.”

“Harry James Potter!” Ginny said sharply. “That is not the shape of things to come! We are going to do much better this time! You are going to beat that bastard and we are all going to help you do it!” she snarled.

Harry, eyes widened and head pushed back against the headrest of his chair, was a somewhat comical sight, but Ginny had no time for humour just then. Instead, she sighed and absent-mindedly straightened the collar of his robes. “I’m sorry, Harry, but I don’t like hearing you talk like that. And none of this is your fault, not Ron, not any of it. You and I both know who is really responsible.”

Harry nodded and his eyes suddenly went very hard. She felt the tension building in him in a way that was almost frightening. “Voldemort,” he whispered in a voice as chill as the grave.

Ginny found the abrupt emotional transitions a little disconcerting, but she supposed he had good reason. Once they knew the source of the problem, she was sure she and her family could help him. Better for now to remind him of ways they’d already succeeded. “You said they burned down The Burrow. Is that why you wanted all those wards built around it?”

Harry shook himself a little and then nodded.

“So that’s not going to happen again, is it? We’re much better protected now,” she said. She was a little surprised that Harry was still so attached to Mum, even when he hadn’t lived with them before. She also remembered what he’d written to her Christmas before last. She silently vowed to pay the Dursleys a visit when she was seventeen.

Harry nodded, a little more energetically.

“And the DA in the future didn’t get started until your fourth year?” she asked.

“Fifth,” he answered.

“So we’re three years ahead there,” she concluded. “He won’t know what hit him, will he? What about these soul containers?” she asked.

“Sirius is looking for them,” Harry said. “He was a little sick when he showed up at The Burrow at Christmas, but he has to have been out for a while.” He made a face. “I wish I could have introduced you, but Snape hates him like poison. He’d relish a chance to inform the Ministry.”

Ginny nodded. “You had to wait until we could block him out.”

“Yeah,” Harry said. “Anyway, I told Sirius where we found the cup, where the locket ought to be, and everything I knew about the ring and the other pieces. He should be able to round them up, saving the cup for last because of the alarm.”

“You’re years ahead of the game there too, aren’t you?” Ginny asked.

“Maybe,” Harry replied. “Something odd seems to be going on. It may just be coincidental, but things sometimes seem to be determined to re-occur, one way or the other. Through different means I come to McGonagall’s attention and still become the Gryffindor Seeker. Ron and I don’t use Polyjuice Potion to sneak into the Slytherin rooms, so Draco uses it to sneak into Gryffindor. I snag the diary out of your cauldron, and those bastards still managed to trick you into writing in it!” Harry flinched as he seemed to realize what he’d just said. “I’m sorry,” he said quickly, “I didn’t mean to bring it up that way.”

Ginny suppressed a shudder and shrugged instead. “It happened,” she said. “I’d rather you be blunt about it instead of tip-toeing around it like everyone else is.”

“You really are a lot tougher than you look,” Harry said, smiling the tiniest bit.

“This me or the other me?” she asked without thinking. Watching Harry’s smile fall away, she wanted to kick herself.

“There’s not much difference, really,” he answered after a moment. “I suppose I really do need a good telling off occasionally.”

“So are you saying you need me?” she asked, laughing softly and willing her voice not to quaver.

Harry looked up at her, his eyes directly on hers when he answered. “Yes, I think I do.”

“Oh,” she said, nonplussed. “That’s good then.”

Harry took a deep breath and smiled wearily. “I suppose we should head back soon. Everyone’s going to want their turn.”

“Turn?” Ginny asked – feeling a little confused.

“To ask me for details,” he said, giving her another squeeze before he unwrapped his arms from around her waist.

“I think you’re right,” she said as she stood up. There were no pins and needles this time; either that conversation had taken less time than she thought or she fit in Harry’s lap better than she had any right to expect.

As they made their way to the exit, which was re-emerging from the wall, Ginny stopped, holding onto Harry’s sleeve. When he turned and looked at her questioningly, she leaned forward, up on her toes, and kissed his cheek.

Harry froze. “Wh-what was that for?” he asked as his face blushed crimson.

“Do I need a reason?” she asked, smiling. “For answering my questions,” she answered after a moment, “for trusting me with the details and not holding anything back.”

For letting me all the way in, she added silently.

Harry shrugged as he struggled to regain his composure. “I just hope I don’t give you nightmares from all that crap,” he grumbled.

“Tom has that covered nicely,” she said with a grimace.

Harry scowled. “How bad was it?” he asked in a quiet voice.

Ginny shrugged as she ignored the way her stomach was turning over. “It only overcame me once, but that was pretty bad. I felt a surge as I was writing and I felt like I was falling, even though I was sitting still. Then everything went black. The next thing I knew, I was waking up in the chamber.”

“He said you were too strong for him to possess,” Harry said gently, “not and be able to block your memories afterward.”

“Did that happen… with the other me?” she asked.

Harry nodded. “Ron thought you were just quiet, what with coming to Hogwarts, and everyone afraid and trying to figure out who the Heir of Slytherin was.”

Ginny let out another less than ladylike snort. “That doesn’t sound like me, does it?” she asked with a nervous laugh.

Now it was Harry’s turn to shrug. “I didn’t know you before the start of my second year, er, before.”

Ginny sighed. “I suppose if I was some kind of wallflower first time around, then it’s your fault I’m different now. Right?”

Harry rubbed at his eyes. “Maybe,” he said slowly. “The way you talk now reminds me of how you were my fifth year, after we started to become friends. Any differences I see might just be caused by the fact that you aren’t so quiet around me now. Does that make sense?”

“I didn’t know the others very well either, did I?” she asked.

“Not so much. I never even met Luna until my fifth year. Can we just say you got a head start?” Harry asked, a little plaintively.

“That’s fine,” she said, “but why are you so upset?”

“I don’t want you to think I changed you,” he said quietly, “at least not on purpose.”

“Changed me?’ Ginny asked. “The only thing you did is what you said in the chamber: You tried to be my friend from the moment we met. Harry, I like this me. I don’t want to be some silly girl with a crush on a boy who apparently didn’t even notice. You said I gave Tom a lot more of a fight this time. Is that a bad thing?”

Harry shook his head violently.

“Good,” Ginny said. “I’d hate to have to hex you right after getting out of the Hospital Wing,” she added with a smirk.

Harry chuckled and offered her his elbow. She hooked her arm through his as he made the door appear with a gesture.

They were quiet as they crossed the seventh floor, heading for the Fat Lady’s portrait and the Gryffindor common room. Ginny didn’t mind, as she had a lot to take in. She found herself feeling a little wistful as she thought about everything she’d learned. It was a lot to absorb all at once. Not to mention destroying some of her more treasured illusions.

She liked to think that she was an optimist, and that things would generally tend to work out for the best. There was no way she’d have allowed herself to have a crush on Harry if she didn’t have at least some hope that he’d return her feelings. Hearing Harry’s story had challenged this worldview to a degree she’d have thought was impossible. Things had turned out so horribly that she couldn’t picture any way it could have been worse. Even the Boy Who Lived died in the end.

Ginny shivered under her robes as she wrenched her thoughts away from thinking about Harry’s future counterpart. She didn’t really know what it must have been like, how he had to be feeling after he’d completed his life’s work, only to find nothing left for him. The way Harry described it, he’d almost been happy to die at that point. As much as the deaths of her family, even more than the betrayal of the Diary, that thought hounded Ginevra Weasley, and she found herself hating Voldemort more than she’d ever thought possible.

She remembered Harry talking about the Killing Curse once, and how you really had to hate your target to make it work. The thought that in the future Harry hated himself enough to use the curse on himself was horrifying enough. But now, with all she’d learned today, she realized that it was indeed possible for her to hate someone that much.

Now she’d learned that things didn’t always work out for the best, and that she, too, could learn to hate, even to kill. Realizations like that had to be part of why Harry acted so differently… It wasn’t like you could learn such things and still be a child, could you?

Ginny slowly realized as they approached the portrait that her childhood had ended. That was why she felt so unsettled. There is a proper time and place for discarding childish things, and not-quite-twelve is a bit young for that. Then she looked over at Harry, his features settling back into what she recognized as his ‘public face’. He needs me, she thought. It was both a scary and a powerful feeling.

Maybe growing up fast wouldn’t be so bad after all.

Harry felt Ginny’s hand tighten around his arm. I can’t believe that just happened, he mused. He’d entered the Room of Requirement with the determination to answer any question she asked. He’d danced around things long enough and she deserved to know the truth. But still… when she asked such an open-ended question as, “What do you dream about at night?” his brain seemed to lock up.

But his mouth didn’t.

He sat there, almost in a daze, listening like a witness as he mechanically told her everything – the whole tragic chronology of the failed Second War against Voldemort. He felt, in a disconnected way, how she shuddered each time his narrative was punctuated with the death of another member of her family.

By the end, he was sure she’d break; sure she’d begin screaming at him, especially when he told her about Ron. His best friend had literally given his life for Harry’s, just so he would have a chance to fulfil that damned prophecy. But that wasn’t really why Ron had done it. He’d done it for Harry, his best mate and brother in everything but name, not the bloody Boy Who Lived.

Ginny had yelled at him a little after that, but only because he’d spoken like the future was a foregone conclusion, exposing his anxiety about the unusual parallels he was seeing between the two timelines. Her words, her righteous anger, her overwhelming confidence that “they would win!” seemed to have re-ignited something inside of himself, something that had guttered out over the last couple of months… choked by his worries about his friends, his enemies, and the future.

Harry glanced sideways at the girl walking beside him, her arm still locked with his. He owed her more than he could likely ever explain.

When the portrait swung aside, they separated and stepped into the Gryffindor common room. They found Ron and Hermione on one of the couches, apparently waiting for them.

“I heard you went flying,” Ron said quickly as he stood up, ignoring an annoyed glance from Hermione, “how did it go?”

Harry shrugged. “Like stretching after a long nap; I should be fine, if Madam Pomfrey will release me to play.”

“No headaches?” Hermione asked worriedly. “No dizziness or spots in your eyes?”

“Nothing,” Harry said, but then paused. “No more than usual, anyway.”

“Yeah, you’ve been talking to my sister,” Ron said with a laugh, earning simultaneous glares from Ginny and Hermione.

“So, Harry,” Hermione said brightly, in an obvious effort to change the topic of conversation and forestall the impending violence, “I understand you still want to take your exams?”

“I still say he’s mental,” Ron grumbled as Harry nodded. “If Professor McGonagall offered to let me skip them, I’d take her up on it so fast it would make your head spin.”

Harry shrugged. “I’d feel pretty odd, sitting around while you all sit your final examinations. I might as well participate and hope Mrs. Weasley doesn’t ground me if I do poorly.”

“Not much chance of that, Harry,” Ron said shaking his head. “You didn’t see how she fussed over you in the Hospital Wing.”

Harry felt his face flush with an odd mixture of pleasure and embarrassment. Mrs. Weasley tried so hard to be a mother to him. He noticed Hermione smiling at him, while Ginny’s gaze was a little more penetrating. He stifled a sudden sense of being exposed. Had he become so used to concealing the truth that being open with one person should make him so uncomfortable? Especially when it was Ginny, of all people? Maybe it was time to practise a little more honesty. “Well, she is the closest thing I have to a mother,” he said, “so it’s nice to hear that she really does love me.”

Harry felt his face colouring again, but that was nothing compared to the embarrassed blush that covered Ron’s face. “Don’t say things like that around her, Harry, or if you do, pass out some earplugs first. She’ll rupture your eardrums if she doesn’t break your back first.”

“Ron,” Hermione said in a disapproving tone, “just because some of us have more emotional depth than a teaspoon is no reason to become sarcastic.”

They both jumped when Harry let out a short bark of laughter. “Sorry,” he said quickly, “that’s not the first time I’ve heard that. Emotional range of a teaspoon, anyway,” he chortled.

They both stared at him for a moment before Hermione’s eyes lit up in comprehension. “I see,” she said. “Anyway, would you like to go somewhere to revise?” she asked. “I have my notes for the classes you missed,” she added, patting the bag hanging from her shoulder.

“I should go over my charms notes,” Ginny said. “And I still have a transfiguration essay to finish.” Her smile toward Harry was a bit knowing.

“That would probably be a good idea, Hermione,” he agreed. “I’ll see you for supper?” he asked Ginny in a quieter tone.

She nodded.

“Good,” was all he said, but her cheeks still flushed a bit. Sometimes it was fun having friends who were so fair-skinned.

Harry went up to his dormitory and came back down with his own bag. The sight of his damaged trunk still stirred up an undercurrent of anger that he tried to banish.

As he left the common room with Hermione, Harry noticed that she hadn’t even made a token effort to get Ron to come revise with them. He headed off down the hall, but stopped when Hermione cleared her throat.

“Harry?” she asked. “Aren’t we going to the Library?”

“I know someplace a little quieter,” he said, and led her to the Room of Requirement. He rather enjoyed the way his friend’s eyes bulged when he summoned the door. Inside was his idea of a nice study room, with a good-sized table, comfortably padded chairs, and a chandelier that spread warm golden light throughout the room.

“Harry,” she breathed when he finished his explanation. “This… this is fantastic. You said it can make itself into whatever we need?”

He nodded.

“We’ll have to start using this for our training,” she said, “especially during the winter.”

Harry smiled. “It can expand the perceived size as well, so we can run in here too. I’d have used it earlier, but…”

Hermione grimaced. “But Professor Snape would have found out and immediately placed it off limits.”

Harry nodded. “Probably while using it himself. Anyway, what are we working on in transfiguration?”

Hermione blinked for a moment, then remembered what they were ostensibly doing there. She reluctantly got out her notes.

Harry probably enjoyed this more than almost any study session he could remember. For one thing, he didn’t have to spend all his time making sure he didn’t appear to be too knowledgeable. For another, Hermione, usually so focused, was obviously distracted by some other questions she wanted to ask. He let it drag out until he began to feel a little guilty.

“Hermione,” he finally said. “Was there something else you wanted to discuss?”

His friend didn’t hesitate, and quickly dug a tightly rolled parchment out of her bag and tapped it with her wand. As it unrolled, Harry saw it contained a long list of questions, with a little space between each one. He couldn’t help but laugh a little at her preparations.

“Harry,” she protested primly, “it’s not that odd I should be prepared. I’ve had most of the night and all morning to think about what you told us. It’s very fascinating, looking at causation and how your efforts have impacted it. Now, you said your future self arrived right before you started your first year. Is it safe to assume that everything before that was congruent between the two timelines?”

Harry nodded. “I think so. I haven’t seen anything to indicate they were any different.”

Hermione jotted down a few notes. “Good. So what is the first major divergence you are aware of? And how did it go in your original memories?”

Harry began to speak as Hermione’s quill never stopped moving. She occasionally interrupted him to ask clarifying questions, but for the most part he did all the talking.

Just recounting the facts was making him start to tighten up again, especially regarding the Dursleys, and he silently blessed Ginny for asking him first. He didn’t think he could have answered all of Hermione’s questions if he hadn’t just purged a lot of his negative emotions.

As it was, he stumbled a bit when he recounted Hermione’s nearly-fatal broom accident.

“Is that why you wanted me to learn how to fly better?” she asked in a small voice.

“Partially,” Harry agreed. “You were actually pretty good after you practised a bit.”

The bushy-haired witch nodded gravely. “I’ll try to remember that,” she promised.

It was funny, in a way, how Hermione’s dry questions and factual dissection of the future disaster also seemed to help put things in perspective. Every time he went through what happened, it seemed to be a little less painful, like he was draining an infected wound. It was also easier to see the patterns that began to emerge. Ginny’s death seemed to galvanize her brothers, and even though they never blamed Harry, they did throw themselves into the thick of the struggle against Voldemort. He didn’t think Bill and Charlie would have been quite as quick to commit themselves to such dangerous offensives if she’d still been alive.

In contrast, Hermione became increasingly agitated as he continued, so Harry didn’t dwell on the details of her own death, only relating that she’d pushed Ron out of the way of the curse that killed her. Unsurprisingly, she didn’t press him for more. Harry couldn’t help but tell her more about Ron’s heroic death, and her eyes were shining by the time he was done.

She was quiet as Harry related his last year, fighting alone against Voldemort and his Death Eaters. Her fingers were white with pressure on her quill as she took down the names of the Death Eaters he’d recognized among those he’d killed in the ruins of Hogwarts. Then he talked of the scheme he’d hatched to feed false information to Voldemort’s suspected spy amongst the Americans, and how he’d finally caught the Dark Lord off guard and finished him.

Hermione began asking questions again when Harry discussed his recovery and how he’d stumbled over the Temporal Transit Field article and realized how it could be used on himself. When he mentioned in passing his ‘inner Hermione’ and how he puzzled things out by discussing them with an imaginary version of his friend, the real Hermione suddenly burst into tears.

“I’m sorry,” he said as she dabbed at her eyes with a handkerchief she pulled from her bag.

“Don’t be,” she replied. “I just didn’t expect… I knew you would have missed me, even if I am a bossy know-it-all, but hearing you say that… just… thank you, Harry.”

Harry blinked. “Er, right. Well, after I saw how it might work, I talked to Albus’ portrait and we figured out how to get the soul to migrate…” He glossed over some of the technical details of the time jump, and noted, with some amusement, Hermione visibly restraining herself from asking for more.

When he was done, Hermione looked back over her notes and began asking questions regarding their years at Hogwarts. Harry was grateful, as the early years, at least, had been relatively peaceful. Some of her questions seemed almost random, but Harry knew her too well not to believe there was a pattern to it. Especially after she tipped her hand a little.

“So as a part of the tournament, they actually held a Yule Ball?” she asked, eyes lighting up. Well, she was a girl, after all, Harry mused.

“Yeah, it was sort of a bother really,” Harry said in a bored tone.

“Really?” she asked archly. “I suppose your date was a bore then.”

“Parvati was okay,” Harry protested, “it was really a hassle though. All those people staring at us, not to mention Rita Skeeter’s articles winding everyone up. I think everyone had their nose out of joint before the year was over – even Mrs. Weasley was giving you the cold shoulder at one point.”

Hermione’s eyebrows went up. “I can see why you appropriated her quill at the first opportunity then. Just out of curiosity, who did everyone else go with?”

“Let’s see,” Harry responded and began ticking off on his fingers. “Neville and Ginny went together. I don’t think Luna went at all. Ron went with Padma, and you were with this Quidditch player from Durmstrang.”

Hermione looked up at him, a little surprised. Then she looked back down at her notes and asked him about the specific tasks used in the Tri-Wizard Tournament. However, some of her later questions nibbled around the area of social relations and who was dating who.

At this point Harry decided to have a little fun with his friend, if she wasn’t able to just come out and ask him what she really wanted to know. “Yeah, after Umbridge forced Dumbledore to leave, Fred and George declared an all out prank war on her. You sort of disapproved at first, but you came around when you saw a lot of the professors discreetly encouraging them. We had a good laugh about that at your wedding reception.”

“My… wedding reception?” Hermione asked. “To who?”

“Well, Fred and George, of course,” Harry answered with a broad smile. He chuckled and shrugged as his friend’s mouth dropped open. “We were a little surprised at first, you know, about your relationship, but you always preferred to do the modern thing… You seemed very happy with the two of them.”

“Both?” she squeaked. Her face had gone absolutely white.

“No,” Harry said straight-faced. “I’m kidding; but you were so busy trying to trick me into revealing something you didn’t want to directly ask that you fell for it. Let’s neither one of us play games; just ask me directly.”

Hermione swallowed. “Did Ron and I end up… together?”

Harry opened his mouth to answer, but paused. “Do you really want to know the answer to that question?” he asked quietly. “Won’t that take some of the fun out of things?”

Hermione frowned. “That’s not the reason you don’t want to answer.”

“It’s part of it,” Harry said defensively. “This is one thing where I am worried about foreknowledge screwing things up. What if I tell you one thing, and that makes you start taking things for granted, and then the whole thing gets bollixed?”

The bushy-haired witch’s eyes narrowed. “If you are so concerned about that, then it must be someone who is here at Hogwarts for me to ignore. And you’ve been subtly nudging me and Ron toward each other even before Ginny and Luna started. It is Ron, isn’t it?”

Harry sighed. “Yes, and if you screw it up, you’ll prove that old saw about people who are book-smart and common sense deficient. I will personally kick your arse if you hurt him.”

Hermione’s eyes widened at his vehemence, and then she looked down. “This is all speculative anyway,” she said, “aside from a desire to show up his brothers, I don’t even know if he likes me or not.”

Harry grunted. This conversation was heading downhill in a hurry. “Yeah, right. I’ll just point out that he did agree to take Arithmancy and Ancient Runes with us, after I told him you were badgering him because you wanted to study with him.”

Hermione’s face flushed. “I didn’t! Not for that! I mean not only for that! Harry, how could you?”

“He said yes, didn’t he?” Harry asked, smirking.

Hermione looked down at her parchment for several long moments. When she looked up again, her expression was merely cautious and no longer flustered. “Did we have a big wedding?” she asked in a small, wistful voice.

“Er, actually you didn’t have much of a wedding,” Harry said. “Things were chaotic, the Ministry was in chaos, there really wasn’t time, with the war and all,” he added quickly.

Hermione’s face still bore a shocked expression. “I’m surprised my parents didn’t object, war or no war.”

Harry blew out a deep breath. “Their neighbourhood was caught in a purge in ‘99… they didn’t make it,” he said in a low voice. “Look,” he added quickly when he saw her stricken expression, “I did bear witness when you two exchanged vows in a burned out Muggle church. They were magically binding, even. Left spots in front of my eyes for nearly a fortnight.”

Hermione was blinking rapidly. “What were the words we used?”

“They were pretty long,” Harry said with a shrug. “Tell you what, if the time comes and you are desperate for inspiration, I’ll get a Pensieve and we’ll go dredging for that memory. All right?”

Hermione nodded, her eyes still a bit bright. She looked down at her heavily annotated parchment. “I’ll get started on a general timeline we can use to compare with ours.”

Harry nodded. “That sounds like a good idea. You and Ron were pretty good at working out strategies, so you may want to get him involved when you get a better idea of what we want to do next.”

She nodded and began gathering up her things.

“Er, weren’t we supposed to revise some more subjects?” Harry asked lightly.

Hermione went very still for a moment. “Harry, surely you don’t need to,” she protested.

Harry shrugged. “We need to spend enough time here that people won’t get suspicious,” he explained. “Could you at least list the topics that will be covered? These exams took place a long time ago for me.”

His friend smiled as she dug out her charms notes.

Harry and Hermione left the Room of Requirement in plenty of time to go to dinner with everyone in the Great Hall. A few whispers followed them through the corridors, but it was hard to tell if they were muttering about Harry, who was awake after his coma, or Ginny, who had disappeared shortly before the entire school had been locked down.

Not that it really mattered. Harry sent pointed glares at the worst offenders and tried to ignore the rest. Ron also looked particularly murderous, and the back of his neck was bright red. From what Hermione had told him, his friend got detention while Harry was unconscious in the hospital wing for decking a fourth year Slytherin student who’d picked a bad time to crow about the comatose Gryffindor.

Ginny didn’t act like she had a care in the world, and Harry envied her aplomb. Luna maintained an equally clueless façade. Maybe. Neville, on the other hand, seemed to be channelling his grandmother, and looked down his nose with extreme scorn at the students who did not meet his standards of acceptable behaviour.

One glance at his friend even jarred Ron out of his sour mood. As they sat down in their usual places, he whispered, “That’s bloody brilliant, Neville.”

The stocky boy shrugged. “Luna suggested it. She said if it intimidated me, it should work really well on others. It’s sort of fun, really, being on the other side of that.”

Harry also wondered if it would make such glares from Madam Longbottom a bit less effective on her grandson. He gave Luna a quick smile, but she didn’t seem to notice.

While they were waiting for the food to be served, Harry’s eyes were drawn toward the Slytherin table. Melissa Bulstrode wasn’t hard to recognize, and she seemed to be involved in an argument with a smaller boy who also had a prefect’s badge on his robes. The words were too quiet to hear, but from the boy’s posture and clenched fists, Harry didn’t doubt he’d have attacked Melissa if she wasn’t head and shoulders taller than he was.

The stalemate was broken when Professor Sinistra descended from the high table. Her face was set in a disapproving expression as she spoke to the two prefects. Abruptly she scowled and seemed to speak sharply. With a muted clatter, the emeralds in the Slytherin hourglass shifted to show they’d just lost ten house points.

The male prefect’s face purpled and he spat something angrily. Professor Sinistra spoke again and Slytherin lost another twenty points. The boy seemed on the verge of apoplexy when Professor Sinistra reached out and plucked the prefect badge from his robes.

“Never thought I’d see that,” Ron said in a low undertone. He was too shocked to openly gloat about the lost points, for which Harry was quietly grateful.

As Professor Sinistra returned to the high table, the air above the plates wavered and the students were suddenly distracted by the presence of their evening meal. Harry tried to relax and enjoy the first meal he’d eaten with his friends in a while, but it still felt a little odd not to have Snape glowering at them from the high table.

A nudge in his side jolted him out of his thoughts, and he looked over at Ginny, who was passing him the mashed potatoes. “I’m not getting lectured by Mum if I can help it, so we’ve only got a week to get you fattened up a bit,” she said primly.

Harry smiled at her and scooped some of the starchy mass onto his plate. He put that down and grabbed a platter loaded with steaks still smoking from being grilled. He slid one off onto Ginny’s plate before taking three for himself and passing the platter to Neville. Hermione nagged Ron, whose plate was already loaded with meat and jacket potatoes, into taking some of the vegetable medley.

He was healthy, his friends were alive, he’d told them his secrets and none of them cared. It was good to be alive, Harry reflected as he dug into his meal.

It was over an hour later that they returned to the Gryffindor tower. Harry was a little on edge, knowing Ron and Neville would want their turns as well. He wasn’t sure about Luna – which was nothing new.

After a single game of chess, which he of course lost since he was playing Ron, Harry yawned and said he was making an early night of it.

Ginny, who was still reading her charms textbook, smiled as Ron and Neville both said they were going to turn in as well.

Harry pondered his options as they ascended the stairs. Dean and Seamus usually stayed up fairly late on weekend nights, so they’d have a little time to talk, even if their dormitory wasn’t quite as secure as the Room of Requirement.

He decided to go through his usual evening routine, and was putting on his pyjamas before Ron spoke up.

“Did Hermione put you through the third degree?” Ron asked.

Harry straightened as he buttoned up the front of his shirt. “Yeah,” he said after a moment.

Ron stared at him. “You’re pretty calm about it. I figure she’d have worn you to a frazzle by now.”

Harry shrugged. “She has a right to know. So do you.”

Ron looked thoughtful as he sat down on his bed. “I can wait,” he said. “If you and Hermione know what’s coming, you’ll let us know when we need to. I also don’t have to worry about letting something slip.”

Harry stared at Ron, who fortunately didn’t notice.

“It’s a little like chess, innit?” Ron asked in a thoughtful voice. “When you are trying to anticipate your opponent’s moves, if you change one move in a sequence, they do something different, and it throws everything else off. You’ve been making a lot of changes, haven’t you?”

Harry nodded.

“Then it’s going to be ruddy complicated. We can talk about it later, back at The Burrow,” Ron said. “Er, V-Voldemort isn’t likely to attack before end of term, is he?”

“No, Ron,” Harry said with a laugh. Then he turned toward Neville, who’d just finished brushing his teeth.

“I talked to Luna,” the round-faced boy said. “We both know it was pretty bad, but you told us almost the minute you knew you could. She said we should trust you, and I agree.”

Harry had to clear his throat before he could speak again. “Thanks mate.”

“It’s not like Hermione doesn’t trust you,” Ron said quickly. “She just can’t stand to not know something, and she may not be around much this summer if her parents take her on holiday.” Ron didn’t look particularly happy about that, but Harry decided not to mention it. “You know how she is about summer homework,” Ron added with a grin.

Harry shrugged. “It’s all right. She might be able to see a pattern in things that I can’t. She’s clever, and she’s bound to be more objective. I actually feel better with her fully in the know.”

Ron nodded as he swung his legs up on the bed and lay down. “She is a bit frightening when she sinks her teeth into something. Even Percy doesn’t get as focused as she does.” He smiled up at the canopy as he stretched out and folded his hands behind his head.

Harry blew out the candle as he climbed into his own bed. Neville followed suit and soon the room was lit only by the moonlight filtering through the window.

“Harry,” Ron asked after a moment.

“Yeah?”

“Am I wasting my time going out for Quidditch? Should I just focus on other things?” Ron didn’t succeed in keeping all of the tension out of his voice.

“Only if you don’t want to play Keeper after Oliver leaves,” Harry replied. He wondered if Ron could see his smile in the moonlit gloom.

“Was I any good?” Ron asked in a very small voice.

“After your first few games, they started singing songs about you,” Harry replied. Then he cleared his voice and softly began to sing:

Weasley is our King,

Weasley is our King,

He didn’t let the Quaffle in,

Weasley is our King.

Weasley can save anything,

He never leaves a single ring,

That’s why Gryffindors all sing:

Weasley is our King.

“They sang that?” Ron asked in an awed voice, “about me?”

“They did,” Harry assured him. “When you were on your game you were bloody near impossible to score on. If things had turned out differently, you might have gone pro.”

“That’s brilliant,” Ron whispered.

“No, you were brilliant,” Harry corrected him.

Harry didn’t know it was possible to hear someone smiling.

The next morning, Harry resumed his interrupted training routine. While Madam Pomfrey’s salves had prevented atrophy of his major muscle groups, Harry had still spent a long time on his back. He was forcibly reminded of this during the morning run, which he finished lagging well behind his friends. When they sparred, his reactions all seemed a half-second slow, so he gave up in disgust and just worked on his katas until everyone was ready to go in.

At breakfast, a nondescript owl dropped a letter on Harry’s plate. Harry tossed it a bit of sausage and discreetly waved his wand over the parchment, something he usually did when he didn’t recognize the owl. Nothing seemed amiss, so he broke the seal and read the message within:

Some of my colleagues are taking certain personnel changes quite seriously and are seeking to address their grievances with someone they believe to be responsible. Other elements would rather make sure that a certain injured player does not become healthy enough to participate. Even if they have no prayer of winning the Cup, they’d rather take steps to ensure you don’t. Watch your arse.

—Your favourite prank victim

Harry frowned and slipped the folded parchment into his pocket.

“What is it?” Ginny asked him.

“Slytherin is gunning for me,” he said in a low voice.

“So what else is new?” Ron asked, scowling.

“Aside from avenging their former Head of House, they are looking to make sure I don’t play against Ravenclaw,” Harry added dryly.

“Those bloody bastards!” Ron spat.

“Ron!” Hermione barked. “Language!”

“But this is Quidditch!” he protested.

“No,” his sister corrected, “this is Harry!”

“Could we possibly keep it down to a dull roar?” Harry asked plaintively. Some of the Gryffindors were eyeing them curiously.

“Sorry,” all three of them muttered simultaneously, causing Neville to choke on his pumpkin juice. Harry snorted and shook his head.

After Neville wiped his mouth with his napkin, he frowned. “So what do we do about this?”

“We could talk to Professor McGonagall,” Hermione suggested.

“After we hex any Slytherins that look twice at Harry,” Ron growled.

“I’m not letting Harry out of my bloody sight,” Ginny grumbled.

“Might get a bit tricky in the loo,” Harry whispered, making her blush and laugh. His emotional rollercoaster was still on an upswing, and after all, it was only a threat against him, personally.

“You know, no one has ever caught a Crumple-Horned Snorkack before,” Luna said dreamily. “Father thinks it’s because they are far smarter than people like to believe. When they see an expedition show up, with their baits and their traps and their nets, they just vacate the area until it leaves.”

Ron and Hermione stared at the blonde Gryffindor like she’d grown an extra head for the fun of it.

Neville, frowning as he scratched the side of his head, suddenly straightened up in his seat. “You mean instead of taking obvious precautions, we should be more subtle?”

“If you think the average Slytherin is as clever as a Crumple-Horned Snorkack, then I think we should,” Luna replied.

“So we bait the trap,” Harry said in a quiet voice, “and let them set up an ambush. Only the ambush gets sprung on them.”

“Bait?” Neville asked.

“Me,” Harry answered with a shrug.

“Absolutely not,” Ginny said firmly. “Not alone anyway.”

“She actually has a point,” Ron said thoughtfully, ignoring the glare from his sister. “We don’t usually leave you alone much, especially not since you were hurt. They’d smell a trap a mile away if you were wandering around by yourself. And the best time I could think of to set up an ambush is one of those times when we’re all together.”

“When no adults are around… After our morning exercises?” Hermione asked in a very quiet voice.

That conversation set the tone for the rest of the week. Harry rejoined his classes with nary a stumble, given that his missed assignments had been waived at the headmaster’s request. He was able to follow the final lessons of the term, sitting his examinations without much difficulty, and brazenly gave Hermione credit for telling him where they were in the textbooks. It wasn’t his fault if people assumed she’d done a lot more than that.

To make the bait a little sweeter, they stopped practising spell work during their morning practices, and made sure their wands were concealed from casual observers until they were getting dressed for classes. Harry found the wand-holster he’d received for Christmas particularly useful.

At Ron’s suggestion, they also went a bit easier on the physical training. It rankled a bit, but Harry recognized his friend’s reasoning. It would be better, in the event of a confrontation, if their hands were steady and their breathing was not laboured.

Of course, Harry still pushed himself a bit. He still had to convince Madam Pomfrey that he’d be fit to fly for the match. It would be a rather painful sort of irony if his preparation to avoid being knocked out of competing resulted in him not being able to play anyway.

That thought made him wonder if the note had been a bluff, possibly sent by someone else, but he quickly dismissed the thought. There were details included that only he and Melissa knew. Given her venomous hatred of Marcus Flint, Harry also doubted she would do anything to help her housemates, quidditch-wise.

By Thursday morning, though, Harry was starting to wonder. Had he misinterpreted the note? Did the Slytherins have an attack of good sense? Had they accidentally tipped their hand? Those thoughts were unwelcome companions as they ran along the lakeshore. It was almost a relief as they returned to the castle and several figures in hooded cloaks stepped out of the early-morning shadows of the courtyard. A muted boom echoed from the depths of the castle and Harry had little doubt that Argus Filch would be rather distracted for the next few minutes.

“We know what you did, Potter,” one of the figures said, its voice rasping and echoing hollowly. Harry was surprised for a moment, but then realized that it was a charm – the Slytherins didn’t want their voices being recognized. It was a relief, in an odd way: they obviously weren’t intending to kill them all in cold blood if they were worried about witnesses.

“What I did isn’t as important as what I’m about to do,” Harry snarled and suddenly his wand was in his hand. “Protego Maximus!” he yelled as the first curses arced toward them. The shimmering wall appeared before them, and the Slytherin spells began to ricochet back into the courtyard at crazy angles.

Harry easily held the shield as his friends quietly pulled out their wands. He kept a close eye out for the Unforgivable curses or anything else he couldn’t block, but he didn’t think they’d resort to those. As it was, sparks and bouncing rays of light filled the dewy air and left faint scorch marks on the weathered stone.

“I count seven of them,” Ron said, blinking at a particularly bright flash of light as a curse dissipated against Harry’s shield charm. “Call your targets, counting from the left. I got one.”

“Four,” Hermione hissed, sighting down her wand at one of the smaller figures.

“Five,” Neville said.

“Seven,” Luna said, her voice showing no signs of distraction at the moment.

“Two and three are close together,” Ginny said in an uncharacteristically grim voice, “I’ll see if I can get them both.”

“Then I’ll target on six after I drop the shield,” Harry agreed. “Remember to scatter when it drops.”

They nodded and touched their wands to each ear. Harry copied their gesture with a grin.

Harry watched the volume of incoming fire, waiting for it to falter. Continuous spell casting required a lot of energy, especially if you were throwing curses and trying to batter down someone else’s shield. A moment later, the flashes of magic subsided. A couple of the cloaked figures were still casting, but most of them were moving to each side, trying to reach a position from where they could shoot around his barrier.

Harry dropped to one knee and raised his wand, letting the barrier dissipate almost immediately. He saw his friends scatter soundlessly, firing spells he couldn’t hear. Then he brought his wand back down in a slashing motion toward target number six and shouted, “Concussus!”

A sphere of air seemed to shimmer in the middle of the courtyard, contracting sharply and then exploding outward. A visible ripple in the air reached them and his skull rang with the sound of an explosion – the only thing he’d heard, aside from his own voice, since charming his ears to block out all sounds.

The cloaked figure near the epicentre of the detonation was picked up and flung bodily into the air. The others, many of whom were stunned, bound in ropes, petrified, or being attacked by animated mucus, were also knocked to the ground. A final volley of stunners from the Gryffindor students put most of them out of their misery.

Harry tapped his ears to restore his hearing, just in time to hear Hermione say something under her breath that was highly out of character. He looked at her in confusion, but then followed the direction in which she was pointing.

Several of the windows facing onto the entrance yard now had significant cracks, and a few were completely missing panes of glass.

“Bugger,” was all Harry could say as the front doors opened.

As they all stood in the Headmaster’s office for the second time in less than a week, Harry was trying to figure out if the old man was more amused than angry about the damage to the school. His friends were a lot easier to read; they were petrified. As soon as Harry explained that he’d cast the spell that created that thunderous detonation, the attention was focused primarily on him.

“I got the idea from a muggle device I saw on the telly,” he explained. “It’s called a Flash-Bang, basically a small bomb that just makes a very bright flash and a very loud sound. They use it to disable people without killing them, sir.” The American War-mages had not been averse to using Muggle technology to gain an advantage in a fight.

“So you took a regular noisemaking spell and…?” The headmaster asked, his eyes twinkling again.

Harry shrugged. “I cast it a lot harder than what it takes for a simple noise-maker, so that stepped up the output a bit.”

“A bit,” Professor McGonagall said in a very chill voice. “Enough to shatter twenty-three panes of glass and damage a dozen more.”

Harry scowled. “We were defending ourselves from an unprovoked attack.”

“That is what you say, Mr. Potter,” Professor Sinistra replied calmly. “We will see what my students say when they are released from the Hospital Wing.”

Harry nodded politely. “I understand that you have to be their advocate in these circumstances, but it might be interesting to ask them why they were up at that hour wearing hooded cloaks and using voice-altering charms.”

“I will,” the dark-haired woman responded, “as soon as Madam Pomfrey has regrown their eardrums and they can hear the question.”

“Which brings us back to my point, Mr. Potter,” Professor McGonagall continued. “Don’t you think your response to this situation might have been a bit extreme? Seven students are in the Hospital Wing.”

Harry stared his Head of House directly in the eye. “No Ma’am, I do not. From our work in the Duelling Association, I’ve become fairly adept at recognizing various spells on sight. I blocked at least two cutting charms, and perhaps as many as five. It was a little hard to see with all the flashes at one point. In any event, as we both know that particular spell can be lethal, depending on where it strikes, which is why we don’t allow it for practice duels.”

“You are quite certain of this, Harry?” Professor Dumbledore asked.

Harry nodded. “I got a warning that some of the Slytherin students were determined to make sure I was too injured to play Quidditch this weekend. Stunners won’t do that, but gross bodily harm will.”

Professor McGonagall went very still and then her facial expression became truly frightening. The Astronomy professor began minutely examining her fingernails.

The headmaster’s face, however, settled into lines of disapproval. “Harry, you should have come to me or Professor McGonagall as soon as you received this warning.”

“I’m sorry, sir,” Harry replied, “but that would have put my Slytherin source at risk. This person warned me at a potential risk to themselves. If you had taken steps before the actual event, it would possibly have exposed them. I am not willing to gamble with the safety of an ally.”

“So,” Professor McGonagall observed, “you decided to risk the lives of six students instead.”

Harry shrugged. “I wanted to spring the ambush myself, but…”

“But we wouldn’t let him do it alone,” Ron said quickly, and then ducked his head back down.

“I’d have preferred for them to stay out of it,” Harry said ruefully, “but I have enough people wanting to send me to Madam Pomfrey as it is. Tactically, when an ambush is reversed, the initiative belongs to the side that was being ambushed. The enemy was not able to pierce my shielding charm, and when they moved to flank us, we counterattacked and defeated them. I wonder if we can write this up for extra credit in Defence Against the Dark Arts?”

Professor McGonagall, who was a bit annoyed at having to supervise Lockhart’s classes after Madam Pomfrey was unable to restore his mind, shook her head.

“Be that as it may, Harry, I would rather you brought these things to me, or your Head of House,” Professor Dumbledore said in an even voice.

Harry sighed. “I understand. But you know what I have to do; the sooner we grow accustomed to dealing with things ourselves, the better for everyone.”

“I’m truly sorry you feel that way, Harry. But pending the results of an inquiry with the injured students, I must place you on restriction and bar you from playing Quidditch this weekend. Justice is not something to be lightly taken into your own hands,” Dumbledore said, his eyes twinkling even less than usual, “It pains me to do this, but the safety of all of my students must be my highest priority.”

Harry stood rigidly, ignoring the outraged expressions on his friends’ faces. “I understand, sir. Completely. The message you are trying to send is quite clear.”

“I hope that you do understand, Harry. Please report to Mr. Filch. When the glass has been cleared away and the windows repaired, you may return to class. I believe your next exam is not until this afternoon, so you should have sufficient time to prepare. Harry, please try to think about what I’ve said today.” Dumbledore sat back in his chair and turned toward Professor McGonagall.

Harry didn’t need to be told he was dismissed. He ignored the professors’ voices behind him as he marched toward the door. It flew open as he reached for the doorknob, but he was too angry to think about that at the moment.

As soon as the door shut behind the students, Minerva McGonagall spun toward the headmaster. “Albus, have you completely lost your mind?” she hissed.

“Lemon Sherbet?” he asked her in an irritatingly mild voice.

“My students defend themselves from an unprovoked attack, so you decide to punish them, alienating some of the best students in their year, and you think offering me a Muggle sweet will shut me up?” she demanded, her accent becoming thicker as her voice became louder.

“Professor,” Dumbledore said with a sigh, “the Slytherin dormitories are filled with some very unsettled children at this moment. With the departure of Professor Snape, many of them feel they have no advocates left on the staff. I have received several owls from the parents of Slytherin students, stating that they are considering withdrawing their children from Hogwarts.”

“And good riddance to them, if they are leaving because that man is gone!” she countered. “His gross favouritism toward his students was a professional embarrassment to the rest of us.”

“I must admit,” Professor Sinistra added cautiously, “that while many of the students are upset, I have also noticed that many of them have… unusual… expectations regarding my policies as temporary Head of House.”

“If these students see seven of their housemates put in the hospital wing, and the one who did it receives no punishment, I fear that will be all it takes to drive them away. Many of them come from families with unsavoury reputations. Hogwarts may represent their last chance to choose a different path.”

“And to save them from their own choices, you’ll treat other students unfairly.” McGonagall replied. “I wonder how many will see how you punish them and act accordingly. If Mr. Potter’s informant was to be believed, the sole aim of this attack was to prevent him from playing this weekend. Congratulations, Albus, you have succeeded where they failed.”

“Harry is far too…” Dumbledore began, but paused before continuing. “Far too dangerous to be allowed to take matters into his own hands. Those students could have been killed this morning.”

“All the better reason to punish those who started it,” she observed primly. “Besides, what could you have done if he had reported it to you beforehand?”

“We could have taken steps to ensure this battle never started,” he answered.

“That is exactly why he didn’t tell you, Albus! Mr. Potter as much as said he was afraid his informant would have been harmed if it was obvious he’d received a warning.”

“I think you both exaggerate the danger,” the headmaster replied sternly. “A student won’t be murdered for carrying tales.”

“Mr. Potter has far less confidence in the safety to be found within Hogwarts, and with good reason! In two years he’s encountered V-Voldemort, a basilisk, and three different professors who assaulted him or were party to an assault. Beyond that, there’s at least one student roaming at large who robbed him and nearly killed him! And now you have told him that if he defends himself, he will be punished. Albus, the wise ruler punishes vice and rewards virtue. You have turned that rule on its ear,” Minerva said bitterly.

McGonagall rarely gave in to her temper, but this was too much – and she had several sore points where Harry Potter was concerned, one of them over a decade old.

“Might I remind you, Albus, that it was you who entrusted him to his Muggle relatives, over my severe reservations, and notwithstanding Hagrid’s report about their incompetence as guardians, you returned him to them last summer, where they nearly murdered him themselves. With all of that history, you expect that he would come to you? To trust you? To believe that you can do anything at all to protect him? My goodness, I’ll be amazed if his name isn’t at the top of the list of students withdrawing over the summer.”

Albus Dumbledore sat back in his chair, wincing visibly at the deputy-headmistress’ words. “You’ve made your point,” he said after a moment. “I will be questioning the other students after they have recovered, and will make my final decision at that point.”

“I would not wait too long,” McGonagall warned. “I wouldn’t advise taking any students for granted in this situation.”

“Rest assured,” Dumbledore replied, “I do not take Harry Potter for granted in any way. He is a bit of an enigma in some ways.”

The conversation’s sudden change in direction left McGonagall a little confused. “In what way?” she asked warily.

“He reminds me of another student, one who graduated before you returned to Hogwarts,” he said quietly. “That one also had a group of followers who were intensely devoted to him.”

Minerva’s eyes narrowed as she recalled their conversation regarding the original owner of the cursed diary. “Albus, you are wrong; Harry Potter is nothing at all like Tom Riddle!” she exclaimed.

“You think not?”

“No. I’ve watched how he acts around them,” she answered. “During one of the Duelling Association meetings Miss Weasley tripped while dodging a stinging hex and hit her head as she fell. Mr. Potter went absolutely white, even though she was only disoriented for a moment. He was about to cancel the rest of the meeting when she insisted she was all right and I volunteered to accompany her to the hospital wing for a headache potion. Even then, given the promptness with which he and the others arrived to check up on her, it was obvious he’d cut the meeting short.”

“So you are saying that he is as devoted to his friends as they are to him?” Professor Dumbledore asked. For some reason, his eyes were sparkling even brighter now.

“I should think that would be obvious,” she replied with just a touch of asperity in her voice.

The headmaster was silent for a moment. “You have given me quite a lot to think about, Minerva. I will speak with the Slytherin students and advise you as to the results.”

Professor McGonagall stood to leave, giving an apologetic nod to Professor Sinistra, who seemed relieved that the confrontation was over, at least for now.

“I can’t believe you are taking this so calmly,” Ron said as he swept up the last of the glass shards.

“He expected me to explode,” Harry said with a sigh. “I’m not going to give the barmy old bastard the satisfaction of being right.”

“Harry, you shouldn’t call him…” Hermione began, but her voice trailed off. “Well, don’t do it somewhere you can get caught,” she said instead.

Harry frowned as he tapped his wand against one of the shards of glass still remaining in the frame. “Reparo!” he said as a now unbroken pane of glass filled the space. Technically, he was supposed to do the entire cleanup himself, but pretty much everyone shouted him down when he suggested it. Neville, Luna, and Ginny were on the ground floor at the moment. Ron recommended against splitting into more than two groups, and Harry agreed with his reasoning. With all the extra help, he was nearly done.

“McGonagall looked ready to breathe fire as we were leaving,” the red-headed boy observed as Hermione vanished another small pile of broken glass.

“I’m not surprised,” Harry said as he restored another pane. “The Slytherin Quidditch Team decided to make sure Gryffindor lost its Seeker for the last game of the season, and, with the Headmaster’s help, they succeeded.”

He scowled. He’d been hoping to discover some of the unknown Junior Death Eaters, perhaps even the one that had petrified him. Instead, they’d defeated Pansy Parkinson, Marcus Flint, and his merry little band of Quidditch Hooligans. All of them had obvious reasons to go after him, and not an ounce of subtlety between them.

“You make it sound like he’s personally out to get you,” Hermione said.

“That’s the way it worked out, wasn’t it?” Harry observed. “Actions are what matter, not intentions.” He paused and looked around. “Remember, even without Snape,” he continued in a low voice, “he’s the other reason you all needed to learn Occlumency.”

“Harry, he’s still Albus Dumbledore,” Hermione insisted in a whisper.

“You’re right. He’s one and one – he got rid of Grindelwald, and then dropped the Quaffle with Voldemort,” Harry spat bitterly.

“Is that why you are so angry with him?” she asked. Ron looked very uncomfortable, and Harry was reminded of how his parents were at odds with the Headmaster because of Harry. He owed them an explanation, at least.

“Before the first war, he had suspicions about Voldemort all along, but didn’t act on them until it was too late. Even aside from that, Voldemort didn’t destroy the British wizarding world by himself,” Harry said in a low tone. “His Death Eaters actually did nearly as much damage, because there were so many more of them. After Voldemort went poof when I was a baby, his followers all claimed they’d been coerced or enchanted. They paid huge bribes to the Ministry and were pardoned. When their Dark Lord returned in my fourth year, the core of his new army was waiting for him. Dumbledore watched them lie and buy their way out of Azkaban; he just let them do it.”

“Harry,” Hermione objected, “if the courts are corrupt, then what could he do?”

“He’s the Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot; keeping the Ministry and the courts honest is supposed to be part of his job. And if the guilty evade justice, well then, there are other ways to see that it is served.”

“You can’t just kill people because you think they are guilty,” she insisted.

“Even if they are murderers a dozen times over? Even if they’ve raped and killed so many people that they’ve lost count? Oh wait, most of them were Muggles, so they don’t really count, do they?” Harry asked in a sarcastic tone. He felt a stab of guilt as Hermione blanched. “To be honest, if I knew a foolproof way to do it and get away with it, I’d kill every single man who Apparated into that graveyard in Little Hangleton that night. They all claimed to be victims, but the instant they felt their Dark Marks burn, they were scrambling to get there to welcome their master back into the land of the living.”

“Harry’s right,” Ginny said, startling him. “But if he doesn’t calm down, he’s going to have to fix that window again.” Neville and Luna were staring at him, but Harry thought he saw Neville give a small nod.

Harry looked at the window he’d just finished working on. The panes were all vibrating in their frames and he realized his magic was threatening to do something uncontrolled. He took a deep breath and blew it out. The rattling died down as his temper got back under control. “Sorry,” he said quietly, crossing his arms and gripping his elbows tightly.

“You do have a right to be angry,” Ginny said quietly as she laid her hand on his forearm. “The Headmaster wasn’t being at all fair. I don’t understand why he’s bending over backwards to help the people who seem to deserve it the least.”

Harry cocked his head at her while he shrugged. “He has one serious flaw: he wants to try and coax them back to the light. It’s a laudable goal, but I think he takes it to extremes.”

“Like punishing us for being attacked,” Neville said with a scowl.

“He did say it was his preliminary decision,” Hermione reminded them, “he may change his mind after talking to the Slytherins.”

“Fat chance of that,” Harry muttered under his breath.

Albus Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore was approaching a century and a half of life, but seldom did he feel as old as he did at that moment. It wasn’t a physical weariness per se, as much as a spiritual one that caused his steps to slow as he quietly slipped out of the hospital wing.

He’d waited until Friday afternoon to speak with the Slytherin students. Given that Madam Pomfrey assured him the worst of their wounds would be repaired in less than twenty four hours, it gave them plenty of time to recover and not feel like they were badgered.

Unfortunately, it seemed like it had also given them time to agree on a story. While Madam Pomfrey stated that their eardrums had fully re-grown the day before, they all claimed not to hear anything, and complained of severe pain. Their ‘injuries’ didn’t prevent them from giving a written description of their side of the story.

Mr. Flint claimed that they were trying to implement a conditioning program to improve the fitness of their players, including Ms. Parkinson who was considering trying out for Seeker next year. As they were leaving the castle they were accosted by the Gryffindors and attacked with no reason. After attempting to defend themselves from the unprovoked savagery of the younger students, led by Harry Potter, they were disabled and heavy cloaks were placed over them before the teachers arrived, to make it appear as though they had been lying in wait.

Each account was detailed and well-written, disagreeing on no major points. In fact, they were far too polished to have been produced except through collusion. When he tried to question them about the details, like why Ms. Parkinson’s cloak was under the ropes that bound her, they indicated they were unable to hear him, and complained of blinding headaches. Checking their wands would merely confirm that they had been recently used to fire a wide variety of curses, something they already admitted to – having been ‘surprised’ by the violent Gryffindors.

The headmaster found their excuse for not answering his questions particularly frustrating. It wasn’t uncommon for students to milk an injury or illness to get out of exams, but another day’s delay in getting at the truth would be disastrous. He was sure that Professor Sinistra had told her temporary charges of the punishment levelled against Mr. Potter, to assure them that they could feel safe at Hogwarts. Unfortunately, it seemed that they realized that feigning deafness and severe pain for another day would accomplish what Harry claimed to be their goal. Aside from the injustice of such an event, he was worried about the repercussions such an outcome would have on his rocky relationship with the boy. Harry was the key to defeating Voldemort, but it seemed like everything he did to keep the boy safe backfired or alienated him even more. Minerva warned him that the boy might leave Hogwarts if he thought he wouldn’t be allowed to defend himself from attack. At first he thought it ludicrous that James and Lily’s son would abandon Hogwarts, but then he remembered the real bitterness he heard in the boy’s voice during that encounter just before his first Christmas at the school and began to wonder. Failing to uncover the truth in time was not something he could afford.

So it was with extreme reluctance that he began to probe the memories of Marcus Flint. The Quidditch Captain was the oldest of them, and seemed to be the leader. Legilimency was not something he enjoyed performing on students, and reserved it only for extreme situations. The Slytherin students’ refusal to cooperate, delaying to ensure Harry Potter was punished, probably unjustly, was forcing his hand.

The headmaster limited his initial probe to the seventh year student’s memories related to Harry Potter. Specifically, he wanted to see what his true intentions were toward the young Seeker. What he found repulsed him.

Dumbledore saw a dreamy image that he realized was the older boy’s fantasized objective. He saw Harry laid out in his exercise clothes, face down on the ground. Both of his arms had been broken, with jagged shards of bone sticking out, and judging from the bloody divots taken out of the backs of his ankles, both of his Achilles tendons had been severed. It took a significant effort to not let any of his disgust show on his face.

Where had the boy learned such viciousness? Almost automatically, he began tracing the linkages to that image and saw other, related images. These, unfortunately, were far more detailed. In the first sequence, he saw the boy and his father on holiday, travelling in the dead of night and waylaying an unsuspecting family of Muggles. After immobilizing their captives, the father and son did… unspeakable things to them, finally killing them an hour before dawn and setting a fire to conceal their crime.

It took an incredible effort to turn away from the boy without showing any more reaction than a slight frown. There was no way he could present his knowledge to the Ministry, not in any way that would be accepted in court. But he would advise certain people he knew to keep a close eye on Mr. Flint, Sr.

Hoping to find an exception, he directed his attention to Ms. Parkinson. The second year girl couldn’t possibly be as hardened as young Mr. Flint. When he looked into her memories for what she hoped to accomplish the previous morning, he only received a vague impression of Harry lying on the ground, which almost aligned with their story about defending themselves from him. However, crowding this aside was a gleeful image of Ms. Granger and Ms. Weasley, their faces disfigured by jagged scars. The emotion driving these images was a desire to get even with Harry for Draco’s expulsion.

With a wrench, Professor Dumbledore pulled his eyes away from the Slytherin girl and withdrew his awareness from her mind. He thanked Madam Pomfrey for her efforts and asked her to inform him the moment her patients could answer his questions. He didn’t miss the small smiles the younger Slytherins attempted to conceal at his words. He had no doubts now that all of them were faking.

It was painful for him to admit, as he made his way to Professor McGonagall’s classroom, but he wasn’t sure he could save any of those benighted souls. They had behaved just as Harry described, seeking to maim a fellow student to assuage their wounded pride. Now that he knew the truth, he needed to mend his bridges where he could.

He’d spent more time in the hospital wing than he realized, because it appeared that the second years’ transfiguration final examination was over. Mr. Weasley, Mr. Longbottom, and Ms. Granger were waiting in the hallway outside the classroom door. They eyed him coolly as he approached, and while he supposed he did not deserve a friendly welcome, it was still uncomfortable to be so regarded by children that young.

“Harry is talking to Professor McGonagall about the DA,” Ms. Granger volunteered after a moment.

“Then I think I will interrupt them for a bit,” he said with a small smile, “for what I have to say needs to be heard by both of them.”

With that he opened the door and entered the room, watching both occupants look up at him as he entered.

Minerva’s eyes narrowed slightly, and her lips compressed into an even thinner line. She was still angry about the previous day, and he supposed she had the right to be. She was a true Gryffindor, and his preliminary decision had gone against the grain. It was Harry’s reaction that was more unsettling. The boy’s eyes flashed toward him as he stepped through the doorway, but then they went completely blank. They were watchful, but gave no hint of his emotions. Dumbledore didn’t need his Legilimency to guess that the boy’s natural Occlumency barriers were as smooth and hard as polished obsidian. With an uneasy epiphany, he realized that the boy regarded him as a threat, a potential opponent. How had things degenerated to this point?

“Harry,” he said gravely. “I wish to speak to you and your Head of House, if I am not interrupting.”

Harry glanced over at Professor McGonagall, who nodded, a slight smile on her face. While steadfast and loyal as any Hufflepuff, Dumbledore also knew that Minerva derived an unusual degree of satisfaction from telling him, “I told you so!” He sighed. In this case, she was more than justified.

Harry turned back toward him. “We are at your disposal, Professor,” he said formally.

“I have attempted to speak with the injured students. However, they claim to be unable to hear,” Dumbledore began. Ignoring the raised eyebrow from Professor McGonagall, he continued. “In light of… other information, I have decided to rescind your restricted status. You are free to play tomorrow, provided, of course, that Madam Pomfrey agrees.”

“She cleared me this morning,” Harry said thoughtfully. His eyes narrowed. “You saw something in their heads that you didn’t like.” It wasn’t really spoken as a question.

“I believe the situation was as you described, Harry,” he agreed with a slight nod. “In light of their… prolonged… disability, I’m afraid Madam Pomfrey will need to keep them in the hospital wing for further tests to ensure that there are no permanent hearing losses. Between that and making up the examinations they missed, I am afraid they will not be able to accompany their classmates on the Hogwarts Express at the end of the term.”

Harry let out a long exhalation. “That might also prevent any unpleasant confrontations on the way home. Thank you, Professor.”

Dumbledore smiled at a boy he wished he’d been able to get closer to. There were so many demands on his time, and the term seemed to pass so quickly… but those were just excuses. Harry was still a mystery in many ways, but hints from Minerva and others suggested that he did have a good heart. He could only hope to do better in the future.

The morning of the final Quidditch match of the season dawned bright and clear. Oliver had them up and moving quite early and Harry suspended the normal morning exercises. He also didn’t want to slip and get a black eye or a bloody nose a few hours before the match started. He didn’t put Madam Pomfrey above retracting her approval if she thought he was being reckless with his recovery.

This loud, happy, and vigorous Oliver was a pleasant contrast to the way he’d been Thursday evening. With the news of Harry’s suspension from playing, the older boy visibly sagged in his chair. Harry suggested Ginny could borrow his broom and take his place, but Oliver morosely waved that idea away. With Ginny also involved in the morning’s altercation, he doubted she’d be allowed to substitute.

Likewise, when told of Dumbledore’s final decision, Harry was afraid his captain might kiss him in front of the whole of Gryffindor House.

Harry escaped that fate, but the next morning found himself trapped between his own desire not to eat much before a match and Ginny’s determination that he put on some weight before holiday. They compromised on tea and toast with some bacon, and a promise to eat a hearty lunch after the match.

Ron, Ginny, and Neville, as members of the reserve squad, also suited up and joined the regular team as they marched out to the pitch. All four of them waved to Hermione and Luna in the stands, both of whom were openly carrying their wands – though Luna’s was stuck behind her ear, rather like a Muggle pencil.

It was a bit odd, Harry reflected as the Ravenclaws filed onto the pitch, being in a completely friendly match. The Slytherin section of the stands was almost empty. He’d come to know Cedric and Cho better during the DA meetings. Without his crush, it was surprisingly easy to become friends with them both. He didn’t know the other Ravenclaw players, but Seekers competed primarily against each other, aside from the occasional Bludger.

Still, Cho beat Cedric to the Snitch while Harry was in detention, giving Ravenclaw a close victory over Hufflepuff, despite what Ron described as a brilliant performance by the ‘puff Chasers. That meant that the championship was still up in the air if Ravenclaw won today. Harry really wanted to nail down a Gryffindor championship for this year as well. He remembered Oliver’s disappointment his first two years playing. Harry shook his head and forced his thoughts back to the here and now.

Cho grinned at him as Madam Hooch made the captains shake hands, and Harry smiled back. It was a great day to be flying, final examinations were over, Professor Dumbledore seemed to be catching on, and he felt better than he could ever remember. He glanced over at the sidelines and caught Ginny’s eye. He winked, making her blush as she smiled back. At that point Harry wasn’t convinced he needed a broom to fly.

When the whistle blew, he kicked off and shot into the air like a rocket. Cho followed him in a vertical climb that levelled out more than five hundred feet above the pitch.

As he circled above the now-tiny stands, Harry called out, “Are you stalking me. Ms. Chang?” to his counterpart.

Cho gave him a jaunty wave. “No free shots at the Snitch on my watch, Harry.”

“If you’re going to mark me,” Harry said with a smirk, “you’re going to have to play follow the leader.” With that, he tipped his broom forward into a steep dive. He didn’t have to look back to know that Cho was hot on his heels.

With half his attention on scanning for the Snitch, Harry dove through the melee of Chasers and Beaters. He avoided three separate mid-air collisions by making minute course corrections. At his speed, the smallest deviation quickly translated into a large displacement. The plummeting Seekers made two Ravenclaw Chasers bobble a pass and Angelina snagged the Quaffle, streaking toward the Ravenclaw hoops.

Harry levelled out barely six feet above the pitch, the air screaming in his ears drowning out the cheers from the stands. He leaned closer over the broom and pushed it to go faster as he tore toward the Gryffindor hoops. For an instant he was clear of the other players, so he risked a quick glance back at his opponent.

Cho was still hanging on, eyes narrowed against the wind, and for once Harry was glad he wore glasses. He knew the Ravenclaw Seeker tended to mark him when they played – watching his reactions more than she looked for the Snitch itself. It was a strategy that normally worked quite well for her. She was a fast flyer and good at reading people. She regularly beat her opponents to the Snitch, including Cedric, much to his chagrin.

But Harry had shown he was fast as well, so she couldn’t afford to let him get too far away. She needed to be right on top of him if the Snitch appeared. Otherwise, if she was on the opposite side of Harry from the Snitch, the extra distance might be too much to make up.

Harry looped around the hoops and flew back onto the pitch. Cho stayed with him for the most part, though she took the turn a little wider. Most players didn’t like the feeling that they were about to get torn off their broom if their grip slipped for an instant.

Harry grinned as his eyes scanned the pitch. He was rewarded with a very faint flash of gold near the Ravenclaw end. He streaked toward midfield, then pulled up the shaft of his broom and made a big show of scanning the entire field. He’d read once that one’s peripheral vision was better for detecting motion, and he picked up a faint flicker again in the corner of his eye as he climbed slowly in a lazy spiral. When he was facing the Gryffindor goals, Harry’s eyes widened and he mouthed, “Bugger!” as he slammed the nose of his broom forward.

Cho hauled her broom into a tight turn and took off like a shot for the Gryffindor hoops.

Likewise, Harry spun and rocketed toward the Ravenclaw hoops, eyes narrowed as he sought the flash of gold he’d seen earlier. The confused shouts from the stands indicated that he’d faked out more than just Cho. He didn’t take his eyes off the last place he’d seen the Snitch, but Harry wondered if she’d caught on yet. He smiled as another flash of gold wove between the posts: the Snitch.

Lips widened in a predatory grin, Harry veered toward the winged ball he saw shooting away from the Ravenclaw goals. His attention was so focused that he almost missed Angelina screaming at him. He looked up from his goal and saw a Bludger heading directly toward his face. He was too low to dive and it was already too close to dodge. His left hand seemed to rise in slow motion as the iron ball approached his skull. Madam Pomfrey was going to have a fit.

With a resounding clang, the other Bludger slammed into its counterpart, and the two sprang apart in a shower of sparks. Harry tore through the curtain of glowing motes, scattering them in his wake, and his fingers closed around the Snitch an instant later.

Harry slewed his broom into a wide and sloppy skid, pumping the fist with the Snitch in it up and down, as Madam Hooch blew her whistle, making it official. Fred and George were above him, Fred a lot farther back, both of them looking a little shaky. Angelina and Alicia were closing in on the twins, shrieking at the tops of their lungs. Kissing someone riding a separate broomstick is a tricky proposition at best, but the Gryffindor Chasers proved up to the task.

It took a while before Oliver got everyone back on the ground for the presentation of the Quidditch Cup to Professor McGonagall. For once, Fred and George weren’t acting up. Oliver waved the reserves onto the field, and Harry was glad the captain acknowledged the hard work they’d put in during practice. His thoughts were interrupted by the steely glare Ginny gave him as she marched out onto the field. Harry shrugged and gave her an apologetic smile, and she thawed a little as she lined up next to him.

Harry saw Cho standing with her team-mates, looking a bit pale. He caught her eye and she smiled ruefully, shaking her head. The stands erupted in applause as Professor Dumbledore handed the cup to Professor McGonagall.

They were back in the castle before Fred and George, the heroes of the hour, seemed to have snapped out of their daze. Harry caught the Snitch every time he played, but the Weasley twins had pulled off a one-in-a-thousand Bludger shot.

“I’m not exactly sure what I was thinking,” Fred said slowly as they marched up the stairs. “I had just stopped one Bludger when Baum sent the other right at your melon. When I realized you didn’t see it, I was out of position at mid-field.”

“I was closer,” George said, “but the angle was wrong. No way I could get it with me bat.”

“I could see that too,” Fred continued. “But I had this one Bludger handy, so I winged it at George.”

“You put it right in my sweet spot, brother,” George congratulated him. “As nice a set-up as I’ve ever seen.”

“Not as nice as that shot you made,” Fred disagreed. “I don’t think I’ve ever seen anyone block a Bludger with a Bludger before.”

“I think you were both bloody brilliant,” Ginny said with a sniff. “Just for that, I’m even going to forget about you two snooping in my room last summer.”

Fred and George stopped in mid-step.

Ron let out a low chuckle. “That’s quite a prize,” he said, “you don’t want to know what she and Harry had planned.”

Ginny hadn’t stopped moving, and Harry followed her. As he passed Ron and Neville, who had also resumed their climb, he heard Neville whisper to Ron, “What did they have planned?”

“Don’t know,” Ron whispered back without moving his lips, “but whatever it is it can’t be as bad as what they will imagine.”

Hermione bit her lip, but nonetheless looked slightly impressed.

“Sorry,” Harry murmured as he drew up alongside Ginny.

She glanced over at him and sighed. “Don’t be. You play Quidditch and you’re a Seeker – that’s just part of the game. It’s not your fault I get upset when you almost get k-killed.”

Harry reached out and took her hand, something he found easier and easier to do. “I’m sorry I didn’t pay better attention, and gave everyone a bad scare. It’s just… it was a friendly match, no one out to get me, and I was having a lot of fun. So I got a little stupid. I was so focused on faking Cho out and getting the Snitch that I lost my situational awareness.” They’d talked about that term, something he’d found in a Muggle psychology book, during their morning training sessions.

Ginny squeezed his hand. “Then it’s a good thing your team was there to pick up the slack, wasn’t it?”

Harry smiled ruefully at her, and she slowly returned his grin. He hadn’t anticipated that telling her everything she wanted to know would make her so serious, but he supposed it was inevitable. Harry’s anxieties about losing the people close to him seemed to have communicated themselves to Ginny to some extent. He knew better than to think she was just concerned about the Prophecy.

Well, she’d helped him a lot with his problems. It was time to return the favour.

The last two weeks of term consisted of waiting for exam results and (for the older students) finishing up independent study projects, sitting special certification exams, and presentations. Hermione took advantage of the uninterrupted time to practically camp out in the Hogwarts Library. She emerged only for meals and morning training the first week, until Harry, Ron and Neville bullied her into taking a break. Ginny took advantage of the initial distraction to nick her friend’s wand. Luna merely packed up Hermione’s bag as the protesting girl was nearly dragged outside.

“Is there a problem here?” Professor Flitwick asked as they rounded a corner.

Hermione, a little red-faced, opened her mouth to speak but stopped. No matter how angry she was, Harry knew she wouldn’t deliberately get them in trouble with a professor. He was scrambling for an explanation when Luna beat him to it.

“Our friend has been attacked by wrackspurts,” the blonde-haired girl replied in a dreamy voice. “There seems to be an infestation of them in the library and Hermione opened the wrong book. Now her brains have gone all fuzzy and she just wants to spend all day in the library when she could be outside in the sun with her friends.”

The diminutive charms professor looked thoughtful as he stroked his tiny beard. “This sounds like a serious matter. Miss Granger, I would suggest avoiding the library until I have had time to deal with this infestation. You seem particularly susceptible to wrackspurts.”

Hermione stood, frozen in place as the professor bid them good day in his high, piping voice. Harry nudged her after a moment and she began walking on her own. “Fine,” she said in an aggrieved tone, “what do you want me to do?”

“I think you should hang out with your friends and get a little sun,” Harry said. “You’re as pale as Nearly Headless Nick, you know.”

“Oliver lent me the key to the broom shed,” Ron added, “I thought we all might practise a bit of flying and enjoy the weather.”

Ron’s tone was nonchalant, but Hermione wasn’t fooled for a second. Her face reddened until Harry gave her a very direct look. He knew she wasn’t very comfortable on a broom, and hadn’t really flown one since last summer at The Burrow. But he’d also told her how her lack of proficiency on a broom had nearly killed her in the future, and that negated most of her objections.

The June sunshine was bright enough to make one forget how far North Hogwarts was located. The breeze blowing across the lake was refreshing enough to stay cool. In other words, it was almost perfect flying weather.

Knowing how Hermione hated being reminded of anything she was bad at, Harry watched closely as Ron pulled her aside and gave her a quick refresher. He was surprisingly patient with her, or perhaps merely afraid of her temper. In any event, he managed to correct her balance and loosened the death-grip she maintained on the shaft. All without a single harsh word passing between the two of them.

Harry was trying to balance his broom on the twigs, using just his legs to balance, when Ginny slowly flew around him. “Am I seeing things?” she asked in a quiet, but clearly amused, voice.

“Not really,” Harry said as he twisted his hips to keep the Nimbus from side slipping, “he’s actually pretty patient… when he’s too distracted to remember to get flustered.”

“You’re slipping, Harry,” she said with a small laugh, “you almost made sense that time.”

“Give him a break, Weasley,” Harry replied with mock sternness, “she’s his first female friend who isn’t his sister, and Hermione is wired quite differently from you. That said, I’m surprised they’re getting along so well.”

Ginny smiled at him, and it was just a trifle smug. “Whatever you told her, it seems to have settled her down a bit.”

Harry frowned as he almost overcorrected his drift. “You think so?”

Ginny nodded as she wheeled her broom back on its twigs, copying him. Only she was doing it with considerably more grace, to his annoyance. “She’s more focused, less anxious about some things.”

“Like whether Ron likes her or just argues with her for the hell of it?” Harry asked.

“Something like that,” Ginny agreed. “You’re pretty perceptive,” she complimented him. “For a boy!” she added as she let her broom shaft snap forward and shot away from Harry before he could react.

Things degenerated rapidly after that, resulting in a free-wheeling game of aerial tag. Ron and Hermione even joined in toward the end, and Harry wasn’t sure Ron was playing around when Hermione’s free hand snagged the trailing edge of his robes.

Unfortunately, Luna didn’t seem to really understand the point of the game. Ginny tried to explain it several times, but Harry almost fell off his broom when her friend asked, “What if I want Neville to catch me?”

Overall, a good afternoon was had by all. After that, Hermione didn’t require such extreme measures to persuade her to take a break from the books.

Of course, it wasn’t all flying in the sun. Harry persuaded Professor McGonagall to allow them to hold nightly DA meetings, culminating in a small single-elimination mini-tournament the last Friday of the term.

The duels were limited to non-damaging spells, of course, but Harry was still eager to see the matches. Even the first year students had practised enough to master Expelliarmus, and most of them could do Stupefy as well. With the extra training, his friends should do well, but “the proof was in the pudding” as Mrs. Weasley liked to say.

Ron gulped nervously as the slip of parchment with his name came out of the jar with Cedric Diggory’s.

“Keep it simple, Ron,” Harry whispered to his friend as he stood up.

Cedric, with his greater experience, had evidently been researching some spells for the tournament. As soon as McGonagall’s hand dropped, the Hufflepuff cast some complex-looking spell that caused random distortions in the air between him and Ron. Ron began casting quickly, alternating stunners and disarming spells, but the distortions seemed to throw off his aim and none of them even came close to Cedric. The Hufflepuff didn’t have the same problem, and his stunning spells forced Ron to duck and dodge to avoid being eliminated.

Harry saw Ron squeeze his eyes shut as he raised his wand, and looked away just his friend yelled, “Lumos!”

The bright flash of light that burst from the end of Ron’s wand dazzled his opponent, along with most of the spectators. Ron wasted no time and charged toward his opponent.

Cedric waved his wand in Ron’s direction, blinking rapidly, but his stunner flew wide of the approaching Gryffindor. Everyone seemed to be holding their breath, and the slap of Ron’s trainers on the floor was the loudest sound in the room. The older student looked puzzled for a moment as Ron approached the distortion spell, but then he stepped back and a smug smile grew across his face.

Harry had to bite his tongue to avoid shouting a warning. Cedric wasn’t a true enemy. Whatever that spell would do when Ron passed through it wouldn’t be harmful, except to his pride.

But Ron had seen Cedric’s smile as well and he dropped to the floor and skidded across the smooth stone, inches beneath the distortion spell.

Blinking owlishly, the Hufflepuff turned toward the rustle of Ron’s robes as the Gryffindor cleared the distortion field. Ron quickly yelled, “Stupefy!” and the jet of red light caught Cedric in the side, lifting him a few inches off his feet before he collapsed bonelessly to the floor. The slip of parchment with Ron’s name was dropped back into the jar and Cedric’s name was erased from the board as the Gryffindors applauded.

Neville had the bad luck to be paired up against Luna and very reluctantly squared off against the girl. He cast a few half-hearted Expelliarmus spells at Luna, who carelessly skipped aside from each one. Then she raised her wand and cast the same spell back, but with a peculiar hooking motion to her wand. The spell missed Neville by a wide margin but when it struck the chalkboard it rebounded with a peculiar cork-screw motion and struck Neville in the back.

The wand flew out of the startled boy’s hand and arced toward Luna, who carefully caught it. Neville walked back to his seat, his face red. He barely looked up when Luna handed him his wand. A few students were snickering about Neville’s reluctance to fight his friend, and Harry’s eyes narrowed as he took note of names and faces.

As luck would have it, Harry’s name came up next, along with Stephen Cornfoot, a second year Ravenclaw that joined the DA a couple of weeks after Cho. Stephen was one of those laughing at Neville’s expense, so Harry was feeling less than charitable.

The sandy-haired boy was fond of shield charms, Harry remembered, and could create a fairly powerful one for someone his age. In free-for-all duels, he preferred to let his foe exhaust himself against his defences, then strike when they were winded.

Sure enough, when McGonagall’s hand dropped and Harry’s wand came up, Stephen had already begun the wand motion for Protego. Harry let him complete the incantation, and then growled, “Stupefy!” The jet of red light that extended from the end of Harry’s wand was a bit brighter than normal, as he put enough force behind the spell to overcome the strongest shield he’d ever seen Stephen cast. The barrier around the Ravenclaw fragmented and he slumped bonelessly to the ground.

Harry walked over to Stephen, Rennervated him, and offered the confused boy a hand up. “Need to work on that shield charm a bit,” Harry said nonchalantly, then sauntered back to his seat. His remark left several people, most of whom had fought the Ravenclaw before, chuckling. At least Neville was smiling now.

Luna’s name came out again a couple of duels later, this time paired against Cho Chang. Luna dodged in the boneless-appearing manner she’d acquired when learning ‘Drunken Style’ Kung Fu, flopping to one side or another avoiding Cho’s strikes, and at one point bending over backwards at the waist so sharply that several people winced.

After Cho’s stunner skimmed past her chest with inches to spare, Luna’s upper body sprang forward and she fired another disarming curse at Cho. This one hit the wall behind the Ravenclaw and rebounded toward her back, but Cho remembered the previous duel and dropped into a low crouch. Luna’s spell passed over the girl’s head and struck the blonde-haired girl, costing Luna her wand along with the match. Harry had his suspicions though…

McGonagall called the next pair of names as soon as they left the floor. As Luna skipped back toward Harry and the rest, he saw her give Neville a smile and a shrug. “I think we both need some practice,” she said as she sat down. “I don’t have much planned this summer, do you?”

Neville smiled as he shook his head.

“Good, I think we need to practise sparring with each other,” she said. “I know you won’t hurt me, now we just need to convince you that you won’t hurt me.”

Neville let out a sigh and nodded.

“Good,” Luna said brightly, “I was hoping you weren’t going to be too much of a boy about it.”

“What’s that supposed to mean?” Ron asked warily.

“It means when you listen in on private conversations, you hear things you probably shouldn’t,” Ginny reminded her brother.

“How was that a private conversation?” Ron objected. “They’re both sitting right here!”

“Was she talking to you?” Hermione said primly.

“Er, no,” Ron said, clearly confused.

“Then it was a private conversation,” Ginny said firmly.

“Mate, I think you’re outnumbered,” Harry whispered with a grin.

“How can they-?” Ron started to ask, but subsided when McGonagall gave him a look.

The next duel pitted Hermione against an older Ravenclaw student who had enormous round glasses that made her eyes look huge. The girl wasn’t a particularly good duellist, but she seemed to have an encyclopaedic memory for spells, and she demonstrated this at every opportunity.

Oddly enough, Hermione appeared to be holding back, and stayed on the defensive, countering or dispelling those attacks she could, and side-stepping the rest. It took a couple of minutes before Harry realized she was waiting to see what the older girl would come up with next.

He was about to say something when the Ravenclaw girl repeated an earlier attack and Hermione deflected it with a wave of her wand. She followed this with a lightning-quick Expelliarmus that caught the older girl off guard. Hermione caught the flying wand easily and stepped forward, politely handing it to her opponent. Rather than returning to her seat, the bushy-haired witch followed the Ravenclaw back to hers, sitting down next to her and conversing in quiet whispers.

“She’s absolutely mental,” Ron muttered, and Harry couldn’t completely disagree.

Ginny was the only name not picked yet by random draw, and Harry almost cringed when it came out paired with Cho Chang. He knew Ginny believed him, but he felt she still had some issues with the pretty Ravenclaw.

It didn’t help that the older girl was smiling indulgently at the red-haired witch. She had, it was true, defeated Luna, but Harry suspected Luna hadn’t really given that match her all.

Cho’s overconfidence disappeared after the first volley of spells, when Ginny bracketed her with a pair of stunners, missing her by a hair on each side. Ginny was just as fast and agile as the other girl, but her casting was faster and more accurate. What followed was almost like a choreographed dance as each of them attacked, dodged, and counterattacked. As fast as they were, defeat would likely come to whichever of them made the first mistake, but Harry thought the odds were in Ginny’s favour.

Sure enough, Cho lost her footing for an instant as she spun away from a stunner, and Ginny’s follow up caught her squarely in the stomach. The Ravenclaw crumpled to the floor.

Ginny was red-faced and breathing pretty hard when she Rennervated her opponent. She quickly walked back to her seat, ducking her head down as the Gryffindors applauded. Cho seemed a little disoriented as she walked out of the circle and sat back down next to Cedric, who patted her on the back.

The random draws continued. Harry and Ron eliminated Fred and George, though he wasn’t completely sure which one he’d faced. The twins accepted defeat with grace, but Harry didn’t doubt they’d come up with something especially creative over the summer.

Three duels later, Hermione was partnered with Ginny. In a contest like this, where spell options were limited and speed was everything, Harry knew his Muggle-born friend was at a significant disadvantage. Still, she held on longer than he expected, and he could tell by watching that Ginny wasn’t holding back either. He began thinking about ways they could work on speed and accuracy when Ron jostled his elbow.

“Wake up, Harry,” Ron murmured with a grin, “time to get your arse whipped.”

Harry looked up at the chalkboard with the elimination list. Three names were left: him, Ron, and Ginny.

Harry suppressed a groan as he got up. Ron had sparred with him more than anyone else, and knew pretty much all of his moves.

The duel that followed was less of a battle and more a war of attrition. It was almost impossible for them to surprise each other, so it came down to who would tire first. Ron was a little bulkier than Harry, and his greater strength wouldn’t help here. On the other hand, three weeks ago Harry was reviving from a month-long coma, so he wasn’t really in top form. Harry’s greater magical reserves were of little use. Most of the spells that would leverage those reserves weren’t ones he could use here, and Ron wasn’t foolish enough to think he could hide behind a shield like Cornfoot. In fact, his friend relied solely on speed and agility to avoid Harry’s spells.

Harry did scratch out a win in the end, but it cost him. He’d dived awkwardly to the side to avoid one of Ron’s stunners. Instead of tucking and rolling to absorb the impact, he’d extended his arm and fired his own stunner back while he was in mid-air. The unexpected counterattack did catch Ron off guard, but it also meant that Harry landed hard, with all of his weight on his right shoulder. He bounced twice before skidding to a halt, all the wind knocked out of his lungs. For a moment he thought he’d dislocated it, but he was able to shift it slightly as Neville helped him sit up.

He wheezed for breath as he heard Hermione revive Ron. After half a minute he stood up, being careful not to use his right arm very much.

“Mr. Potter,” McGonagall asked him as he made his way to his seat, “do you wish to forfeit the next match?”

Harry looked up at the board. He and Ginny were the last two names. He glanced over at the girl, but her face was unreadable. “No, Professor,” he said after a moment, “I will accept the duel.”

Harry tried to flex his right arm and winced. His wand motions would be too restricted. He switched his wand to his left hand and walked back into the centre of the circle.

Ginny eyed him curiously as she made her way into the circle. He smiled at her and she grinned back. Win or lose, what was the point if they weren’t going to enjoy this?

Harry was slower and a little less accurate with his left hand, but the short breather had restored his wind and he was steady on his feet. Nonetheless, Ginny was all over him, and quickly forced him onto the defensive. As he dodged a stunner that just missed his left shoulder, he recalled that she’d been particularly focused during the morning training sessions. He was seeing the payoff now.

He dropped to one knee, letting a bolt of red light pass over his head and muttered, “Incarcerous!” hoping to catch her legs. She leaped into the air, the spell passing harmlessly under her feet as her wand tracked downward…

Harry opened his eyes and looked up at Ginny. She bit her lower lip and Harry realized he was lying on the floor, and she’d just revived him. “Nice move, Gin-gin,” he said, extending his left hand. “Help me up?”

She reached down and helped him stand. Harry picked up his wand as most of the DA erupted in applause. He grabbed Ginny’s wrist and held up her wand hand and the applause became even louder, particularly from the Gryffindors.

Professor McGonagall presented Ginny with a small trophy made out of red and yellow marble, with crossed brass wands on top. With a wave of the transfiguration professor’s wand, the front was engraved with the following:

Winner, Hogwarts Duelling Association

1993 Spring Tournament

Ginevra Molly Weasley

The next day was Saturday, and the Hogwarts Express was coming to take them home for holiday. Of course, no one except Hermione was completely ready to go.

The scene inside the Gryffindor second year boys’ dormitory was utter chaos. Unclaimed clothes were scattered across the floor. Books were piled everywhere. And no one had remembered to set their alarm clock. Harry silently blessed Hermione for knocking on their door and waking them as he struggled with his trunk. The latch had been completely destroyed, but Hagrid had lent him a length of rope to tie around it to hold it shut for the journey home. He’d have to either get it repaired or buy a new one over the summer.

In the end, he and Ron just threw everything into their two trunks, not really caring which one they aimed for, since they’d be sharing a room at The Burrow anyway. He did make a point of slipping the Glock out of his trunk and concealing it under his robes. Harry rolled his shoulder when they were done, wincing. He was still sore from the fall he’d taken at the tournament, but he resisted the idea of seeing Madam Pomfrey. He’d rather be sore a little while than get lectured again.

Ron levitated their trunks down the stairs, saying he was going to enjoy doing magic as long as he could. Neville muscled his trunk through the doorway, and then pulled it up onto his shoulder with disturbing ease.

Hermione, Luna, and Ginny were waiting for them in the common room, most of the other students having gone down to the courtyard to board one of the carriages. Hermione and Luna were on their feet as soon as the boys arrived, but Ginny remained on the couch, holding something under her light cloak.

Luna took Neville by the elbow, while Hermione gave Ron a very direct look. The four of them left while Harry looked at Ginny, raising his eyebrows.

“Th-this should be yours,” she said quickly, taking the DA trophy out from under her cloak. “It’s n-not fair. I only won because you were hurt.”

Harry shook his head. “You won because you were bloody effing brilliant,” he said with a smile. “I got hurt because I was too stupid to land right. Maybe it would have been luckier for me if you’d been the one to face Ron in the semi-finals instead of me, but luck is part of tournaments as well.”

Ginny shook her head. “Harry, I saw what you did in the courtyard. You could have brought the whole room down on me if you wanted to.”

Harry shrugged. “Maybe, but the rules wouldn’t allow it. Tournaments can be fun, but we know they aren’t meant to be a full-blown combat simulation. Even if we wanted to hold one, Professor McGonagall wouldn’t let us do something that dangerous with other students.” He smiled at her. “Part of the challenge is figuring out how to win within the rules. And you did.”

“You really aren’t mad?” Ginny asked.

Harry peered at her a little closer. Ginny looked down, but Harry noted the smudged circles under her eyes, indicative of a sleepless night. “Were you really worried I’d be mad about that?”

Ginny shrugged but didn’t otherwise answer.

“I’m glad, you know,” Harry said.

Ginny’s head came back up and she frowned, clearly puzzled.

Harry smiled again. He’d been doing that way too much lately. “Ginny, the better you are, the less likely you are to get hurt if there’s a cock-up.”

“You really mean that?” she asked in a small voice.

Harry suppressed the urge to frown, knowing it would be misinterpreted. Where was the confident girl he’d told all his problems to a couple of weeks ago? I suppose we all need reassurance at times, he mused as he put his hands on her shoulders and squeezed. “Really, Ginny. In fact, I’m looking forward to the look on your Mum’s face when she sees that trophy and realizes what it’s for.”

Ginny let out a laugh. “Merlin, Harry, you are awful.”

“You’re right,” Harry said. “And we’re going to miss the Express if we don’t hurry.”

Harry silently blessed Dumbledore as they settled into the compartment Ron and Hermione found. The Slytherins who’d attacked them had been confined to the hospital wing an additional week out of concern for the ‘delays’ they’d experienced in recovering their hearing. Then they were required to sit their remaining exams and wait for the results. Mysteriously, some of the professors involved had been particularly busy and weren’t able to immediately oblige them. Sadly, this meant that they were still waiting to complete their last finals when the Hogwarts Express took their classmates back to London.

Nonetheless, Harry didn’t take any chances. As soon as the train began moving, he put the strongest locking charm he could manage on the compartment door. Hermione pulled a book out of her bag and began reading while the rest of them settled down for an Exploding Snap marathon.

A year ago, Harry had dreaded this trip ending, knowing he’d be going back to the Dursleys. He’d had no idea that twelve months could make such a difference. This year, he was eager to be back at The Burrow with his new family. He wondered how soon he could tell the other Weasleys what was going on.

This year, the journey to King’s Cross was blessedly uneventful. Harry became increasingly edgy, like he was waiting for something that was overdue. It wasn’t until they were close to London that he realized Draco hadn’t shown up for his end-of-term hexing.

Harry laughed out loud.

30

A Busy Summer

Things soon became rather busy at The Burrow.

Harry’s owl to Remus Lupin was answered almost immediately, and the man agreed to come ‘round The Burrow at lunch the following day. Mrs. Weasley insisted on the timing — she displayed a fondness for the reserved man, and never missed an opportunity to feed him. Harry found that slightly amusing, given the hints of disapproval she’d displayed regarding Sirius. He wondered how all that might change if she discovered that the two of them were Marauders — Fred and George’s role models as pranksters.

“It’s good to see you again, Harry,” Remus said as the dishes were cleared. “But I take it you had something you wished to discuss?”

“Well, I wanted to congratulate you on your new job,” Harry replied. “I’ll have to get used to calling you ‘Professor’ now.”

The man cracked a rare grin, and it seemed to subtract years from his face. “Not outside of Hogwarts, Harry.”

“I’ll still need to get into the habit,” Harry replied with a shrug. “What would you say to fitting in a little teaching practice before you start? With a friendly audience?”

Remus chuckled. “I’ll be glad to show you anything you want, Harry, but you won’t be able to practise it until September.”

Harry took out the partially completed Ministry form and slid it across the table toward Remus. Harry watched his brows furrow as he read through the jargon-laced instructions. “I wasn’t aware of this law,” he said after he’d finished. “I take it you’d like me to sign this form?”

Harry nodded. “And teach us as well. There are ‘people’ out there who’d like to have me and the Weasleys out of the way, so we need to know how to defend ourselves.”

Remus nodded. “Agreed, but I won’t take any money for this, Harry. Your parents were very dear friends of mine, and—”

“Er, not to be a pain about it, but actually, you have to,” Harry said. He pointed at a blank on the form where the instructor’s wage was reported. “I don’t think they will approve it if you don’t. And you need to spend the money too, in ways that can be proven. I’m probably going to be put under a magnifying glass by the Ministry and anyone else who this will inconvenience. So everything needs to be completely above-board. Buy clothes, buy a new broom, buy calligraphy supplies — but keep the receipts so they can’t say you gave the money back under the table.”

Remus’ eyes narrowed. “You’ve given this a lot of thought,” he said slowly.

Harry nodded. “Last year the Malfoys sent me a box of angry Doxies for my birthday, trying to get me expelled for under-age magic use in a Muggle home. I don’t doubt they’ll be looking for any pretext to haul me up in front of the Wizengamot.”

Remus sighed heavily and Harry had to suppress a grin. “Don’t worry, I’m sure we’ll be getting our money’s worth,” he reassured the man.

“We?” Remus asked, frowning curiously.

Harry nodded. “Me, Ron, Ginny — the twins and Percy, if they want to — and Hermione, Luna, and Neville when they can make it. Call it a Defence Against the Dark Arts summer seminar.”

“Harry, I’m not sure I can teach things that everyone would find useful,” the professor-to-be objected.

“I wouldn’t be too sure of that,” Harry said with a sigh. “The last two Defence professors have been bloody awful.”

“Ah, I guess I will be starting from scratch then.”

“Not quite,” Harry said. “We’ve been practising our spell work most mornings at school,” he explained. “We’re familiar with most of the basic hexes and jinxes, as well as some of the more advanced spells like Stupefy, Incarcerous, Reducto, Diffindo, and Protego.”

“All of you?” Remus asked quickly.

“Well, not Percy, and the twins miss a lot of practices, usually because they are up to something,” Harry explained.

“First- and second-year students are practising spells like that?” Remus asked incredulously.

Harry shrugged uncomfortably. “It’s not like the incantations are that hard. I read them right out of the fifth- and sixth-year Defence books. It’s not like a Jelly-Legs Jinx will do more than inconvenience a Death Eater.”

“Really? I wouldn’t think you and your friends would have the magic to cast such powerful spells. The lot of you must be very gifted.”

Harry shrugged, a little embarrassed at the praise as well as for the slip. “Well, we did practise a lot. I think that helped more than anything.”

“What kind of practising?” Remus asked dubiously.

“Casting repeatedly at the edge of the Hogwarts lake to build up our power,” he explained, trying not to think about the time Ron startled him and he’d accidentally cast a Reducto at full power, dousing them all, “or at conjured bubbles to work on accuracy. That’s when Luna found out she needed glasses for distance work.”

“Interesting,” Remus said thoughtfully. “If you did that every morning, I can see where you’d develop your potential much more quickly than normal. Is there a reason you all are working so hard at this?” he asked quietly.

Harry sighed. “Dumbledore told me the prophecy,” he said flatly. “But even before that we were having trouble with the Slytherins.”

“He told you?” Remus asked, clearly shocked.

Harry nodded. “It wasn’t like I gave him a lot of choices. Voldemort already hinted about it when I confronted him first year when we were tussling over the Philosopher’s Stone. Besides, if I know what’s coming I can prepare for it, rather than sit around wasting my time trying to be a normal student.”

“Harry, there’s nothing wrong with having a life,” Remus said in a firm voice.

Harry sighed. “One of these days, Remus, he’ll be back. One way or another, I’m going to have to deal with him. He’s killed too many people we love already… including my mum and dad. I’ll have plenty of time for a life after I’ve sent him back to hell, where he belongs!” he said, banging the table. He’d felt his chest tightening as he spoke, and the last words left his mouth as little more than a snarl.

Remus Lupin recoiled a little when Harry’s fist thumped the wood. Then he smiled. It was a little wistful, but this time it lit up the tired-looking wizard’s face. “I’d say you inherited James’ and Lily’s tempers, Harry. I’ll go through my advanced lesson plans and see what I can come up with.” He quickly filled out the Ministry form, signing it with a flourish. “If we use the same hourly rate that I will draw at Hogwarts, I don’t see where anyone can complain, yes?”

Harry nodded. That remark about his parents had caught him slightly off guard.

Remus gave a sharp nod. “Right. I assume you want me to start tomorrow?”

Harry nodded again.

The shabbily dressed man stood up from the table. “I’ll get started on a preliminary syllabus,” he said. He paused as he moved toward the fireplace, and gently placed his hand on Harry’s shoulder. “I think they’d be proud of you, Harry,” he said. “I know I am.”

After a somewhat shaky start, things soon fell into a routine around The Burrow. Their mornings would begin with a run around the inner boundary of the wards, followed by a solid hour of martial arts practice. Most days Luna would join them for sparring, having jogged all the way from the village. Fred and George began to join them more often, especially after Ron made some less-than-subtle hints about being able to thrash them if they pranked him again. Harry was about to roll his eyes at his friend when he noticed Ron wearing a very self-satisfied smirk.

The idea of Ron being subtle anywhere outside of the chessboard felt like an utter violation of the natural order, but there it was.

Hermione’s first letter after Harry invited her to the summer lessons with Remus was rather hard to read. Over the years, he’d noticed that her normally precise hand became less than neat when she was agitated. Between her indignant outrage over the law that favoured pureblood students and her excitement at the opportunity to learn new things over the summer, her reply was nearly illegible.

After talking to Mrs. Weasley, the Grangers decided to go ahead and get their home hooked up to the Floo Network, so it was much easier for her to arrive at The Burrow in time for the morning run. At the same time, her parents were less than enthused that she would be gone most of the weekdays.

Harry actually ended up Flooing over to the Grangers after their house was connected, to talk to Hermione about the letter. Her parents could tell that she was working hard on more than one project, and she could tell they were feeling increasingly excluded from her life. The solution ended up being simpler than he thought it would be. They moved the early evening martial arts practice to the Grangers’ fenced-in back garden.

That arrangement meant a lot more Flooing around, but Harry just owl-ordered several large bags of Floo Powder for everyone to use. He wished he could buy a simple cure for the nausea and dizziness as easily as he’d just purchased the powder!

Hermione seemed to be right about her parents wanting to get to know her friends better, though her dad seemed very keen to chat with Ron in particular at every opportunity. After talking to Harry, Mr. Granger also had his friend, Paul Ishimura, come by while they were practising.

Harry’s study of the martial arts was haphazard at best. He’d learned some from the American War Mages, some from books, and some from bloody hard work. But he knew enough to notice how Mr. Ishimura moved. The man seemed to almost glide as he walked, and his centre of gravity was always planted squarely between his feet. Harry couldn’t help but feel impressed.

After watching them practise, he asked Harry who their teacher was. He didn’t seem too surprised when Harry admitted they’d picked up most of it from books and self-study. “It’s no reflection on you,” Mr. Ishimura said, “but there are some flaws in your stances and such that a good teacher should have corrected. But if you pretty much taught yourselves, well, it’s understandable. What got you interested?”

Harry explained that they had a fairly bad bullying situation at the school they attended — which was the literal truth. Luna also added in the part about the television programme she’d seen with her father, making the middle-aged Eurasian man crack a broad grin. Mr. Ishimura was quite willing to talk about his favourite subject, and in between stories about his teachers, he showed Harry quite a few things Harry and his friends could improve on.

By the time he left to go home for dinner with his family, Harry was amazed at the changes a couple of tweaks made in the strength and flexibility of his stances; something as small as turning a foot farther inward seemed to make an enormous difference. All in all, he was grateful for the pointers.

Mr. Ishimura was good friends with the Grangers, and he ended up dropping by a couple of evenings each week as they trained with his goddaughter. Occasionally, the students stayed to eat with the Grangers, and Harry and Hermione had to quietly demonstrate for their friends the intricacies of various Muggle conveniences.

After a week or so of visits, the Grangers seemed much more at ease with things, and Hermione told Harry privately that her mum didn’t feel so excluded from her life.

The real capstone to the holidays was the lessons with Remus. His first class with them was spent behind The Burrow, demonstrating practically every bit of defensive magic they knew. Fred and George were far too curious to exclude themselves from the lesson, and even Percy was drawn in without much effort. All other considerations aside, the fact that the man would be a Hogwarts professor next term carried considerable weight with Ron’s fastidious older brother.

Of course, between Harry’s extra training and the incompetence of Quirrell and Lockhart, even Percy wasn’t that far ahead of the first- and second-year students. Harry made sure to mention within earshot that Percy had also received one of the highest Defence scores in his class. While that soothed the prefect’s wounded pride, it made Remus grimace. He’d likely have a job making sure Percy and his classmates passed their N.E.W.T.s.

While Mrs. Weasley accepted Harry paying for Professor Lupin’s tutorial fee, she insisted on feeding him a substantial lunch as well. After the first session, they sat down to a generous array of sandwiches served with fruit and chips, and she rather hesitantly asked how their morning had gone.

“Quite good, Mrs. Weasley,” Remus replied after swallowing.

“Call me Molly, Professor,” she said with a smile.

“Only if you call me Remus; every time you say ‘professor’ I want to look around to see who you are addressing,” he replied. “I’d say that those morning practices last year were more effective than I’d have thought possible.”

“I’ll say,” Fred said ruefully. “Ickle Gin-Gin won the Duelling Association tournament at the end of the term.”

Harry winced. He’d noticed Ginny’s reluctance to mention that award in front of her mother, but he hadn’t pressed her about it. Fred, on the other hand, had no such compunctions about spilling the beans.

“Ginny?” Mrs. Weasley asked her daughter, who was currently glaring at her supremely unconcerned brother.

“Might as well show her,” Harry suggested with what he hoped was an encouraging smile. Their… whatever it was between them was quite confusing. Some days they seemed to share the same brain, and the next day they would be awkward over inconsequential things and then be almost too embarrassed to speak with each other. He knew quite well how his future self had felt about that Ginny, but for himself? This body hadn’t even finished puberty yet! But this Ginny was even braver, and he…

Harry shook his head as Ginny returned to the kitchen with her trophy, and rather hesitantly handed it to her mum. Mrs. Weasley’s eyes grew wide as she read the inscription. She looked up at the others seated at the table.

“Harry and Ron fought in the semi-final match,” George explained. “Gin took Harry in the final.”

“I tried to snag her legs with Incarcerous,” Harry explained, watching Ginny. She looked like she wanted to explode and sink through the floor at the same time. “She jumped over it and Stunned me while she was still airborne. Beautiful shot, it was.” He nodded and took another bite from his corned beef on rye.

Ginny let out a startled yelp as she was engulfed in a hug from her mother. “I’m very proud of you, Ginny!” Mrs. Weasley said, “In your first year, yet!”

The twins were staring at them, clearly outraged. Ron struggled to contain his laughter and Percy just shook his head.

“I’m not surprised most of you placed well,” Professor Lupin said. “Not with the way you’ve been doing accuracy drills. Precision casting is not something emphasized in the Defence curriculum.”

“It’s good to know we were doing something more productive than scaring the fish,” Ron said as he refilled his plate.

“Prat,” Ginny said, but her heart wasn’t really in it. She was staring as her mother set the trophy on the mantel in a place of honour — next to awards and mementos from Bill, Charlie, and Percy. Harry imagined that the twins’ numerous disciplinary notices ended up inside the fireplace instead of on the mantel.

After lunch, Remus told them that he’d be previewing some things that might be covered in later Defence classes, but that he’d also try to include curses and techniques that were not in the standard class work. “Frankly, your basic skills are sufficient that it would be a waste of time for me to drill you further on those,” he explained. “Continue working as you have been and I’ll touch on anything that needs special attention.”

By the time Remus left that afternoon, Harry felt better about their preparations than he had in months. There were only two sore points: two people who were missing.

Sirius had not returned to The Burrow. There had been no announcements of his capture, and Harry couldn’t imagine Fudge keeping that quiet. Announcing his capture would reassure his supporters, as well as justify pushing to have him executed before he escaped again. Harry could only assume he was still on his self-imposed mission to retrieve the Horcruxes.

The other absence was Neville. When Mrs. Weasley Flooed the Longbottoms to invite him over, she was rather coolly informed by his grandmother that he was busy. Harry’d had a bad feeling about the way she acted at King’s Cross, and it appeared he was right.

This was borne out as his friend was not allowed to attend any of the sessions for the rest of that week. As they returned from the Grangers’ Friday evening, he was troubled by how quiet Luna had become. After the blonde girl Flooed back to her house (she offered to jog back for exercise, but Mrs. Weasley wouldn’t hear of it), Harry went up to the room he shared with Ron. Hedwig eyed him curiously as he dug some parchment out of his trunk, sat on his bed, and began writing.

Neville,

Hey mate! How are you doing? Your grandmother told Mrs. Weasley you were busy all this week, but we’ve really missed you. Is everything all right with you? I don’t want to make you feel bad, but we’ve got Professor Lupin, who’ll be teaching Defence at Hogwarts next term, tutoring us mornings and afternoons. While he’s doing that, we have an exemption to use our wands during holiday.

Maybe if you tell her about that, she’ll let you come over. This could really give us a leg up on our classes, as well as other things.

Wishing you were here,

Harry

“Now, Hedwig,” Harry said as he rolled up the parchment. “I know you usually deliver mail in the mornings, but I’m not sure that would be a good idea with this one. Can you give it directly to Neville tonight? Or next evening, if it’s too far? And wait for him to give you a reply. Can you do that, girl?”

Hedwig just clicked her beak at him and stuck out her leg for the note. As soon as he’d secured it, she was flying out the window into the gathering gloom.

“Is that for Neville?” Ginny asked from the doorway, making him jump.

“Yeah,” Harry confirmed, “this has been going on too long.”

“It’s only a week,” Ginny said, “but still… Did you notice Luna?”

Harry nodded. “She barely said a word today.”

“Harry, she didn’t mention a single imaginary creature today. She’s really depressed.”

Harry sighed. “I know, but what else can I do?”

“Nothing really,” Ginny agreed. “So don’t beat yourself up about it. Mum sent me up because dinner will be ready soon.”

“Ah,” Harry grunted as he stood up. He smirked. “Your mum surprised you a bit, didn’t she? About the Duelling trophy?”

Ginny sighed and rolled her eyes at him. “Not really, she just waited until later to warn me.”

“Oh?” Harry asked.

“Yeah, she came by my room that evening for a little chat,” Ginny said shaking her head ruefully. “She warned me about how, if I was too aggressive or too skilful, it might intimidate boys. She didn’t tell me I should have thrown the tournament, otherwise you would have heard an explosion, but she didn’t want me to be disappointed if I kept it up and hurt my social life later on.”

Harry winced. “And how did you reply to that?” he asked in a small voice.

Ginny tossed her head and used a large elastic band to tie her hair back into a loose pony-tail. “I said that any boy who’d be intimidated by that wasn’t worth wasting time on. And then I told her you were proud of me for beating you.”

Harry coughed. “I imagine that went over well.”

Ginny shrugged as she turned toward the hallway. “She didn’t bat an eye, so I’d say you were right, she at least considers it a possibility. But she did look at me like I was hopelessly naïve.”

“Well,” Harry said as he followed her down the stairs, “if I turn into a prat again as I get older, you can always hex me.”

Their training was suspended on the weekends, mostly so they could rest, catch up on household projects, and work on whatever summer assignments they’d been given. Hermione and Luna’s parents also appreciated seeing more of them, Harry imagined. The pace wasn’t exactly gruelling, but their days were full. It was a little surprising that no one baulked at this, but Harry supposed that his revelation in the Chamber of Secrets had given most of them a certain sense of urgency. Fred, George, and Percy probably regarded the lessons with Professor Lupin as something of a novelty. Harry had also hinted to the twins that they might learn a thing or two for their ‘vocation.’

Harry still went for his morning jog that first Saturday, but his other plans fell by the wayside when he saw that Hedwig had returned from visiting Neville. He thought she looked a trifle smug as she extended her leg with a note attached.

Dear Harry,

Gran is being very odd, but I’m not sure why. She says I have duties at home that I need to attend to, and won’t let me leave. I’m not quite sure what these duties are since the greenhouse is immaculate, and she hasn’t asked me to help around the house — not that the house-elves would let us.

We have had an awful lot of people dropping by, pretty much every day. Some of them are distant relatives; others are families of people Gran says she went to school with. I’ve never known her to be very sociable, but maybe she’s making up for lost time.

I really wish I could be there with you. The sessions you describe sound very interesting. If Gran doesn’t change her mind, I’m afraid I’ll be far behind you lot when the term starts.

Sincerely,

Neville

PS — How did Hedwig know where my room was? She came right to me, and not the regular owl perch, which was probably a good idea, now that I think about it.

Harry immediately started digging out some owl treats for his familiar. Rather, for his very clever familiar.

After that, Harry spent a couple of hours writing down everything he could remember Professor Lupin covering since he started working with them. When he was confident he’d got it all, and Ron and Ginny could think of nothing to add, he folded up the parchment, added a short note and sent it to Neville via Hedwig. None of them could think of what Neville’s grandmother was playing at, but they definitely didn’t want him to feel left out.

Mrs. Weasley assigned some major tasks to everyone as they ate lunch. Ron and the twins were a little boggled at the number of tasks, until she reminded them that they could now legally use their wands.

Painting the shed was more fun than work after Mr. Weasley showed them a paint spreading charm. Not that the twins didn’t still manage to get more paint on each other than their assigned wall. Still, with magic, the work went much faster. Following that with a couple of hours working with Ron in the garden, Harry had a healthy appetite for dinner.

The food was good, as always, but there was an underlying tension around the dinner table. Harry had taken a few minutes each night to probe Mr. and Mrs. Weasley’s Occlumency barriers. With each session, there were fewer and fewer leaks for him to highlight. Last night there were only a few faint cracks.

Percy, on the other hand, seemed to have mastered Occlumency faster than Harry anticipated. When Harry checked his shields at dinner the previous night, they were nearly flawless. Harry wondered if the desire to know had driven Percy to work extra hard to overcome the difficulty younger minds seemed to have with Occlumency. It was possible that being at odds with much of his family made it easier for him to learn how to conceal his thoughts. Likewise, Fred and George’s defences were secure before they even left Hogwarts, but Harry didn’t completely trust them not to tease Percy if they knew before he did.

Of course, that also gave him an excuse to put off telling anyone else his secret.

As Harry chewed his last bite of shepherd’s pie, Mr. Weasley cleared his throat. “Harry,” he said, “would you mind sticking around for a moment after the table is cleared?”

He nodded and locked eyes with his guardian. Harry tried not to let any disappointment show on his face when he failed to find any flaws in his Occlumency. Instead, he smiled and nodded, then turned to Mrs. Weasley.

Hers was perfect as well. Bugger, he thought. It’s time.

“We might as well all sit back down,” Harry said as Fred and George began to leave. “As best I can tell, you’ve all mastered Occlumency.”

“About time, Harry!” Fred said with a grin. “Now what’s this secret all about? You make it sound like a matter of life and death…”

Harry inhaled sharply, and reminded himself that cursing Fred here and now would be somewhat counterproductive to convincing his guardians to keep his secrets.

“Both of you idiots sit down and shut up!” Ron snarled. “This is bloody serious!”

“Ron! Language!” Mrs. Weasley snapped.

“Sorry, Mum,” Ron replied, never taking his eyes off the twins. Harry didn’t think he sounded very apologetic.

Fred’s mouth was still hanging open at Ron’s ferocity, and George was looking only slightly less gob-smacked.

“Right,” Harry said in a voice that felt both too tight and too loud. “As far as I can tell, you’ve all mastered Occlumency, so you can keep secrets. I… I’d ask that you all keep your Occlumency and what I’m going to tell you to yourselves. I think when you hear what I am talking about, you will understand why.”

He frowned for a moment, wondering where to start. He felt something nudge his calf and he saw Ginny out of the corner of his eye, giving him an encouraging smile. He took a deep breath and pulled out his wand.

“This will save some time,” Harry said as he raised his wand. “I swear, upon my magic, that the secrets I will impart tonight are, to the best of my knowledge, true and factual.” Forewarned by the last oath he’d sworn in this kitchen, he squinted against the glare as his magic flared up. He knew he was tense enough that it was likely to surge again.

When he fully opened his eyes, everyone was blinking rapidly. “Harry, dear, was that really necessary?” Mrs. Weasley asked.

Harry shrugged. “What I’m going to say is sort of hard to believe. I thought that might help move things along.”

He opened his mouth to continue, but then stopped. “Are all of you familiar with what a Time-Turner does?” he finally asked.

“It’s a restricted artefact,” Percy replied in a dubious voice, “that allows the user to move backward in time for short jumps.”

“That’s right,” Harry agreed, “but there are other ways to do it. Some are not as limited in how far you can go back.” He noticed Arthur’s eyes growing wider. Somehow he wasn’t surprised that he would put it together first.

“But if that was possible, why haven’t we heard about it? Or is it a Ministry secret?” Percy asked, brows furrowed.

“What if the Ministry didn’t develop it?” George asked.

“Then who did?” Fred countered.

“I did,” Harry said quietly. “With some help from Professor Dumbledore,” he added, wary of his oath.

“Harry,” Mrs. Weasley said, “I thought you were rather at odds with the Headmaster?” she asked in a hopeful voice.

“With his portrait,” Harry clarified, shaking his head.

“You’re mucking it up, mate,” Ron said. “Just tell them like you told us.”

Harry nodded. He glanced over at Ginny, who was very quiet, but seemed to be listening intently. She nodded once in agreement.

“You’re right. Best to be more direct about this… In another time, there was another Harry Potter. He wasn’t nearly as good in school, but he was still clever enough to make friends with Ron Weasley the first time he rode the Hogwarts Express. He had no idea that he was already a marked man, and at the end of his fourth year at Hogwarts, he was kidnapped by one of Voldemort’s agents. His blood was used in a ritual to reincarnate Voldemort. This Harry eventually escaped, but not before the damage was done. While the Ministry dithered and denied that ‘You-Know-Who’ had returned, Voldemort built up his forces. Eventually, Voldemort struck, and there was a terrible war; it lasted for years. This Harry eventually killed Voldemort, but by then everyone he cared about, along with more than half the British Wizarding world, was dead.”

By now, everyone’s eyes were bulging, except for Ron and Ginny. Mrs. Weasley was slowly shaking her head.

“This Harry didn’t really know what to do with himself. He was recovering from the final battle when he read a journal article regarding temporal transit fields. They were largely theoretical exercises, since nothing that had any mass could be passed through one. But Harry saw a way to use it anyway. With the help of the portrait of the late Professor Dumbledore, Harry was able to work out the equations for a transit field that could stretch back nineteen years.”

He stared down at his hands, clasped together so tightly his fingers were white from loss of circulation.

“He Apparated to the ruins of number four, Privet Drive, set up the field around himself, and then he separated his spirit from his body, allowing it to pass through the field.” He paused and swallowed. “Once in the past, his soul was attracted to the still-living analogue of its former body. The two began to merge over the space of about a day, and, after a particularly vivid nightmare, eleven-year-old Harry Potter received all the memories from his future self.”

Harry looked up. Mrs. Weasley was still slowly shaking her head, but her face had gone deathly pale. Mr. Weasley and his sons were sitting so still, it was as if they’d been Petrified. “Since then, I’ve been trying to arrange things so the war doesn’t happen again,” he continued. “I was able to intercept Professor Quirrell without much trouble. This time he didn’t get his hands on me, and Ron and Hermione weren’t hurt. Other things still managed to get past me, like that ruddy diary. My older self knew Occlumency, and passed that on to me. In my first class with Snape, I discovered he was using Legilimency on me, and probably had been all along. After watching him murder Professor Dumbledore in my memories, I wasn’t about to risk him finding out the truth. I don’t want to try and imagine what the Ministry would do if they found out.”

“They’d arrest you on the spot,” Percy breathed. “Tampering with the past is strictly forbidden!”

“I don’t think you really understand how bad it had become,” Harry whispered. “The last vestiges of the Ministry of Magic were wiped off the map more than five years before the war ended. We had Americans trying to reclaim Britain, and rescue the pitiful few survivors that remained; that’s how bad it had become. The Muggles were told it was some terrible civil insurrection, but the Statute of Secrecy was wearing very thin. An American Wizarding general, chap by the name of Hastings, said it was only a matter of time before the Muggles figured everything out. The worst case scenario his superiors were considering was another war with the Muggles, one they couldn’t possibly win.”

“Harry?” Mr. Weasley asked, “All this… training? You’re teaching our children how to fight this war?”

His guardian’s voice sounded concerned, and Harry knew Mr. Weasley had to be less than enthusiastic about what he was hearing. “I want them to know how to survive,” he clarified. “Voldemort galvanized his supporters with the old blood prejudices. Being Muggleborn automatically made Hermione a target. Aside from your family’s relationship with me, it was no secret that the Weasleys supported Dumbledore and doing what was right. That’s why you were… targeted so early in the war.”

“Targeted?” Mrs. Weasley asked in a sick voice.

Harry turned toward the trembling woman and slowly nodded. “Ginny — died first; she was still attending Hogwarts when it was attacked and destroyed. Mr. Weasley was next. You should know that Lucius Malfoy has a poisoned blade concealed in that pretentious cane of his. Percy gave his life saving many of his co-workers when the Ministry building was overrun. Fred and George were lost in an attack on Diagon Alley. Bill and Charlie died striking back at Voldemort’s armies. Ron… Ron was with me almost until the end, when he gave his life to save mine.” Harry took a shaky breath, and something seemed to break inside him as his composure shattered. “I am not letting that happen this time!” he half-shouted as his eyes burned.

“Shhh… we know that, Harry,” Ginny murmured. “Just don’t destroy the kitchen. It didn’t do anything to deserve it.”

Harry shook his head as he realized that the pots, pans, and dishes were all rattling in the cupboards. He took a deep breath and forced his magic back down. Within moments, the clamour subsided. “Sorry,” he muttered, hanging his head, wondering if he could have screwed this up any worse.

Mrs. Weasley’s reaction, however, was still unexpected. “Stanhope,” she said suddenly.

“What?” Harry asked.

“Your healer at Saint Mungo’s,” she said, frowning. “He spoke to me before you were released. He was concerned by the extent of your nightmares and wanted to make sure we knew what to expect. But you weren’t just dreaming about the Dursleys, were you, Harry?”

He shook his head. “I hardly ever dreamed about them,” he admitted. “It’s not like I really cared that much about what happened to them. You lot were more of a family to me than they ever wanted to be.”

Mrs. Weasley visibly bit back the first thing she wanted to say. “He also discussed your physical condition with us as your guardians. That secondary corpus magi he found… it’s not from your curse scar, is it?”

Harry shook his head. “I think I have my future self’s magic as well as his memories. My magic is stronger than I ‘remember’ it being at this age. Healer Stanhope said it would likely get stronger as I got older and the two cores finished merging. He predicted I’d keep doing accidental magic until then, and he was spot on with that.”

“So you’re going to keep this older Harry’s magic?” George asked, frowning.

“That’s a rum deal for him, isn’t it?” Fred added.

Harry paused as he groped for how to answer that.

“How did you, or rather he, separate his spirit from his body?” Percy asked shrewdly.

“Avada Kedavra,” Harry whispered, hunching his shoulders, “the Killing Curse.”

There was a moment of shocked silence, and then everyone was speaking at once. The voices all blurred together, but he could pick out expressions of shock, dismay, and horror.

Harry lurched to his feet and bolted from the room.

Ginny found him in the orchard, sitting under a tree. She extinguished the Lumos spell on her wand and sat down beside him with a sigh.

“So… how long before I need to clear out?” Harry asked. His voice was a little ragged, but he’d managed to get his emotions under control again.

“Don’t be dense,” Ginny said. “You’re missing quite a show right now.”

“What?” Harry asked. “Did they already call the Aurors?” he asked, “Or did they send for someone from St. Mungo’s?”

“Neither,” she said. “Ron would probably hex them if they even thought of touching the Floo powder right now. He’s currently tearing the rest of the family up one side and down the other.” She gave a little laugh. “I suppose he’s learned more from Mum than anyone thought, because he’s doing her Howler impression spot on.”

“You’re having me on,” Harry said.

“Not one bit,” Ginny replied. “As I was heading out the door, he was asking if he should just change his name to Malfoy and be done with it.”

Harry’s mouth dropped open. “That can’t have gone over well,” he said.

“It didn’t,” Ginny agreed. “I could still hear them past the garden.” She gingerly patted his knee. “I don’t think we should leave him all alone in there, do you?” she asked. “He’s likely to start hexing them if they don’t start listening.”

Harry rose to his feet. “I’m not going to let it go that far. I didn’t come here to break up your family, Ginny. If I’m not welcome at The Burrow anymore, I’ll just go catch up with Sirius. Besides, if I’m out of the picture, your family might be able to avoid the worst of what’s to come.”

No sooner did the words leave his mouth than he found himself hopping on one foot, holding his bruised shin.

“If you will stop trying to martyr yourself for a moment,” Ginny demanded, “and actually think, you’ll know what a stupid idea that was. As if you could take off like that without the rest of us chasing you down and bringing you back! You belong here, Harry James Potter, and don’t you forget it. Now… now get back in that house before I hex you.”

Her voice went a little ragged at the end, and Harry realized she was struggling not to cry. It was too dark to clearly see her face, but he had little doubt that he’d both scared her and hurt her feelings as well. “Sorry, Gin,” he muttered in a very small voice, “you’re right, it was a stupid idea. I’m just… wound up… a bit right now.”

She sniffed once. “I suppose you are, so I’ll forgive you. But don’t let it happen again.”

The house was ominously quiet as they approached the back door. Harry opened it first, just in case someone cursed him. He only had it halfway open before it was pulled open and he was dragged forward off his feet. It took him a moment to realize that he’d been pulled into a very firm embrace by Mrs. Weasley, and he stopped trying to grab for his wand.

“Harry, dear Harry, don’t think we… it’s not that…” she began. He felt her take a deep breath without slackening her grip the tiniest bit. “It’s just all a lot to take in at once.”

“I understand,” Harry breathed and awkwardly patted her back.

She let him go, but steadied him as he stumbled. Her eyes were a bit teary, but she was smiling, at least. “Let me make some tea,” she murmured and headed toward the kitchen.

Harry didn’t protest as Ginny and Mr. Weasley led him back to the table.

“I think further details can wait for another day,” Mr. Weasley said firmly, sending a quelling glare at the twins.

Fred was holding a wet towel to his eye; George had a split lip. Harry glanced over at Ron who looked entirely too pleased with himself.

“Harry,” Mr. Weasley continued, “I assume you’d like us to not reveal this to anyone else?”

Harry nodded. “Sirius knows. The order had him studying Occlumency during the first war, because of his family.”

Mr. Weasley blinked at the casual mention of the Order of the Phoenix, but Percy’s outrage was far more audible. “Sirius Black?” he gasped.

“He made it to The Burrow during Christmas hols,” Harry confirmed.

“Harry, he’s an escaped convict,” Percy half-shouted, ignoring Ron’s scowl as the youngest son reached for his wand again.

“He’s completely damn innocent, Percy!” Harry shouted. “He was condemned to hell on Earth in Azkaban because the Ministry you worship was too busy pardoning rich Death Eaters to even bother to give him a trial!”

Percy froze in place as Harry leaned across the table, utterly furious now. His own actions might be questionable, but Sirius had done nothing to deserve his fate. “Even after all that, in my old time, when he escaped, he still joined the fight against Voldemort, and he died rescuing me and some other students when we were trapped by Death Eaters within the Department of Mysteries.”

“Is the Ministry that corrupt, Harry?” Mr. Weasley asked, clearly disturbed by the implications of Harry’s words.

Harry nodded. “As best I can tell, every suspected Death Eater that was found ‘Not Guilty’ because they were allegedly under the Imperius curse, rejoined Voldemort the minute he returned. Lucius and his allies have their nasty little fingers in almost every department, and the Malfoys owned Fudge outright. The first year after I saw Voldemort return, the Ministry ignored him and spent all their time trying to publicly discredit me as a liar and getting Dumbledore removed from power. Fudge had to see Dumbledore fighting Voldemort in the lobby of the Ministry Headquarters before he would believe he’d returned. I might also add that, after Fudge was thrown out of office, you were made a senior department head within a week.”

Harry took a deep breath. “I trust the Ministry about as far as I can spit a dead ferret.”

Mr. Weasley’s face had gone grim, and Harry supposed he’d done little more than confirm some of his nagging doubts. Percy, on the other hand, looked like a little boy who’d been told Christmas was cancelled.

“Anyway,” Harry continued, “Sirius knows. Goldfarb at Gringotts might suspect, but I think he’ll stay quiet if he does somehow guess.”

“Harry,” Mrs. Weasley asked, “why don’t you want to get Professor Dumbledore involved? Couldn’t he help a lot?”

“He could,” Harry agreed. “But he might also decide that my future knowledge was dangerous and decide to remove it.”

“You mean Obliviate you?” George asked, aghast.

“Harry! He wouldn’t do that,” Mrs. Weasley assured him.

“His own portrait in the future warned me it was possible. The consequences of a temporal paradox are supposed to be severe, but I haven’t encountered any of them, aside from a certain tendency for things from my memory to repeat… and that may just be my imagination.” Harry shrugged. “That’s why I think travelling back into the past has created an alternate timeline to the one my future self grew up in. That would explain why my future memories remain unchanged, no matter what I do now.”

Harry took a sip of tea to soothe his throat. “But present-day Dumbledore doesn’t know that. If he finds out, he may try to Obliviate me immediately before I can tell him too much and cause a paradox. He may not even agree that the probability that this is a parallel timeline justifies taking the risk.”

“Then why would his portrait agree to help you?” Mr. Weasley asked.

Harry looked down for a moment. “I don’t think either of us really had anything to lose at that point. I was basically the last living person he knew, and I’d been fighting repeating bouts of depression… pretty soon I would get into one that I couldn’t come back out of. It takes a lot of self-loathing to use the Killing Curse on yourself, you know.”

Harry’s eyes were riveted to his teacup, but no one had anything to say to that. “I don’t feel that way now. I mean, right now I have a chance to make sure none of this happens; maybe I can even prevent him from coming back at all. But I can remember how that other Harry felt. He’d be happier dead than being the sole survivor. The only reason he hung on until the end was to avenge everyone he’d lost.”

He looked up, almost out of reflex, when Mrs. Weasley refilled his cup. She absent-mindedly smoothed back his fringe as she poured. “I don’t really understand it, though,” she murmured. “If Voldemort was gone, then he was free of everything. Why…?” She shook her head.

Harry inhaled the fragrant steam from his cup as he struggled to find the proper words. “The Weasleys were the only family either of us had known,” was all he could say. “Hogwarts and The Burrow were the only places he’d ever felt at home, and both of them were gone as well. Even without Voldemort, there was nothing left for him. Without family and home, there was nothing left to live for.” It felt better, more comfortable to refer to his future self in the third person. He didn’t know if this was caused by further integration of his personality, or if he was simply keeping the pain at arm’s length.

“Well,” Mrs. Weasley said after she sat back down. “I think it would be best to involve Professor Dumbledore as early as possible. If you can explain yourself fully, I don’t think he’d overreact.”

Harry took a deep breath but otherwise remained silent.

“However,” she continued. “I also think you need to act as you think best. It’s going to be… difficult… to think of you as older. You still look like a boy to me.”

“He still is, Mum,” Ginny said quickly. “He honestly thought we were going to kick him out of The Burrow over this, stupid prat.”

Harry cringed, but Mrs. Weasley seemed oddly comforted by that. “We’d do no such thing!” she said in a shocked voice. “There’s a large difference, Harry, between being surprised and angry, though maybe you haven’t seen many people that make a distinction between the two. I want you to promise that you will stop and talk to Arthur and me before you make any precipitous decisions. Is that understood?”

Though her voice was stern, Harry felt oddly relieved. This was despite the fact that he was being chewed out. He nodded.

“Good,” she said. “I think maybe we should all make an early night of it? We’ve got a lot to think about, and everyone looks worn out.”

Harry nodded and allowed himself to be shooed out of the kitchen with the others.

“Ron?” Mr. Weasley asked as they began to climb the stairs.

Harry hung back as his friend slowly turned to face his father.

“I understand why you did what you felt you needed to do,” Mr. Weasley said slowly as his youngest son swallowed. “But you should understand that this was a unique occurrence. I trust that such behaviour will not occur again in the future.”

“I hope not,” Ron said with a grimace.

“Good lad,” Mr. Weasley said, clapping his startled son on the shoulder. “It took guts to do what you did, and I’m sure Harry appreciates that. Don’t you, Harry?”

Harry jumped guiltily, embarrassed at being caught eavesdropping. “I do. I just… don’t think it was really necessary, was it?” he asked his friend.

Ron started to open his mouth, but Mr. Weasley spoke first. “I doubt you two will ever agree on that, so it might be better to just let it lie. Now, off to bed with you!”

Neither of them spoke again until they were both settled in their beds, staring up at the ceiling.

“Thanks, mate,” Harry whispered.

“You’re welcome, Harry,” Ron answered. “Bit of a relief?”

Harry pondered the question. “It wasn’t anything like what I expected, but yes.”

“Sometimes we’re all a bit like Mum,” Ron said philosophically. “When we get surprised we say a lot of things, some of which we mean. But we don’t do anything until we’ve thought it through; most of the time, anyway. Saying you’d used the Killing Curse was a bit of a shocker, it’s supposed to be pretty Dark magic, from what Mum said, and Percy agreed. Saying you used it on yourself, well… that kind of pushed them over the top. I had to point out a few things.”

“Like what?” Harry asked, honestly confused.

“Like you did it to come back and save us all,” Ron said, turning toward him and grinning at Harry’s embarrassment. “How Ginny might already be dead now if not for you. How we’d all likely end up owing you our lives if we survive this thing. You know, little things like that.”

“How did I end up with such a manipulative wanker for a friend?” Harry asked the ceiling.

“You’re making up for a past life of sin and debauchery,” Ron answered, “at least, that’s what the twins think, anyway.”

Surprisingly, Harry slept without a single dream that night, and Ron actually had to wake him up in the morning for their pre-breakfast run. After drinking some water and washing his face, Harry felt unusually refreshed by his abnormally long slumber. He celebrated this fact by knocking Ron on his arse five straight times when they sparred.

“What’s got you so bloody chipper this morning?” Ron groused as Harry gave him a hand up after his leg-sweep had sent the red-haired boy tumbling.

Ginny rolled her eyes at her brother’s intermittent clueless-ness and smiled at Harry. “Ron, what happened last night?” she asked sweetly.

“We talked about… oh, right.” He cocked his head and peered curiously at Harry. “You even tried to have a lie in today. Is it really making that big a difference?” he asked.

Harry shrugged. “I’m not going to see a single person today that I have to keep any secrets from. I don’t think I’ve been this relaxed in… years.”

“That’s good to hear,” Ron said, “even if it is a bit hard on my bum.”

“Let’s not talk about your bum, Ron,” Ginny shot back, rolling her eyes.

“All right then, what do you want to worry about now?” Ron asked with a grin.

“How about Neville?” Harry replied with a frown.

“Blimey, I wasn’t serious, Harry!” Ron objected, shaking his head.

“Well, his grandmother is acting very peculiar,” Harry said.

“Luna is upset about it too,” Ginny added. “She seems to think that it’s her fault.”

“Do you remember his gran doing anything odd like this the, er, before?” Ron asked, a little hesitantly.

“No,” Harry said, shaking his head. “But then again, I didn’t know him nearly as well, so he might not have talked about it.”

Ron frowned. “Well, Luna might be right, you know.”

Harry nodded. “Because she’s doing something she doesn’t seem to have done before, and Luna’s, er, friendship with Neville is new too? I suppose they might be related.”

“I don’t know that ‘friendship’ is the right word,” Ron shot back.

That earned him a glare from Ginny. “I’ll have you know, I think it’s rather sweet!”

“That’s because you’re a girl,” Ron replied, rolling his eyes. “It’s like it’s built in for your kind, liking mushy rot like that.”

Ginny’s eyes narrowed. “I think we should continue this conversation when Hermione’s around, with her wand. I don’t want to be the only girl sticking up for my kind.”

“Don’t look at me,” Harry insisted, raising his hands. “I happen to think she’s good for him. She drives him crazy at times, but I think he’s getting used to that.”

Ron gave Harry a betrayed look which he blithely ignored.

“Hedwig is able to deliver your notes to him,” Ginny mused. “I wonder if Luna would like to send her own notes along with yours?”

Harry nodded. “I don’t think Hedwig would mind at all.”

After a day of relaxation and light jobs, they returned to their training with a vengeance the following Monday. Luna visibly brightened after Harry told her about Hedwig’s cleverness. The blonde witch said she’d Owled Neville twice so far, but both letters had been returned unopened. The next day she handed Harry a rather thick packet of parchment. When Hedwig returned, she brought two replies, one addressed to Luna.

Two weeks later, Neville explained some of what was going on at the Longbottom manor house.

Well, Harry, I think I know what Gran is up to, thanks to an explanation from a fifth cousin of mine, one Melinda Hawkshorne. I didn’t really pick up on the fact that each set of visitors to date has included a young, unmarried female, mainly because most of them were far older than I was. The youngest was fifteen, for Merlin’s sake!

Anyway, I’m not quite as dense as Ron, so once I realized that, I put the rest of the pieces together. I don’t think Gran approves of Luna for some reason, so this promises to be a real pain this summer.

When I talked to her, she just said that if I was lonely, then I needed to “cultivate better companions” or something like that. I actually asked her if she thought I could find a better companion than ‘The Boy Who Lived’ and that put her off balance for a moment. If you suddenly felt your ears burning yesterday afternoon, I heartily apologize!

I don’t know why she doesn’t approve of Luna, because she won’t say. Maybe she thinks The Quibbler is silly or something, but that seems awfully petty to me.

I brought up the fact that I was missing out on the tutoring sessions with the rest of you, so she went and hired one of her friends who was a tutor somewhere around the dawn of time. I don’t mean to be disrespectful to Madam Esmeralda, as she does know a lot of magic, but I don’t think she’s been around children very much this century. She looks even older than Dumbledore, and she just sat me down and asked me what I wanted to know. At least with those outlines you sent me, I could ask her to show me something useful.

I’m still exercising and working on my katas, but without anyone to spar against, my timing is going to be rubbish by beginning of next term. This is very frustrating. I never imagined I’d want the summer to be over so fast.

Your friend,

Neville

Harry restrained his first impulse, which was to Floo over to Neville’s and give Augusta Longbottom a piece of his mind. Ron, Ginny, and Hermione were similarly incensed, but no one could come up with a course of action that wasn’t more likely to backfire.

Luna wondered if Mrs. Longbottom might relent if she stopped coming to The Burrow, but everyone vetoed that decision. Loudly.

The summer wore on. Harry’s birthday party was also an early celebration of his first year at The Burrow. Knowing that Neville’s birthday was nearly the same day, he made a point of sending a formal invitation to his friend, but no response came back. Neville later confirmed that his grandmother made no mention of the invitation, which infuriated Harry even more.

He made an effort not to let it cast a pall over the celebration, but every time he saw Luna’s sad smile, he wanted to blow up something.

Mrs. Weasley, of course, made it a far bigger production than Harry was really comfortable with… but he’d been foolish enough to answer truthfully when she’d asked how he’d spent previous birthdays, so he had no one to blame but himself.

It wasn’t that bad, to be honest. She’d just invited over everyone that Harry had more than a passing acquaintance with, fed them an enormous dinner, and baked a cake that seemed larger than Hagrid. The latter, fortunately, had taken the Knight Bus to Ottery St. Catchpole, rather than Flooing into Mrs. Weasley’s already-crowded kitchen.

Harry really enjoyed the dragon-hide boots that his family had clubbed up to get him. They were sturdy and surprisingly comfortable after they contracted to conform to his feet. Harry thought the glossy dark hide looked very smart with the blackened metal fittings.

He was, however, secretly glad that they hadn’t bought him a bunch of expensive presents. He was a little surprised that Mr. Weasley didn’t win this year’s Daily Prophet Galleon Draw, but he supposed his presence had changed things enough that his guardian bought a different ticket this time. Of course, Bill was in Hong Kong at the moment, still working with Carpenter, Fitz-Willis, and Holmes, who were improving the wards around specific hidden areas of the British Consulate. Mrs. Weasley was happy at her eldest son’s success, but not so pleased at how far away from home his new job took him. Errol was definitely not up to carrying responses halfway around the world, so Harry volunteered Hedwig. She’d given him a long withering look when he asked if she could fly to China. Evidently, according to Hedwig’s view of the world, he shouldn’t question her abilities.

Harry wondered if the Weasley trip to Egypt was just something that Fate didn’t really care about, or if it the parallels were breaking down as the time lines diverged. It wasn’t a question he’d be able to really answer until after the fact, but that didn’t stop him from brooding over it. Only Hermione seemed to enjoy pondering such things for extended periods of time, and after hours of circular, inconclusive internal debates, Harry determined that she was welcome to them.

But all in all, the birthday celebration turned out to be a very fun day. He was a little shocked when Professor McGonagall arrived. She wished him a happy birthday and then handed him a very thick sheaf of parchment. Harry paged through it, puzzled.

“I’ve prepared notes for the Duelling Association curriculum, Mr. Potter,” she explained. “As you have older students expressing some interest, I’ve taken the liberty of breaking down some of the topics and referencing at what point in the year students of various years will have the necessary background knowledge to perform various exercises. As you can imagine, not everyone will be ready for some of the topics you may be prepared to cover next term.” She actually smiled at that point. “I was made aware of your holiday arrangements. I commend all of you on your industriousness, and I expect to see great things from my Gryffindors next term.”

Ron’s face looked a bit green, but Harry just smiled up at her.

Harry slipped away after dinner and took a walk around the property in his new boots. It had been a fun, albeit exhausting, day and it felt good to unwind a bit. He also found his thoughts drifting back to an uncomfortable topic.

He’d been fairly certain that Sirius would have made it back to The Burrow by now. His godfather certainly knew his birthday, and Harry didn’t think that gathering up the Horcruxes would be able to keep him away.

Unless he was in trouble.

Harry paced through the orchard, trying to organize his thoughts. While a small, childish part of him wanted Sirius to be there, he was more concerned about the implications of his absence. It was true that Sirius’ mission was far more important than a stupid birthday party, but it seemed almost out of character for him to exercise that degree of restraint. It was also possible that Sirius was hiding out somewhere, unaware of the date. Perhaps he’d been delayed while travelling.

There were a lot of variables, Harry reminded himself, and there wasn’t a lot he could do about it anyway. Except, perhaps, walking in the twilight and glaring at innocent trees.

Harry sighed aloud at his foolishness and turned to head back to The Burrow when he heard a distant baying that raised the hairs along the back of his neck.

He spun toward the south-eastern corner of the property, the direction the sound seemed to be coming from. It was probably just a local farmer’s dog, but that didn’t stop Harry from sprinting toward the sound.

Harry dove around the slate-grey stone hut that marked the corner of the Weasleys’ land, ignoring the tingle across his skin as he passed through the wards. A couple of minutes later he emerged from the woods and slipped past a tumbled-down stone wall into an overgrown pasture.

The baying had stopped, but his instincts drove Harry to continue on in the direction it had come from. Something dark burst from the trees on the opposite edge of the pasture, loping toward him. Harry let out a sigh of relief as the crescent moon shed enough light to reveal the outlines of a very familiar, very large, black dog.

But then he stiffened as a chill ran down his spine. The dog’s eyes were rolling wildly in their sockets and the black muzzle was flecked with foam. Its gait was uneven and its flanks heaved as though it were out of breath. In the back of his mind, Harry could hear the faint double-echo of a woman screaming. Harry felt his hands tremble as his whole body felt like it had been dunked in ice-water as the evening sky grew darker.

Under the trees on the opposite side of the pasture, a host of dark cloaked figures surged out into the dimming moonlight.

Author notes

31

Harsh Words

Harry’s stomach lurched as a small horde of Dementors surged out of the woods. His hand reached toward his wand, but he knew it would likely be futile. There were too many of them, and they could come at him from too many angles.

Then he remembered the wards.

Harry dashed forward, ignoring the faint screams bubbling up from his memories. His Occlumency barriers were, at best, slowing down the effects of the Dementors, but he couldn’t count on them for long.

The huge black dog was almost oblivious to his presence until Harry grabbed the fur on the back of his neck and began hauling on it. He supposed he should be glad the presence of his godfather’s mind kept the dazed animal from snapping at his hands as he half-dragged him back the way he’d come. He could feel the animal shivering fiercely through the thick fur.

Harry had no idea how closely they were followed as they scrambled through the overgrown woods. He didn’t dare waste a moment to look back over his shoulder as they staggered around trees and crashed through lesser vegetation. Surely the underbrush wasn’t this thick going the other way.

His best gauge was the chilling presence the mass of Dementors were having on his mind and body. He could feel the barriers around his mind rime with ice and grow brittle under the influence of the unwholesome creatures. Their very presence sought to suck the joy out of any nearby mortals, leaving them with only the worst of their memories echoing through their minds.

And Harry had a lot of bad memories aching to be set free.

The faint sound of screaming voices became louder and louder, threatening to drown out the rapid pulse of his heart. Harry wondered if he should have spared the time to fire off a Patronus and hope it delayed them for a few moments. As spread out as they were, he doubted it would have worked.

Fortunately, Sirius was starting to recover. Harry’s touch seemed to have reawakened his awareness of their situation, and now his steps grew steadier. Instead of Harry half-dragging his godfather, the Animagus was surging ahead, pulling Harry along by the grip he still had on the loose skin on his neck.

“More to the right,” Harry gasped as he recognized the tree they’d just passed, despite the frost that frosted the bark. He could hear the bushes behind them break off as their pursuers closed in on them. The air grew chill and the springiest vegetation became frail and brittle wherever Dementors approached.

Against his will, Harry felt his mind drifting back to the aftermath of the Hogwarts Massacre. No matter how hard he blinked, he’d see Ginny’s red hair spread out on the ground next to her cold, still, mutilated body…

“She’s not dead!” he snarled as they burst out of the woods and the pair staggered past the stone hut. The instant they passed the plane of the property line, the voices and the disturbing images cut off, and the air returned to its normal late-summer warmth.

Harry fell to his knees as Sirius collapsed, panting, onto the grass. Harry let go of the thick fur, patting the animal’s shoulder as he whined softly. No sooner had Harry staggered to his feet than he felt eyes on his back, making him spin around.

Arrayed all along the border of the property, at least twenty Dementors hovered, seeming to stare hungrily into Harry’s soul. Ever so slowly, the one immediately across from Harry raised a glistening, skeletal hand. He froze in horror as the creature calmly reached forward, pushing through the wards.

The fused stone blocks of the outbuilding began to glow slightly as an ominous hum made Harry’s feet tingle inside his new boots. A lattice of multicoloured light appeared around the Dementor’s outstretched hand, glowing brighter by the second. The hand jarred to a halt as the lattice turned red and abruptly began glowing brighter. A grating screech erupted from the creature and it abruptly pulled backward as the hand suddenly began to smoke.

“Oh no you don’t,” Harry spat, pulling out his wand. Whatever the wards were doing, this was the first time he’d ever heard a Dementor exhibit anything akin to pain. “Accio Dementor!” he growled, stabbing his wand at the thing.

The Dementor lurched forward, and the cries that erupted threatened to rupture Harry’s eardrums as its whole body was outlined in an angry blaze of crimson light. The exposed flesh he could see was visibly withering away as the tattered black robes began to smoke. In seconds, all that was left was a foul-smelling pile of burning cloth.

Harry quickly glanced at the ward-anchor. The stones were only glowing a little brighter than before. None of the warning signs of an overload were present. Harry glared at the remaining Dementors, which had started to drift backwards, reluctant to give up their prey. He brought his wand around in a sweeping gesture.

“Accio Dementors!”

Remus John Lupin was never one to overstay his welcome. The fact that he was welcome within a wizarding home was miracle enough in itself, given the fact that they knew about his ‘condition.’

He would have left by now, but he had wanted to say goodbye to Harry before he left. The boy’s birthday had fallen on a Saturday, so he wouldn’t see him again until the day after tomorrow. He’d have all day Sunday to prepare a ‘special test’ for their little defence seminar, but he wanted to get Harry’s thoughts on how realistic to make it. On the other hand, he could understand why the boy might want to take a walk by himself on such a day. He was no doubt thinking about his parents. The Weasleys were very understanding as he lingered in their kitchen after helping with the washing up.

It was… odd, really… teaching James and Lily’s son. The boy was surprisingly mature for his age, though the circumstances of his upbringing were far from ideal. While Remus had the utmost respect for Professor Dumbledore, Arthur had hinted at some things that were highly disturbing. If it were not for Harry’s obvious enthusiasm at having him for a teacher, he might have reconsidered his decision to apply at Hogwarts.

Not that he could really afford to, he mused wryly. His finances were far from stable, and he was ashamed to admit that the tutoring stipend he accepted in order to satisfy the Ministry was a windfall he’d sorely needed. It galled him to have to accept money from Harry for doing something he’d ordinarily do for free, but it might be no less mortifying to show up at Hogwarts with little more than the robes on his back.

He looked up and smiled as Molly Weasley freshened his tea. He thanked her politely, and complimented her on one of the best meals he could remember ever eating. She blushed at the praise, but as far as he was concerned it was the unvarnished truth.

The Weasleys were quite probably one of the kindest families he’d ever met, and in the absence of James and Lily, he couldn’t think of anyone he’d rather see taking care of Harry. All the same, he could tell they were a little… guarded… in their conversations. At first he thought their reticence might be related to his condition — many people were uncomfortable in his presence, but reluctant to say so directly. But over time he’d ruled that out. Today, with several people from Hogwarts around, they were similarly guarded. And the fact that their children were apparently in on it as well was equally surprising.

Harry himself had dropped a few hints that there were things afoot that he couldn’t safely speak about. Lupin desperately hoped that he was correct in assuming they had to do with Sirius. He had a lot of things to say to his oldest surviving friend, starting with an abject apology.

His mind was jerked from its gloomy introspection when a shrill whistle erupted from a small brass fixture near the back door. No sooner did the noise begin than half the people in the room had their wands out.

“Something’s trying to breach the wards,” Arthur hurriedly explained as he followed his children toward the door. As fast as the adults had reacted, the youngsters he taught were even faster, and Molly called after her two youngest as they dashed out the back door.

Remus had no idea what could even consider an attempt on the wards as they had been described to him. On the other hand, it was easy to see where the breach had been attempted. A reddish glow lit up the treetops over the southern end of the property. A faint keening wail echoed through the evening air.

“Ron, Ginny, wait!” Molly shouted again from behind them.

“Harry’s out there!” Ron puffed as he ran, but he did slow his pace slightly so the adults could catch up. The morning runs they’d described were definitely having a positive effect.

“We need to stay together,” Arthur said, puffing a bit.

“Concentration of force,” Remus added, which caused his students to slow even more. “We’ll be more effective if we arrive together,” he said quickly, which got a quick nod from Ron, who never ceased peering into the deepening gloom. The half-moon visible didn’t shed enough light to see very well this late, not after being inside a well-lit house.

Not that he wanted it to be a full moon, of course.

The wailing and the hints of redness faded from the tree tops as they advanced, and the whistle from the open back door abruptly cut off. Remus hoped that was a good sign as they cut through the orchard.

“They must have held up,” Arthur murmured next to him. “If they’d gone down, there’d be a lot more noise than that.”

Remus nodded, grateful for the information, but they still pressed forward. There was light up ahead, flickering like a fire, as well as voices.

When they broke through one last thicket, Remus could see Harry standing next to the corner outbuilding, leaning with one hand resting gingerly on the stones as their glow slowly faded. He and another man, lying sprawled on the ground, were silhouetted against several piles of dark fabric burning fitfully in a line along the border.

Remus froze in shock as a very familiar voice came from the man laying with his back to them. “Do you think the Weasleys would take it amiss if I gave Bill a big sloppy kiss the next time I see him?”

“S-Sirius?” Remus gasped.

Harry bit back a curse as he stiffened at the sound of Remus’ voice. He really had only himself to blame though — he should have remembered that any significant load on the wards would signal an alarm inside the house. Of course that meant the Weasleys and any remaining guests would be there in seconds.

But there was something extremely satisfying about watching Dementors burning down to ashes. Rogue Dementors were almost unheard of in modern England, especially given the rather cushy deal the Ministry offered them at Azkaban. Nonetheless, Goldfarb hadn’t even reacted when Harry specifically requested that the wards be made capable of stopping the horrid creatures.

Of course, this went a good bit farther than ‘stopped’. On the other hand, given the number of warnings he’d received from various parties concerning the strength and dangerous nature of the new defences, he shouldn’t have been at all surprised. Seconds after incinerating a score of creatures that were immune to most magic, the ward anchor, drawing on the local geo-magical fields, was almost back to normal.

Sirius, who changed from a large dog back to his human form as he watched the show, seemed particularly gratified — not that Harry could blame him. And he agreed with his godfather regarding Bill. The oldest Weasley brother was getting a very sincere thank-you when he returned from China.

But that was in the future. For now, he had to deal with an extremely gobsmacked Remus Lupin. Sirius, for his part, was cringing like he’d been caught with his hands in the biscuit tin. Harry sighed. It was probably safe for Dumbledore to know that he’d had contact with Sirius. The Headmaster acknowledged his former student’s innocence and had received at least one report that the Ministry’s intransigence on clearing his name had ulterior motives behind it. As long as he didn’t discover from Remus the reason Sirius had been away from The Burrow…

“Padfoot, is that any way to greet an old friend?” Harry asked his godfather.

Sirius shook his head and stood up, leaving a large sack on the ground. He dusted the grass from his clothes before he turned around. “You’re looking good, old man,” he said with a smirk.

Lupin seemed to snap out of his trance at the words and bounded forward, seizing his friend in a rough embrace as he babbled apologies. Sirius’ eyes widened for a moment as his normally reserved friend lifted him a few inches above the grass in his enthusiasm.

Harry couldn’t resist laughing at the sight, but the chuckles died in his throat when he saw Ron and Ginny’s faces. He sighed and rubbed wearily at his eyes. He was definitely in trouble again.

A few minutes later, they were all back in Molly’s kitchen, drinking tea and munching on left-over birthday cake. Sirius, in particular, was famished, and had to dissuade Mrs. Weasley from getting out her frying pan. Harry held onto the sack Sirius had given him with a wink. It took no small amount of willpower to avoid opening the bag and checking out his ‘Birthday Present’ from Padfoot.

Of course, his other hand was not available at the moment. Ginny had it in a death-grip under the table as she sat next to him, on the opposite side from Sirius. Harry might have been a little awkward with this display normally, but he wasn’t about to argue with her right now. Ron and Ginny had been clearly vexed with him as they walked back to the house, and he rather hurriedly explained why he hadn’t had time to come back for help when he heard Padfoot’s cries.

Eventually, Ron just let out a disgusted sigh and shook his head. “It’s unreal, mate, the way things happen to you. This gets much worse, we’re not letting you go to the loo by yourself. You know that, right?”

Harry snorted and looked over at Ginny, but she wasn’t enjoying her brother’s jibe. In fact, she looked rather miserable. She didn’t say a single word on the way back to the house, so Harry didn’t protest when, after they sat down at the scrubbed wood table, he felt her fingers wrap around his.

“I’m sorry we had to conceal things from you,” Mr. Weasley apologized, “but it was necessary if you were going to be teaching at Hogwarts.”

“How so?” Remus asked.

“Even if you wanted to keep it to yourself,” Harry spoke up, “Professor Snape would have pulled that information right out of your head, using Legilimency.”

Remus’ eyes widened in alarm.

“Hermione figured out how he seemed to always know things he couldn’t have. Legilimency lets him view your thoughts and memories,” Harry explained. “Both he and Professor Dumbledore can do it. The Headmaster believes Sirius is innocent now, but Snape would love to put him back in Azkaban.”

Sirius muttered something under his breath that earned him a sharp look from Mrs. Weasley.

“We’ve all learned Occlumency to block out Snape…” Harry said. “I can loan you a book if you are interested in the process.”

Remus nodded gravely.

“Furthermore,” Harry continued, “Professor Dumbledore knows that he needs me to deal with Riddle… so if he views this memory he’ll hear me saying that if he tips off the Aurors, all agreements between us are null and void. I understand that Australia is rather nice this time of year.” Harry scowled directly into Remus’ eyes as he said this, hoping that if the Headmaster picked out this memory, he could tell Harry meant business.

Despite himself, Remus looked rather shocked.

“Looks just like James when he had that row with his father, doesn’t he?” Sirius asked with a grin. “That first weekend you came to visit?”

Remus nodded slowly.

“I’d say he’s well on the way to becoming the next Marauder,” Sirius added with a smirk.

Harry tried not to cringe as Fred and George’s heads snapped around with an audible crack. “Marauders?” they asked in unison.

Remus rolled his eyes as Sirius frowned. “Yeah,” he drawled, “that’s what they called us when we went to Hogwarts.”

Fred dashed out of the room and pelted up the stairs with audible thumps. George just stared at the two men until his brother returned with a very familiar piece of folded parchment. Their parents looked back and forth between the twins and Sirius in obvious confusion.

“If you’re who you say you are,” Fred said quickly, “you’ll know what to do with this.”

Sirius plucked the parchment from Fred’s trembling hand with a large toothy grin. “I thought this had been lost forever,” he murmured as he pulled out his wand. “I solemnly swear I am up to no good,” he said.

As the map activated, Fred and George got up from their chairs and dropped to their knees on the floor of the kitchen. “We’re not worthy! We’re not worthy!” they chanted as they kowtowed to Sirius and Remus. Harry wondered if this was something else they’d learned from Lee Jordan’s cousin…

Remus at least had the grace to look embarrassed, while Sirius nearly fell out of his chair laughing at the twins. Remus shook his head and tapped the map, murmuring, “Mischief managed.”

“How did you get hold of this?” Sirius asked when Fred and George stood up again.

“We nicked it from Filch’s office,” Fred said with a grin. “Took us nearly a fortnight to figure out the command words.”

Mrs. Weasley looked back and forth from her sons to her guests, her face slowly reddening. “Mischief managed?” she asked. “So it’s you two I have to thank for all the trouble my sons get into?”

With his guardian radiating a palpable sense of malice, Harry quickly spoke up. “Er, look at it this way, Mrs., er, Molly,” he said. “Look at Sirius.” He paused. “I mean, look at how Remus turned out. Doesn’t that mean there’s still hope for Fred and George yet?” He ignored the betrayed look Sirius gave him.

Mrs. Weasley opened her mouth, and then paused, peering at the genteel tutor-and-soon-to-be-professor. Remus shifted uneasily under her gaze, and then attempted a faint smile.

“I suppose you are right, Harry,” she said after a moment, visibly subsiding.

Remus didn’t leave until nearly midnight, and only Molly’s offer to let him sleep over made him realize how late it had become. With several apologies that were promptly waved off, he departed through the Floo.

Once the green flames died away, everyone turned toward Harry and Sirius expectantly. Harry hated leaving Remus out of the loop on things, but he couldn’t risk Dumbledore knowing of the Horcrux hunt just yet. “Should I open my present now?” he asked Sirius.

Sirius glanced at the Weasleys.

“They know,” Harry said quietly.

“Then feel free,” Sirius said with a broad grin.

Harry gingerly poured out the sack’s contents onto the table. Along with the ring and the locket was a small golden cup engraved with a badger. He looked up sharply at Sirius. “You nicked the cup as well?” Harry demanded. “We aren’t ready for Voldemort to know we’re on to him yet!”

“Relax, Harry,” Sirius said with a grin. “I thought I’d just pop by and have a look-see. With what you told me, it wasn’t hard to spot the alarms he’d placed on it. Dark Lord or not, he’s not skilled with some of the finer details. We had far more trouble getting itching powder into Flitwick’s wardrobe our fifth year.”

“See, Mum,” Fred quipped, “there is some practical use to what we do!”

A quick glare from Mrs. Weasley silenced her son.

“I also stopped by Little Hangleton,” Sirius added. “All of Tom Riddle Senior’s bones have been pulverized and banished to the four winds. I Transfigured some twigs and left them inside the grave though. If they don’t notice, they’ll be in for a nasty surprise if they try that ritual.”

Harry nodded slowly, trying to assimilate it all. With these out of the picture, that left only Nagini and the Sorting Hat. Voldemort’s familiar was eaten by Norbert in the original timeline, and its death proved to be sufficient to release the piece of Voldemort’s soul that it housed. And he knew where the Hat was.

“Good work,” Harry said. “But how did you acquire that entourage?” he asked.

Sirius made a face. “I’m not precisely sure. They were roaming around in a grove of trees near the river… about ten miles from here. I didn’t think Dementors would recognize me as a dog, but they immediately began chasing me. I wasn’t sure if the wards would stop them, but if they didn’t, I planned to drop the bag here and then lead them as far away as I could.” He shrugged uncomfortably under Harry’s glare.

“Now you know how it sounds,” Ginny murmured, bringing Harry up short.

“It’s been a long day,” Mr. Weasley interjected, “perhaps we should all get some sleep.”

Sirius was all for sleeping in the shed again, just in case someone came to call, but Mrs. Weasley wouldn’t hear of it. The twins quickly volunteered to double up so Sirius could use their other bed. Harry smiled faintly as they dragged their idol up to their room. He walked up the stairs with Ginny, pausing at her landing.

“I’m sorry I worried you today,” he said in a low voice as Ron passed them.

Ginny made a face and rubbed at her eyes. “I know you didn’t do it on purpose,” she said. “But that doesn’t make it any easier.”

Harry sighed. “How about I promise to be as careful as I can, and to get you and the others involved whenever possible?”

Ginny looked up at him suddenly. “You really mean that?” she asked.

Harry nodded. “If I had you and Ron with me, and all three of us were able to cast the Patronus charm, I think we could have driven them off. I’ll admit I enjoyed seeing them burn on the wards, but it was a close thing getting back here.”

“You really mean that?” Ginny asked. “No more of that ‘keeping us safe’ rubbish? And what is the Patronus charm?”

“It’s one of the few spells an individual can do to hold off a Dementor,” Harry answered. He took a deep breath. “And as for the rest… I can’t promise I won’t ever think that again, Ginny. I really don’t want anyone else I care about getting h-hurt. But I’ll try.”

“I suppose that’s all I can ask for,” she said ruefully.

“It’s not that I don’t think you are capable,” Harry reminded her, “it’s the… other things. You know?” Like seeing you dead again.

“I know,” she said, looking down. “Good night, Harry. Happy birthday.”

“Good night, Ginny.”

Harry did not sleep well that night. He dreamt of another time when Dementors had almost consumed the souls of himself and his godfather. When he awoke, he was still thinking about the foul creatures.

The fact that they immediately pursued Padfoot was quite… interesting. He mulled this over as he awoke and walked the bounds of the property in the early pre-dawn light. He carefully banished the charred remnants of their cloaks and removed any sign of their struggle against the wards.

A colony of rogue Dementors would have preyed on nearby humans, Muggle or wizard, until they were stopped. The fact that these had kept to themselves was highly suspicious.

Their pursuit of Sirius in his Animagus form was even worse. According to what he’d been told long ago, the emotions of animals didn’t excite them very much. They had to know, in some way, that Padfoot was no ordinary animal.

And only Wormtail could have revealed that particular piece of information.

Since the traitor had been given over to the Ministry, it seemed likely that the Dementors that attacked yesterday had been sent, more than likely on the orders of whoever now controlled the island prison.

This did not bode well. For any of them.

As Harry walked back to the house, he pondered his options. Whoever had sent the Dementors wasn’t likely to publicly admit it — most wizards and witches hated the damned things. The implication that the Ministry was severely compromised at high levels was troubling though.

He sighed as he wandered into the kitchen and fired up the stove. Perhaps if the Dementors just disappeared, whoever sent them might wonder if they’d gone rogue. Best if no one at The Burrow ever mentioned seeing them, at least for now. He let his hands begin the preparations for a large breakfast as he wondered what they should do next. Perhaps Remus should jump ahead a bit in his syllabus.

As appetizing smells began to fill the kitchen, Harry sighed. This was a lot easier when he knew what was going on, and what would happen next. He’d truly taken the bull by the horns altering the timeline, and now he was stuck with everyone else, wondering what the hell was going on.

The following Monday, Remus had a surprise for them. He arrived at The Burrow with a large trunk in tow. Once they were assembled for class, he popped open the catches on the trunk and opened it to reveal a large number of Quaffle-sized spheres.

Clearly enjoying the curious stares from his audience, the wizard lifted one out of the trunk, revealing it to be fairly light. He tapped it once with his wand, whispering something under his breath, and the ball abruptly lifted into the air. It floated about ten feet in front of them and began to shimmer. Suddenly, it seemed to expand as if black fabric was sprouting from its surface. In seconds the sphere was replaced with the form of a wizard in black robes with a featureless blank white face.

It wasn’t a Death Eater mask, but it was close enough for Harry to feel his insides freeze up. He didn’t even recall drawing his wand, but it was nonetheless pointing squarely at the target. “What are you playing at?” he snapped.

Remus raised his eyebrow at Harry’s vehemence. “I’ve prepared some targets for you to practise on. I thought you might prefer something with a bit of realism, but faces are devilishly hard to get right.”

Hermione gave Harry a careful sideways glance before clearing her throat. “Er, it does look a bit like a Death Eater, doesn’t it, sir?”

Remus frowned. “A bit, I suppose, but how did you…? Never mind.” He raised his wand and, with a flick, changed the robes to a dull brown. “Is that better?”

Harry nodded, trying to get his heart to slow back down. He knew he was over-reacting, but he just couldn’t seem to help it. For an instant when he first saw it, the smooth white face was replaced with the hated mask of one of Voldemort’s murderous sycophants. The rage engendered by that visage was very familiar to Harry’s older self, but it was nonetheless a nasty surprise to him now.

It took several moments, while Remus set up the other targets, before Harry could get himself completely under control again. He didn’t even want to imagine what Remus thought of that display. Or what Dumbledore might make of it if he viewed the memory.

Ginny gave him a careful nudge as Remus finished. He had them line up so there was a figure opposite of each of them, and on his command they started to duck and dodge like a real opponent. Objectively, Harry had to admire the thought and workmanship his teacher had put into them.

Subjectively, his face was still burning from his earlier display.

When Remus signalled for them to start, Harry’s wand was a blur of motion. They were instructed to just use Stinging Hexes — the magical field surrounding the orbs would register each hit and signal when twenty had been made. While Harry was using the suggested spell, he had no doubt that he was letting a bit more power flow into them than was strictly required. His brown-robed opponent tried to twist and turn to avoid his hexes, but each one struck, jarring it backwards a little each time. It seemed that he’d hardly started before the ball let out a loud ding. The simulacrum surrounding it faded away.

Harry took a deep breath and blew it out, ignoring the tiny wisp of smoke curling from the end of his wand. From the sound of things, his friends were all still firing. From the sound of Ron’s muttered swearing, they probably would be for a while. Harry bowed to the inevitable and turned toward Remus.

The man was staring at him with unabashed concern etched on his features. Harry shrugged helplessly.

Ginny finished next, then Ron, Hermione, and Luna all completed the exercise at roughly the same time. Percy, Fred, and George were the last to finish.

Remus nodded. “Very good. Ron, you kept up an impressive rate of fire, but your accuracy suffered. Hermione fired less than half as many hexes, but completed in roughly the same time. That said, Hermione, you would do well to loosen up a bit and try to go a bit faster. Percy, that goes doubly so for you. While a direct hit is preferable, it’s not necessary for most curses that they strike the exact centre of the target. Fred, George, both of you would do well to work on smoothing out your wand motions — less jerking back and more follow-through.” He continued, critiquing each of them, but not mentioning Harry’s performance at all.

Harry couldn’t help but notice that the twins were even more attentive than usual.

The rest of the session continued as normal, but when he was preparing to leave, Remus asked Harry to help him with his trunk. As they made their way toward the Floo, the older man spoke in a low voice. “I’d like to apologize, Harry. The resemblance hadn’t even occurred to me as I was finishing the orbs. Of course, if I was in your position, I would have read up on everything I could find concerning the war. That was frightfully insensitive of me, and I must apologize.”

Harry shook his head. “It wasn’t your fault,” he insisted, “I was just overreacting. I do that, a bit.”

“Like when you sent the Slytherin Quidditch squad to the hospital wing for a fortnight?” Sirius asked as they entered the kitchen.

Harry scowled at the shocked look on Remus’ face, and the wide grin on Sirius’. “I see the twins have been carrying tales again,” he observed sourly.

“Well, I did ask how the Quidditch season went,” Sirius said innocently, “but it seemed that more action happened off the field last season.”

Remus, of course, was not about to leave until he’d had the whole story out of Harry. He supposed the man worried he’d be partially to blame if Harry misused something he’d taught, but he really wasn’t in the mood for any second-guessing.

Fortunately, the man’s reaction was a pleasant surprise. “That’s quite an interesting use for a Noise-Making Charm,” Remus murmured thoughtfully when Harry was done. “And an ingenious way of ending a fight without inflicting permanent harm. Top marks, Harry!”

“I just wish Dumbledore agreed,” Harry snorted.

“I heard about that as well,” Sirius commiserated. “But he did come around in the end, right?”

Harry nodded. “I suppose he had no choice once he knew they were lying. I practically dared him to view their memories of the ambush.”

“This Legilimency business seems very questionable to me,” Remus said. “But it appears I have little choice but to learn Occlumency if I wish to teach at Hogwarts and keep my thoughts to myself.”

“At least now you know why it was so hard to get anything past Dumbledore,” Sirius said with a grin.

“Quite,” Remus replied, deadpan. Then he grinned at his childhood friend in a way that seemed to melt years off his face.

Harry was mostly calmed down by the time they arrived at the Grangers’ house. He was also sufficiently aware to notice the concerned looks Ginny was giving Luna. The blonde girl had grown increasingly quiet and withdrawn over the summer, despite their best efforts — including letters relayed from Neville.

After Ginny’s last attempt to draw the girl out as they marched out into the Grangers’ back garden, the redhead gave Harry a very direct look. Harry nodded back, earning a quick smile as they paired off for some warm-up exercises.

Paul Ishimura couldn’t make it today, so Harry was leading the group. While Harry ordinarily liked working with Hermione’s godfather, today he was glad because it gave him a chance to talk to Luna.

When he paired everyone off to spar, he held Luna back and suggested she do some extra stretches with him. The ‘Drunken Boxing’ style she’d adopted often sorely pushed the limits of her flexibility. It also gave him a pretext to talk to her as they moved off a ways from the others and dropped onto the soft grass to do some hamstring stretches.

Trying to mince words with Luna Lovegood was futile at best, so Harry decided to borrow a page from her grimoire and go for the incredibly blunt approach. “You seem very sad today. Ginny and the others are worried about you.”

Luna’s expression didn’t change, but she did pause as she leaned her torso forward until it almost touched one thigh. “I miss Neville,” she said.

“We miss him too,” Harry agreed. “But you two do at least get to write each other.” Hedwig was visiting the Longbottom house at least as often as she’d visited The Burrow his first year.

“That’s part of the problem,” she said quietly. “Even though he doesn’t come right out and say it, he’s been dreadfully unhappy this summer. He misses his friends, and he’s worried about getting behind in the training and becoming a liability.” She sniffed. “And most of the reasons for why he is unhappy have to do with me. I really don’t care for that feeling.”

Harry scowled. “I think it’s a load of rubbish if you are blaming yourself, Luna. I think his grandmother is the only one responsible for this mess.”

“She wouldn’t have confined him to their house if it wasn’t for me,” she said. “I think I went a bit too far, too soon. I wanted him to like me, but now he’s probably wishing he’d never met me.”

Harry grew rather alarmed at the tone of his friend’s voice. He’d never really seen Luna so focused like this before. For once, that faraway, dreamy look of hers was completely absent. But in its place was a visage of pure misery and guilt. Harry didn’t have to think twice about which one he preferred.

“Luna,” he said firmly, “I think he does like you. And he’s not stupid enough to blame you for his gran’s actions. In fact, I bet he even misses the gentle teasing you put him through.”

“You do?” she asked suddenly, looking up. “You know, don’t you?” She peered at him rather intently, the wire-frame glasses making her gaze seem even more intense. “Were we… together? In the future, that is?”

Harry looked down and swallowed. “I don’t know, really. You didn’t date when I was at Hogwarts,” he said, looking up. Luna’s frown made him quickly qualify that statement. “But then again, you were in Ravenclaw, and we’d never got to know you until fifth year. And I was gone for Neville’s seventh year, so I really don’t know.” He paused, swallowing. “But I do know that you two were friends. And after Hogwarts fell, we found the two of you lying next to each other where the students made their stand.”

Luna’s eyes were shining, but she didn’t seem quite so sad, so Harry pressed on. “And remember, the Neville I knew then was a lot different than the one I know now. He hadn’t really come into his own until later. That Neville had very little confidence for most of the time I knew him. He was afraid of Snape, afraid of getting hurt, afraid of failing.”

“My Neville isn’t afraid of anything, is he?” Luna asked softly.

Harry stifled a grin at the possessive pronoun. “No, he isn’t,” he agreed. “And I don’t think he’s afraid of his grandmother anymore, either.”

“No… no, he’s not, is he?” Luna said slowly. After a moment she finished the stretches and they both stood up and got into ready stances.

As Harry led them through a three-step blocking drill with a palpable sense of relief, he wondered what they could possibly do about Neville’s situation. He had a feeling things might get worse before they got better.

The last month of the holidays passed with much less drama than it started. At Harry’s request, Remus had taught them the basics of the Patronus Charm. While Harry allowed no more than a thin silvery vapour to escape his wand, none of his friends could even get that far. Remus consoled them that the spell was highly advanced magic, and not something children of their ages could be expected to know, let alone master.

All the same, Harry couldn’t come up with an innocent explanation for the presence of the Dementors that ambushed Sirius. None of his friends could either. So they all practised the charm on a daily basis.

Finally, the end of August arrived, and with it the annual trek to Diagon Alley. This year the plan was a little different than normal, for more than the usual reasons.

Harry awoke early on a slightly overcast Tuesday, taking care not to wake Ron or anyone else as he took a shower and did his normal daily grooming with somewhat greater than usual care, and finished by donning the plain black robe he’d worn to the custody hearing. When he softly crept down the stairs, Mr. Weasley was waiting for him in the kitchen, reading the Daily Prophet and frowning.

“You know, you don’t have to take time off from work for this,” Harry said quietly as he poured some tea.

“It’s not a bother,” his guardian said. “And it’s important that Molly or I be present when this interview takes place.”

Harry shrugged uncomfortably. “I know you don’t approve of this.”

Arthur made a dismissive gesture. “At the time, your agreement made sense. We had no idea where… your godfather was, or what condition he was in. Using her to put pressure on the Ministry was rather resourceful. I just hope you don’t have cause to regret this all later.”

Harry nodded. “I think I’ve demonstrated to her satisfaction that she has a lot more to gain by being civil with us. Exclusive interviews with The Boy Who Lived let her name her price with most editors.” Harry grinned ruefully. “She was a holy terror, er, before, and I’d much rather have her on our side than our enemies’.”

“I suppose you would know,” Arthur agreed thoughtfully as he put the paper down. “Have a bit of toast and we’ll be off. Molly would flay me, but I’d rather not keep this woman waiting. We can always get something to eat afterwards.”

Harry nodded and ate quickly.

He was slowly getting better at Floo travel… the emphasis on slowly. This time he managed to only fall to one knee when he arrived at the Leaky Cauldron. Arthur gave him a hand up and they made their way to the bar.

Old Tom brought them up to a private room reserved for this meeting and bid them a good day. Harry was sort of relieved that the man didn’t make a huge fuss over him, or even stare too long.

Harry took a deep breath before opening the door. A tall woman in a venomous-looking green robe was sitting in a chair pulled up to the table. Her stiffly-curled hair didn’t sway in the slightest as she turned toward him and smiled, rising to her feet. “Mr. Potter!” she said in a falsely cheery voice. “It’s so good to finally meet you in person!”

Harry nodded and shook the hand she extended toward him, careful not to jab himself on her long red fingernails.

“And this must be Arthur Weasley, your guardian?” she asked. “I understood this was to be a one-on-one interview,” she observed, though her smile didn’t waver at all.

“I’m afraid I did insist that one of us be present for this interview,” Mr. Weasley explained in a friendly, but firm, voice.

Harry shrugged. “He’s completely within his rights to do so. If you prefer, Ms. Skeeter, we could conduct this by owl post,” he offered.

“Oh no,” Rita said, waving one of her manicured hands. “That won’t be necessary. I’d have prepared some questions for him as well, if I’d known he was coming.”

Arthur looked somewhat startled by this admission, but quickly busied himself moving an extra chair up to the table.

Harry moved the unoccupied chair to one side so that he and Arthur both sat facing the reporter. “I don’t think Mr. Weasley is ready to be the subject of an interview,” Harry said carefully. “And I don’t have the right to promise anything on his behalf. I’d prefer it if his name was left out this, for now.”

Rita seemed to think it over for a moment before nodding her agreement. “First of all, I would like to thank you for consenting to this interview,” she said in a somewhat ironic tone as her words were taken down by a floating quill. When it was done, she tapped it with her wand and wordlessly handed the parchment to Harry. “As you can see,” she continued, “this is a standard dictation quill — and not a Quick-Quotes Quill.”

Harry nodded. “I appreciate that, Ms. Skeeter. If all goes well, we may be able to do this again in future.”

Rita’s pencilled eyebrow lifted as she absorbed Harry’s implied offer. “I think… we can be helpful to each other in future, Mr. Potter. I have no interest in roasting the goose that lays such golden eggs.”

Harry carefully ignored the tightening muscles along Arthur’s jaw. “That would be nice,” he agreed. “And if you ever have… difficulty… in persuading your editor to run a story as it is written, I have a friend who may be able to help.”

“The Lovegood girl?” Rita asked.

Harry raised an eyebrow.

“Anyone with time and resources could find out quite a bit about you and your friends at Hogwarts,” she explained. “I’ve had both as I prepared for our little talk. All the same, I’ve never really been interested in writing for The Quibbler.”

Harry shrugged. “Once the story is out, if it’s good enough, it will spread on its own. That alone will put pressure on your editor.”

Rita nodded. “But do you really anticipate anything of that… nature?”

Harry smiled. “Anything’s possible. I think you may find that The Quibbler is a bit less subject to… outside influences… than other publications.”

Rita’s eyes narrowed and her nails tapped a staccato on the worn varnish of the table. “The Ministry?” she asked quietly, darting her eyes toward Arthur.

“Anything is possible,” Harry said blandly. “I appear to have attracted the attentions of a wide variety of people.”

“That’s one way of putting it,” Rita said as she reactivated her quill. “Let’s start at the beginning. I understand you were raised by your aunt and her family?”

Harry felt a muscle in his cheek twitch at the mention of the Dursleys. “Yes,” was all he said.

“Why did you leave?” Rita asked, her features taking on a slightly predatory cast.

Harry had no doubt she knew exactly why he’d left Privet Drive, but this wasn’t something he wanted discussed in the press. “It didn’t work out,” he said shortly. He took a breath. “They were terrified at the idea of magic, and it was unacceptable to them that I continue living under their roof. After my first year at Hogwarts, it was necessary for me to find somewhere else to live. Fortunately, my friend’s parents agreed to take me in.”

“Do you agree with the members of the Wizengamot who maintain that Muggle-born witches and wizards should be removed from Muggle households as soon as they are discovered — both for their own protection and to maintain the Statute of Secrecy?”

Harry raised an eyebrow at that while Arthur’s face slowly reddened. “No, I do not,” he said firmly. “I think that would be a complete overreaction. Not all Muggles hate magic — they vary as much as wizards and witches do. One of my close friends is Muggle-born and her parents are not only supportive, they are completely fascinated by what they’ve learned of magic. They even host our study group in the afternoon.”

“Ah yes, your study group,” Rita said. “Quite a bit of luck, having a Hogwarts professor teach you over the summer, isn’t it?”

Harry shrugged. The Ministry records were, of course, open to the public, and Rita was displaying an unnerving tendency for having done her homework on him this time around. “He was a good friend to my parents, so I suppose I had an in there. Of course, the underage magic laws are not really fair to the Muggle-born students, since they don’t really have access to tutors who can train them over the summer.”

“Perhaps,” Rita agreed, “but it is the law. On the other hand, do you think it will be hard for him to mark you fairly during the coming term?”

Harry sighed. “Remus Lupin is what I would call a ‘tough but fair’ teacher. If anything, I’m afraid he’s going to expect more from us than he will from the other students. In the end, though, what will really matter is what I get on my Defence O.W.L. and N.E.W.T.”

“You’re already worrying about those?” Rita asked. “Your O.W.L. exams are not for almost three years, correct?”

Harry nodded. “Perhaps, but I’m always looking forward.”

“Is that why you started a… Duelling Association, I think it was, at Hogwarts?”

“I didn’t really create it,” Harry said diffidently. “Professor McGonagall is the faculty sponsor, and she established most of the curriculum.”

“You are far too modest, Harry!” Rita said with a somewhat predatory smile. “I understand that you teach most of the sessions, and that you’ve become quite an accomplished duellist yourself!”

Harry felt his stomach roll over. Who the hell had she been talking to? “Well, I only came in second in the tournament at the end of the year,” he temporized. “I suppose I was inspired by Gilderoy Lockhart,” he said.

Rita’s eyebrows rose at this. “How so?” she asked.

Harry didn’t know what kind of favours or currency Lockhart’s publicist had used to keep Rita from pressing charges against his comatose client, but Harry doubted anything he said would be included. “Well, he tried to organize a duelling club right before winter holiday, but it was a complete shambles. The man didn’t know the first thing about it and Professor Snape trounced him without even trying. That, among other things, clued me in that whatever he might be teaching us in his classes was extremely suspect.”

“So you are pleased that he is to be replaced this year with Professor Lupin?” Rita asked archly.

“Words cannot convey the depth of my gratitude that I will not have to sit another class with that utter fraud,” Harry said firmly.

That earned him a smile. “You said earlier that you came in second in a duelling tournament… who won?” Rita asked.

“That would be Ginny Weasley,” Harry said as Arthur let out a sigh.

Rita looked faintly surprised. Harry mused that she apparently hadn’t consulted her source since the end of term. “How did you feel about being defeated by a witch who is, I believe, a year younger than you?”

Harry shrugged. “She’s a founding member of the Duelling Association and she’s dead quick with her wand. I tried to snag her legs, but she leapt over the spell and Stunned me senseless while she was in midair. It was a beautiful move.”

“She also lives at The Burrow, doesn’t she?” Rita asked. “Is there a bit of romance brewing for you, Harry?”

Harry tried not to let any tension show as he sensed Rita falling into habits he knew all too well. He very carefully avoided looking over at Arthur. “Er, we often get stuck together on kitchen duty. But she’s not the only witch to join the Duelling Association. Hermione Granger and Luna Lovegood also helped found it, and we have students from all houses and years now. And I’m a little young to have a girlfriend yet.”

“Why all the sudden interest in duelling by Hogwarts students?” Rita asked, smoothly ignoring his glare. “It’s been outlawed by the Ministry as a way of settling disputes for many years now.”

Harry took a deep breath as he formulated his answer. “Well, Rita, an accomplished duellist is far more capable of defending themselves from attack than an untrained witch or wizard. If anything, the last war should have taught us that it doesn’t hurt to be too careful.”

“I see,” Rita said, watching the quill move. “How are you adjusting to your new home?”

Harry smiled. “I feel very fortunate that the Weasleys took me in. They are a great family and they’ve gone out of their way to make me feel at home. I’ll be a lifetime paying back what I owe them.”

Arthur’s face turned very red at this and he opened his mouth to protest, but glanced at the quill and shut it quickly. Harry smiled at him fondly.

“I understand that the decision regarding where you would live was rather hotly contested at the Ministry,” Rita said, her eyes glittering behind her bejewelled spectacles.

It occurred to Harry that this was probably why she got into journalism in the first place. She genuinely enjoyed the thrill of the hunt as she put people on the spot and winnowed out all their secrets. Even in this setting, with all she had to lose by antagonizing her interview subject, she couldn’t completely suppress that side of her nature. Instead of opposing it, it occurred to him that it might be better to point her at more deserving targets and then get the hell out of the way. “Yes, it was,” he replied. “Lucius Malfoy tried to have me delivered to his mansion so I could be brought up to hate Muggles and non-pure-bloods like that murderous thief he calls a son. Fortunately, Madam Bones saw through his design and assigned me to more suitable guardians.”

Rita blinked and her mouth dropped open slightly. “That’s quite an accusation,” she said carefully. Arthur just stared at him.

Harry nodded. “The incident that precipitated my removal from the Dursleys occurred when someone sent me a box full of angry Doxies on my birthday. I was bitten and poisoned, and my familiar nearly blinded. As you can imagine, for a family that disliked and feared magic, this was the last straw. As the sole wizard in a Muggle house, I was, of course, monitored for magic use. Defending myself, I risked expulsion from Hogwarts and the destruction of my wand.”

Rita’s face was rapt as her quill moved over the parchment, so Harry doubted she’d learned all these details.

“When I mentioned this incident at the Ministry hearing, and how I’d been rescued by the Weasleys, Mr. Malfoy’s fury was clearly visible. As a member of the Hogwarts Board of Governors, he was no doubt ready to have me expelled at the first hint of trouble. Fortunately, the investigating Auror had the charges dismissed under the self-defence clause.” Harry took a deep breath to collect himself. “His son, Draco, was also involved in my injuries this past term. I was hit in the back with a Stunning Spell while climbing a flight of stairs. I didn’t see my attacker, but I did hear him and Draco’s nasal twang is very distinctive.”

“Why would he do something like that?” Rita asked as she placed a fresh sheet of parchment under the quill.

“He needed me out of the way so he could use a Polyjuice Potion to impersonate me and burgle my dormitory. He stole a family heirloom and some other items that were used in an attempt to murder another student the day you arrived at Hogwarts.”

Rita just stared at him for a moment. “Can you prove any of this?” she asked.

“Only indirectly,” Harry admitted. “Draco was caught red-handed with the item that was stolen from my trunk and was expelled for it. As for the rest of it, the timing of certain events doesn’t allow for any other interpretations.”

“If you are so certain, why wasn’t this brought to the Department of Magical Law Enforcement?” Rita asked.

“Well,” Harry explained, “I knew that without overwhelming evidence, it would be useless.”

Rita paused, frowning. “Would you care to explain why, Mr. Potter?”

“Certainly,” Harry said. “As you can imagine, when I became aware of the Magical World and my place within it, I read every book I could find on recent history, especially with regards to the war. The more I read, the more I came to one inescapable conclusion.” He knew he was being a trifle theatrical, but his audience seemed to appreciate a little showmanship.

“And what conclusion was that?” Rita asked, her eyes glittering.

“As a whole, the Wizarding World is almost irretrievably corrupt,” Harry declared. Out of the corner of his eye, he saw Arthur turn to stare at him again.

“Can you elaborate, Harry?” Rita asked.

Harry shrugged. “One of the first things I looked up was what happened to Voldemort’s followers. Naturally, I was wondering who I needed to keep an eye out for. I noticed something rather odd… All of Voldemort’s followers who were captured before he disappeared went to Azkaban and, with very few exceptions, never repudiated him. But after his disappearance, practically every captured Death Eater claimed to have been placed under the Imperius Curse, and most were released by the Ministry. That’s quite a statistical anomaly, isn’t it?” He pretended to ignore the start Rita gave when he used the Dark Lord’s name.

“So you maintain that those claims were false? And that they were willing followers of He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named?” Rita asked.

“It’s awfully fishy, isn’t it?” Harry observed. “Besides that, I looked up some old articles in Forensic Thaumaturgy regarding the Dark Mark. The terminology is pretty dense, but it implies that it’s a modified version of the Protean Charm, and according to my N.E.W.T. study guide, the Protean Charm is awfully fussy. Casting it on an unwilling magical subject or one already subjected to powerful magic like an Unforgivable Curse would be nearly impossible.”

Rita’s eyes were wide as the quill continued taking down Harry’s words. “And so with respect to the Ministry…?”

“Well, it’s obvious, isn’t it?” Harry said. “Those forgiven Death Eaters were all from wealthy and influential families, or were closely allied with them. Money and/or favours had to change hands for that many people to drop the ball and let them go free. But that’s just the tip of the iceberg. Look at my godfather, and the Ministry’s complete failure to give him a trial while he rotted in Azkaban — for a crime he never committed. Look at the goblins, treated as second-class citizens, despite the vital role they play in the Wizarding economy. Look at house-elves, who are treated even worse. Sometimes I wonder if the Statute of Secrecy isn’t maintained more to prevent the Ministry from being scrutinized too closely by the Muggle governments. By Muggle standards, I’m afraid the Wizarding world would be considered hopelessly backward and barbaric.”

Rita’s eyes were bulging now, though Harry couldn’t blame her. She’d just watched the Boy Who Lived declare war on half of the Wizarding world.

Harry was very stiff and absolutely famished by the time they were done. They left Rita with a fat stack of parchment. Her photographer arrived near the end of the interview and Harry reluctantly allowed them to take a picture of him sitting with Rita. He tried to look as calm as he wasn’t.

Afterwards, they took the stairs back down to the tap room. Arthur led him to the back wall, where he quickly tapped the bricks and opened the passage into Diagon Alley.

The Alley was already full of families purchasing school supplies and various sundries. To Harry’s surprise, Arthur led him to Florean Fortescue’s ice cream parlour, where he purchased both of them an ice cream sundae.

“Ordinarily, this isn’t my idea of a proper luncheon,” Arthur said quietly as they sat down at a table in the back, “but you look rather worn out. Just don’t say anything to Molly, all right?” He looked left and right. “I sometimes duck in here when work has been particularly vexing.”

Harry nodded wearily and smiled. “Your secret is safe with me,” he said.

“I just hope you don’t have to do that again any time soon,” Arthur said, frowning. “That woman was absolutely insatiable with all her questions. I mean, why should she even care if you wear boxers or briefs? You’re thirteen years old!”

Harry shrugged, glad he hadn’t brought up other issues. “I think she may be planning to sell a story to Witch Weekly as well; that question sounds right up their alley. I suppose I can’t blame her for trying to get as much mileage out of this as possible.”

“Perhaps,” Arthur said dubiously. “Harry, I do hope you know what you are doing. When that interview is published, you’re going to make a lot of very powerful enemies.”

Harry nodded, and then leaned forward, lowering his voice to little more than a whisper. “I know. But the way I see it, it’s inevitable. Do you know what the Ministry did the first year after Voldemort returned?”

Arthur shook his head.

“They attacked me and Dumbledore for making up stories. Dumbledore was removed from most of the offices he held, and the Daily Prophet published story after story about how I was a mentally unstable, attention-seeking liar,” Harry said, his eyes hardening. “It was a nasty surprise when Fudge turned on Dumbledore, and the free year Riddle was given to build up his forces cost us dearly. The Ministry didn’t even fight until Dumbledore and Voldemort duelled in the Atrium practically in front of Fudge. By then, Tom was nearly ready anyway, and his second reign of terror started where the first one left off.”

Arthur looked sick.

“I’m just striking first this time. Right now, Fudge barely goes to the bathroom without Lucius Malfoy’s permission. Both of them have got to go. And if they start their smear campaign second… well, then it just looks like payback — and people might not take everything they claim about me as the gospel truth.” Harry looked down at his melting ice cream. “I don’t see a better way to stop them than taking the offensive.”

“I understand, Harry,” Arthur said. “But I hope you are ready for the repercussions from this.”

“I’ve been publicly vilified before,” he replied, “I’m sort of used to it by now. And Rita knows that if she wants any more from me, she’ll keep your name out of this. If anyone approaches you at work, you’re not sure, but you think we made contact through owl post, and you don’t want it to get back to her that you’ve forbidden us to communicate. You can also imply that Dumbledore is involved.”

Arthur raised an eyebrow at him. “That’s hardly honest,” he said.

“No, it isn’t,” Harry agreed. “But anyone asking you to silence me is at least probably an enemy. You planted disinformation during the first war when you were part of the Order, didn’t you?”

Arthur’s eyes bulged in their sockets for a moment. “How did you-? No, never mind. You’re right, though, I suppose this really is a wartime situation.” He sighed. “I’d hoped my children would never see it in their lifetimes.”

Harry nodded. “The Horcrux situation made it likely we would, and the Ministry guaranteed it. But maybe, if we do it right, your grandchildren won’t.”

32

Fear and Loathing

Fortunately, the remainder of their day at Diagon Alley passed with a bit less drama. Mrs. Weasley and Mrs. Granger arrived with Hermione and the Weasley children just after noon, and Harry and Arthur met them in front of Gringotts as planned.

Books and supplies were purchased as they fought through the crowds of school children and their parents. While Harry recognized many of the younger faces, he was pleasantly surprised by the occasional smile or greeting from fellow Hogwarts students. He didn’t remember being that popular before, which made it rather odd. Was it the Quidditch victories, or had some hint of the events surrounding Draco’s expulsion made it onto the grapevine?

At least no one here seemed to be bent on avenging that loss. While he saw several Slytherin students, most of them maintained carefully neutral expressions. No one from the Quidditch team or Draco’s inner circle made an appearance, for which he was glad.

Another deviation for this trip was a quick errand Harry and Arthur ran to Chisam’s Captivating Cases to look at some magical luggage. He definitely didn’t want a repeat of last term’s burglary — he was just lucky Draco hadn’t found the Glock, or, if he had, didn’t know what it was.

Just thinking about that made him shudder.

Knowing that this was one area in which he mustn’t cut any corners, Harry made sure to withdraw a goodly sum from his vault after the interview. Arthur Weasley eyed the bulging sack of Galleons curiously, but didn’t say anything as they left the lobby of Gringotts.

Chisam’s shopfront looked a bit dusty and out of date, but it was the only one on the Alley that specialized in magical luggage. There were some businesses on the continent that did custom orders by Owl Post, but Harry didn’t really want to return to Hogwarts without secure storage for his belongings. He kicked himself for not thinking about this sooner, but they’d been so busy while on holiday this year…

He shook his head to clear it of regrets, lips twisting at the irony of such a sentiment, and pushed open the door.

The shop was dimly lit, the walls lined with shelves holding trunks, cases, and valises of all shapes and sizes. A bell attached to the door rang softly as they entered, and a dark-haired young wizard in his twenties stepped out of the back room. “Can I help you?” he asked in a pleasant voice.

“Mr. Chisam?” Arthur asked curiously.

“My father,” the younger man explained. “I’m standing in for him while he and Mum are on holiday. Can I help you with something?”

“Er, yes,” Mr. Weasley answered. “My ward here had his trunk broken into last term, and we’re looking for something a bit more secure.”

Harry barely followed the conversation, as his eyes drifted toward a dusty black trunk that had four identical combination latches holding the lid shut. A vague memory stirred at the back of his mind. “What kind of trunk is that?” he asked, pointing toward the one that had seized his interest.

“Ah,” Chisam the younger exclaimed, “I’m afraid that may be a bit out of your budget. That’s one of the smaller Auror models. Extremely secure, but a bit pricey you know. We have…”

“Why does it have four locks?” Harry asked suddenly, as he remembered a larger version that had belonged to a certain retired Auror.

The clerk seemed a bit taken aback by the question. “Well, it’s considerably larger on the inside than the outside, and depending on which lock is opened first, you can access four different coexisting storage spaces.”

Harry, his suspicions confirmed, nodded happily. “How much?” he asked.

Mr. Chisam sighed and quoted a figure. “As you can see,” he added reluctantly, “it’s not really priced for the student market.”

“If you can add a charm that will let me tell when someone’s been tampering with it, you have a deal.”

Arthur didn’t say or ask anything, other than looking vaguely amused, as Harry and Mr. Chisam haggled over the minor details. But as they left the shop, he asked in a low voice, “I assume there’s a purpose behind this?”

Harry nodded. “I still have a few things I need to keep secure,” he answered cryptically. “And with the extra spaces… well, I’m sure it will come in handy. We can move things forward a bit without revealing too much to our room-mates.”

Arthur nodded slowly, digesting this. “Well, I suppose this would be a good investment for the future, if you plan to travel when this is all over.”

Harry shrugged. “I’m not really thinking that far ahead, but you are right.”

Arthur frowned, but didn’t say anything.

In fact, they were both quiet until they rejoined the group led by Molly and the Grangers. The rest of their expedition passed as usual, though Harry did spend most of the remaining galleons at Flourish & Blotts. The manager also gave him a hefty discount after Harry showed him how to calm down the animated copies of the Monster Book of Monsters. Harry couldn’t help but smile as he stroked the spine of the copy a scared-looking Hufflepuff purchased, lulling it into somnolence. Hagrid had assigned this book, so it looked like their revelation of the true monster from the Chamber had cleared his name in this timeline as well.

At one point, Harry thought he saw Augusta Longbottom’s vulture hat sticking up from the press of people near Gringotts, but he didn’t say anything. Luna was with them, and seemed to be a bit cheerier than before, but the letters she exchanged with Neville had come less frequently as his grandmother seemed to monopolize more and more of his time. At least that’s what Neville implied in his last letter. In any case, Harry didn’t want another public confrontation with Neville’s gran until he had a better handle on things. They’d see their friend soon enough on the Express.

Of course, as soon as she got him semi-alone, Molly asked him how things had gone with Rita Skeeter. Unfortunately, Harry’s reply of “about how I expected” wasn’t as reassuring a response as she seemed to be hoping for. Harry also noticed the concerned glance she shot at Arthur. He wasn’t that good at reading this byplay, but he got the impression she was now just as disturbed as her husband. He wondered if there would be another long conversation after dinner that evening.

Albus Dumbledore slowly put down his copy of the special edition of the Daily Prophet. His eyes stared off into space as he frowned, and he opened his desk drawer and retrieved a light blue potion. Madam Pomfrey had presented him with a set of mild pain-relieving potions after Minerva had seen him rub at his temples one time too many during a staff meeting. Even with his glasses, he was occasionally subject to a touch of eyestrain, and reviewing the joint budget allocations seemed to be quite sufficient to present him with a pounding headache.

But his current migraine had nothing to do with finances.

He barely registered the taste as he drank the potion, his mind still trying to make sense of everything he’d just read. The boy’s statements were true, perhaps too much so. His bluntness, recorded with great glee by Ms. Skeeter’s quill, was going to cause all manner of problems, both for the boy and for himself.

But the Headmaster was forced to admit that Harry’s rage was more than understandable. He and his friends had been targeted quite deliberately last term, victims of a plot that nearly cost Harry and the Weasley girl their lives. His violent response to the ambush at the end of the term made even more sense in that context, and he began to wish he’d handled things differently.

Harry’s response to these attacks seemed somewhat childish… publicly calling out the Dark-aligned pure-blood families like the Malfoys, attacking those he blamed for not having done more in years past. While his anger was justifiable, Albus Dumbledore did not see what the boy hoped to gain in doing all this. When he returned to Hogwarts he’d be an even bigger target than before, and not only from Voldemort’s former servants. The Ministry would not take this lying down, by any means. He did not look forward to his next meeting with Cornelius — he had no doubt the man would suspect him of playing a role in this. He’d resented Albus not allowing Harry to become a ward of the Ministry after the deaths of his parents, and this interview would, to him, be a justification of his most paranoid fears.

There was little doubt in Professor Dumbledore’s mind that this would drive a wedge between Hogwarts and the Ministry. But what he couldn’t fathom was why this was happening.

Hermione stayed at The Burrow that night, sharing Ginny’s room. In the interests of both convenience and security, the Weasleys offered to bring the Muggle-born girl with them to catch the Hogwarts Express. Since they still had no idea who’d sent the Dementors, Harry could find no fault in their logic.

Molly Weasley was a bit old-fashioned in many ways, and seemed to feel more comfortable drafting the girls to pitch in for dinner. Since Luna had gone home for one last dinner with her father, this meant Hermione received an impromptu review on household charms. Harry was quietly amused, watching Hermione’s feminist sensibilities go to war with her desire to learn new things.

Dinner was prepared without too much drama and, as he expected, afterward he was asked to stay in the kitchen to discuss the interview. He knew Molly likely wouldn’t approve of some of the things he’d done, but he did catch her a little off balance when he asked that Percy be present for the discussion.

Harry was also inwardly pleased that Sirius was lingering around the kitchen as well. The Weasleys might be his legal guardians, but his godfather was taking his responsibility quite seriously.

By the time he was done explaining his reasons for the pre-emptive strike, Mrs. Weasley wasn’t completely convinced, but admitted she could see the sense of his plan. Percy was disturbed to hear of how far the Ministry had sunk in the future timeline, but he did ask a relevant question.

“Why didn’t you discuss this with us ahead of time, if you were planning to do it all along?” he asked in that fussy tone that seemed to drive his brothers wild.

Fortunately, Harry wasn’t his brother. “I wasn’t sure I would be able to do it, not at first. Rita was far more cooperative than I expected. This won’t work if she distorts or blunts my words — I made some very specific accusations that will be hard to directly refute. But if she wasn’t sincerely cooperative, well, it would have been wasted effort.”

Percy nodded slowly as he digested this. Sirius’ tight grin needed no explanation.

Eventually, Harry was off the hook and sent off to bed for the early start they had tomorrow. As he passed Ginny’s door, he thought he heard muted voices. Shaking his head, he continued on toward the room he shared with Ron.

Girl talk; he was probably better off not knowing.

When they arrived the next day at King’s Cross, Harry was a little surprised to see Aurors stationed all around the platform. A pair of very serious-looking men stared at them as they passed through the barrier, and Harry had to resist the urge to slip his wand into his hand.

Arthur, who’d taken the day off to drive them in to London, was grim-faced, but didn’t appear to be surprised. Harry caught his eye and raised an eyebrow.

“There’ve been rumours in the Daily Prophet,” he murmured as he bent down to straighten Harry’s new trunk. “Sirius Black has been reported to be skulking around Hogsmeade and was once seen near the train station.”

Harry frowned. He knew those sightings to be false — Sirius hadn’t stirred from The Burrow since his close call on Harry’s birthday, mostly at Harry’s insistence. Someone was planting those rumours for their own purposes. He just didn’t know why. What he did know was that he was very glad Arthur had talked Sirius into staying at The Burrow. Even as Padfoot, it would have been far too risky for him to accompany them.

Under the watchful eyes of the Aurors, their goodbyes were quieter and shorter than they might have been. Harry’s uneasiness seemed to be contagious.

By unspoken agreement, they all moved toward the train as a group. Even on the crowded platform, Harry noted with pride, they all stayed together. Aside from keeping an eye on the Aurors, Harry also tried to find Neville or Augusta in the crowd. But his search proved fruitless by the time they boarded.

To their surprise, the last compartment was already occupied. Professor Lupin was there, a new valise stowed in the overhead luggage shelf. Harry smiled at their mentor, but his grin grew even wider when he saw who Remus had been speaking to.

“Neville!” a mixture of voices exclaimed, making the stocky boy jump. Harry wondered fleetingly if being isolated all summer had affected their friend’s confidence.

Ron, of course, broke the ice in his usual manner.

“Good to see you, mate. Now give me a hand with the trunks.”

Harry stifled a snicker and Hermione sighed, but Ron’s demand seemed to snap Neville out of it. In short order, they had everyone’s luggage stowed… but then the compartment grew quiet as they all looked at each other.

Harry was about to open his mouth when Luna beat him to it.

“I’m sorry about your summer, Neville,” she said in a very small voice.

Neville frowned and his mouth dropped open for a moment before he spoke.

“Like I told you before,” he finally said, “it’s not your fault. This is just something I have to work out with my gran.”

“But if I hadn’t—” she began before Neville cut her off, something Harry ordinarily never saw the boy do.

“You had no way of knowing,” the dark-haired boy insisted. “I didn’t see this coming and I grew up with her. So, stop it,” he demanded. “Er, please?”

Harry was uncomfortably reminded of a conversation from summer of last year…

Luna bit her lip and looked down, nodding.

Harry guessed he was seeing a replay of their letters, but it was still somewhat painful to watch. Professor Lupin watched the whole thing with a slight smile, making Harry wonder how long Remus and Neville had talked before they arrived.

The train whistle blew again, signalling the last call for passengers. Everyone took a seat. Harry noticed Remus had today’s Daily Prophet, so he angled for the spot next to the man, wondering if the interview had been printed yet.

Ginny flounced down between him and the window, but it was her elbow that got his attention as he was turning toward Remus. Harry turned back and saw Neville softly pat the bench next to him as he looked at Luna with one eyebrow raised. The blonde girl nodded and took her seat next to him.

Ginny sighed happily and Harry suppressed a grin of his own. Luna had been unusually apprehensive for most of the summer, so it was good to see that her fears seemed, for the most part, to be unfounded.

His good mood became a bit strained as he read the headlines over Remus’ elbow.

“Boy Who Lived Attacks Ministry, Pure-bloods.”

Harry suppressed his habitual annoyance at the title society seemed overjoyed to bestow upon him. He supposed it would rankle less if it had been based on something he’d actually done, or even remembered. At his snort of amusement, Remus folded the paper and Harry apologized for reading over his arm.

The professor gave him a tired grin. “Here,” he said, handing Harry the paper. “I’m a bit tired, as you can guess, so I’ll just take a nap.”

Harry nodded slowly. Last night had been a full moon, so he was wondering why Professor Lupin was riding the Express. Harry knew that Professor Dumbledore began supplying him with Wolfsbane Potion as soon as he had accepted the position at Hogwarts, but even when kept artificially calm, the transformation itself was physically draining. “Go ahead,” Harry said earnestly. “I’m surprised you didn’t go on ahead to the castle.”

“Normally I would,” Remus replied, cracking a wan smile. “But the Headmaster asked that a couple of professors ride with the Express, just in case.”

Harry frowned. “Is it these stories about Sirius Black that have him concerned?” he whispered. “Surely he doesn’t believe…”

Remus shook his head. “No, he doesn’t. But others do. And there is a lot of pressure being brought to bear. Some measures…” He shook his head as he yawned widely. “Pardon me. I’ll get up when the cart comes by and check in with Professor Sprout. In the meantime, I’d ask that you and your friends keep your eyes open. If anything, and I mean anything, odd occurs, please wake me immediately.”

Harry nodded firmly. He was touched when he realized why Remus had chosen to sit in their usual car. They’d be his eyes while he recovered from his monthly ordeal. “You can count on us,” Harry said.

“I know I can,” Remus said as he settled back in his seat and drifted off.

Out of deference to their tutor’s slumber, they decided to forgo their normal game of Exploding Snap. Instead, they either read quietly or gazed out the windows as the Express drove north under the increasingly overcast skies.

Harry tried not to think too much about the ‘some measures’ Remus had mentioned in passing. He had a feeling he’d find out all too soon.

Instead he tried to read ahead for his lessons, which was easier said than done. Ancient Runes Made Easy seemed anything but, and Numerology and Gramatica wasn’t exactly light reading either.

All the same, it was the first time he’d been exposed to something he didn’t at least half-remember from his older self’s memories. Learning something completely new would be a challenge, which was part of the reason why he’d been so interested in signing up for different electives this time around.

The other part was a little more practical. When they’d embarked on the ill-fated Horcrux Hunt, Hermione insisted on bringing a couple of her N.E.W.T.-level textbooks. He and Ron acquiesced, more out of deference to their friend’s bookish nature than anything else. It wasn’t until she began creating customized versions of different charms and spells that they realized that her wishes were rooted in wholly practical ground.

Being able to retrieve a Horcrux without losing a limb was more than enough to make a believer out of Harry.

Hermione was just a trifle smug as she explained how she used what she learned in two of her favourite classes to calculate the wand motions, incantations, and other configurations necessary to change a simple cutting charm into a spray of razor-sharp shards of magical energy. Her new version, though far more destructive, was also much more draining. But that was the trade-off, she’d explained to them. The real science of spell creation was to get the maximum effect for the least energy and effort. Harry thought it sounded more like an art, the way she described it, but he wasn’t about to argue with the smartest person he knew.

They still had a little time while Voldemort didn’t have a body… a little longer before the second war truly started. Harry hoped that he and the others, working with Hermione, might give them more of an edge before things came to a head.

Between trying to get a head start on Arithmancy, subtly watching Neville and Luna quietly converse, and occasionally dozing off, time passed quickly for Harry as the Hogwarts Express drove north.

The skies overhead grew steadily darker and more overcast, and he tried to suppress a shudder. He had an idea of the ‘measures’ the Ministry was taking, but he hoped he was wrong.

As the rain began and the late afternoon became as dark as twilight, Harry stared apprehensively at the windows. Still, the train continued moving, and his heart began to lighten. They were well past the point where the Dementors had stopped them the first time around when he let out a relieved sigh.

Ginny looked at him curiously, but didn’t ask.

The sight of familiar hills in the distance made Harry smile — they were near their destination.

At first, Harry thought they were slowing for the Hogsmeade station, but the train was braking too much, too early for that to be the case. The train came to a halt a little more than a mile away from Hogsmeade. He peered out the window, dreading what he would discover.

When dark-cloaked figures began to emerge from the misty gloom, Harry frantically reached for the wand strapped to his wrist. But a sudden thought stopped him. Conjuring a Patronus here and now would lead to far too many questions that he didn’t want to answer — even from Remus.

As the Dementors approached, a chill seemed to seep through the windows to find a home in Harry’s bones. Despite that, he tried to make himself relax. Professor Lupin and Professor Sprout were with the train for a reason. The Dementors were only supposed to be looking for Sirius Black.

Harry deliberately took his hand off his wand and began concentrating on reinforcing his Occlumency barriers. He hoped that would at least make it harder for the creatures to dredge up his worst memories.

But there were just so many for them to choose from…

Harry stumbled back to his seat. “I’m not feeling too well,” he murmured as the lights switched off. Faintly at first, but growing ever louder, he heard the murmur of voices wailing with grief and loss, punctuated by explosions. One of those voices, he knew, was his own. He tried to sink deeper and deeper within himself, isolating his mind, protecting it. But the sounds grew steadily louder.

He felt Ginny’s hand on his arm as a more personal darkness claimed him.

When he regained consciousness, the lights were on again and the train felt like it was just slowing to a stop. He blinked and heard Ginny let out a sigh of relief.

“He’s awake now,” she announced in a hoarse whisper.

“Are you all right, Harry?” Professor Lupin asked, leaning over him with a concerned expression on his face.

Harry nodded and slowly sat up.

“Here, eat all of this,” Lupin said in a no-nonsense tone of voice as he handed Harry a large bar of Honeydukes chocolate.

Harry accepted the bar without expression. He blinked and snapped his head up, glancing at his friends. All were present and accounted for within the car.

“They’re all right, Harry,” Professor Lupin assured him. “You had, by far, the worst reaction.”

Harry sighed. “Without the wards in the way… I heard them dying,” he whispered.

Lupin’s face went grey, but he just nodded as this seemed to confirm what he suspected. Hermione’s swift intake of breath was shockingly loud in the silence. Only the low murmur of passengers in neighbouring cars reminded them of where they were.

Ginny’s hand tightened on Harry’s and he wasn’t embarrassed to realize that she’d been holding it all this time. He squeezed back before letting go. His fingers mechanically tore open the paper on the chocolate. It wasn’t until the warmth began to spread from his stomach that he realized how cold he’d been.

He looked up when Hermione cleared her throat. Like the others, she was still looking a little washed out, but her jaw was set in a determined line. “I think we should all practise a bit more on the Patronus Charm,” she said firmly.

No one disagreed.

The Gryffindor Six, as they came to be known, were still a bit subdued when they parted company from Professor Lupin and made their way to one of the carriages for the short ride to the castle. Fortunately, no one insisted that Harry needed to visit Madam Pomfrey, or otherwise made a big deal about his passing out. Slipping into a sort of trance was a bit less embarrassing than collapsing in a fit, but the fact remained that, without his Patronus, he was much more susceptible to Dementors than his friends.

Most of their fellow students also seemed less than pleased at encountering the creatures. Several of the younger students were still visibly upset, or appeared afraid. Not that they didn’t have good reason.

Harry’s spirits didn’t completely revive until dinner, when Dumbledore’s announcements began. The Headmaster’s displeasure at having Dementors near his school was quite apparent to Harry. Dumbledore’s warnings about the foul creatures surrounding the grounds and patrolling Hogsmeade didn’t reassure the frightened students in the slightest. Harry could pick up a few faint flashes of anger in those twinkling blue eyes and knew he’d been forced to accept them, just as before. He hoped no one was foolish enough to try and sneak past the quartet guarding the gates in this timeline.

Harry wondered if he could see the Headmaster’s anger easier now or maybe it was because the old man knew the so-called ‘threat’ posed by Sirius Black was a fabrication.

In any event, Dumbledore had his professional demeanour firmly in place when he announced the new faculty members. The reactions to these announcements, however, varied widely.

When it was announced that Professor Emeritus Horace Slughorn was returning to teach Potions, there was scattered applause from all tables. Harry had no doubt that many students had parents who were protégés of Slughorn — the man’s contacts were scattered far and wide throughout Wizarding Society, and those parents no doubt alerted their children to the opportunities he represented. For his own part, Harry made a show of politely clapping his hands. For an instant, the round little man caught Harry’s eye, and the Boy That Lived knew he’d been marked. He chuckled. Smarminess aside, anything would be better than Snape.

That good mood improved further when Professor Dumbledore announced Hagrid’s appointment as professor for Care of Magical Creatures. Harry stood up as he applauded, followed by his friends, and soon most of the Gryffindor table had joined in. Hagrid’s face was red as a tomato by the time they’d quieted down.

The introduction of Remus Lupin was curiously mixed as well. As with Hagrid, the Slytherin table seemed determined to ignore him, while the Gryffindors acknowledged him as a former alumnus. Several of the Ravenclaws and Hufflepuffs who’d seen him handle the Dementors were likewise enthusiastic in their endorsement of the new Defence Against the Dark Arts professor.

After the meal, they sought out Hagrid to congratulate him on his new position.

“It’s all thanks you,” he said thickly as he gently patted Harry’s shoulder, nearly driving him to his knees. “With you lot discoverin’ what really happen wit’ th’ Chamber and all…” He visibly caught himself before he said more than he should. “Well, Professor Dumbledore lobbied the Board of Governors to reverse my expulsion. Great man, he is! I can even get a wand now, if I want to.”

“Will you?” Harry asked quickly.

“I dunno,” Hagrid said, frowning uncertainly. “It’s been a long time since my last classes, I probably forgot everthin’…”

“Hagrid,” Hermione interjected. “That’s no reason not to try! It’s not your fault you were wrongfully accused, and it’s despicable how you were punished with no real proof… But it will be your fault if you don’t do something about it now. Don’t you want to learn magic?” she asked. Harry noticed Ron ducking his head down, refusing to meet the eyes of their classmates as they filed past them toward the dormitories.

Hermione was on a tear, but Harry knew she was right. “She’s got a point there, Hagrid. If you don’t learn magic now, then Tom Riddle will have won in the end, right?”

Hagrid’s eyes flashed darkly at the mention of his old classmate. “Yer righ’, both of ye. I’ll talk to Professor Dumbledore right now.”

Harry smiled widely as he watched Hagrid march back up to the head table. Though their words were inaudible, Harry noticed the Headmaster’s eyebrows lift slightly in surprise, and then a faint smile creased his face. He nodded slowly as he spoke, but his eyes wandered past the bulky form of his groundskeeper… and found Harry’s. Dumbledore’s face didn’t change expression, but he did make a fractional nod before Harry turned away.

Not for the first time, Harry wished his own Legilimency was up to the task of reading the old wizard’s thoughts. Did he understand? Was he finally getting with the program? Or was he just trying to draw Harry out? But there were no easy answers for the Boy Who Lived, so he was left frozen with indecision.

“You seem to have had quite an effect on him,” a quiet voice observed.

Harry flinched in spite of himself, spinning around to see Professor Slughorn standing right behind him. The old man’s gooseberry-coloured eyes seemed to bore into Harry’s, but he didn’t feel the slightest touch of Legilimency. Then a smile lifted the corners of the huge silvery moustache. “It’s odd to finally be meeting you at last,” Slughorn said in an unctuous tone.

“Er, yeah,” Harry stammered.

“Don’t worry,” the short little man assured him. “I’m over here to warn you off about pursuing any vendettas against members of my house, and threaten to have you removed from Hogwarts if there are any more incidents like last year.”

Harry’s uneasy smile froze in place as Ron began to sputter.

“Of course,” Slughorn continued, “that’s what I let them believe I was doing when I came over here. You know, line in the sand and all that. I taught that same technique to Madam Bagnold back before she became Minister. She didn’t forget it either — gave me advance notice on all kinds of things. Saved me a Galleon or two on my investments, let me tell you!”

Harry blinked. A ruse. He wondered if his mind was still foggy from the Dementors.

“Anyway, I’ve let it be known that I’m going to have it out with you, and when I hold the next House meeting, they’ll know that I got you to agree to suspend all hostilities, as long as they don’t start anything new. That is what Professor Dumbledore said you wanted, yes? To be left alone?” Slughorn waggled his eyebrows in such a comical fashion that Harry heard Ginny squeak beside him.

Harry nodded. “That’s all we’ve ever—”

“Good! Good!” Slughorn enthused. “Of course, after a couple of weeks, we’ll have to work on some social activities to thaw out relations between Slytherin and Gryffindor. You’ll work with me on that, right, Harry?” Slughorn asked in an innocently earnest tone.

Harry sighed. He knew from the moment he wrote the retired Potions Master that this would be a consequence. There was no escaping the Slug Club. “We’ll be happy to, Professor. All of us.”

“That’s the spirit, Harry!” Slughorn commended him. “People are already talking about you and your friends. ‘Gryffindor Six’, ‘top marks in their year’, I tell you, Harry, with my help, you’ll go far!” Then he cleared his throat and glanced back toward the Slytherin table. Harry could see several people watching this conversation with varying degrees of subtlety. “Right!” Slughorn continued in a louder voice. “See that it doesn’t!”

With chin raised, and moustache aquiver, the Head of Slytherin house returned to his table and led them out of the Great Hall.

“D’you think any of them fell for that?” Ron asked dubiously.

“They followed Draco, didn’t they?” Harry shot back. Ron shrugged.

Mindful of the milling crowds of students, they were quiet as they made their way up to the Gryffindor tower. Percy gave them a small nod as he concluded his lecture to the first-year students. Harry wasn’t sure if it was his imagination or not, but the Head Boy didn’t seem to act nearly as pompous as he remembered from the original timeline. Had Harry’s revelations about corruption within the Ministry shaken the boy’s confidence, at least a little? If this was the effect, he wasn’t really sure he minded… he’d have to keep an eye on Fred and George as well. He knew the estrangement between Percy and his family wasn’t entirely one-sided.

Harry shook his head as he almost stumbled going up the stairs. There would be time enough to think about that tomorrow, perhaps when he was feeling a bit sharper. He nodded hello to Seamus and Dean as they entered the third-years’ room, but made a bee-line for his new trunk. He was barely able to refrain from yawning as he dressed for bed and lay down. The low murmur of Ron and Seamus talking Quidditch as he pulled the curtains shut was almost soothing, in an odd way.

Harry soon discovered that there was at least one positive side to the ordeal he had undergone on the train… he was so exhausted, mentally and emotionally, that he was asleep the instant his head touched the pillow and had no dreams at all that he could remember. He’d wonder, later, if the Dementors had exhausted the nightmares, at least for a night.

Harry was still a little groggy the following morning as he made his way down to the Great Hall for breakfast. For some reason he’d been unable to wake up early to work out, and Ron and the others decided to let him have a bit of a lie in. He knew they were just worried about him after his reaction to the Dementors, but he still felt a bit crabby about the whole thing. Still, there was nothing to do about it now. His class schedule said he had Arithmancy first thing in the morning, so he wanted to make sure he had a good start on the day.

Ron, of course, took this idea to ridiculous extremes, falling on his breakfast like a starving wolf. Hermione looked faintly nauseated as their friend quickly worked his way through a heavily laden plate. Although her scolding was fairly mild, she rolled her eyes when Ron protested that he was ‘still a growing boy’.

Harry had to suppress a grin. Lame or not, Ron’s words were truer than anyone else knew. In time he’d be even taller than Bill, but with Charlie’s husky build — a born Keeper, as he’d said on more than one occasion. There was some irony in the youngest Weasley boy growing up to be the largest, not that any of his family had been around to appreciate the humour.

Harry scowled and bit off the end of a sausage. That was not a productive line of thought to be pursuing. He was so preoccupied trying to lighten his mood that he almost missed the glances exchanged by Hermione and Ginny.

Knowing he was barely fit to talk to, Harry occupied himself with his breakfast, letting his eyes roam around the hall. Most of the students seemed subdued as well, though whether the impending classes or the Dementors were to blame was anybody’s guess. At the head table, Slughorn was oddly jovial, sitting next to Dumbledore and holding forth about something. Harry guessed that his house meeting last night must have gone fairly well. The other professors seemed to be quietly talking amongst themselves as well, all except for Hagrid.

For some reason the new Care of Magical Creatures professor seemed preoccupied, almost… pensive? For the bluff and hearty groundskeeper that was a most unusual look. From what Harry remembered, he should have been very eager to begin his new teaching career, and had even lined up a special treat for his students… Buckbeak the hippogriff.

Harry blinked and set his fork down. With Malfoy gone, that can’t happen again, right? he mused. Still, it can’t hurt to take precautions, can it?

Harry hurriedly finished his food and was up and out of his seat as Hagrid left the Great Hall early, his breakfast half-eaten. Coming up behind the large man in the corridor, he coughed and asked, “Looking forward to your first class, Professor Hagrid?” he asked.

“Oh! Hello there, Harry,” Hagrid said, half-turning. “Yeah, got ever’thing lined up. Going ter give them a special surprise today too, get things started off with a bang.” He paused. “I kind of wish you lot were able to be there, seeing as how you made it possible,” he concluded sadly.

Harry felt like he’d been punched in the stomach. He hadn’t thought about it, in his enthusiasm to learn Arithmancy and Ancient Runes, but not taking Care of Magical Creatures would have its own effect on things. Evidently, their friendly presence at that first class had encouraged Hagrid more than they knew. “Sorry about that,” he muttered.

“Oh, don’ mind me,” Hagrid said. “Ye had no way of knowing.”

Harry silently cursed himself as he forced a smile onto his face. “I suppose,” he said. “So what is the big surprise?” he asked in a conspiratorial whisper.

Hagrid quickly looked left and right. “I got some hippogriffs from the school herd, including my favourite, Buckbeak. They got a real taste for rodents and after fumigating the dungeons right before start of term, I had enough rats and such to get them willing to meet my classes today.”

Harry blinked in surprise at the thought of Hagrid needing to bribe his subjects, and raised his estimation of Buckbeak’s intelligence a few more notches. “Er, that will be brilliant!” he enthused in what he hoped was a believable manner. “But… didn’t I read that hippogriffs are a bit ticklish if shown disrespect? It might be trouble if someone starts acting up, you know.”

Hagrid nodded. “I’ll explain to them before hand that y’ got ter show a hippogriff proper respect. Buckbeak’s a good lad, as long as they don’t insult him or the others…” his voice trailed off as Harry gave him an extremely dubious expression. “You don’t think someone would deliberately act out, do ye, Harry?”

Harry shrugged. “I’d just be careful, that’s all. Some people were raised to think that magical creatures are just stupid beasts, so showing proper respect to this Buckbeak will be well beyond them. And if one of them got hurt, even if it was their own fault, do you think the Ministry would give Buckbeak a fair hearing?”

It was slightly dirty pool, playing on Hagrid’s own mistreatment after he was falsely accused of opening the Chamber of Secrets, but it was effective. “Ye got a point there, Harry. I’ll keep a tight rein on things. Anyone acting up will get sent straight ter Filch, ye can count on that.” Then Hagrid smiled. “Ye say ye read about hippogriffs?”

“Yeah, someone got me the Monster Book of Monsters for my birthday,” Harry replied with a smile.

Hagrid reddened a bit. “Well, if you want, you can come down after classes and I’ll introduce ye,” he offered tentatively.

Harry nodded. “Do you mind if the others come?” he asked.

Hagrid looked a little surprised. “No, of course not. All of ye are welcome,” he assured Harry.

Harry grinned again as students began to fill the corridor from the Great Hall. “I need to get to class, but we’ll see you this afternoon,” he promised.

Even after lunch, Harry’s head was still spinning. There was a lot more to Arithmancy than he’d anticipated, and Professor Vector promised to be quite a taskmaster. She’d even assigned an essay the first class, asking them to fill two feet of parchment listing out the reasons why they wanted to study Arithmancy, and what they expected to do with what they’d learn.

Ron looked particularly dubious about this, as some of his major reasons he didn’t really care to discuss with a witch as formidable in her own way as Professor McGonagall. It wasn’t until Harry suggested discussing battlefield tactics and duelling strategies that his friend’s expression had gone from panicked to thoughtful.

Hermione, of course, was right in her element, and had apparently already composed most of her answer in her head before they finished eating. Neville was quiet, but didn’t seem overly perturbed about the assignment. Ginny and Luna, clearly not wanting to be completely left out, asked quite a few questions about the new class and its professor. Harry had little doubt that one or both of them would be taking it next year as well.

The third years had also had Transfiguration that morning, and while it was more familiar, Professor McGonagall was never what one would consider an ‘easy’ instructor. At least their summer practice had kept their wand-work sharp.

They made plans to get the study group together after dinner, all the better to start on their new assignments. However, before the evening meal, they all paid a visit to Hagrid. The early evening air was still quite raw from the previous day’s storms, leaving their breath misting in the damp.

Fortunately, when they arrived at the groundskeeper’s hut, he’d already had the kettle on. The strong hot tea he served was welcome after being outside, and Harry discovered, to his amazement, that Hagrid’s ubiquitous rock cakes were somewhat edible when you dipped a corner in one’s tea and nibbled carefully.

“I’m glad you said that this morning,” Hagrid said as he finished pouring.

“Oh?” Harry asked.

“Aye. Crabbe and Goyle started acting up this afternoon. One of them said something he shouldn’t have, and if I hadn’t gotten between them and old Bucky…” he said, plucking at a fresh rent in the sleeve of his moleskin coat, “Well, it might have been bad.”

Harry winced. “I always thought those two were lacking in good sense.”

Hagrid nodded. “Well, the two of them will be spending their evenings with Filch for the next couple of weeks. Can’t have students not respectin’ the creatures they study. Ain’t safe for nobody when that happens.” He shook his head. “They even complained ter Professor Dumbledore about th’ detention, and we had a meetin’ about it.”

“What did he say?” Hermione asked, concerned.

Hagrid grinned suddenly, his great white teeth gleaming amidst the tangled black beard. “Great man, Professor Dumbledore is, great man. He told them they’d been very foolish to disregard my warnings, and since I got hurt protecting them from their own foolishness, then they might even owe me a life debt.”

Ron and Neville both let out strangled barks of laughter. Ginny held hers in, but her eyes were flashing with amusement in a way that was rather distracting.

“Of course,” Hagrid continued, “I knew Buckbeak wouldn’t really hurt anyone, so I couldn’t press a claim, but that shut them up right on the spot. And before we left, Professor Slughorn added another week of detention, on account of them embarrassing the Slytherin house.”

Most of his friends looked rather amazed at that, so Harry spoke up. “Professor Slughorn was Head of Slytherin before Professor Snape, and I think his policies were a bit different. He didn’t favour students from his own house quite so much. In fact, I found out that my mum was one of his favourites, and she was in Gryffindor.”

“Yer spot on about that, Harry,” Hagrid said, getting a little misty. “There was some folks who were a bit surprised at that, but yer mum had a way about her… People liked her in spite of themselves, an’ even those that didn’t, still respected her.”

Harry was caught completely off guard by Hagrid’s words, never having heard Lily Evans described in quite such a fashion before. He resolved on the spot that he would not let himself grow distant from the man who’d introduced him to the Wizarding world.

After tea, Hagrid led them out to the paddock and whistled for Buckbeak. After cautioning them again about showing respect, he led the reluctant hippogriff into the clearing. Harry stepped forward, somewhat confident, but still respectful. Cognizant that the poor creature had been stared at by Hogwarts students all day long, he dropped to one knee as he bowed, reasoning that a little extra respect couldn’t hurt. He knew all too well what it was like to be stared at all day.

Fortunately, everyone passed inspection and Buckbeak consented to a light currying. He might have been a little tired from the previous excitement, since he showed no desire to go flying this time around. Harry was just as relieved as he was disappointed. While it had been exciting enough in his borrowed memories, the air was growing chill and he had no desire to draw more attention onto himself if he could avoid it.

As they walked back to Hagrid’s hut, Hermione asked the large man what he had planned for his next class. Harry knew that being a professor was one potential career that the bushy-haired witch was considering, but after Hagrid’s remarks about Harry’s warning, he suspected that she had an ulterior motive.

Harry realized that Hermione must have read Hagrid’s textbook, or a similar book at some point, because she knew exactly what he was talking about when he mentioned bringing in a Niffler for the next class. Her motivations were a mystery, right up until she frowned.

“Hagrid?” she asked, “Nifflers are strongly attracted to shiny objects, aren’t they?”

“That’s right,” Hagrid nodded, pleased that she knew. “Should be quite a surprise when I show him digging up a Galleon I buried that morning.”

“What if some of the students are wearing jewellery? Won’t the Niffler become hard to control?” she asked, concerned. “There have been reports of them biting off rings and necklaces; someone could get hurt if you don’t warn them first.”

Hagrid frowned. “I hadn’t thought o’ that, Hermione,” he admitted. “It’s no wonder Professor McGonagall is always going on about how clever ye are.”

Hermione’s face went bright red, but Hagrid didn’t notice as he dug a grubby sheaf of parchments out of his pocket and carefully added notes with a quill that looked ridiculously small in his enormous fingers.

As they made their way back to the castle for dinner, Harry congratulated his friend. “That was a good thought there, Hermione,” he said.

She just shrugged. “I just don’t want to see Hagrid get into any trouble,” she said.

“Well, his students will be thanking you too,” Ron observed. “It’s kind of scary how things like that just never occurred to him.”

“Part of it isn’t his fault,” Harry insisted. “He’s just so… big… that things like an offended hippogriff just don’t seem like a problem to him.”

“That makes sense,” Neville said.

“Well,” Ginny added, “we have a standing invitation, so we can come out each week and ask him about what new creature he’s going to cover, and try to anticipate any problems like we did today.”

“We?” Ron asked weakly.

“Uhm,” Ginny temporized, “Hermione will. And we will keep her company while she does it,” she added with an impish grin.

Laughter trailed them back into the castle.

Potions class with Professor Slughorn was substantially different from what Harry’s friends had come to expect. Harry had already been thinking about teaching styles after their conversation with Hagrid, so he noticed a few things after they filed into the dungeon laboratory with the Slytherin third years.

Some things were the same, of course. The glares from Pansy Parkinson, Vincent Crabbe, and Gregory Goyle were just as venomous as Harry expected. What he didn’t expect was how Professor Slughorn segregated the two houses, pulled out his wand, and placed a magical barrier between the enemy camps.

“There have been reports,” he said in a serious tone at odds with his jovial features, “of rampant sabotage in this class. My predecessor’s notes were especially concerned with this year. As such, I will not tolerate any foolishness of that sort in my classroom. Some of the potions we will be brewing can be quite dangerous if tampered with, and I will not have any of my students reporting to the hospital wing if I can help it. Is that clear, Mr. Potter?”

Harry nodded gravely, as he struggled to keep a smile off of his face. In truth, most of the sabotaging was done by the Slytherins, though Draco and the others blamed the Gryffindors any time their potion came out less than perfect. Slughorn’s magical barrier would hinder Pansy and the rest far more than it would help them. But they couldn’t protest without revealing their previous lies. In short, it was brilliantly devious — aiding those Slughorn wished to curry favour with, and discreetly punishing those he didn’t wish to be seen as actively hindering.

No wonder he was head of Slytherin.

As the Slytherin students sat fuming, while most of the Gryffindors looked gobsmacked, the Potions master began lecturing. Or rather, he began chatting with them.

Instead of the demonstration potions Harry expected — perhaps he saved those for the N.E.W.T. level class — Professor Slughorn began by introducing himself and asking each member of the class a couple of questions about themselves. After each answer, he’d ask them a question or two regarding potion-making. Harry guessed that he was looking for potential contacts, as well as getting a feel for their general grasp of the subject matter. The interspersing of the academic with the personal also seemed to keep everyone slightly off-balance and, on the average, more attentive. In a way, Harry had to admire his style; Slughorn always seemed to keep a careful balance of self-interest with professional standards, never wholly discarding one for the other. It was almost artistic. Maybe his conduct was also a performance for the benefit of the young Slytherins he was responsible for…

If that was the case, Harry concluded, they could do far worse. Working to further one’s ambitions without harming the rest of society seemed to be beyond the capabilities of the Malfoys or the other dark pure-blood families… even if that lack of malignancy vastly improved their long-term prospects. Harry realized that Slughorn wanted to use him to further his own plans, but at the same time, the round little man would also do his best to manipulate things to Harry’s advantage. Mutually beneficial relationships were logically more viable in the long run. He didn’t necessarily trust the man to do anything that didn’t serve his own interests, but Harry would go out of his way to make sure that their interests remained congruent — which meant that Professor Slughorn would be looking out for them as much as himself.

Harry’s thoughts were cut off abruptly as his name was called. “So, Mister Potter,” Slughorn observed coolly, though his eyes seemed somewhat amused, “I understand you are quite active in the Duelling Association, yes?”

Harry nodded slowly.

“And I suppose you think potions are useless in such a venue?” Slughorn asked archly, causing several of the Slytherins, especially Pansy, to smirk as he put Harry on the spot.

“Absolutely not, sir,” Harry replied evenly. “Even Muggle soldiers have members of their combat units assigned to carry bandages and Muggle medicines. Potions are usually more reliable for curing burns and other types of spell-damage than medical charms, which can be quite tricky. If I was going into a situation where I was expecting a fight, I’d prefer to have a few common remedies and pain-relieving potions handy. Some potions can also be used in a more… direct… manner, if one can contrive an appropriate means of delivery. Even something as simple as Zonko’s Belching Powder can give you a decisive advantage — it’s hard to cast a spell when you are constantly belching.”

“I see,” Slughorn said, slightly nonplussed. “I understand you were raised by Muggles? What was that like?”

Harry frowned at the extremely personal question. “Rather unpleasant. My aunt and her family disliked my mother and hated the idea of magic. If it weren’t for meeting people like the Grangers, I might have ended up thinking rather poorly of Muggles as a whole.”

Slughorn blinked as he digested this, and then moved on to Ron. Harry had to suppress the urge to turn around and see who might be staring at him.

At lunch that day, Harry ate very little. Despite Ginny’s protests, he only picked at the small amount of food on his plate, and left early to go back to his room. Ron and Neville offered to take him to see Madam Pomfrey, but Harry just waved them off. “You go on to class,” he said, glancing over at Seamus. “If I’m not feeling better by dinner time, I’ll go see her myself.”

After they left, Harry stretched out on his bed. Unless something changed, the Boggart would be found in the staffroom again, inspiring Professor Lupin to use it for a demonstration. He had absolutely no desire to have any of his deepest fears paraded around for public display. The chances of revealing something disastrous were just too high. As much as he hated the idea of skiving off from Professor Lupin’s first class, it was really the only prudent thing to do, under the circumstances.

And so Harry occupied his time working on his Arithmancy homework until he actually dozed off. He awoke with a start at the sound of Ron’s voice.

“That was brilliant, mate,” the red-head enthused, “making that Death Eater’s mask slip down and cover his eyes, right before he fell on his arse!”

“She,” Neville corrected quietly.

“He, she, hard to tell under those robes,” Ron shrugged, frowning. “That Boggart looked so real, I almost lost my lunch when that spider appeared on my turn.”

“You still made its legs fall off,” Dean said. “I thought Lavender was going to scream when it rolled toward her,” he continued with a laugh.

“I suppose,” Ron agreed as he dumped his bag on his bed. “Harry, it’s too bad you missed Lupin’s first class. It was brilliant, he had a Boggart and showed us how to stop one and…”

Harry shrugged. “I wasn’t feeling too well earlier, probably wouldn’t have been a good idea,” he temporized. Neville gave him a quick look.

Ron frowned. “Oh, yeah. How’s your stomach now? You still look a little peaked. Do you need to…?”

Harry shook his head. “I think it was just something I ate. I’m actually a little hungry now.”

“Well good,” Ron said happily. “We’re just getting ready to go down to dinner now. We’ll get you fed up in a hurry.”

Harry shook his head ruefully as he got up and stretched. “You know, sometimes you sound so much like your mum that it’s scary.”

Ron’s indignant sputters continued all the way back down to the common room.

Professor Lupin seemed to accept Harry’s apologies for missing his class, and nothing more was said as they moved on to cover other Dark creatures. Examining his memories, it seemed to Harry that the Defence curriculum was covering a bit more spellwork than he originally remembered. Of course, Professor Lupin had some forewarning this time regarding the sad state of affairs left by his predecessors.

It was with great difficulty that Harry refrained from dwelling on the damage that affairs at Hogwarts had inflicted on Wizarding Britain. The curse on the Defence Against the Dark Arts position practically guaranteed that an entire generation had very little idea how to defend themselves against Voldemort’s followers or anyone else who came along. Snape’s policies regarding his N.E.W.T.-level Potions class also sharply limited the number of potential Aurors the Ministry could recruit.

Something General Hastings had once said stuck in Harry’s mind: “All real power flows from the end of a wand.” The weakness rotting away the core of society was concealed as long as Dumbledore was there to hold Voldemort in check — the only one he really feared. But once the Headmaster was gone, there wasn’t really anything to hold back the Darkness. The Order of the Phoenix tried, but they were more of an information-gathering auxiliary — they were better trained than most of the younger Aurors, but the same could be said of the students he trained in ‘Dumbledore’s Army’.

With Harry’s surety regarding Voldemort’s return, Professor Lupin also seemed to be aware of this danger. The snippets he overheard from Percy and the older students suggested that the genial-looking man was quite the taskmaster with the O.W.L.- and N.E.W.T.-preparation classes. They may have thought he was working solely to ensure they passed their exams, but Harry knew better. There was even a rumour that students sufficiently far behind on Defence were being strongly urged to join the Duelling Association to hone their practical skills.

With Professor Lupin’s attention focused on whipping the Defence classes into shape, Harry was a little surprised when he received a note at lunch the week after Hermione’s birthday.

Please report to my quarters following your afternoon classes.

—R. J. Lupin

Harry showed up at the appointed time, though doing so did require reminding Ron that Lupin could be trusted, perhaps more than anyone else on staff. If he was going to write lines or serve detention for missing class, he didn’t want to do so with an audience, and he felt Professor Lupin would appreciate one even less.

But when Harry knocked, the man who opened the door didn’t seem angry or disappointed. “Ah, there you are,” he said with a genial smile. “Follow me and I will explain.” After locking his door, he led a confused Harry through the corridors to the Defence classroom.

Several of the student desks had been pushed aside, and a large packing case was sitting on top of the professor’s desk. It looked vaguely familiar and Harry felt his stomach drop.

“I’ll admit I was rather surprised when you were not in my first class,” Professor Lupin said quietly as he locked the door behind them. “From your records, you never missed a class unless forcibly restrained by Madam Pomfrey. It was then that I realized that you had somehow discovered, probably from Mr. Filch’s grumblings, that I was going to cover Boggarts.”

Harry opened his mouth, but was forestalled by Lupin’s dismissive gesture as he leaned against the doorframe.

“I can understand such a reaction,” Lupin continued. “In fact, I can appreciate your desire for some discretion. Some people’s deepest fears are worse than others, and perhaps shouldn’t be aired in public. If you’d faced a Boggart that turned into a representation of Voldemort, it might have caused a panic.” Lupin lightly placed his hand on Harry’s shoulder. “On the other hand, facing one’s fears can be therapeutic, in a way. I remember how you reacted to the training target, Harry, so I’m offering you a chance to do so in a private setting, and perhaps make up your class grade.”

Harry opened his mouth to protest. He really didn’t want to face a Boggart, even with an audience of one, but he didn’t know how to object without talking about… “Thank you, Professor Lupin,” he finally said in a low voice.

Lupin’s eyebrows knitted together, but Harry didn’t volunteer anything else. “Well, there’s another one in the case that we found in Mr. Filch’s office. You know the incantation is Riddikulus… Do you know what frightens you the most?”

Harry nodded slowly as he stepped forward into the area cleared of desks. But what form could a Boggart take to symbolize the immutability of fate? What colour was predestination? What hue futility?

He almost didn’t notice at first when Professor Lupin opened the case with a flick of his wand. He braced himself as something seemed to peer at him as the lid flew open…

Author notes

36

The Slughorn that Stole Christmas

Like most of his classmates, Harry was looking forward to the end of term and going home for Christmas. It still struck him at times, how very different the idea of going home felt when home was The Burrow and not Privet Drive. The complete lack of dread was the biggest difference that came to mind.

Not that there weren’t other things to keep his mind off the anticipation. Their morning runs became more and more unpleasant as the weather turned. At least the martial arts practice kept their blood warm before they showered for class. Neville’s rustiness from the missed summer was more than gone. While he wasn’t quite as quick as Harry or Ron, he was noticeably stronger — Harry had a collection of bruises to attest to this.

Harry had been tempted to use the Room of Requirement for their morning runs, especially as it grew colder, but he also knew that their morning training had acquired some attention. Pansy and Flint’s ambush, not to mention the aftermath, had driven that point home. He didn’t want anyone wondering where they were, so they continued to half-freeze in the mornings. Harry tried to tell himself that it was good training, but it was a hard sell.

At least the occasional practice sessions with Remus Lupin had changed in focus. Rather than seeing how much power Harry could generate, they instead worked on fine-tuning his control over how much he expended per spell. This change came shortly after Remus said he received a reply from Mr. Ollivander. The odd man never came out and said it, according to the last Marauder, but he strongly implied that their previous course of action was ‘ill-advised’.

Given the wand-maker’s propensity for elliptical dialogue and enigmatic silences, he might as well have screamed, “Stop!” at the top of his lungs.

While that was worrisome, other aspects of his education were going better. Under Professor Slughorn’s gimlet eye, Potions was becoming interesting. With his prohibitions against “foolish Gryffindor pranks” stymieing any potential Slytherin troublemaking, Harry — for the first time — was able to actually concentrate on what he was doing. Hermione was subtly encouraged to ask more questions on the theories behind the instructions, and before he knew it, Harry was actually learning something about what he was brewing. It was all quite shocking. He’d known from the first class that Slughorn was no Snape, but it was nonetheless a pleasant surprise to discover he was actually able to keep his House in order. While there were still… unsavoury elements… in the Slytherin dungeons, they were keeping their heads down and not causing trouble for others, at least as far as he knew. But Harry knew he had enough to worry about without borrowing more trouble.

More encouraging was the gradual thawing of his relationship with his own Head of House. Despite their differences, they still had to work together on the Duelling Association meeting plans. The first few meetings after their argument had been horribly uncomfortable, but ironically it was these discussions that eventually led to their rapprochement.

“Professor Lupin?” she asked, her surprise overcoming her normal reserve.

“Yes, Professor,” Harry confirmed. “He’s the one that taught me the Patronus Charm over the summer.”

McGonagall peered intently at him. Despite himself, Harry began to feel acutely self-conscious. “With the new additions to the school wards you have… arranged… Mr. Potter, is this still a pressing need?” The pauses in her question were not lost on Harry, making him want to wince.

“I’m more worried about Hogsmeade weekends,” Harry replied. “I’m not comfortable leaving anyone to the nonexistent mercies of those creatures if I can prevent it.” He’d already decided to ignore the subtle digs. His Head of House could deliver a surprisingly sarcastic turn of phrase when she wanted to, but trying to match that would only make things worse.

“I see,” Professor McGonagall said, still eyeing him. “Is there a reason, Mr. Potter, that you feel personally responsible for the safety of your classmates? Do you perhaps plan to confiscate their wands before they leave the grounds? Or are the Dementors here because of your actions?”

While her words were pointed, her tone wasn’t entirely so. Harry swallowed, biting back his first reply, and decided to take her question literally. “Well, Professor, we started the Duelling Association because we’ve had some… bad luck… with Defence professors. If I don’t do everything that occurs to me to address those shortcomings, well… then, in a way it would be my fault, wouldn’t it?”

The professor just stared at him, with only an upward twitch of one eyebrow displaying emotion. “I hardly think that makes you responsible for the Defence Against the Dark Arts training of everyone attending Hogwarts,” she said after a moment.

Harry shrugged. He should have known that they’d just end up arguing again. Still, she did ask. “I’m not,” he agreed. “I can’t make anyone join the DA. But I can help the people who do, so I have to do what I can for them. I suppose I am responsible for them, to some degree.” He made a frustrated gesture. He knew he wasn’t making a great deal of sense. “I know I’m not thinking of everything that could happen. I’m not clever enough, or experienced enough, to even come close. But if something did occur to me, and I didn’t follow through on it and someone got hurt as a result… well, I wouldn’t be able to live with myself.”

It was odd, how Harry’s thoughts had turned. He’d just managed to articulate one of his greatest sources of stress to someone who’d added a great deal of it lately. The irony wasn’t lost on him, but it did, oddly enough, make him feel just a bit better to express that.

Even stranger was the way she was now regarding him, clearly surprised by his words. “That is an… unusual… stance to take, Mr. Potter,” she said after a moment. “But not one totally out of keeping with your character. Moreover, it also sheds a different light on some of your actions of late.”

Harry did his best not to scowl. He didn’t like to be reminded of her accusing him of acting Slytherin with respect to the Ministry.

If she noticed his demeanour, McGonagall gave no sign of it. “While I still do not condone your actions… I do find your reasons make them less objectionable than I had originally thought,” she continued. “Given those priorities, I do agree that we can work Professor Lupin into the schedule to give a seminar on the Patronus Charm. I will caution him, however, that while he may wish to alert his upper forms, it should be made clear that their attendance is not mandatory for the Defence curriculum.”

Harry frowned. “I’m afraid I do not understand.”

“Official curriculum is decided by the Hogwarts staff, which is led by the Headmaster,” she explained. “Were it to get back to the Ministry that Hogwarts was requiring students to learn a charm designed to repel their designated agents, it would only create more difficulties. The actions of student-led organizations are under far less scrutiny, and moreover would not be our direct responsibility.”

Harry nodded slowly as it all sank in. It made sense, albeit of a twisted, bureaucratic sort. It occurred to him that he wasn’t the only one capable of acting Slytherin towards the Ministry, but common sense forbade him voicing that thought.

The rest of the scheduling passed in a far less dramatic fashion, planning up through the winter hols. After promising to report to her after they returned to review their progress and schedule the new term, Harry was dismissed.

Harry smiled a little as he made his way to the Great Hall. Professor McGonagall’s manner towards him had noticeably warmed by the end of the meeting.

While he could sense that she still disagreed with some of his methods, she also respected his reasons. “Agreeing to disagree” was frankly more than he’d hoped for from the stern professor, so he was happy to accept that.

Of course, a few days later Harry was wishing some of his professors were a bit more aloof. He’d known, objectively anyway, that this was coming. The quid pro quo had to be fulfilled.

It still didn’t help when the owls arrived with their invitations to their first Slug Club soiree.

On the plus side, it seemed Professor Slughorn had picked up on a few hints and invited all six of them, rather than trying to cherry-pick a few. Harry didn’t think it would make Ron or the others jealous, not from the expression of distaste on his friend’s face as he read the invitation, his eggs cooling and his bacon going soggy. On the other hand, Harry knew they’d like it less if they weren’t all there to watch each other’s backs. Besides, if Harry was right about the real purpose of the Slug Club, it wouldn’t hurt to spread the largesse around a little.

Neville seemed pretty resigned to going, making Harry wonder how many stuffy parties he’d been dragged to as a child. The girls seemed awfully cheery about it, for reasons Harry didn’t want to think about too hard.

Only Ron was really reluctant. Harry asked him about it as they were getting ready. They decided to just go in their school robes, as it was a school function, though Harry vaguely remembered a few people being dressed up before. Or was it just the visiting adults? It bothered him a little that he couldn’t really remember, but then again it was a long time ago, and such a minor detail. Hardly worth worrying about, really.

It was almost a relief, really, to focus on something a bit more concrete, like Ron’s scowl as he combed back his hair, trying to get it to lie down over his ears.

“You seem less than enthused,” Harry said as he wet his own comb.

Ron shrugged. “Doesn’t feel too right,” he said shortly.

Harry sighed. “You want to spit it out, or are we going to play Twenty Questions all night?”

Ron blew out a breath. “Look, it’s not your fault, I know that. But I also know that you are the only reason I’m invited, and I’m trying not to be a prat about it.”

“What makes you think you don’t belong?” Harry asked. “Have you looked at your marks lately? Not to mention being Oliver’s anointed heir at the hoops?”

“I wrote Mum, you know,” Ron said, staring into the mirror. “To ask her what she thought of all this. She didn’t have much nice to say about Slughorn. Didn’t think much of Weasleys when Dad was one of his students. Never invited him to anything like this.”

“Oh,” Harry said. Now that he thought about it, he remembered Mrs. Weasley telling the other him something similar once upon a never. “Percy’s going to be there.”

“Head Boy, professional suck-up, and not exactly my favourite brother at the moment,” Ron said flatly. “Not helping, Harry.”

Harry muffled a snort. Despite the lessening estrangement, the differences between the Weasley brothers were still quite apparent. “Okay, so Slughorn snubbed your dad a long time ago. He’s got to be kicking himself about it now.”

“Yeah, it would definitely give him an in on getting close to you,” Ron replied, though not in a totally unfriendly fashion. More like someone pointing out a bit of dung on your shoe.

“More like getting close to you and your brothers, too,” Harry pointed out.

Ron turned to look at him.

“Professional Curse-Breakers dual trained as Ward Jockeys are not a dime a dozen,” Harry observed. “I don’t think Gringotts wastes time hiring ninnies, do you? And I don’t think ‘useless’ is how you describe someone who became a professional Dragon-Trainer right out of Hogwarts. There are at least two Head Boys in Arthur Weasley’s brood, and there’s no telling what the twins will get up to if they don’t blow themselves up first.”

“At least two…? No way in hell, Harry,” Ron objected. “I know you’ve got that locked up seventh year. More likely Dumbledore will pick Fred or George as a lark, wanting to liven things up a bit.”

Harry suppressed a shudder at the thought of either of the Weasley twins being Head Boy. “I don’t think I’ve got a chance,” Harry observed philosophically. “There’s no way Dumbledore will pick someone he doesn’t trust. Not after seeing what Riddle got up to under Dippet.”

“That’s a long way off, Harry, and…” Ron broke off. “And you’re changing the topic of conversation, aren’t you?”

“Maybe,” Harry admitted. “But don’t sell your or your brothers’ achievements short. Look, I don’t idolize the man, but you have to admit Potions has been much more bearable this year, right?”

Ron nodded. “Too true, but after Snape, that isn’t saying much.”

“Yeah, but look at how he did it,” Harry reminded his friend. “He out-thought and out-manoeuvred them from the very start — the Slytherins. The house that’s supposed to embody cleverness and guile never had a chance, did they?”

“What are you getting at?” Ron asked.

“Just this,” Harry said, “Slughorn is pretty good at social games like that and making useful contacts is his way of keeping score. It’s pretty Slytherin, but it’s mostly harmless as well. He trades favours and information back and forth in ways that benefit people in his little network, incidentally making sure he comes out ahead. It’s a lot more tolerable way of getting ahead than killing people and ruining lives, right?”

“Okay, I get it,” Ron said. “He’s no Death Eater, that’s for sure. Doubt he could even fit in the robes.”

Harry rolled his eyes. “Ron, I don’t want you to accept that he’s harmless. I want you to watch what he does and how he does it. He might introduce us to some people that can help us in the future, but more importantly I want you to get a look at how he operates. We need that skill, Ron. We need someone like Slughorn who we can explicitly trust.”

Ron blinked, clearly taken aback. “Why me? Why not Hermione or Ginny? People will tell pretty girls things they’d never tell me.”

Harry shrugged. “I know Hermione’s going to watch as well, but she’s not as good with people. Her idea of how people should act tends to get in the way. Ginny could be good too, but she doesn’t have your head for tactics or strategy.”

“Don’t let her hear you say that,” Ron warned him. “You know, the more you talk, the more this just sounds like a big chess game.” He scowled abruptly. “Do you and Hermione always have to make something about chess when you want me to do something? You make me sound like some complete nutter who can’t think of anything else!”

Harry jumped a little at his friend’s vehemence. Guiltily, he realized he had a point, too. “Well, maybe it’s because once you do look at something like a chess scenario, your brain goes into overdrive and you arrive at an answer so bloody quick it gives Hermione the colly-wobbles.”

“Oh,” Ron said, and turned back to the mirror. He finished straightening up as Harry fought a valiant rear-guard action against his perpetually unruly hair.

Just as Harry was giving it up as a bad job, Ron turned back to him with an odd expression on his face. “She thinks I’m clever?” he asked.

Harry worked very hard at suppressing a snicker.

As they entered Professor Slughorn’s magically expanded office, Harry was slightly amused to see that for once he wasn’t the most nervous person in the room. As soon as they passed the gaudy crimson, gold, and emerald wall hangings, his friends instantly adopted the tight formation they normally used in chaotic crowds such as at King’s Cross. He didn’t doubt for a moment that a single sharp noise would have instantly produced a wand in most of their hands.

Even more gratifying, in a totally childish way, were the reactions of the other attendees. Harry saw some of the Slytherin upper forms freeze in their tracks when they saw the Gryffindors arrive. He didn’t doubt that the stories of last year’s ambush in the courtyard had been wildly exaggerated over the summer. He idly wondered if they were looking for horns and a tail. Maybe some bat wings and eau de brimstone…

The scattering of older Ravenclaw and Hufflepuff students looked more curious than alarmed, much to Harry’s relief. Cedric and Cho were there, quite obviously together, and he gave them a smile and a nod at their friendly waves.

He caught Percy’s eye as the Head Boy nodded seriously, clearly attending to their host’s every word. It might have been Harry’s imagination, but he thought the Head Boy’s manner had a slightly watchful quality to it, something that had been missing from the mindless sycophant his other self had known and resented until he’d received word of his death. Still, Harry had little doubt that Percy could do his career no small amount of good here.

The Head Boy earned a smile of gratitude from their host when he pointed out Harry’s arrival to Professor Slughorn. Harry braced himself as the round little man descended on them.

The next few minutes were a whirl as Slughorn introduced his latest trophy to well over a dozen adults who were attending the party. Most of them seemed rather bored, but perked up when Harry’s name was dropped. The Boy Who Lived grinned and bore it, but made a point of introducing his friends as well. Slughorn seemed to take the hint that the Gryffindors were truly a package deal and began including them in the introductions as well. Ron was a bit startled when an older grey-haired witch asked if he was Arthur Weasley’s son. It turned out she knew the elder Weasley before she retired from the Ministry. Harry suppressed a grin as he saw Ron’s features grow more and more intent. It really was just like watching him get into a chess game.

Ginny caught his eye and smirked, but Harry just shrugged. He was being straightforward with his friend when he said he wanted him in this, and fully engaged. Luna, on the other hand, was quieter than he remembered, though she also stood next to Neville almost constantly. Harry wondered if she was self-conscious about bringing disapproval onto Neville again, or if she didn’t speak up as much because she felt more secure.

Hermione, on the other hand, had a faint but unmistakable look of disapproval on her face. Harry excused himself from a conversation between Percy, Cedric, Ron, and Professor Slughorn regarding Percy’s incipient entry into the Ministry and joined Ginny and Hermione at the overly ornate punch bowl.

“All right?” Harry asked quietly.

Ginny gave Harry a grateful look. Apparently Hermione had been working herself into quite a state.

“I’m sorry,” his friend said. “I’m just having trouble with… all of this.”

“‘All of this’?” Harry asked quietly.

“This,” Hermione repeated, gesturing at the rest of the room. “Back room deals. Trading favours. Bartering influence. My parents had to deal with a lot of this with the National Health Service contracts, and I’ve heard them talk about this sort of thing. I don’t want to spoil your plans, Harry, but… this just isn’t right.”

Hermione actually looked to be on the verge of tears and Harry mentally kicked himself. She was a lot more upset than she let on, and he belatedly realized she’d been putting up a brave front. He racked his brain for a moment, trying to find a way to explain, quickly, why this was important. “Hermione, do you like hurting people?” he finally asked.

“What?” she asked. “No! Of course not!”

“But we still know a lot of curses, don’t we?” Harry asked. “Every day we practise magic that could put someone in a lot of pain.”

“But we only do that so…” her voice trailed off. “I see. So this is only about… that thing we discussed on the seventh floor?”

Harry nodded, and then leaned closer. “Do you think I really came here to get some cushy Ministry job in the future?” He shuddered. “If I had my druthers, I’d play Quidditch professionally for a few years, save up my salary, get married and have a family, then retire to coach or manage my investments.” He paused for a moment, and then continued. “Not necessarily in that order, but I’d rather do something I know I’m good at, something where any success I have I know is deserved.” Harry swallowed, a little embarrassed at his outburst. The faint smile of approval Ginny was giving him was not helping one damn bit.

Hermione was still frowning, but now it was more thoughtful than upset. “So all this…?” she asked, waving her hand around to indicate the room in general.

“Is to help ensure we’re allowed to do that,” Harry confirmed. “And it’s not just our immediate problem either, you know. Have you ever asked Mr. Weasley how many Muggle-borns work at the Ministry?”

Hermione slowly shook her head, her frown deepening.

“Well, it’s not as many as should be,” Harry continued, his voice growing more intent as it dropped to a whisper. “It would be better if government work was a strict meritocracy, but we both know that isn’t the case anywhere. But what we can do is try to stamp out these ridiculous blood-prejudices. And that means you, little Miss Highest-Scoring Student in however many years who just happens to be a Muggle-born, need to meet the people with influence and show them just who you are, so they can see blood means bollocks. And once you’re the Minister of Magic, you can bloody well fire the bigots, right?”

Hermione blinked at that last bit and actually giggled slightly, leaving Harry to wonder if someone had tampered with the punch. She smiled at him for a moment as she digested all that, then gave him a firm nod. “So this isn’t just about the ends justifying the means, is it? Thanks, Harry.” And with that, she strode over to where Ron was listening to Professor Slughorn’s reminiscences. As Harry watched, it wasn’t long before she joined into the conversation easily and without a hint of awkwardness.

“I don’t hold out much hope for your dream,” a voice said in his ear, making Harry jump and turn around. Ginny was still standing there. He stared at her dumbly. She’d been increasingly quiet around him over the course of the term. Not really unfriendly, more like just not having much to say. Things were still a little awkward between them. There weren’t any secrets, not anymore. But as she was well aware, he was still heavily conflicted where she was concerned. Part of him was still getting to know a girl he’d already opened up to more than anyone in this existence. But part of him saw her and remembered a different Ginny. The whole thing made him excruciatingly uncomfortable at times, because he wasn’t always comfortable with the… appropriateness of his feelings. Part of him, the memories of his older self, was just that — older. Old enough that seeing this Ginny as that Ginny raised some moral quandaries of a sort he’d rather not think on too hard. Even if he’d never… well… nevermind.

Ginny seemed to accept this diffidence, at least for the moment. Perhaps she hoped, as he did, that it would become less of an issue as they both aged. But she always seemed to be watching him. Waiting. And she occasionally made him very, very nervous. “Y-you don’t?” he asked, rather stupidly in his opinion.

Ginny shook her head, and this close up. Harry couldn’t help but notice the errant colours of the individual hairs. “I don’t think you will ever be just a Quidditch player,” she confirmed in a low voice. “Not after hearing you give a speech like that.”

Harry frowned. “What are you talking about?” he finally asked. “All I did was explain why I think this isn’t a complete waste of time.”

Ginny shook her head, grinning. “You addressed her fears, gave her a solid moral justification, and then set a long-term goal for her to pursue. Did you actually read all of those Muggle psychology books you bought?”

Harry nodded warily. “Yeah, but evidently not as well as you did. Last summer?”

Ginny nodded. “I don’t just read poetry,” she informed him in a crisp voice. “Besides,” she added with a grin, “didn’t we agree that girls are smarter than boys?”

By the time they returned to Gryffindor Tower, each of them tightly clutching a pass signed by Professor Slughorn, Harry’s throat was dry and his jaws actually ached from a combination of smiling and talking too much. Hermione and Ron had their heads together, thick as thieves and oblivious to the rest of them as they verbally compared notes. Hermione mentioned drawing up some sort of influence chart and Ron replied he’d be eager to see it, nearly causing Harry to step off into thin air as a stairway moved out of the way.

Neville just looked a bit tired. He’d been monopolized by friends of his grandmother and his great uncle most of the night, and didn’t appear to have enjoyed it that much. He gave a tired grin though, when Luna shyly took his hand.

When Harry’s gaze wandered over to Ginny, he found her looking right back at him, causing him to quickly look away. The staircase returned at that moment, so he took the opportunity to begin climbing again. But Ginny didn’t let it go.

“Checking over the troops?” she whispered quietly, leaning close.

Harry eyed her sidelong. “Hush you,” he replied just as quietly.

“Not something to be ashamed of,” she replied easily. “Actually, I think it’s rather sweet,” she added with a grin.

Harry just shrugged, refusing to be baited.

“Nothing wrong with looking out for your friends,” she added. “That’s not just a Hufflepuff trait, you know. Just make sure you let them look out for you as well.”

“Yes, Mum,” Harry quipped.

“Prat,” she said with a small smile. “You don’t want me acting like Mum. Ron says I do a pretty good impression of her.”

“Must be the genes,” Harry said as they approached the floor with the Fat Lady’s portrait.

Ginny rolled her eyes. “In case you haven’t guessed, she’s made me pretty much responsible for your physical condition when we return to The Burrow.”

“I caught that much,” Harry admitted. “I suppose Ron is in charge of making sure I sleep at night.”

Ginny gave him a quick look that informed him his guess was spot on. “I imagine so. It’s not like she’s the only one that’s worried about you, you know. She’s just…”

“Being motherly,” Harry finished for her. He shrugged. “I don’t really mind that much.”

“I noticed,” Ginny said. “Which is sort of odd, you being a boy and all. It’s not very macho, is it?”

Harry grinned, a little wistfully. “Not really; I missed you guys a lot, you know?”

Ginny frowned, and then looked stricken for a moment. “Sorry, I forgot. I, uh, I didn’t really think, you know…”

Harry could see her struggling with her words, not wanting to mention anything too incriminating in the hallway. “I know. The longer I’m here, the more… well… I’m sleeping a bit better these days, if you know what I mean.”

Ginny nodded, biting her lip. “That’s good, I think. Er, it is, isn’t it?”

Harry nodded. “I think so. And I think it’s good that I’m acting… well, maybe a little more normal?”

Ginny grinned. “Normal for you, anyway.”

Harry grunted. “I suppose.”

The next Potions class ended rather oddly, with Professor Slughorn minutely examining Harry’s potion, swishing it in the vial. With a frown, the portly professor asked him to stay after class, implying that his results were less than acceptable.

Ron nodded to Harry as he and the other students packed up their bags and filed out. Nothing was said, but Harry knew the others would linger in the corridor until he emerged. It wasn’t so much distrust of their professor as a determination to never again be caught off guard.

Besides, was it truly paranoia if you knew someone really was out to get you?

Once they were alone, Harry approached Slughorn’s desk and asked if something was wrong with his potion.

“What? Oh no, my boy!” the man replied. “Your work is just as superlative as ever. I just wanted an excuse for us to chat a bit, away from curious ears. Did you enjoy my little gathering the other night?”

Harry relaxed slightly and nodded. “Yes, it was quite fascinating. You were not joking in the slightest when you said you knew a lot of people at the Ministry.” Harry suspected the man had another reason why he wanted to talk to him, but knew he had to play along for the moment.

Slughorn beamed. “I’ll admit I was a bit worried,” he said. “There was a bit of excitement from people when they realized you’d likely be there. I even received several requests for invitations from old friends who’d never shown an interest in attending before… but I didn’t want to overwhelm everyone.”

Harry could recognize a hint when he heard one. “Perhaps we can do that again, maybe next term, and you can accommodate some of the others?”

The professor nodded happily, and Harry wondered if that was it. Then the man cleared his throat nervously. “I, ah, understand there was a bit of unpleasantness last year,” he ventured, “involving a rather large Basilisk?”

Now Harry understood where this was going. “Er, yeah, there was,” Harry confirmed in a low voice. “We ended up killing it, but it was a close thing. I assume the Headmaster told you?”

Slughorn nodded. “He did mention it, in general terms. About how large was this beast?”

Harry shrugged. “Fifty or sixty feet.”

Slughorn blinked. “Did you say fifty or sixty… feet?”

Harry nodded.

The corpulent professor staggered back a step as all of the colour drained out of his face. Harry recalled the man’s reaction to Hagrid’s collection of magical animal by-products and began to worry about the Slytherin’s heart. “Good heavens, Harry! Do you know how much that’s worth?”

“Wouldn’t it be decomposing by now?” Harry asked.

“Not in less than a year, young man,” Slughorn assured him in his best lecturing tone. “The normal processes of decomposition will be delayed until the Basilisk’s venom has lost most of its potency. The poisonous essence suffuses the Basilisk’s entire body, and it’s so strong and so inimical to other forms of life that fully grown specimens are immune to diseases of any sort. In this case, it’s barely been half a year, so the body should be intact.”

Harry frowned. He wondered why no one had sought to reclaim it in the previous timeline, aside from the fact that doing so would require a Parselmouth to open the passage. Perhaps there had just been too much going on. “Would you happen to know buyers who might be interested in Basilisk parts?” he asked after a moment — already knowing the answer.

“Why, yes, I would,” Professor Slughorn confirmed with a wide smile. “Several of my former students are quite adept at brokering rare ingredients. Jacob Reeves, for example, holds the exclusive contract for St. Mungo’s. I’m sure, for a small commission, we can get you top prices — you’ll be the recipient of a tidy fortune.”

Harry waved his hands. “Wait a second, there are a couple of problems. First we have to get it out of the Chamber.”

Slughorn nodded. “But I understand that you can… facilitate access to the creature’s lair?”

Harry’s eyes narrowed. “Dumbledore told you that?”

Slughorn nodded. “Don’t worry; I’m hardly one to support that ridiculous superstition. I understand that one of my great-great uncles had the same ability.” The way the professor drew himself up proudly after that statement sorely tested Harry’s ability to keep a straight face. “From what I understand, the Headmaster has little interest in claiming a share on behalf of the school itself. I imagine he’d rather this was all taken care of with as little fuss as possible.”

That last aspect hadn’t really occurred to Harry before. The last thing Dumbledore wanted to do was publicize the fact that an enormous Basilisk had been living under Hogwarts for centuries. That might get people wondering what else might be laired below the dungeons. Not terribly comforting thoughts for the parents of the next crop of firsties.

But that didn’t change Harry’s other stipulation. “I’ll open the passage,” he said to Slughorn’s delight. “But remember that I wasn’t the only one down there. My friends were there as well. It was all six of us — I think we should all share equally.”

“That’s very generous of you,” Slughorn commended him. The way the old man’s fingers were twitching, Harry imagined he was already contemplating how many crystallized pineapple bits and fine liqueurs his share of the commission would net him.

“Not really,” Harry said firmly, hoping to make his point. “It was massed spell fire from all of us that took it down. They earned any reward as much as I.”

Slughorn swallowed hard and looked a bit queasy. Thinking about fighting a Basilisk that large, in close quarters, was more than enough to dispel his pleasantly greedy haze. “Yes. Well. Albus said he’d like to have this taken care of while school is not in session.”

“I can see that. Hardly anyone from Gryffindor has signed up to stay here over the holidays. Is the same true for the other houses?”

Slughorn nodded, regaining a little of his gleeful anticipation. “I’ve already confirmed with the other Heads. So when should I expect you all?”

Harry shrugged. “That’s really up to my guardians, not to mention the Grangers, Madam Longbottom, and Mr. Lovegood.” He made a face, wondering how much Hermione had really told her parents about what happened in the Chamber. Mr. Granger hadn’t ever tried to kill him, so he doubted she’d been totally straightforward about the danger she’d been in.

Slughorn frowned. “I’d better owl them immediately.” Harry wondered idly if his discomfort was because of the extra complications or because the inclusion of more adults meant more haggling over his commission. Harry didn’t really care — he considered payment for the Basilisk parts to be more like ‘found money’ — but parents whose children had been in danger might feel differently.

To be honest, he wasn’t sure how all of them would react, and it made him a little nervous. Hermione, at the least, might not have been totally forthcoming with her parents regarding the events of last spring. However, it wouldn’t be fair to not divide the windfall with everyone who was down there. At least he could warn everyone that Professor Slughorn would be contacting their parents and let them take it from there.

“I’ll let my friends know,” Harry assured him. “Thanks for organizing all of this, sir.”

“Oh, my pleasure, dear boy, my pleasure,” the portly professor assured him with a smile.

As he rather suspected, Harry’s news had Hermione and Neville writing some quick letters that evening. At dinner, Harry couldn’t help but notice Ginny’s face fall as she watched Hermione frantically revise the letter she was sending her parents. But when she glanced at him, the red-headed girl’s eyes hardened and Harry suspected he was in trouble.

Sure enough, as the group returned to the Gryffindor common room after a brief stop at the Owlery, Ginny held him back with a very firm grip on his elbow.

Watching the rest of his friends file in past the Fat Lady, Harry sighed and turned to her. “Was there something?” he asked mildly as she dragged him several paces down the hallway from the now curious portrait.

“What is this about it being split six ways?” she asked in a low voice, her eyebrows drawn together in a fierce scowl. For some reason, Harry thought it looked extremely cute on her. He wisely decided not to voice this sentiment.

Instead he just shrugged. He wasn’t nearly as good as Ron at that gesture, but it would have to do. “There were six of us down there. It seemed the fairest way to do it.” He looked over his shoulder at the Fat Lady’s portrait. With a nod, he indicated they should move a little farther down the corridor.

“Five of you killed that great nasty thing,” Ginny reminded him as they walked. “And the other one was the reason you were down there, rescuing an idiot,” she added bitterly.

Harry winced. “I… look, it definitely wasn’t your fault. Whoever set that up did a really good job of it, you know. If anyone’s at fault, it should be me. I should have secured that stupid diary better.”

“But I’m the one that read it,” Ginny insisted, looking more and more upset. Harry wondered how long she’d been carrying this guilt around. He was a little upset that she hadn’t said anything… a split-second before realizing the massive hypocrisy of that sentiment. He had no business complaining about anyone keeping things bottled up.

“You had no reason not to,” Harry said firmly. “I’m just sorry that the bastards who sent it to you were able to use my name on it to trick you.”

Ginny made a frustrated noise. “I just feel so stupid about the whole thing. And weak.”

“Definitely not weak,” Harry corrected her.

“What do you mean?” she asked.

“Remember what the spectre told us? Your will was so strong he couldn’t keep you controlled for very long, or even suppress your memory,” he reminded her. “That’s a big difference,” he added, then wanted to kick himself.

“Difference?” Ginny asked, her eyes narrowing. “You said this had happened, you know, before. Was that other… person… affected that way?”

Harry grimaced. He didn’t like where this was heading, but he’d promised that once he could tell them the truth he wouldn’t hold anything back. “Uh, several times. And she had no clear memory afterwards.”

“She sicced that… that thing on students?” Ginny asked in a stricken voice.

“Well, yeah, but no one was killed. They didn’t get a clear look, they were just temporarily Petrified,” Harry assured her.

Ginny sagged back against the stone wall, looking decidedly ill.

“It doesn’t matter,” Harry said quickly. “It didn’t happen. No one was hurt. Everyone is fine. You did… better. And it helped. A lot.”

“But why?” Ginny asked after taking a moment to gather herself.

Harry considered her question. “I think… I think it originally took advantage of some… insecurities she had. Things it could capitalize on.”

Ginny frowned. “That explains a lot. You went out of your way to reassure me and make me feel included the summer before I started. Was that why?” she asked suddenly, “Just in case?”

Harry swallowed convulsively. “No, that’s not why,” he insisted. “At least not all of it. I mean, well. Look. We talked, or rather a ‘you’ and a ‘me’ talked about that whole mess once. And that ‘you’ said those feelings were one reason why that thing was able to get its hooks in good. So, yeah, because of that, I knew how it was for you starting Hogwarts, how left out you felt.” He took a deep breath. “And that’s one reason why I wrote all those letters.”

Ginny just stared at him for an uncomfortably long time. Finally, she just sighed and shook her head. “I don’t need you protecting me from everything, Harry.”

Harry shoved his hands into his pockets to stop them from fidgeting. “I know you don’t need it, Ginny, but that’s not going to stop me from trying. I just can’t help it. When you’re cut, I bleed.” He couldn’t remember where he’d read that, but it seemed particularly apt. He’d nearly lost it in a Duelling Association meeting when she slipped and hit her head.

Ginny’s lips pursed in annoyance, but her eyes weren’t as hard. “You’re impossible, you know that, right?”

Harry shrugged again. He was getting better at it. “We’d better head in before curfew.”

Harry had a rather bad shock in the days before they went home for the Christmas hols. They’d been revising in the Gryffindor common room when Ron reminded Ginny to retrieve her Transfigured Christmas ornament from the tree. With a disgusted sigh, she flounced over to the tree and pulled something from the branch that she quickly concealed in her robes.

“What did you make?” Hermione asked curiously.

Ginny gave her a betrayed look, but reluctantly pulled the bauble out of her pocket and held it out for them to see.

It was a shiny metallic ball, coloured a rich shade of green. A very familiar shade of green. Harry felt his heart stop.

“I wasn’t having a very good day,” Ginny said truculently, “and I couldn’t really think of anything to add to it.”

“I think it’s quite nice,” Hermione reassured her. “That’s a lovely colour on it; does it signify anything?” Harry remembered discussing the Weasley ornament tradition with her last term. Hermione thought it was quite intriguing, and was glad she’d saved her own ornament to show her parents.

Luna spoke up. “I think it’s the same shade as Harry’s eyes.”

Ginny shrugged, but Harry thought her complexion was reddening a little. He tried to remember when he’d made an ornament like that. So close to the holidays, was he thinking about his mother’s eyes?

But such speculation was beyond him as he stood up, murmured something about a headache and quickly made his way up the stairs to his dormitory.

He spent a good bit of time on his bed, shivering and wondering if this was another warning of future parallels with his past. When he finally fell asleep, he dreamt of a time he’d looked at another metallic green bauble.

The morning could not come soon enough.

The ride to King’s Cross was blessedly uneventful — much to Harry’s relief. The worst part was the carriage ride past the patrolling Dementors, but with some forewarning even an incorporeal Patronus mist inside the carriage was enough to block them out. Harry just gritted his teeth and resisted the urge to unleash Prongs on the foul things.

However, when they disembarked from the train, they discovered a welcoming committee on the platform. All of the parents were there — Arthur, standing next to Molly, had evidently taken time off from work, and there was a thin, slightly cross-eyed man with wispy white hair that Harry recognized as Luna’s father. Augusta Longbottom and the Grangers were there as well, and Harry mentally compared them to a firing squad.

Arthur looked around a bit nervously, and then stepped forwards. “Ah good, you’re… you’re all here. Well, we all got together and thought it might be a good idea to discuss some things.” Mr. Granger’s scowl deepened and Harry thought he could hear Hermione swallowing behind him. “I’ve got a private room reserved at the Leaky Cauldron,” he continued, “so we can get right to it.”

Molly bustled forward. “Bring the Anglia around,” she suggested, though her smile seemed a bit forced, and Harry wondered what the hell had been discussed before they arrived. “We’ll meet you out front.”

Arthur nodded and took off towards the platform exit at what Harry would describe as a very fast walk.

As they rolled their trunks towards the group of assembled parents, Harry felt like he was going into battle. Mr. Granger still looked angry and Mrs. Granger didn’t look too happy either. Harry supposed he shouldn’t be surprised by that, but Ron positioning himself beside Hermione was a little unexpected. He knew his friend was a little intimidated by Hermione’s father, but he was still willing to brave that to support her. It was a nice gesture, but this could get ugly quickly.

Fortunately, the fragile peace held for a while longer. None of the adults, no matter how upset, seemed eager to make a scene in public. There was a strained silence as they made their way to the street. The Grangers did not seem eager to pile into the Ford Anglia with everyone else, and took their own car. Augusta Longbottom eyed the Anglia rather warily, but followed Neville into it without a word. Hermione rode with her parents, but didn’t seem very enthusiastic about it. She seemed relieved when Luna innocently asked if she could ride with them, explaining that she’d never been in a Muggle car before. Her father, chatting animatedly with an uncomfortable-looking Arthur Weasley, didn’t seem to care.

Hermione was awfully quiet when they all disembarked on Charing Cross road. Luna kept asking Mr. Granger questions. Harry couldn’t hear them, but Mr. Granger seemed oddly disconcerted. Harry was amused to note that the two parking spaces in front of the pub appeared to have been affected by the Muggle-repelling charms as well. At least they didn’t have to go around the block to park the Anglia.

His good humour seemed to evaporate as they entered the pub, replaced by a sense of foreboding. It only increased as they all filed into a back room and sat down at a large table. The fragile peace ended the moment Tom the barman closed the door behind them.

“All right,” Mr. Granger said in an angry voice, “we want some answers. What exactly is a Basilisk?”

Harry closed his eyes and rubbed at his forehead.

Harry admired Arthur Weasley’s courage as he took it upon himself to answer the first barrage of questions. It didn’t seem to help much, as Mr. Granger seemed to get more and more upset with every word.

“Are you people bloody insane?” he finally demanded. “Why the hell would you keep something like this in a school full of children?” His wife gave him a sharp look when he said “bloody”, but didn’t look much happier.

“Daddy, no one knew it was there!” Hermione finally said.

“How could they not know?” he asked, exasperated. “The letter we got said it was over fifty feet long!”

“It was in a hidden chamber, buried under the castle,” Harry ventured, feeling like a bit of a coward for saying nothing so far. He changed his mind when Mr. Granger’s glare focused on him. It didn’t help that the man’s anger was mostly justified.

“And what were a bunch of eleven- and twelve-year-old children doing down there?” Mr. Granger asked icily.

“It’s all my fault!” Ginny wailed. Mrs. Weasley tried to shush her, to no avail. “If you have to blame someone, blame me!”

Ginny’s distress seemed to remove most of Harry’s restraint. “It’s not her fault either,” he grated. “Someone tried to kill her and they almost succeeded. That’s what we were doing down there.” Respect his reasons or not, Harry wasn’t going to let him rail at Ginny for that mess with the diary. He folded his hands when he realized his fingernails were making indentions in the table top.

Mr. Granger opened his mouth, but his wife put a hand on his arm. “We don’t really understand any of this,” she said. “Hermione explained that there was some unpleasantness last year.” This was accompanied by a direct look that made Hermione bite her lower lip. “But she didn’t go into any details, so we thought it was fairly minor,” she explained. “Why would someone want to kill your daughter?”

“Do you remember when we discussed the, er, prejudices some people have against Muggles?” Arthur asked delicately.

Mr. Granger nodded slowly. “Yes, but your family is, how do you say it? Pure-blood, right?”

Arthur nodded. “Yes, but we still support equal rights for Muggle-born witches and wizards, as well as fair treatment of Muggles in general. I helped author a bill presented to the Wizengamot to make certain practices illegal and it… well, it made a lot of pure-bloods very upset.”

Mr. Granger frowned. “Let me get this straight. This was politically motivated? Someone tried to kill your daughter over this bill?” To Harry, he looked even more outraged.

“Partially,” Arthur agreed. “It doesn’t help that the person we think was behind this… Well, he’s been an enemy of mine for years, so this is indirectly my fault.”

“Stuff and nonsense,” Molly interjected. “That vile man is a public menace. While I don’t approve of public brawls, Arthur, it did my heart good to see you hit him.”

“Wait,” Mr. Granger said, “it was that guy at the bookstore? The one who called us—”

“The one dressed like a French pornographer?” Fred asked innocently. Harry was rather happy not to hear that word again, but several adults turned gimlet stares at the twins.

“Looks like Lee was right,” George observed. “He must, or they wouldn’t all be so mad at you for saying.”

“Ah, yes, it was him,” Arthur said quickly, trying to draw attention away from the furious whispers Molly was directing towards the twins.

“So if you know he did it, is he in jail?” Mr. Granger asked hopefully.

Arthur shook his head and sighed. “I’m afraid not. We don’t have enough evidence to press charges, much less guarantee a conviction.”

“And I imagine you’d need an airtight case against someone like that,” Mr. Granger added dryly.

“There was enough suspicion to get his son expelled from Hogwarts and to have him removed from the Board of Governors,” Arthur said.

Mr. Granger’s hands fisted at his sides. “Someone like that was on the committee in charge of my daughter’s education?” he asked in an outraged tone.

“Not anymore,” Arthur assured him.

“And how many others are there like him?” Mr. Granger asked in an icy tone.

Arthur frowned and started to say something, but stopped.

“Right,” Mr. Granger said, standing up. “That settles that. Hermione, say your goodbyes. We’re putting you in a proper school next term, away from all these nutters.”

“Daddy!” Hermione fairly shrieked.

“No arguments,” Mr. Granger commanded. “I can see why you’ve been covering up for so long.” He gave his daughter a sympathetic look. “I know how you love learning new things, but it simply isn’t safe. This is really our fault,” he added, “We should have asked better questions of that Professor McGonagall and sent her packing at the very start.”

Hermione’s mouth was opening and closing, but no words were coming out. Ron was frozen in place. His face had gone so pale that his freckles stood out like beacons. The adults all looked exceedingly uncomfortable, but none of them seemed inclined to interfere. Ginny looked perfectly miserable, and Harry had no doubt she’d blame herself for Hermione’s removal from Hogwarts as well. Neville was frowning, gripping the edge of the table, and Luna…

Luna was staring right at Harry, meeting his eyes for once. It was just a bit startling, but the imperative was unmistakable. Do something!

“If you do that, you’re placing her in even more danger,” a voice said, and it took a moment for Harry to realize that it was his own.

Mr. Granger rounded on Harry. “I’m not sure what you would know about it, but I suppose I should have guessed all that physical training had a purpose,” he said bitterly.

Harry shrugged. “I thought you knew. I imagine Hermione had good reasons for not telling you, though, even if you don’t agree. She never does anything without a reason. Maybe she didn’t want you to think she was ashamed of you, because she was looked down upon because her parents weren’t magical.” All three Grangers stiffened. Harry was cheating just a bit, recalling an emotional conversation a future Hermione had with his analogue after her parents died.

“But that’s neither here nor there,” Harry continued. “Hermione Granger is one of the most intelligent witches to attend Hogwarts in generations. Her very existence as a Muggle-born is an affront to the pure-bloods and their belief that their ancestry is more important than anything else. She regularly out-performs the scions of some very prestigious and bigoted noble houses. That already makes her a target. If you pull her out of Hogwarts and put her in a Muggle school, she’ll never realize her magical potential, and as a half-trained witch, she’ll be an easy target. They will come after her, and she won’t be able to defend herself, even if the Ministry lets her keep her wand, which I doubt. With no one to maintain them, the wards on your property will slowly fade over time. You’ll have made it easy for them when they come for her.”

“You make it sound like we’re trapped,” Mr. Granger accused in a sick and angry voice.

“I suppose you are,” Harry said in a resigned tone, ignoring the imploring look Molly was giving him. All of the other people in the room were staring at him. Some knew the secret and therefore knew what his predictions were based on. For the others, they stared either because they didn’t seem to understand why Harry was so sure, or why half the room was staring at The Boy Who Lived.

Harry sighed. “It’s Hermione’s nature to be brilliant, and it shows in everything she does. She’s the proud nail that stands up and we all love her for it,” he said with a sad smile, watching Hermione’s face turn crimson. Then he looked at Mr. Granger and the smile disappeared. “But anyone wanting to play the hammer is going to have to get through me first,” he added, his eyes boring into those of the older man.

“Me too!” Ron croaked, having finally found his voice. Neville, Ginny, and Luna said much the same thing half a beat later. To Harry’s surprise, the twins and Percy added their agreement as well.

That seemed to take Mr. Granger back, and Mrs. Granger leaned over to put her arms around Hermione, who had burst into silent tears. After a moment, Hermione’s father sat down, propped his elbows on the table, and massaged his temples. “All right,” he said after a moment. “We won’t make any rash decisions. I don’t think Hogwarts is in any way an appropriate learning environment, but we may not have any better options.” He looked up and glared at Harry. “You debate rather viciously for a thirteen-year-old.”

Harry looked down. He picked at the edge of the table. “I’m trying to protect my friend the best way I know how,” he said after a moment, then looked up.

Mr. Granger nodded slowly. “All right. So can anyone tell me what’s so valuable about a dead snake?”

After the initial drama, getting schedules worked out was rather simple. The day after Boxing Day, Harry and his friends would Floo over to Slughorn’s office, accompanied by Mr. Weasley. Professor Slughorn would oversee the actual quartering of the body and evaluating what materials would still be suitable for potion-making or other uses. As expected, the Head of Slytherin was fairly cautious in his estimates, but even the low-end figure for the individual shares had Mr. Granger raising his eyebrows.

“That’s more than enough to pay for university after Hermione finishes school,” Mrs. Granger noted.

Mr. Granger was still less than enthusiastic, but nodded. He mellowed a bit more when Molly invited all the Grangers over for dinner on Boxing Day. Harry thought it was a nice gesture after all the earlier tension. For his part, he couldn’t really blame anyone. It was an ugly situation the parents of every Muggle-born had to deal with. Maybe Hermione should have been more straightforward with her parents, but it couldn’t be easy telling them either.

After Tom the barman brought a light meal to the meeting room, and everyone had a sup and a bite, Arthur and Mr. Granger fell into a bit of good-natured wrangling over who was paying the tab. Mr. Weasley had just made the point that his brood represented a majority when Tom returned with the bill and was intercepted by Madam Longbottom.

Both men turned to stare at her as Tom left, realizing they’d been outmanoeuvred. Augusta Longbottom merely looked at them with an arched eyebrow. Neither of them said a word.

Harry glanced over at Neville, who was openly grinning.

It wasn’t long after that before everyone went their separate ways. After Arthur helped him retrieve his trunk from the Anglia’s boot, Neville and his Gran used Tom’s Floo to get home. Hermione left with her parents while Molly offered Luna and her father a ride to Ottery St. Catchpole.

The long drive home passed more quickly than Harry expected. Mr. Lovegood and Mr. Weasley chatted all the way, Xenophilius asking Arthur about the Ministry, while Arthur in turn asked about the Lovegoods’ Muggle neighbours. Harry was too entertained by the verbal fencing to get nervous about being closed in. While Mr. Lovegood would no doubt love to get material for his next Quibbler article, Mr. Weasley worked for a department that regulated interactions between Wizarding folk and Muggles — including rules regarding enchanted objects that Mr. Lovegood no doubt bent more than once. But the back and forth between them was entirely amicable, more like an old game between friends. Harry remembered that Ginny knew Luna from before Hogwarts, so there was little doubt the men were at least acquainted with each other.

Harry’s thoughts strayed to the redheaded girl sitting quietly next to him. She hadn’t said much since her outburst during the confrontation with Mr. Granger. Now her expression was composed, but pensive. Harry awkwardly patted her knee and she looked up and gave him a wan smile. He smiled back at her and shrugged. She sighed and leaned her head against his shoulder.

Harry closed his eyes, listening to the faint sounds of her breathing, feeling better than he had all day.

Harry was sitting next to the door, something he doubted was an accident, so he jumped out to help Luna with her trunk when they stopped at the Lovegood house. Mr. Weasley complimented Xenophilius on how well his home blended into the neighbourhood and Luna’s father responded that he was thinking about moving to a small tower just outside the village he’d heard might be up for sale soon.

Luna turned and stared at her father, who quickly reassured her it wasn’t too far out of town, and it would give them a little more room. She was still frowning a little when she turned back to Harry.

“As long as you’re on the Floo, you’ll always be close enough,” Harry murmured as they wrestled the trunk onto the front porch. He wondered if Luna had taken up rock collecting.

“That’s not really it. My mother lived here,” Luna said in a quiet voice.

“I see,” Harry replied. He waited until they got the trunk into her room. Thinking about the troubles he had the first night at The Burrow, he lowered his voice to little more than a whisper when he spoke again. “Maybe that’s why. Your father might want to live somewhere that doesn’t always remind him.”

Luna cocked her head and gave him one of those disturbingly direct looks again. “Is it hard for you?” she asked.

Harry shrugged, wondering how this had suddenly become a discussion of his mental state. “Sometimes,” he admitted. “But I’m also building new memories, so I think…” he frowned. “I think those are helping dilute the effects of the bad ones. I hope so, anyway.”

Luna nodded thoughtfully. “Maybe that will help my father,” she mused. “If not, I can always find a Three-Tailed Mookabaru to cheer him up.”

Harry smiled.

37

Return to the Chamber

By the time they finally arrived at The Burrow, Harry was nearly done in. The stress from the unexpected confrontation with the Grangers was bleeding off, and there was little he wanted to do besides have a bit of a kip before dinner.

Of course, his plans didn’t account for a large black dog that was frightfully eager to say hello. After giving Harry’s face a thorough lick, the shaggy mutt gently seized his sleeve and pulled him toward Arthur’s shed. Harry waved helplessly to Ron as he was dragged off. Ron just laughed and offered to haul his trunk inside for him, the prat.

No sooner were they inside the shed with the door closed, than Sirius changed to his human form and gave Harry a firm rap on the head. Harry winced and grabbed at his scalp. His godfather had rather hard knuckles.

“What the hell was that for?” Harry snapped, rubbing his abused skull.

“I got your letter,” Sirius said, leaning back against the wall.

Harry looked around, avoiding the man’s glittering black eyes. The shed looked definitely cleaner than he remembered. There was even a comfortable-looking chair in the back, next to the camp bed, along with a small table piled high with musty-looking tomes. “You getting by all right in here?” Harry asked.

“It’s a hell of a lot more comfortable than what I’m used to,” Sirius replied. “And don’t change the subject. I read what you wrote about that Slytherin girl.”

Harry spun to face the man. “She wasn’t just a Slytherin,” he said hotly, “she was my friend and I got her bloody well murdered.”

“Right on one, wrong on two,” Sirius quipped. “Though you picked up on that faster than your dad did.”

Harry blinked.

“How do you think we managed all those pranks without getting caught? You don’t think Snape ever got lucky or had a good day?” Sirius shook his head. “There were a few people in that House who despised the very air he breathed. They’d sell him out for a Knut, so we always stayed one step ahead of him.”

“You had spies? In Slytherin?” Harry asked, wide-eyed.

“I wouldn’t go that far,” Sirius replied. “We had a few acquaintances in other Houses that would help us out from time to time.” He shrugged. “Everyone traded favours; it’s how you learned to deal with people. Your mum was uncommonly generous with her tutoring help in Potions and Charms. I think that’s one reason she had such an easy go at being Head Girl.” He shook his head, as if to clear it. “Anyway, the part with you blaming yourself for what happened to her – that’s the rubbish.”

“But she didn’t die in the original timeline!” Harry protested. “Something I did caused it to happen,” he concluded in a sick voice.

Sirius made a weary sigh. “Did you kill her, Harry? Did you use the Imperius Curse on one of her classmates to get them to stab her?”

“No,” Harry said, “but I’m still responsible.”

“Dammit, Harry, you’re not a god!” Sirius barked. “So something didn’t turn out the way you expected. Deal with it and move on. You don’t think I wish I’d handled Peter differently? All those Muggles would still be alive and I would never have seen the inside of Azkaban. Worse, I could have pressed my claim as your godfather before the Wizengamot if I thought the Dursleys weren’t treating you right.”

The unshed tears standing in Sirius Black’s eyes killed any protest Harry might have tried to muster. Uncomfortable, he looked away. “Then why do I feel so bloody guilty?” he finally asked.

“Because you are a responsible git, just like your dad.” Sirius sighed and ran his fingers through his hair. It was still a bit long, but much neater than Harry remembered. “Coming back the way you did,” his godfather said after a moment, “you have a lot of advantages. But it’s not everything. Maybe it’s easier to feel like it’s your fault than admit you can’t control everything.”

Harry thought about that for a moment. There was a certain… perverse logic to that, he supposed. At the same time, he felt bands around his heart, bands he didn’t even realize were there, slowly loosen a bit. “When did you get so wise?” Harry asked.

Sirius shrugged. “I nicked your mum’s notes every chance I got.”

Harry laughed at that, feeling a little better. Just like bloody Sirius to slip a joke in to break the tension. After a moment, he looked up at his godfather. “My dad was ‘responsible’?” Harry asked in a small voice, remembering Snape’s memory of James publicly taunting him.

“Yes,” Sirius replied. “Good thing too. Maybe, anyway.” He looked away, going suddenly serious. “When I was bloody pissed at Snape, I set him up to walk in on Moony on a full moon. James found out and decked me, then caught up to him and Stunned the tosser right before he opened the door.” Harry noticed the man’s fists clenching. “Of course, with what you told me, if he’d snuffed it, Voldemort would never have heard the prophecy and your parents would still be alive.”

Harry’s eyes narrowed. “Remus would never have forgiven you if he hadn’t,” he snapped.

Sirius sighed. “It seemed appropriate at the time. Remus’ books had been scattered during a scuffle our seventh year and I saw Snape picking up a letter from his parents before McGonagall sorted everyone out. A week later, Death Eaters attacked their hideout and burned it to the ground. I thought it was too big a coincidence to ignore and arranged a little payback for the Lupins.”

“That’s quite a stretch,” Harry said, still a little annoyed, even though it was years ago and Remus had obviously forgiven him.

Sirius shrugged. “They’d gone into hiding over a year before, but the letter might have held clues as to their location and I never said Snape was stupid.” He shook his head. “It couldn’t have been a coincidence.”

“Even so, I don’t think Remus would have accepted that,” Harry said.

“Probably not,” Sirius agreed. “It took a month before he’d even talk to me after what did happen. But I think what Snape did later with that prophecy means I was right.”

Harry scowled. He didn’t think this argument was worth continuing. They’d probably never know.

Sirius seemed to agree, because he changed the subject; sort of. “So what did the greasy bastard do after you got him sacked?” His lips curled into a rather evil leer.

Harry grimaced. “I don’t know. He was gone by the time Dumbledore made the announcement.” He frowned. “If he really was accepting money from Lucius to spy on me first year, he may have gone to the Malfoys for help.”

“Better to have him clearly on the opposite side then,” Sirius said with a grim smile and a satisfied nod. “Harder for him to play us off against each other.”

“Maybe,” Harry said. Now he had something new to worry about.

Mrs. Weasley put her foot down when it came to dinner that night, so Sirius joined them at the table, rather than under it. He was a little wary of being seen by an unexpected visitor, but Mr. Weasley did something to the Floo to make it chime if someone wished to enter, but not admit them until they were approved.

Harry made an honest effort to join in the meal time conversations, but afterwards he would have drawn a blank if asked what they discussed. For the most part, his mind was still going over what Sirius had said. It was very tempting to believe he truly was not responsible for Melissa’s death, but could that be merely rationalizing?

He was drawn out of his thoughts when someone kicked him under the table. Ginny was sitting beside him, but she didn’t even spare him a glance as she talked to Percy.

Someone had evidently declared The Burrow a “no moping zone”.

He wondered how far she’d go to enforce that edict, but he wasn’t sure he wanted to know. Picturing Ginny kicking him repeatedly as he stubbornly tried to maintain a sulk was so ridiculous he nearly choked on a bite of potatoes.

He shifted a little on his chair and the thick vial in his pocket dug into his leg. Sirius had given it to him as they walked back from the shed.

“See if you can nick a bit of the Basilisk’s poison when Sluggy recovers it,” Sirius said with a grin.

Harry peered sideways at his godfather. “Do I even want to know what you need Basilisk venom for?”

“Been doing a bit of reading while you were away,” Sirius replied breezily. “Basilisk venom is incredibly destructive, and it seems to be the only thing you tried that could damage the Diary. If I’m right, we can use it when we destroy our little collection of keepsakes.”

Harry reluctantly nodded. That made a certain amount of sense. “I’ll see what I can do. If not, he’s going to sell the rest anyway. We can always buy it then.”

“I’d rather not advertise that we even have it,” Sirius replied. “I know it’s a long shot, but I’d rather not leave any pieces lying about for anyone to put together.”

Harry shook his head as Mrs. Weasley asked if he wanted thirds. Molly. He was supposed to start calling her Molly, but the habit was harder to break than he’d realized.

Of course, the shock of Sirius being cautious about anything was enough to make you forget things. He listened as his father’s friend described a prank to the twins that had backfired spectacularly. Harry supposed telling him how he’d died had more of an impact than he’d appreciated. Or maybe just hearing about Harry’s old future had driven home the idea that things can get much worse.

After dinner, most of them retired to the sitting room as Harry and Ginny cleared the table. Physically, they were still the two youngest people in the house, and that chore usually fell to the youngest Weasley that could manage it.

This time, however, Mrs. Weasley stayed behind and showed them both a few simple spells to clear the dishes and start them washing. Harry smiled a little when he realized she was finally accepting the loophole in the underage magic laws. She had always seemed a bit less comfortable with it than Arthur had, but they’d evidently talked it over during the term.

Once the dishes were drying, the three of them joined the rest of the family. Percy had one of his textbooks open, reading ahead for next term. Ron, Sirius, and the twins were playing Exploding Snap and Harry smirked at how well Sirius seemed to fit in with boys half his age.

He was also apparently better at cheating than Fred and George put together.

Harry stretched and yawned.

“Are you all right, Harry? You look tired,” Mrs.– Molly said with a light frown.

Harry shrugged. “I didn’t get a lot of sleep last night, and your dinners always fill me up,” he said with a crooked smile. “I may just go ahead and go to bed so I can catch up.”

Molly nodded. “You do look a bit worn out. Let me know if you have any trouble getting to sleep. I’ll leave the kettle out and a cup of warm milk won’t take but a second to heat.”

“Thanks,” he said. “I’ll do that.” As he turned towards the stairs, Ginny caught his eye. She was frowning a little until he nodded.

He just needed a bit of rest. But it was nice to have so many people looking after him again.

There was good and bad news as Christmas approached. Bill and his co-workers were able to get their new project done ahead of schedule and earned an unexpected holiday over the holidays, which made Molly and the rest of her brood extremely happy.

Charlie, on the other hand, wrote from the dragon reserve to report that a dragon-pox outbreak at one of the camps had many of the handlers too sick to work. His boss made a personal appeal, reminding him that if they were too short-staffed some of their charges might suffer, until Charlie reluctantly agreed to cancel his leave. Molly was a bit upset that he wouldn’t be joining them for Christmas that year, but Arthur beamed with pride at how responsible his son had become. It took a while for him to cheer her up, but eventually he managed and the whole family mailed off a care package that required four owls to lift.

Harry was looking forward to talking to Bill again, and secretly relieved not to have to explain things to someone else. He felt a bit guilty about that, but he never really knew which way someone would react to hearing his tale. Bill’s blasé acceptance still intrigued him a little.

Bill doubled up with Percy when he arrived the day before Christmas Eve, and volunteered to lead everyone on a shopping trip to Diagon Alley. Molly’s reflexive misgivings didn’t last long against the combined enthusiasm of her offspring. Bill was very much the ‘cool’ older brother, even to Percy. For the latter, it probably didn’t hurt that he’d also been Head Boy in his day, and had a thriving career.

Sirius, however, was rather disappointed with the eldest Weasley brother.

When Bill went out to take a look at the ward stones, he looked up at the huge black dog bounding toward him. “When did you lot talk Mum into a dog?” he asked curiously, and Harry realized that Sirius never really came up in their conversation at the Three Broomsticks.

The Grim-like dog skidded to a stop in front of Bill, then cocked its head and whined. Ron started laughing, making Bill turn toward him – long enough for Sirius to transform.

The Curse-Breaker did jump a little when he turned back around, but didn’t even reach for his wand. “Sirius Black?” he asked.

Sirius nodded.

“Wanted mass murder?”

Sirius nodded again, grinning.

“Harry, right?”

Sirius sighed and looked disappointed. Ron laughed even harder, but the twins looked crestfallen.

Sirius was also rather sad at being left behind again, but not knowing if Peter had talked made even his animal form too dangerous to reveal. Harry grabbed some parchment and a quill and pulled his godfather aside.

“What?” the older man asked petulantly.

“If I’m going to be doing your bloody shopping for you,” Harry said in an exasperated tone, “I don’t want to forget something and give you an excuse to whine.”

“I do not whine!” Sirius exclaimed in a wounded tone.

“If you were any more disappointed that Bill didn’t freak out, you’d be crying your eyes out,” Harry said, rolling his own eyes.

“I wasn’t that bad.”

Harry just looked at Sirius, slowly raising one eyebrow.

“Oh, damn!” Sirius spat. “You got Lily’s eyebrow!”

“What?” Harry snapped.

“That was damn scary,” Sirius said, clutching his chest. “Your mum had this way of looking at us when she was annoyed or thought we were being stupid. James tried to copy that when he became Head Boy, but he could never quite pull it off. She could shut us down faster than McGonagall.”

Harry burst out laughing.

Ginny also received a list from her mum, and Arthur asked Bill to pick up a few things as well. From what Harry overheard, Professor Lupin was invited to Christmas dinner, and Molly was planning just as big a meal for the Grangers on Boxing Day. Harry smiled as he watched her bustle about The Burrow. She definitely loved playing the host.

Bill led them through the Floo to the Leaky Cauldron with little fanfare. The pub was fairly busy for the middle of the day, but Harry supposed it was the impending holiday. He reminded himself again that people were a lot more carefree about gathering in public before Voldemort returned.

When Bill asked which shop they wanted to hit first, Ron surprised them all when he said, “Flourish and Blotts”. He promptly turned red as everyone turned to stare at him. “What?” he demanded.

Ginny just smiled slightly and shook her head.

Harry turned towards the twins just as Fred was opening his mouth. George quickly elbowed his brother and the comment died aborning.

As they made their way around the first bend in the alley, Ron quietly edged towards Harry.

“Right,” Bill announced. “Mum made me promise to keep an eye on you lot, so go in, get what you need and come back out here. I’ll be waiting.”

“What about you?” Ginny asked.

“I already did my shopping,” Bill said smugly as he handed her Arthur’s list. “Amazing what you can find when you travel.” He turned towards the twins, who were looking entirely too innocent. “And I wouldn’t suggest messing about with my baggage,” he warned. “I’ve learned some rather nasty tricks this past year.”

“Wouldn’t think of it,” George assured him as he walked into the shop.

Bill snorted.

As soon as they entered the bookshop, Ron grabbed Harry’s elbow and steered him off to the side. “You’ve got to help me,” he said quickly.

“With what?” Harry asked, guessing he already knew the answer.

“I need to get something for Hermione,” Ron said quickly. “She likes books, right?”

“I guess,” Harry said slowly.

“Last year, she said she really liked your present from here. How did you know which one to get her?” Ron asked. “She’s mad about reading, you know. How can I tell if she’s read one already?”

“That’s a good question, Ron,” Harry said. “You could get her a general reference work, so she’ll still need it even if she’s read it before.”

“You mean like a book of Arithmancy tables?” Ron asked, clearly dismayed.

Harry nodded. “I know, it doesn’t seem very… special… does it? Not for a present.” Especially not if Ron was starting to have some feelings for their mutual friend.

Ron nodded.

“Well, I knew it was useless to try and keep up with her reading list,” Harry continued, “So I just set up a tab here, with their owl order service, and sent her the details.”

Ron frowned. “That’s not much better, is it?” he asked. “I mean, you’re making her pick out her own presents. Is that… I mean… did she like that?”

“I think she did,” Harry said. “But it was a very practical gift, I agree. I think you want to give her something more… personal… right?”

Ron coloured a little. “Well, I want…I want her to like it. If I do this tab thing, she’ll think I just copied you.” He paused. “She… I want her to think I went to a little effort, you know?”

Harry nodded. Even if Ron was picking his brain for ideas, he was clearly making an effort here. Admitting all that must have been even harder for him. “You know, there’s a stationery shop next door. She’s always writing things, and getting after us about our penmanship. You could get her a really nice quill and ink set… sort of acknowledging that she writes as well as she reads.”

Ron nodded slowly. “That’s a good idea,” he said. “You doing the book tab here again?”

“Yeah,” Harry admitted. “There are… other… reasons as well.”

Ron looked puzzled for a moment before nodding again. “Yeah, you’re right. She’s scary smart, so that can’t hurt. Good thing you convinced her parents to keep her at Hogwarts.”

Harry shrugged. “They just didn’t have the whole picture, I think.”

Ron looked up, right into Harry’s eyes. “Are you really sure it’s better, for her?”

Harry felt unaccountably proud of his friend at that moment. “Without a doubt, Ron,” Harry replied.

Ron nodded once. “I think I’ll go see if Bill will let me duck into the stationery shop for half a mo’.”

The rest of the expedition passed without incident. Harry was glad not to encounter any unfriendly faces from school, but he also realized that most of the elite pure-blood families were fairly wealthy. As such, he doubted they’d be doing a lot of last minute Christmas shopping. Or if they did, they had servants for that.

That reminded him of something, which led to a quick discussion with Bill and a short detour into Muggle London from the public entrance of the Leaky Cauldron.

The jumpers, trousers, and winter jackets they all wore fit right in with the Muggles outside. Bill was nearly as confident operating in the Muggle world, and he was a calming presence. Percy was visibly agitated – right up until the twins started teasing him about it. Ron and Ginny just walked on either side of Harry, practically in lockstep.

Fortunately, they didn’t have far to go. Harry quickly found a small shop that sold notions and holiday novelties and made his purchases. He still had enough pound notes to cover those and a selection of Muggle candies he introduced to his friends.

Ron’s opinion of Muggles improved noticeably after his first Mars bar.

By the time they returned to The Burrow, everyone thought of that little detour as a fine adventure. Even Percy had unwound a little, agreeing that they should do this again over the summer hols. Harry was a little surprised to see how clearly the prefect was influenced by his older brother. Perhaps, with Bill around, he didn’t feel quite as obligated to set an example for the others.

Molly was a little startled when she heard about their little detour, but Bill seemed surprised that she even thought it was an issue, so she soon dropped it. Harry carefully filed that bit of information away for later.

Harry had a nostalgic moment when Ron actually had to wake him up Christmas morning. It also drove home how much better he’d been sleeping lately. Perhaps feeling like he was actually making significant progress was helping. Sirius securing most of Voldemort’s relics last summer was just the most significant change.

The day went as well as he could have hoped; having Bill there resulted in a few more embarrassing stories being shared, from the time before Harry had even met Ron. Harry laughed along with the others, and just basked in the homey atmosphere of The Burrow. This was what he was fighting for, even if a dark corner of his mind counselled that he enjoy it while it lasted.

Occasionally, he would glance over towards Ginny, who seemed just a shade less cheery than usual. He wondered if she was still brooding about the Chamber. In a way, he could understand why she felt guilty, even if no one blamed her for what happened. Harry didn’t know if Draco was aware of what he’d stolen from Harry’s trunk, but that wouldn’t stop Harry from taking it out of his hide if the opportunity arose.

It was a little harder getting to sleep that night, knowing they’d be going back to Hogwarts tomorrow to salvage Basilisk parts. But Slughorn would be supervising, and it should be safe. Harry was still a little uneasy as he turned over and closed his eyes for the third time.

Harry tried not to let his nervousness show as they waited for the Grangers to arrive. There was no way things wouldn’t be a little awkward after his little performance at the Leaky Cauldron, but he honestly couldn’t see what else he could have done.

It still annoyed him that he jumped when the Floo roared to life.

Hermione was the first to step through, and Harry relaxed a little when he saw the smile on her face. Evidently things hadn’t gone too badly for her. Her parents followed her through and Harry was glad to see that neither of them looked as angry as the last time he saw them.

Molly bustled forward and soon had them settled around the scrubbed wood table with mugs of hot chocolate. They hadn’t really had a chance to get cold, travelling through the Floo, but she tended to treat any visitors to The Burrow like that. Besides, her hot chocolate was rather good.

Ron was rather quiet through all this, hardly seeming to look up at all. After the guests had a cuppa and the adults retired to the sitting room, Hermione zeroed in on them before they could leave the kitchen.

“How was Christmas, Hermione?” Harry asked, trying not to grin openly.

“It went very well, Harry,” his friend answered absently as she tried to catch Ron’s eye. The latter’s ears were slowly turning red as he looked down at the floor.

“No problems with the parents?” Harry asked in a low voice, the corner of his mouth twitching.

“Not so much as I expected,” she replied, actually leaning forwards a bit to try and make eye contact with Ron. Her eyebrows began to knit together as Ron shuffled his feet.

“Did you like your presents?” Harry asked. “Ron insisted we coordinate so we didn’t both get you the same thing.”

An odd, strangled sound came from Ron’s general direction.

“Really?” Hermione asked. “That was very thoughtful of you,” she added softly.

Ron’s hands were fisted so tightly on the hem of his jumper that Harry wondered that it hadn’t torn. “Thanks,” he blurted out.

“In fact,” Harry added, “he insisted on taking care of your gift first thing.”

Ron’s head shot up, giving Harry a glare of pure betrayal as his face went scarlet. But any thoughts of impending violence were clearly dispelled by the brilliant smile Hermione gave him.

Harry backed away, feeling a little smug. Any guilt he might have experienced over Ron’s embarrassment was more than made up for by Hermione’s reaction. In some ways, he thought that her insecurity was the bigger problem than his adopted brother’s inarticulate shyness. From the odd comment he’d picked up, Hermione’s intelligence had prevented her from making any friends before coming to Hogwarts, so it was sort of understandable.

He passed through the doorway to the sitting room and came face to face with Mr. Granger. The dentist glared down at him. “What exactly is going on over there?” he asked in a harsh whisper.

Harry shrugged and tried to suppress his smile. “Hermione really liked her present from Ron. I sort of let her know that he went to a lot of effort to pick it out.” He glanced back. Fortunately, neither of his friends had even glanced in his direction.

“So what are you two playing at with my daughter?” the dentist asked, eyes narrowing.

Harry sighed. “Your daughter,” he replied, keeping his voice down, “who is smarter than both of us put together, is talking to one of my best friends, who would sooner gouge out his own eyes than deliberately hurt her.”

Any further conversation was forestalled when a hand appeared behind Mr. Granger, tapping him on the shoulder. As he turned, Mrs. Granger’s hand moved to his elbow, and she firmly guided him back into the sitting room.

It was almost a relief when they took the Floo to Hogwarts. Harry never knew when Mr. Granger’s gimlet eye would come to rest on him, and he had the feeling the man knew more than he let on. Unfortunately, it was almost impossible for Muggles to learn Occlumency, as they had no inherent magic. Hermione said she’d explained to them, in as general terms as possible, that there were a few things she wasn’t able to talk about for magical reasons, but Harry didn’t think Mr. Granger fully accepted that. Not that he could really blame the man.

Things like this really drove home how vulnerable most Muggles were to magical manipulation. Any time they stepped outside the wards around their house, any wizard could sift through their memories. Well, any Legilimens could. Of course, someone unconcerned with casting Unforgiveables could use the Imperius Curse on them and then Obliviate the memory.

As Harry stepped into Professor Slughorn’s office, he decided that thinking about all the ways things could go wrong was not the way to start this project. He swallowed and glanced over at Ginny. She had been rather quiet all morning, and seemed a little paler than usual. He nudged her shoulder gently with his and was rewarded with a wan smile.

Neville and Luna were waiting for them, and from the odd look on Slughorn’s face, and the repressed grin on Neville’s, she’d been talking to them for quite a while now.

Bill came along partly out of curiosity and partly to reassure his mum. Evidently remembering Bill’s assignment with Carpenter, Fitz-Williams, and Holmes, the corpulent professor’s handshake was rather enthusiastic. Horace Slughorn wasted no time ushering their party down, chatting with Bill about other Gringotts employees he knew.

They made a quick trip outside to the broom shed. Professor Slughorn said the Deputy Headmistress had given permission for them to use the Gryffindor brooms for this task, provided they were responsible for any damages. Given the market price of Basilisk parts, that wouldn’t be a problem, Slughorn assured them with a smile.

Moaning Myrtle’s bathroom was just as damp and dreary as Harry remembered. He reluctantly shuffled up to the marked basin. Slughorn’s avid gaze made Harry rather self-conscious as he cleared his throat. “Open!” he commanded in Parseltongue, wondering whether he’d really acquired this ability from Voldemort, or if some ancestor of his carried the trait like Slughorn claimed his great-uncle did.

The basin obediently sank into the floor, revealing the dank passageway that descended into the darkness.

“Lumos,” Harry incanted softly, lighting up the end of his wand. He mounted his broom and slowly floated over to the chute. He would be in the lead to open the doors below, but Bill would be right behind him, keeping an eye out for any dangers they’d bypassed the first time. Harry didn’t think there could be anything left that wasn’t triggered the first time around, let alone during the barrage they’d laid down in this timeline, but it never hurt to have a professional Curse-Breaker along. Besides, it meant Molly would worry less and that alone was worth it.

Floating down slowly on a broom took considerably longer than sliding down on one’s arse, but it was a lot cleaner. Fortunately, the new brooms didn’t have any tendency to drift, so even Hermione was able to manage with no problems. Not that it kept Ron from following her down as closely as possible, talking to her in a quiet voice the whole time. The bushy-haired girl let out a quiet sigh of relief when they finally reached the outer sections of the Chamber.

Conversely, Ginny looked even more uneasy. Shouldering his broom, Harry quite deliberately walked up to the same side as her free arm and laced his fingers through hers. She jumped a little at the contact and turned her head towards him. If she hadn’t noticed him walking up, Harry reasoned, she was more affected than she let on. He gave her fingers a quick squeeze. “It’s going to be all right,” he murmured.

Ginny nodded once and her fingers tightened around his.

Professor Slughorn opened up a canvas sack he’d been carrying. Inside was a rooster he’d apparently borrowed from Hagrid. The handling, not to mention the light from their wands, was enough to rouse the sleeping bird and it let out a loud cry that echoed through the tunnels ahead. Slughorn patted the bird and carefully put it back into the sack. He coughed once, when he noticed everyone staring at him. “Thought it might be prudent, just in case there were any hatchlings,” he explained.

Harry nodded. Though he didn’t remember any from before, Slughorn couldn’t be sure. It was actually a clever precaution, since traditionally the sound of a cock’s crow would kill a Basilisk stone dead. He reminded himself that, for all his grasping ways, the elderly potions professor was actually a very clever man.

Harry led them forwards, holding onto Ginny’s hand. Her complexion seemed a little flushed in the wand light, but he judged that to be an improvement of sorts. She didn’t even react when he spoke Parseltongue again, opening the final doorway.

Harry cast another spell as he stepped forwards, lighting up the stones in the ceiling. With the Chamber of Secrets better lit than it had been in centuries, he looked around.

Dominating the chamber was, of course, the corpse of the Basilisk. It wasn’t as large as the statue of Salazar Slytherin, but the mere existence of a formerly living being that large drew the eye. Both Slughorn and Bill let out startled oaths. Harry suspected neither really believed it was as large as they’d claimed. To be honest, fighting a horribly dangerous creature in an underground chamber would make one’s memory tend to inflate size, but if anything, they had underestimated it.

The second thing Harry noticed was all the carnage. While the Basilisk didn’t appear to have decomposed at all, it had quite clearly been in a fight. Chunks of its flesh were missing, and in a couple of places Harry could see where a curse had punched all the way through its body. He thought of the last few Reductos he’d cast when it had looked like the snake was about to crush them all and his fingers tightened around Ginny’s hand. It had been far too bloody close.

Even the misses were impressive in their own way. Slytherin’s statue didn’t look half so impressive with all the spell damage it had sustained. As big as the Basilisk was, maybe a third of their spells had missed, gouging out hunks of stone and leaving the remainder spider-webbed with cracks.

Harry heard a soft sigh from his left, and turned to see Slughorn gaze sadly at the damaged effigy of his House’s founder. After a moment, the man shook his head and turned back to the corpse. “I would never have believed it, had I not seen it with my own eyes,” he said slowly. He didn’t look away, but his words were clearly directed at Harry. “That has to be one of the largest Basilisks in recorded history. They grow throughout their lives and this one has clearly lived centuries longer than they do in the wild. To think that a monster that size was destroyed by schoolchildren…” He shook his head.

Harry swallowed quickly. “I think the panic helped actually,” he said. “We were so scared it pushed our magic much harder than normal.” He hadn’t talked about his training session with Remus to any other professors – especially not someone like Slughorn who might find that information useful. While Harry was certain his spells had made most of the larger holes, it wouldn’t hurt to spread the credit around.

Slughorn nodded. “Still, this is quite, quite remarkable,” he said, clearly filing that information away with a smile. Harry hadn’t anticipated that, but as he thought about it, decided it didn’t hurt. Word getting around that some of the new Gryffindor students were rather formidable might help more than hurt in the long run.

The professor’s words seemed to break everyone out of their individual reveries. They eased forwards, using their wands to clear away fallen rubble, as Slughorn began unshrinking a collection of wooden crates and sturdy glass collection jars.

Dismembering the battered corpse of an enormous Basilisk was not what Harry would consider the high point of the Christmas hols. However, Professor Slughorn did try to make it an educational activity, teaching them several specialized charms for sectioning the body and collecting the ingredients with a minimum of contamination. There was actually more to it than Harry anticipated, and Hermione at least seemed to find this a silver lining of sorts. Ron and Neville seemed happier about the money the ingredients would net, especially since they had earned this reward.

Ginny, on the other hand, seemed rather dismayed at the danger in which she’d placed her friends. Try as Harry might to reason with her, she still felt responsible for their being here in the first place.

Harry brooded about this as he left her side for a moment to run an errand. Slughorn was talking to Bill about selling the day’s proceeds on the domestic, as opposed to foreign, markets and he was turned away from the large demijohn of oily black Basilisk venom.

Harry winked at Bill over the short professor’s shoulder as he slipped Sirius’ vial out of his pocket. A quick charm his godfather had shown him let him siphon out an ounce or two of the horrifically toxic liquid, and he had the cap screwed on tight a moment later. The vial was in his pocket before he cleared his throat and asked if the scales at the very tip of the tail needed special handling.

When Harry returned to Ginny, he saw that Luna was talking to her. The blonde girl was speaking too quietly for Harry to hear, and she smiled at him and walked over to Neville and Ron before he even reached Ginny.

“What was that all about?” Harry asked her.

“Luna was talking about right after her mother died,” Ginny replied, frowning in confusion. “She said she blamed herself for a long time, because she wasn’t able to get help fast enough. It’s very sad, but I don’t understand why she wanted to tell me just now.”

Harry swallowed. “Er, maybe she’s saying that you are also blaming yourself for something that isn’t really your fault?”

Ginny scowled at Harry for a moment, then gave a single nod and turned back to the section of scales they’d been working on. Her face looked troubled, but the hand holding her wand was steady as a stone.

Harry let out the breath he’d been holding and went back to work loosening the scales. Maybe Ginny felt like they were ganging up on her, but when Luna Lovegood starts making sense, only a fool would refuse to listen.

By the time they were done salvaging everything useful from the carcass, Harry was starting to crave a bit of sunlight or some open sky. Slughorn’s wand danced as he carefully packed away all the materials. He seemed almost giddy, and Harry assumed things had gone better than expected.

His friends seemed equally relieved to bid goodbye to the Chamber of Secrets. They mounted their brooms with alacrity, this time with Harry trailing behind to close the doors behind them. He didn’t really have any plans for the place at the moment, but leaving it open seemed imprudent.

In short order, they were back in Moaning Myrtle’s bathroom and Harry commanded the passageway to close again. The depressed spirit wasn’t anywhere to be seen, but Harry guessed she didn’t dare mess about too much in front of a professor.

Slughorn insisted on personally escorting them to the Floo in his office, and Harry wondered if he knew how some of their parents felt about the whole thing. Molly could be about as subtle as a Bludger when she wanted to make a point, and Harry thought the Grangers’ feelings about this would make her even more emphatic. As it was, Slughorn insisted on looking them over carefully before they left, using his wand to remove a bit of slime from Ron’s sleeve. Finally, he nodded and stuck his head into the fire to contact The Burrow.

The first things Harry noticed when he stumbled from the fire were the drool-inspiring smells that surrounded him. Molly had evidently been going full-tilt since they left, and from her rolled-up sleeves, it appeared that Mrs. Granger had joined in as well. The way both mothers looked them over after the initial greetings only confirmed Harry’s suspicions as they were sent to wash up.

In the sitting room, Mr. Granger, Arthur, Bill, and Percy were all talking over some papers spread on the table amidst the cups of tea. From the scraps Harry heard before they noticed their arrival, they seemed to be discussing Muggle surveillance technology. Harry shook his head as he headed up the stairs.

Clean, refreshed, and eagerly anticipating dinner, Harry headed back down the stairs. As he passed Ginny’s landing, she stepped out, tying back her hair into a ponytail.

“Mum said she’d need a bit of help getting the table set,” she said by way of explanation.

Harry nodded. “Let me know if you need some help.”

Ginny shook her head, smiling. “Three of us in the kitchen are almost too much. We’re not even asking Hermione, which Mum thinks is too much of a shame.”

Harry smirked. “Doesn’t think any girl shouldn’t know her way around a stove?”

“Pretty much, though I doubt she’ll ever have much time to cook after she finishes Hogwarts.”

“Maybe,” Harry agreed. “She’s made a lot of plans, none of them definite.”

Ginny gave a less than lady-like snort. “She can’t, not if she has to wait on Ron.”

Harry shrugged. He didn’t think that was totally fair to her brother, but she had to know him better, didn’t she? “So I guess your planning is going to be a lot simpler?” he asked without thinking.

Ginny faltered. “I, er, I don’t really know,” she said, face reddening.

Harry wanted to kick himself – hard. “Personally,” he said carefully, “I can’t make too many long-term plans until certain problems are dealt with. But once I’m done with those, I imagine things will be different.”

Ginny nodded slowly, looking at some point off to the side. “I see. That’s understandable, I suppose.”

They were silent as they walked down the stairs together.

Dinner that evening was pretty spectacular, even by Weasley standards. Harry wondered privately if this was Molly’s way of apologizing to the Grangers. From the way the two mothers talked of exchanging recipes, Harry judged it to be a rousing success. Arthur and Mr. Granger seemed to be getting on better, as the two of them spent most of dinner asking Bill questions about his new job.

No one seemed interested in talking about their little errand, and that was probably just as well. The Grangers, especially Mr. Granger, had calmed down, but no one wanted to push it.

Professor Slughorn promised that he’d have a manifest prepared within a week, and would start taking bids at that point. However, he hinted that they’d recovered more Basilisk parts than even his most optimistic plans had allowed for.

Harry leaned back from the table, as full as he could be, and smiled. Things seemed to have turned out as well as could be expected.

The rest of the year passed with a singular lack of drama, something for which Harry was rather glad. Ginny seemed to slowly come out of her guilty funk over the Chamber. Ron’s obvious glee over the money they’d get for the Basilisk parts seemed to help. With her brother clearly considering the whole mess to be a profitable experience, it didn’t make a lot of sense to blame herself.

Molly and Arthur, of course, made it clear that the majority of the money was to be saved for a rainy day. Their past financial difficulties had clearly given them a conservative disposition with respect to their children’s windfall. Even so, Ron only wanted to spend a small fraction of his share on a new broom.

When Molly pointed out that he had use of a new broom at school, Ron nodded his agreement and said that was exactly why. “If I take over as Keeper when Wood finishes school, I’ll need to practise over the summer, and it’s better if I have a broom as close as possible to what I’ll be using at school. That way, when I return, I won’t have to get used to a new broom all over again. I read that causes a lot of Quidditch accidents, you know… trying to practise on an unfamiliar broom.”

Harry was staying well out of this argument, though with his original broom destroyed during the Dementor attack, he’d likely have to do the same thing. But that left him in position to see Bill nod off to the side, a small smile on his face. Harry had to suppress his own grin. Evidently, Ron had been well coached.

“I don’t want to get one of the new Firebolts,” Ron continued, making Harry jump a little. He remembered that those had been introduced this year – but he still had use of a good broom at school, so it hadn’t been as much of an issue. “But I’d like to get a Nimbus 2001, the same model we use at school, so there won’t be any differences no matter where I practise.”

Harry noticed Bill tapping his chin.

Ron paused with his mouth open, looking uncomfortable, and then continued, “The more I practise now… well, the better idea I will have if I am really good enough to play for a living once I finish school or if I need to look at a different career.”

Arthur frowned thoughtfully. “You’ve obviously given this some thought, Ron. But I don’t want you spending all your time coming up with good reasons to spend the rest of your money. If we agree to this…”

Ron spoke up, “The rest goes in a vault and gets used for school expenses until I finish school and I can use it to help rent a flat and get set up in a career.”

Molly’s eyes widened, but Arthur cast a sidelong glance at Bill, who looked remarkably innocent. “I suppose you want to do this as well?” he asked Harry after a moment.

“Well, actually, I hadn’t thought about it,” Harry replied. “With everything that happened, I didn’t really stop to think about replacing my 2000. But Ron makes a good point about practising during the summer. If I get used to a much slower broom, I’m likely to make a mess of things when I return, and Ginny has threatened dire consequences if I don’t stop getting hurt when I play.”

Ginny, who’d been walking past the doorway as this happened, stopped and shot Harry a dirty look. But her mother’s approving smile quickly blunted her ire.

“I think that should go for Ginny as well,” Harry added. “She’s a shoo-in to make Chaser when Angelina leaves school.” He hadn’t meant to embarrass her, and hoped she accepted inclusion as a peace offering.

“We’ll see about that if she makes the team,” Molly said in a dubious tone.

“Er, I don’t think it’s at all in doubt,” Harry said, clearing his throat nervously.

“Oh… that,” Arthur said after a moment. “I suppose you would know, wouldn’t you, Harry?”

Harry smiled. “Yeah; she’s, uh, really good.” Out of the corner of his eye, he saw Ginny’s face turn redder and redder.

Arthur slowly nodded, but Molly still looked a bit dubious. He supposed she didn’t consider Quidditch an entirely proper activity for a respectable young witch.

“I suppose we can just put my part in my trust vault, but we’ll need to get vaults set up for Ron and Ginny,” Harry added quickly before another mother-daughter conflict erupted. “I know Hermione already contacted Gringotts to get a copy of the paperwork. Neville and Luna probably already have something set up.”

“Ah, yes,” Arthur agreed, heading Molly off. “I suppose we should at least get the paperwork started before you all go back to Hogwarts. That way it’ll be ready when the, er, money arrives.”

“I guess I’d better make sure I have my trunk organized for the trip back,” Harry said quickly. “Ginny, I think Ron has the latest copy of Which Broom? upstairs. We should see if there are any cheaper alternatives that have the same specs as the 2001.”

All three of them beat a hasty retreat.

Harry was a little surprised when Neville invited everyone over to the Longbottom mansion for New Year’s Eve, but he was happy that Molly and Arthur had no objections to their going.

Fred and George seemed a bit put out, but Harry suspected that was because some of their favourite targets would not be available this year – they hadn’t been invited for some reason…

The dress was supposed to be ‘casual’, but Molly nonetheless made sure they were looking fairly sharp before she allowed Ron, Ginny, and Harry to leave. Augusta Longbottom tended to have that sort of effect on people, Harry noticed.

However, once they were through the Floo, they found Neville waiting for them in the sitting room, and his expression immediately put Harry on his guard. “What’s wrong, mate?” he asked in a low voice as everyone brushed themselves off.

“Gran said she might invite a few family friends to stop by,” Neville replied. Then he snorted. “A few! It looks like a society ball in there and I think there are still more coming.”

“Why would she do that?” Ron asked, frowning.

“I don’t know,” Neville said, frustration lacing his voice. His expression softened a little when Luna cocked her head and looked at him.

The Floo sprang to life again, disgorging Hermione. She immediately turned around and spoke into the Floo before it went out, telling her mum she was at the right place. Harry and Ron shared the news while Neville looked uncomfortable.

Hermione’s brows knitted for a moment as she digested the facts. “Maybe she’s trying to make up for what happened last summer?” she ventured.

“We, well, we haven’t really talked about that since the beginning of the term,” Neville said. “Er, a lot of harsh words were said, on both sides.”

“Maybe she feels like actions will count more than words?” Harry suggested.

“If she’s introducing all of us as your friends, it means she is publicly accepting us,” Ginny added, glancing over at Luna. The blonde witch didn’t say anything as she brushed a bit of lint from Neville’s sleeve, but her dreamy smile seemed to grow a little wider.

Neville slowly nodded as he led them towards a large double-door. Harry couldn’t recall where this led from the last time they’d visited. “All right, I can see that. But I’m still sorry this got sprung on you all like this.” With that, he swung open the doors.

One look at the ballroom and Harry was rather glad of Molly’s earlier fussing.

Harry never imagined he’d be glad of Slughorn’s Slug Club gatherings – at least not in this way. Horace’s social networking was quite ambitious, but Harry realized that while he had ‘collected’ many up and coming names in the Ministry and in business, he was clearly trying to ‘break into’ the social strata that Augusta Longbottom seemed to have been born into.

Harry made a note to look up the professor’s family at some point. It wasn’t really important, but it might explain why he seemed so desperate to spread his influence.

The Longbottom name, however, seemed to carry a fair bit of weight, and not just within the gardening clubs that Neville described. Harry gave his friend a penetrating glance. It was ironic, given the way Draco had trumpeted the importance of his family, that Neville had never responded in kind. But seeing how uncomfortable the round-faced boy was becoming, Harry started to understand.

Bereft of his parents, in the care of older relatives all his life, Neville was clearly lonely in some ways when he came to Hogwarts. The prospect of making friends at school must have been both terrifying and enticing at the same time. While flaunting his family’s social status might have made things easier in the short term, the quality of those friendships would be suspect. Harry suspected that Muggle-borns, half-bloods, or even pure-bloods from less prosperous families might have been a touch hesitant around Neville if they’d realized. His friend’s growing unease suggested he was worried about something similar happening now.

Harry evidently wasn’t the only one to pick up on this. Luna gave Neville a warm smile and asked if he’d show them around.

Harry nodded and added in a low voice, “We can do this like Slug Club again, everyone all right with that?”

Everyone nodded, but Neville let out a sigh. “I was sort of looking forward to a simple, fun party like last year,” he said plaintively. “You’re all being really good sports about this, but I’m still annoyed at Gran.”

“Maybe she thinks she’s helping us. Someone might have mentioned us being at the gathering at school,” Ginny said thoughtfully. “Mum mentioned hearing about it from one of her friends.”

“Yeah, but she could at least have asked first,” Neville countered. “I thought after we had things out she’d stop springing things on me that she thought were for my own good.”

Ron chuckled. “Mum still does that to all of us, even Bill, and he’s ancient.”

As they moved out and joined the party, they found their normal roles altered. The focus of the conversations was slightly less on the Ministry and slightly more on the interactions between various families. This left Hermione a bit out of her element, as the former was much better documented in her beloved books. Still, she had a few moments to shine. When an older wizard brought up Harry’s allegations that Sirius Black had been treated unfairly under the legal code, Hermione brought forth all the knowledge she’d acquired when they’d been researching ways to get him released last year. She held forth for over ten minutes on the lack of an effective appellate system in British Wizarding law, contrasting it somewhat unfavourably with the safeguards built into both British and European Muggle statutes.

Harry, who’d been reading the same books along with her in the library, was again flabbergasted by the depth and detail of her memory. He couldn’t recall half the things she was mentioning. It was only as she was winding down that she realized how much attention was focused on her and began to show signs of nervousness.

“Studying to be a barrister, are you?” the older wizard asked in a jovial tone in the silence that followed.

“Er, no, sir,” Hermione said quickly. “Harry just asked me to help him look into it, back before Mr. Black escaped. It was sort of a side project we worked on in our free time.”

The man smiled, but Harry thought he also looked somewhat relieved.

Neville, too, as Augusta’s heir and the male host, was called upon to play a more active role than usual. Usually, this took the form of making introductions, which the nominally forgetful boy managed to do with little difficulty. Harry wondered if that was from increased confidence or lots of rehearsal in the past.

And despite his earlier misgivings, Neville worked at being a more active participant in the conversations. Harry didn’t know if it was because of his role as a host, or a desire not to let his friends down, but it was noticeable. Several of the adults also seemed to pick up on this, giving Neville the odd glance.

For his own part, Harry wasn’t mobbed to the extent he expected. Augusta Longbottom’s cohort, the elder wizards and witches, seemed to be more… restrained… than that. He was included in the conversations, of course, but people weren’t obviously seeking him out as The Boy Who Lived.

Harry actually found himself enjoying that a little. He knew he was on display to a certain degree, but no more than his friends. To this crowd, they were all “Neville’s Friends from Hogwarts”, and would likely be judged as such, as would Neville. He hoped they managed to change some opinions regarding their friend, as well as make good first impressions.

Because, unless he changed things, this world was heading into the abyss of war, and he could not afford for all of these people to sit on the sidelines until it was too late.

Author notes

41

The Not So Welcoming Feast

“Avada Kedavra!”

Harry barely had time to register the incantation before it was all over.

He only had one regret.

Harry didn’t think Barty Crouch, Junior, realized he was pointing a bouquet of flowers with lethal intent before he was hit by a stunning spell. Crouch folded up and dropped back into his seat, head lolling forward. Harry’s own wand popped out of his forearm sheath and into his hand as the Top Box plunged into chaos. The Ministry Aurors practically pounced on Fudge, surrounding him against any possible threat. Their Bulgarian equivalents closed ranks around Mr. Oblansk, but several stayed clear, wands out and ready to cast.

There was a sudden commotion near the entrance to the Top Box. Harry could just make out Percy’s hair before there were too many bodies in the way. There was a loud bang then things went still. Harry wanted to push forward and see what happened, but Ginny had a death grip on one arm and Hermione was digging her nails into the other. Ron looked ready to body-check him or anyone that wanted to get at him. It was a little amusing to see the Ministry Aurors step carefully around the putative Heir of Gryffindor, even if he was sword-less at the moment. But Harry’s sense of humour was at best restrained with a Weasley still unaccounted for.

So Harry had to settle for straining to stand on the tips of his toes, peering for any clue as to what happened. His heart re-started when he saw Mr. Weasley extract his son from the melee. The nearest Auror let out a gasp when they got a good look at the assassin’s face. “Barty Junior!” the older man exclaimed in shock.

This caused several heads to turn. As the adults shifted around, Harry caught a glimpse of Barty Crouch, Senior, laying on the floor near the entrance to the stairs. Harry relaxed a little as he watched an Auror extract a wand from the unconscious man’s hand. He shifted his focus to Percy, who Mr. Weasley was leading over to rejoin the family. Percy was pale and sweating buckets, the pallor of his face making his red hair stand out even more.

The Bulgarian Aurors, including that one chap with spectacular aim, were rapidly clearing the corner of non-Weasleys. Of course, that excluded Harry, but interestingly they also let Hermione stay where she was sitting next to Ron. Someone had done their homework, or at least been paying attention. They let Mr. Weasley sit Percy down in a vacated seat as they clapped manacles on Barty Junior and levitated him away. Winky followed them docilely, crying quietly and wringing her hands. A whispered conversation between Mr. Weasley and Bill saw a silver hip flask being handed from son to father.

Arthur Weasley sat down next to his third son, placing an arm across his shoulders. This also allowed him to subtly offer the flask with his other hand. Percy twitched a little, but accepted the offered drink and twisted off the cap with shaking hands. A small sip produced a surprised cough, but some of the colour returned to Percy’s cheeks as well. He handed the flask back to Arthur with a whisper and straightened up a little in his seat.

Harry heard raised voices coming from the exit, and saw Lucius Malfoy berating the Aurors. They appeared to be blocking him from leaving, and Harry wondered if he was afraid of missing a meeting with the other Death Eaters to plan tonight’s Muggle baiting. The argument appeared to be escalating when the suddenly relieved-looking Auror was replaced by none other than Amelia Bones, head of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement. Malfoy swallowed his irritation with a visible effort. Unfortunately, after a few minutes of conversation, he was allowed to pass. The monocle-wearing witch then headed in their direction.

Percy looked a bit calmer, but Mr. Weasley was making a point not to let the twins talk to him at all. “Arthur,” Madam Bones said as she arrived. Harry noticed that Mr. Weasley looked noticeably relieved now. From what little Harry knew about Madam Bones, she seemed fairly honest and apolitical. He wondered if Percy was in some sort of trouble.

Harry edged a little closer. Madam Bones didn’t even look up as an assortment of red-heads and their guests drew closer, with some of them placing themselves between her interview and the politicians raising their voices at the other end of the box. Percy was rambling a bit, but whatever was in the flask seemed to have helped.

“I noticed earlier today that Mr. Crouch seemed a bit out of sorts,” he began after a deep breath. “I know he isn’t the… well, the warmest of people. Very straight-forward, no-nonsense approach to work. Not like some others I could… anyway. He seemed a bit, I suppose you would say, distracted, maybe. And a bit more abrupt than usual.”

Madam Bones nodded, but said nothing, clearly waiting for him to continue.

“Anyway, he was gone for most of the match, though I did see his house-elf holding a seat for him. I thought perhaps there was another complication with those extra seats requested by the Bulgarians.” Percy frowned. “I thought it rather irresponsible how Mr. Bagman dropped that whole mess on him right before the match. His department should have retained at least one competent translator for this event, rather than just dumping it all on International Cooperation… Anyway, he showed up again right as Krum caught the snitch and ended the match. I felt rather bad for him, missing the whole thing after all the work he had done, so I got up to go see if I could help him with anything.”

Percy took a deep breath.

“As I drew closer, I got the feeling something was wrong. His expression was far too tense. Then there was some sort of disturbance behind me and… well… I’d never seen Mr. Crouch look so furious before. It happened so fast. I heard… I heard someone shout the killing curse behind me, but Mr. Crouch was in front of me, looking furious and pulling out his wand… He was turning towards the Auror next to us, who had just cast a stunning spell… Something was wrong here, so I stunned Mr. Crouch. I didn’t even realize I’d pulled out my own wand until he was already falling down… Oh Merlin, I stunned my boss!” Percy rapidly inhaled and exhaled. He might have worked himself up to hyperventilating if Mr. Weasley hadn’t given his shoulder a squeeze that seemed to snap him out of it.

At that point, one of the older Aurors made his way over to Madam Bones. “It’s really him all right,” he said without preamble. “No idea how, but it is.”

Madam Bones let out a sigh. “Of all the…” she said before she cut herself off. “Mr. Weasley, I mean, Percy, I will need you to come down to the DMLE to give a signed statement at some point, but barring further developments no charges will be set. I would, however, like for you to organize your thoughts on any actions you have seen Bartemius Crouch take since you became his assistant. Don’t leave anything out, no matter how trivial.”

“Amelia?” Mr. Weasley asked, clearly concerned.

“Don’t worry, Arthur, Percy isn’t in any trouble,” she reassured him. “The same cannot be said for Bartemius though. That young man is his son.”

“The one who…?” Mr. Weasley gasped. “But how?”

“That’s a very good question. One we will be getting an answer to,” she promised. She turned a little in her seat and continued. “Speaking of answers, can Mr. Potter shed some light on what transpired tonight?”

Mr. Weasley turned toward Harry, who shrugged and swapped seats with a visibly relieved Percy.

“All right, Mr. Potter,” Madam Bones began, “what happened?”

Harry took a deep breath. “I was watching the end of the match, when I felt something pull the wand out of my jacket pocket. I spun around when I felt someone else’s hand and my fingers snagged on something I couldn’t see. When I drew back, it turned out to be an invisibility cloak. The bloke it was covering had the wand in his hand, and he… well, he tried to use the killing curse on me before someone stunned him.”

Madam Bones nodded. “That was one of the Bulgarian Aurors. Good reflexes. But about this wand that was stolen… it was not your wand? And do you know who transfigured it?”

“Ah-heh!” Harry chuckled nervously, “No, that wasn’t my real wand. No one had to transfigure it… it was one of Fred and George’s joke wands.”

“Joke wands?” Madam Bones asked, ignoring the sudden preening displayed by two of the attending Weasleys.

“Yes,” Harry confirmed. “They look like regular wands, but if you try to do any magic with them, they turn into a bouquet of flowers, or a rubber chicken, or something equally embarrassing.”

“Really?” Madam Bones exclaimed. “And they look like real wands beforehand? Do you know where I can acquire some of these items?”

Fred cleared his throat. “Er, we don’t have them in full production yet, but I’m sure Weasley Wizard Wheezes can fill an order for the DMLE,” he said with a wide grin. Mr. Weasley rolled his eyes.

George nudged his twin. “I think we can get you the friends and family discount though, Madam Bones. Our Da has always spoken highly of you, says you are quite brill.” Their father’s face was now turning red.

“I’m not sure we need a large order… yet,” Madam Bones replied, though Harry thought the corner of her mouth was twitching ever-so-slightly. “But for two of them, plus instructions, I’ll make sure the Daily Prophet learns that an attempted assassination was foiled by one of your products.”

Fred and George both blinked at that. “Deal!”

Harry just hoped Mrs. Weasley didn’t lay the blame on him.

After all the excitement, it was fairly late before everyone left the top box. As the DMLE completed their initial investigation, Harry got the chance to shake hands with Auror Buehler, the Bulgarian who’d stunned Barty Crouch, Jr. The tall man was imposing, with his thick black eyebrows and ice blue eyes, but his whole face transformed when he smiled. When he timidly asked if Harry would mind signing something for the man’s daughter, Harry was more than happy to scrounge up a program and add his signature, addressed to Marija. With a smirk, he nudged Ron and had him add his as well. It took a moment before Auror Buehler made the connection that Harry’s embarrassed friend “was being sword-boy!” from the Battle of Hogwarts. That was when the transformative smile came out again.

As nice a shot as the man had made, under pressure, Harry thought it was the least they could do.

On the plus side, the delay had thinned out the crowd streaming out of the stadium. It also meant that it was easy for Luna, her father, and Neville to find them near the exit. Xenophilius already had a scroll and quill out as they approached. Harry was more than willing to share the sanitized details with the publisher of The Quibbler as they made their way out to the camp site. Neville and Luna hadn’t been overjoyed at their exclusion from the plan, but understood the delicacy of the seating issues… and it wasn’t like Neville considered the time spent with Luna, or her father to be wasted.

They were heading back toward the borrowed Weasley tent for a cuppa before bed when Harry first heard the distant shouts and screams of terror. “Looks like Lucius got away in time,” Harry muttered to himself.

Mr. Weasley cautiously led them a little further, but stopped once he made out the crowd of masked and robed figures. Harry could also make out the silhouetted figures of the campsite manager and his family, helplessly levitated above the jeering mob.

Mr. Weasley looked outraged. “Bill, Charlie, Percy, we need to help the Ministry stop this. The rest of you…” his voice trailed off as he looked around.

“I think we’re safer all together,” Harry said quietly. Ron nodded but didn’t say anything. The wand in his hand was enough. The others had drawn theirs as well.

Mr. Weasley let out a sigh. “Molly is going to kill me, stone dead. All right, everyone stick together. We’re going to try and rescue the people floating above them first.”

“Ron and Hermione are good for that,” Harry volunteered, recalling the Hufflepuff girls they’d pulled away from the Dementors.

“Very well,” Mr. Weasley agreed. “Percy, help them with that. The rest of you, stunning spells and the like. Let’s get a little closer if we can.” The group edged forward, partially masked by the people running away in the dark. Just as one of the masked figures turning did a double-take, Mr. Weasley shouted, “Now!”

Ron and Hermione’s wands were twin blurs as they cast Wingardium Leviosa and Accio Muggles. Mr. Roberts, his wife, and eldest child soared toward them, but the youngest child spun slightly askew. Percy, however, was ready and brought his own wand into play, guiding him back on course. The rest of the Weasleys and their allies sent Stupefies into the hooded mob that was only now starting to cast shield charms.

After Harry’s second stunning spell, the Muggles were clear of the resurgent Death Eaters, so Harry cast his modified Flash-Bang charm in their midst. The burst of light was slightly dazzling at range, but Harry could still see his targets. He didn’t need to imagine what it must have looked like up close. The thunderous bang also seemed to knock down figures in the middle of the pack. He saw more staggering figures drop to stunning spells from the older Weasleys when suddenly the lot of them shimmered and vanished with a loud pop.

“Bloody Portkeys,” Harry grumbled as Percy caught the youngest child in his arms. Ron and Hermione guided the rest of the hysterical family to the ground in front of them.

The second round of interviews with Madam Bones lasted well past midnight. This time around, the monocled witch seemed a lot less jocular and a lot more tired. She did, however, order them a Portkey back to Ottery St. Catchpole. For that kindness alone, Harry was more than happy he’d shown the older witch how his Flash-Bang charm worked. She raised an eyebrow when Harry explained it was two basic sound and light charms, just crazily overpowered to make them overwhelming and not terribly efficient. He wondered, though, if he’d revealed a bit more of his capabilities than he should have.

No sooner did they cross over the wards than Mrs. Weasley was out the front door like a shot. She was almost incoherent as she hugged her husband and fussed over her children. Neville quietly made his way to the Floo during the confusion, having already parted from Luna and her father. Harry noticed that Xeno seemed fairly fond of Neville, and even left off some of his stranger conversational topics when the boy was around. Harry hoped Neville acquired more male role models in his life that didn’t think dangling him out a window was acceptable behaviour.

Mrs. Weasley hugged Hermione just as long as Ginny or her boys, leaving the girl somewhat flustered as the matronly woman wailed about how happy she was that they were all safe now. Harry felt a twinge of guilt. She’d only stopped objecting to the plan they’d laid out in broad terms because Harry said he’d make sure “the hidden Death Eater” would never get his hands on a real wand.

Soon they were inside, where Sirius already had the kettle on for some hot chocolate. Of course, as soon as they were settled with their drinks, Mrs. Weasley and Harry’s Godfather wanted to know everything. Mr. Weasley did most of the talking, which was fine by Harry. At this point, the day’s excitements had left him practically dead on his feet. When they got to the point where Percy stunned Mr. Crouch, Sirius couldn’t stop himself. The retelling was interrupted by a large black dog planting its paws on the fussy young man’s shoulders and giving his face a thorough tongue-bath. Ironically, Fred and George were sitting the closest, and ended up having to rescue their brother from dog-slobber.

Charlie passed Percy a slightly used-looking flannel to wipe off his face, while Sirius was man-handled back toward his chair, where he reluctantly transformed back to human. “Maybe they’ll give the hypocrite my old cell,” Sirius mused with a smirk. “If only I could have seen it.”

Harry cleared his throat. “Yes, it’s too bad no one’s invented a magical artefact that lets you view memories. Oh, wait…”

Sirius laughed again. “Just for that, I think I’ll name my first-born child Percy.”

“And if it’s a girl?” Hermione asked.

“I don’t see a problem,” Sirius replied, dead pan.

That remark earned him a dirty look from the Weasley in question. “Maybe I should get started on that report for Madam Bones,” he huffed.

“Finish your chocolate first, dear,” Mrs. Weasley chimed in. Then she turned to Sirius. “Behave!” she barked.

Sirius jumped, seemingly in spite of himself. “Yes, Molly,” he acquiesced.

The following morning saw the delivery of The Daily Prophet, complete with coverage of the Quidditch World Cup Final, and what happened afterward. Fred and George sent off a packet containing two of their prank wands to Madam Bones via Hedwig. Errol probably could have made the delivery, but they wanted to make a good impression and Harry agreed.

Mr. Weasley winced as he read the Prophet. “Rita was busy last night,” he said ruefully. “She’s blaming the Ministry for not having enough security to prevent the ‘Quidditch Hooligans’ from rioting last night.”

“That’s ridiculous,” Mrs. Weasley objected as she plated up a rasher of bacon. She paused, looking around the table. “Charlie? Could you see what’s keeping Percy?” she asked.

The second son took a playful swipe at a smirking Bill as he rose from the table. “Sure thing, Mum,” he replied. “Save me some bacon?” he added with a pitiful look. As he headed up the stairs, Harry noticed that a good bit of the bacon ended up deposited directly on Charlie’s plate. Ron’s fingers also got a swift rap when they seemed to stray on their way back from the serving plate. Harry himself managed two rashers that he folded over into a piece of toast. A dash of HP brown sauce and he set it aside while he addressed his sausage, eggs, and fried potatoes.

Harry hadn’t even started his bacon sandwich when Charlie returned with a rather rumpled-looking Percy. The third-oldest looked like he hadn’t much sleep, and his fingers were ink-stained. “Found him up doing paperwork,” Charlie reported, shaking his head as he sat down.

Percy looked up from the tea his mother passed him. “I’ve been working on that report for Madam Bones,” he explained. “I want it to be as complete as possible, as it will likely be my last project as part of the Ministry,” he continued in a morose tone.

“But you didn’t do anything wrong!” Hermione objected. Ginny, sitting next to her, didn’t say anything, but Harry could tell by her flush she was easily as outraged.

“Doesn’t matter,” Percy explained. “I still ‘turned’ on my superior. Mr. Crouch’s replacement won’t want to deal with me, and none of the other heads will trust me.” He turned to address his father directly. “Do you really think I won’t be blacklisted for this?” he asked in a weary voice.

Mr. Weasley sighed, “Well, Perkins is getting on in years, and…”

Percy shook his head. “No, father. Not that I don’t appreciate it. I do, really. But I vowed to myself that I was not going to be one of those that achieved things because of who they knew, rather than what they could do. And I think it could also be quite awkward.”

“If that’s how you want it, son,” Mr. Weasley agreed. Mrs. Weasley, on the other hand, did not look happy.

Both Mr. Weasley and Percy started spending a lot of time at the Ministry the following week. No new questions were asked when they gave their depositions. Unfortunately, Percy’s predictions came true. Cuthbert Throckmorton was appointed acting head of the Department of International Cooperation, and one of his first acts was to suggest to Percy, in a closed interview, that he should seek other opportunities outside the department. By Thursday, he had cleaned his desk out and come home early. Harry felt a little guilty, wondering if he shouldn’t have warned Percy to keep an eye on Mr. Crouch. If the man had been apprehended by an Auror, rather than stunned by Percy, would Crouch’s successor have been so quick to bin him?

Harry mulled this over as he helped Percy carry his things upstairs. Ron and the twins were making it a point not to tease Percy at all since the World Cup. Ginny had asked them about including Percy in the Weasley Wizard Wheezes plans, but Ron pointed out that he’d likely see it as charity. Harry knew Ginny and Hermione both thought Percy was being a bit too prideful, but he agreed with Ron that his brother just wanted to succeed on his own merits.

As Harry set Percy’s things on his desk, he noticed a thick sheaf of parchment in the older boy’s hands. “What’s that?” he asked.

“Oh, it’s just that request from Madam Bones,” Percy said tiredly. “I’m still fleshing out some details, but I should have it done to deliver to her tomorrow.”

Harry blinked. If that was all one document, it was massive. “She’s going to be all weekend reading that,” he said dubiously.

“Well, she did ask for everything I could remember,” Percy replied testily. “I did, however, colour-code the corners of each entry to signify possible relevance. But there are some things that I think might be significant that are only apparent over time.”

Harry nodded slowly, remembering that Percy made Head Boy for a reason.

Picking up their school supplies from Diagon Alley was a welcome break from the ongoing tension at The Burrow. Percy wasn’t being mean or spiteful, but his family tended to walk on eggshells around him nonetheless. Her son’s crushed ambitions were also making Mrs. Weasley a bit weepy. Her grown sons’ impending departure when their holidays ended didn’t help either. Harry tried to interest Percy in joining their group training, but the young man was wholly focused on completing his report for Madam Bones. Harry sort of wished Charlie had been similarly reticent… he had a few extra bruises after the brawny dragon-tamer joined in one of their sparring sessions.

Sirius was a little mopey as well. Aside from the fact of them leaving for Hogwarts, Harry was also hopelessly stalled on his Animagus transformation. Nothing they had tried seemed to work, and the pain never seemed to diminish. Rather than blame Harry, Sirius seemed to think he was teaching the subject wrong, which made Harry feel even worse. Finally, Remus pulled a visibly depressed Sirius aside for a private conversation after their lesson. Harry hoped a little time apart from his “Dogfather” would make things a little less awkward.

It was a dreary, rain-lashed Monday morning that saw them up early to catch the Hogwarts Express. But as they were loading their trunks, a Ministry owl arrived, addressed to Percy. His expression brightened a bit as he unfolded the parchment, but then he sighed. “Madam Bones wants to speak to me,” he said. “Probably something about my report.”

“Don’t worry,” Mr. Weasley reassured his son. “I’m sure you did a good job. Go ahead and take the Floo. I’ll take this lot to King’s Cross.”

“I can go to the Ministry afterward,” Percy said morosely. He’d volunteered to escort Harry and the others to the train station so his father could have a lie-in on the last of his holiday. He seemed to Harry to be desperate to make himself useful since being dismissed from the Ministry.

“It’s all right, Percy,” Mr. Weasley said with a bit more force. “We don’t want to keep Madam Bones waiting,” he added.

Percy nodded and went upstairs to change out of his Muggle clothes.

Bill and Charlie decided to tag along as well, so it was quite a mob that boarded three Muggle taxis for the journey to London. Fred’s trunk sprang open as it was being loaded, and some Filibuster Wet-Start Fireworks inside it went off, making everyone jump and Crookshanks accidentally scratch the poor cabby. To his annoyance, Harry remembered this happening before, but not in time to do anything to stop it.

After giving it some thought, Harry simply asked Hedwig if she’d rather fly to Hogwarts on her own. She was out of the cage and winging out of sight in seconds, giving Harry a chuckle. That made for a much quieter ride than might have been for him and Ginny. Charlie somehow managed to end up riding with them as well, sitting between them. Harry was inclined to let it pass, but by the set of her mouth he could tell Ginny was getting annoyed.

“So Da rode with Ron and Hermione?” she asked after a few minutes.

“I think he did,” Harry confirmed.

Ginny nodded. “Good thing. Can’t leave those two unsupervised.”

Charlie coughed. “What?”

“Oh yeah,” Ginny said. “There’s a pool on when those two will do the deed.”

Harry had to bite his tongue to keep from laughing out loud.

“There’s what?” Charlie yelled, making the cab driver glance back at them in the mirror.

“You didn’t know?” Ginny gasped. “You never noticed how Mum never left those two unsupervised? Not that it will do much good once they’re at Hogwarts.” Charlie’s face turned redder and redder as his baby sister continued. “That reminds me. I wanted to ask you about broom cupboards.”

“Broom. Cupboards,” Charlie choked out.

“Yes, broom cupboards,” Ginny confirmed. “Which ones are the most comfortable? Which ones don’t get checked as often? I heard you were quite the lady’s man in your day, so I figured you would know.”

“You don’t need to know about that!” Charlie hissed, and gave Harry a filthy look for good measure.

“What?” Ginny asked, clearly scandalized. “Do you want me to get caught shagging Harry?”

Harry muffled a cough. He had absolutely no desire to draw attention to himself at this point.

“You are not shagging Harry, ever!” Charlie declared.

“And how do you propose to stop me when I’m at Hogwarts and you are in Romania?” Ginny asked sweetly.

Charlie turned a gimlet eye on Harry, but froze when Ginny spoke again. “So this is where you threaten to kill Harry, is it? Do you really think you can do that and get away with it? Do you think I would let you get away with that?” Her voice had grown as cold as ice. “Charlie, I love you as my big brother, and I appreciate what you think you are trying to do. But I don’t need protecting from Harry. I don’t think I ever will. What is going on between us is just that. Between us. So kindly take whatever good-intentioned threats you have made and stick them up your nose.”

Harry felt acutely uncomfortable at this point, but Charlie looked poleaxed.

“If you lot want to get out and fight, I’m keeping the meter running,” the cabby advised.

“No need for that,” Ginny said brightly. “Just reminding my darling brother that he needs to mind his own business.”

Harry was relieved to exit the taxi at King’s Cross, even as he got thoroughly soaked manoeuvring his trunk across the road and into the train station. He couldn’t even make eye contact with Charlie at this point, and was happy to cross over onto Platform Nine and Three Quarters as quickly as possible. Ginny was seemingly unaffected, and gave her father and two eldest brothers warm goodbye hugs before boarding the train. Charlie seemed a little confused by this, but Bill just smirked at him. Harry didn’t think he would ever grasp sibling politics.

Harry jumped a little when a hand grasped his shoulder. He smiled though, when he realized it was Mr. Weasley. He shook the offered hand firmly. “Have a good term, Harry,” his guardian murmured. “And do take care of Ron and Ginny, and yourself as well.”

He swallowed. “Of course, sir, I mean, Mr. Weasley.”

The older man gave a genial smile. “Maybe one day, I’ll get you to call me Arthur,” he teased. Harry blushed. “All right then, off with you before the train leaves. We’ll be looking forward to your letters.”

Buoyed by the man’s unspoken regard, Harry smiled and dragged his trunk onto the train. He was pleased to learn that Neville and Luna had already reserved the last compartment for their friends. There was really only room for six and their trunks, but Fred and George just laughed and said they were looking for Lee Jordan anyway.

They were just settling in when a nasal voice was heard from the doorway.

“So, the losers have returned,” Pansy Parkinson announced to Crabbe and Goyle. Harry wondered if they were hired out, or just natural followers.

“The only losers I see here are in the corridor,” Ron shot back.

Pansy opened her mouth to reply when Harry cut in. “Merlin’s beard, Parkinson, is Lucius paying you to sub for Draco now?”

She smirked at Harry, which did no favours to her already pug-nosed countenance. “He doesn’t really need that, all things considered. But I want to know what you have on Slughorn.”

“Slughorn? What?” Harry asked, confused. “What are you on about now?”

“My Head of House,” she clarified in a haughty tone, “It’s nauseating, the way you’ve got him sucking up to you lot. We all know you blackmailed Professor Snape to get rid of him. Now you obviously have something on his successor, and I want to know what it is. Tell me now, and I’ll let you know why this year is not going to go well for any of you.”

Harry sighed. “I didn’t blackmail Snape, or anyone else. Your precious Draco implicated him in the theft of a Potter family artefact, not to mention being an accessory in an attempted murder. Do you really think Dumbledore could keep him around after that?”

“Parkinson, Professor Slughorn might favour you a bit more if you put some effort into Potions,” Hermione added. “You barely passed more than half your brews last year.”

Pansy’s face reddened. Hermione’s words weren’t untrue. Without the more egregious favouritism Snape employed, the Gryffindors as a class were doing nearly as well as their Slytherin counterparts. “So it’s just a coincidence that you all spontaneously turned into Potions prodigies?”

“Mostly,” Harry agreed. “Though according to Professor Slughorn my Mum was one of the two best students he ever taught, along with Severus Snape. We all seem to have gotten better because we don’t have someone breathing down our necks anymore, looking for any pretext to fail us.”

Pansy scowled, which made her look even more unattractive, which Harry wasn’t previously sure was even possible. “Like your Mudblood mother has anything to do with…”

Harry shot to his feet and the glass in the sliding door suddenly crazed with cracks. “You will mind your tongue when you speak of my family, Parkinson,” he snarled. “Girl or not, I will call you out and make you eat your words. We won’t be underage forever, you know.”

Pansy took a step back, leaving Crabbe and Goyle between her and Harry. However, the two showed no eagerness to advance. Harry figured they were at least bright enough to count the wands facing them. Harry took a deep breath, trying to throttle his temper. “Is this what Slytherin has come down to?” he asked. “Has the house of the cunning become the house that can’t compete unless they cheat? Don’t you find that just a little bit embarrassing?”

Pansy huffed. “You think things are going your way now, Potter, but that’s going to change. Very soon.” She turned with a flounce and stalked down the corridor. After a moment, Crabbe and Goyle turned and followed her.

Harry slid the door shut, making a few pieces of glass fall to the floor. Hermione sighed and cast Reparo, causing the broken pieces to fly back into the frame and the glass to knit into a seamless whole. Harry sat down and closed his eyes as Hermione locked the door with a series of charms. He massaged his temples, trying to calm himself and get his head to stop pounding.

“Do you feel better now?” Ginny asked quietly as Hermione sat down. Harry could hear the others talking in low tones.

“A little,” Harry admitted. “What on Earth were you on about with Charlie earlier?”

Ginny sighed. “I knew he’d been… interfering. Soon after he arrived you got very stiff and formal. It didn’t take a genius to see he’d said something to you.”

“Ginny,” Harry began, hesitantly, “he’s your brother. He’s just looking out for you. I can’t really fault him for that.”

“No, you can,” Ginny replied. “Just because he’s my brother, it doesn’t give him the right to mess around in my personal affairs. I get that he meant well, but it doesn’t make it right.”

“He did bring up some valid concerns,” Harry admittedly glumly.

“Did he now?” Ginny inquired. Her tone of voice sent a mild shiver down Harry’s spine. He knew he needed to choose his words very, very carefully.

“Well, you know…” Harry began. “Regarding the age difference.”

“Because if you were theoretically older in some way, you’d be taking advantage of my naïve, innocent self?”

“I’m trying not to make it worse than it sounds,” Harry complained. “I could be manipulating you in some ways. He’s right to question that.”

“Not that you need any prompting to question yourself,” Ginny noted with a huff. “Listen. You, Harry, are the king of unreasoning guilt. Yes, when we first met, you knew more about me than I did about you. And practically the first thing you did was to go about remedying that. If you were really this awful manipulator, you would use every excuse to delay that, wouldn’t you? Instead you pushed us to learn Occlumency as quickly as we could. And as soon as we could keep your secret, you told us.”

Harry tried to look away, but her eyes were almost shining with the intensity of her words. This was one of the things about her that had first attracted him, and he felt his pulse grow slightly faster.

“Despite all that, the first time my brother, who has no idea what he’s talking about, questions your motives you automatically think the worst of yourself.” Ginny sighed. “A little humility is nice and all, but try to have a little faith in yourself. In both of us, really.” She reached out and clasped his hands in hers. “I know you wouldn’t do anything deliberately to hurt me, you need to know it too.” She paused, then smirked. “Or are you going to question my judgment like Charlie did?”

Harry smiled and shook his head. He felt rather like a weight had been lifted from his shoulders. It felt good.

Percy paused to straighten his robes and visitor badge before knocking on the office door.

“Come in,” a voice replied. He opened the door and entered, feeling the gossamer touch of various security charms and anti-eavesdropping enchantments. Madam Bones’ office was very spartan, especially given her seniority within the Ministry. Several filing cabinets jostled for space with an unadorned desk. Even Bartemius Crouch had kept a few decorations and adornments in his personal space. The older witch looked up from what Percy could see was a copy of his report. She gestured for him to take a seat.

“I’ve been going over your notes,” she began. “I must compliment your memory and eye for detail. I agree with some of the items you have flagged. We’re starting to piece together what happened, and it’s not looking too good.”

“Thank you, Madam Bones,” Percy replied quietly. It was good to hear someone appreciate his work. It was galling to think that she’d just given him more positive feedback than he’d ever received from Mr. Crouch.

“I heard that Throckmorton has taken the reins at International Cooperation,” she observed. When Percy nodded, she continued, “and I understand that he feels you might be better suited for a different position?”

Percy swallowed and nodded. “Yes, Madam Bones,” he replied, trying to keep any bitterness out of his voice, “he gave me the option of resigning first.” It was harder than he thought it would be.

Madam Bones nodded, her monocle glinting in the indirect lighting. “Well, his loss, my gain.”

“I beg your pardon, Madam Bones?” Percy asked. His heart was suddenly trying to climb his oesophagus.

“If you can produce documentation of this quality on a regular basis,” she replied, gesturing with his report, “I might have a position for you in the Magical Law Enforcement Squad.”

Percy could feel that damned Weasley flush climbing the back of his neck. “But, I’m not a hit wizard,” he objected.

“Mr. Weasley, pray tell, what is the process for setting up a new undersecretary?”

“Well,” Percy began, caught off guard by the unexpected question. “You would need to get a form 99Q from the Personnel department if they are a new hire, or a 95Q-Zed if they are a transfer from another department. Once that is filled out and returned, they will give you a 53G voucher for basic office supplies, a form 72 to authorize the background check, and a chit to schedule an appointment with Facilities to reserve an office space. Of course, if they are filling a currently empty position, their direct report should still have possession of the requisite office space so you only need to send a memo to Facilities to inform them of the new assignment. You also will want to send a memo to the head of building security to make sure a new hire is added to the building roster. Sometimes they don’t get the updated list from Personnel in time…” he trailed off as Madam Bones cleared her throat.

“That’s precisely what I need you for, Mr. Weasley,” she said. “I know you’re not an Auror; what I desperately need right now is an intelligent, competent assistant who can take on and organize the squad’s paperwork so the Aurors and Hit Wizards can do their jobs. Are you interested?”

“When can I start?”

Harry stared out the window at the passing terrain as he thought about Ginny’s words. He supposed it was sort of presumptuous for her brother to dictate like that. He still felt irrationally guilty at the thought of any Weasley disapproving of his relationship with Ginny. If he could even call it a relationship. He wondered why he felt so guilty and unworthy, even. Like he didn’t deserve her, or deserve any happiness with her, after…

Then it hit him. He didn’t deserve it after letting her die in the original timeline. He gave a guilty sidelong glance at the girl sitting beside him. She was pulling a comb through Luna’s hair as the girl sat sideways next to her. The blonde sat very still with her eyes shut as Ginny slowly ordered her damp and slightly tangled locks. The rest of the so-called Gryffindor Six were spread out across the opposite seat, reading in Hermione’s case, or playing chess.

One thing Harry was certain of: if Ginny knew what he was thinking, she would kick his arse.

Harry smiled a bit, and stretched, taking in a deep breath and releasing it. He knew it was irrational, but that wouldn’t make the niggling doubt go away. He closed his eyes as he leaned back, trying to compose his thoughts. Almost reflexively, he fell into an Occlumency exercise. He visualized all his doubts and fears as a twisting morass sitting in his middle. The appropriateness of his relationship with Ginny, Animagus frustrations, his fading memories and fears for the future – all of it. With an effort, he pictured gathering them all up into a huge rolling ball, then throwing it away, out the window. He relaxed and thought for a while about what he wanted to do, ignoring those doubts.

Eyes still closed as if he was dozing, Harry let his head loll to the side, until it was resting lightly against Ginny’s shoulder. He breathed in through his nose, smelling Ginny’s hair and listening to her voice as she spoke quietly to Luna. Ginny didn’t pause in her ministrations, and Harry let her murmuring voice wash over him like a warm tide.

Perfect.

When the Hogwarts Express pulled into Hogsmeade, the weather was as foul as Scotland could get in the fall. Ice cold rain was bucketing down, punctuated by gusts of strong wind and bursts of lightning crackling overhead. Nonetheless, Harry woke from his nap relaxed and energized at the same time. Ginny had eventually fallen asleep. They were leaning against each other in the corner of the compartment when Hermione woke them. For once, Ginny was the one blushing more, which Harry found utterly charming for some reason. Maybe it was the contrast with her strong words with Charlie earlier. Maybe it was the realization that she was likely to always keep him on his toes.

He and his friends changed into their robes as quickly as they could manage, adding their heavy cloaks as well. Harry was the first of them to disembark, and cast a modified shield charm that was supposed to block solid objects as well. It muted most of the wind and almost all of the rain, if he angled it properly. However, it was surprisingly difficult to maintain, especially when the wind gusted. The drain grew worse as the rest of his friends emerged and he expanded it to cover them as well. Harry gritted his teeth as they made their way to the carriages. He supposed it was the constant pressure of the wind against the entire area of the shield that made it so taxing. He was barely able to spare the concentration to give Hagrid a brief wave as the groundskeeper led the bedraggled first years off to the lake.

Harry was pale and shaking by the time he entered the carriage and dropped the shield. His other hand clutched at the stitch in his chest. He gasped for breath as he sat down.

Ginny looked at his face and appeared to grow alarmed. “Harry, are you all right?” she asked. “You’re as pale as a ghost!”

Harry took a deep, shuddering breath. “That was… that was a lot harder to hold than I expected,” he explained.

“That might be why we didn’t see the upper years doing something similar,” Hermione theorized.

Harry nodded, still catching his breath.

“Don’t do that when we get to the castle,” Ginny scolded. “It’s not like we’ll melt.”

Harry took another deep breath. “Don’t worry,” he reassured her. “I had no idea it would be like that. I just wanted to do something nice.”

Ginny accepted this, and patted him on the back as he rested his elbows on his knees. Harry heard Hermione demonstrating the Impervius charm to Luna as she applied it to Harry’s cloak. He tensed as the wind gusted again, setting the carriage to rocking on its springs. It wasn’t long before they arrived at the castle.

The cloaks weren’t perfect as they rushed across the courtyard, but they stayed mostly dry. Harry was breathing easier by the time they scurried up the rain-slicked steps and into the entrance hall. Remembering the rude welcome that was in store, Harry looked up as soon as they cleared the doorway. Spotting Peeves and his water balloons, Harry raised his voice. “Peeves! Throw that and we’re cutting you off for a month!” he yelled.

The Poltergeist paused, red balloon in hand, as if weighing his options.

“Fred and George will cut you off as well,” Harry warned. “No pranks, no surprises, nothing.”

“Potty is no fun!” Peeves whined. “Already wet, aren’t they? Little squirts!”

“Then what’s the point of getting wet people wet again?” Harry asked. “It’s like taking coals to Newcastle!”

Peeves paused, and Harry swore he could hear the gears grinding in his immaterial head. “Peeves will save for later!” he finally crowed, and zoomed off cackling… right over the head of Professor McGonagall as she hurried in from the Great Hall. She glanced back over her head at the retreating Peeves, then turned toward Harry and raised an eyebrow.

“It’s ah, a negotiated truce, Professor,” Harry stammered as his friends looked away and busied themselves casting drying charms. He winced as screams of outrage and a cackle of maniacal laughter echoed from the Great Hall. “I, uh, just pointed out that we were already pretty damp,” he added lamely.

Professor McGonagall sighed. “Please make your way to the Great Hall,” she said. “I need to meet the First Years.”

Harry nodded and led his friends past the Deputy Headmistress into the Great Hall. He could still see some students milling around the Hufflepuff table, several with wands out, but there was no sign of Peeves. The Great Hall itself was decked out as usual for the start-of-term feast. The light from the floating candles glinted off of the golden plates… though a few candles over the Hufflepuff table looked like they’d been snuffed out. As Harry watched, they sparked and re-lit. Harry glanced at the head table and wondered if they did that on their own. Professor Dumbledore and most of the staff were already sitting down, though Professor Sprout looked like she was still settling into her chair. Professor Lupin, caught his eye and nodded.

“Hiya Harry!” Colin Creevey called from the Gryffindor table as they approached.

“Hello Colin,” Harry said. Colin’s hero-worship could be a bit wearing at times, but he was, with some less than subtle encouragement, getting a handle on it. Still, he was tolerable in moderate doses, and Harry hadn’t seen him all summer. Besides, he felt he sort of owed a little extra leniency to anyone who was in the original Dumbledore’s Army.

“Guess what! My brother Dennis is starting this year,” the mousy-haired boy announced.

“That’s great!” Harry replied.

“Do you think he’ll get sorted into Gryffindor?” Colin asked. “I’m really hoping he’ll be here with us.” He paused for a moment and turned to Ron. “Brothers usually end up in the same house, right?”

Ron paused as he was sitting down. “Er, I suppose so,” he said after a moment. “It worked out that way for us.”

“But not always,” Hermione chimed in. “Parvati’s sister is in Ravenclaw, and they were twins.”

Hearing her name, the Gryffindor in question looked up from her conversation with Lavender Brown. “Padma and I are only the same in looks,” she declared. “Personality-wise, well, she’s a good fit in Ravenclaw, while I’m a lot more sociable.”

Harry saw Colin’s brow furrow. He couldn’t tell if it was worry or unaccustomed introspection. “We’ll just have to see what the Sorting Hat thinks,” Harry gently reminded him, “It’s been doing this for centuries. I think we can trust it to do right by him.”

Colin smiled. “You’re right Harry, thanks!” he gushed. Harry nodded and finally sat down.

It wasn’t long before Professor McGonagall led the thoroughly bedraggled first years into the Great Hall, including the tiny boy Harry was pretty sure was Dennis Creevey. His guess was confirmed when the boy, wrapped in what appeared to be Hagrid’s moleskin coat, waved at Colin and mouthed, “I fell in the lake!” with evident delight. It bothered Harry just a little bit that he didn’t immediately recognize the boy.

Harry concentrated as the Sorting Hat began its song, but he couldn’t recall enough of the lyrics from the original timeline to determine if they had changed. He wondered why his memories seemed to be fading. Was it some side effect of the merger? Was it because he was changing things so they couldn’t happen as before – was he somehow eroding the original timeline that only seemed to exist in his borrowed memories? It was a profoundly troubling train of thought – even more so because he wasn’t sure which was preferable.

If he thought about his future self as a separate person, like he’d appeared in that first dream, it seemed like a damn poor reward for the extraordinary lengths the haunted man had gone to in order to make Harry’s life better. Well, to be honest, he hadn’t really done it for Harry’s sake – he’d done it for everyone else. Maybe Harry could honour that sacrifice by making the most of the advantages he’d been granted.

Harry sighed as the song continued. When he arrived at Hogwarts his first year, he felt more like he was his future self, operating inside a younger body. Now, he realized it was more like he was that Harry, only with some added memories and an inflamed corpus magi. He found this more than a little disturbing, and thought back to when this transition occurred. As best he could tell, it started happening after second year. Maybe it had something to do with finally being able to tell his friends? He wondered if he’d ever know for sure.

Harry shook his head as the song concluded and the sorting began. He needed to pay at least a little attention or people would start to wonder. He clapped with the others as Dennis Creevey was sorted into Gryffindor. No surprise there. Neither was Colin pointing Harry out to his brother.

Desperate for distraction, Harry focused on watching Ron fidget as the sorting dragged on. Every time he whispered for them to get on with it, Hermione silenced him with a sharp look. Harry’s amusement grew until, right after Graham Pritchard was sorted into Slytherin, a hollow growl seemed to echo from the vicinity of Ron’s midsection. Harry suppressed a snicker as Ron flushed and Hermione rolled her eyes. Luna, of course, immediately began looking around for the Bordellian Kroogah, as she’d just heard the Kroogah mating call. Ron slouched a little lower in his seat.

Fortunately, it wasn’t too much longer before the sorting was completed. Professor Dumbledore rose to his feet. “I have only two words to say to you,” he announced, “Tuck in.”

With that, the tables filled with food. Ron filled his plate and fell upon it like a hungry lion, so to speak.

Once they were fed and the tables were cleared, Professor Dumbledore began his start of year announcements. After reviewing Filch’s list of banned objects and warning everyone about the Forbidden Forest, he dropped the bombshell regarding the Quidditch Cup being cancelled that year.

Harry carefully aped an appropriate expression of shock and disappointment. He didn’t want to cause any issues for Mr. Weasley if someone thought he’d disclosed Ministry information prematurely.

“This is due to an event,” Professor Dumbledore continued, “beginning in October and continuing throughout the school year that will occupy much of the teachers’ time and energy. However, I am sure you will all enjoy it immensely. I have great pleasure in announcing that this year at Hogwarts, we will be hosting the Triwizard Tournament!”

There was a murmur of surprise from the assembled students.

“For those that are not familiar with this event,” Dumbledore said, his voice rising above the noise, which cut off as he drew everyone’s attention again, “the Triwizard Tournament was first established some seven hundred years ago as a friendly competition between the three largest European schools of wizardry: Hogwarts, Beauxbatons, and Durmstrang. A champion was selected to represent each school, and the three champions competed in three magical tasks.”

Everything was as Harry could recall, but the explanation was suddenly cut off as the main doors to the Great Hall were thrown open. Harry spun in confusion, wondering why Mad-Eye was here, but the retired Auror was not who strode into the room.

There was a man and woman, both looking rather damp, flanked by a pair of Aurors in their distinctive brown trench coats. The man, who looked to be in his 40’s with a salt and pepper goatee, was not anyone Harry knew. He wished the same could be said for the woman.

Dolores Umbridge was just as Harry remembered, only now the toad-like woman was wrapped in a cloak that ranged from a dusky pink at the top to a muddy brown at the hem. Harry wondered for a moment why his memories of the foul woman were still as vivid as ever. Maybe it was the sheer loathing he held for the woman.

Dumbledore, on the other hand, didn’t miss a beat. “Ah, Mister Throckmorton, I was just telling the students of our big event this year.”

“Yes,” the man replied brusquely, “I’m sure they are quite thrilled. However, something quite urgent was brought to my attention that I think we need to speak upon at your earliest convenience.” He glanced around the Great Hall. “I see now why there was no response from your Floo, but if you would indulge me…?”

Dumbledore peered at them over the lenses of his spectacles. “Very well. Students, the delegations from the other schools will be arriving on October thirtieth. Please make them welcome. Students that wish to participate may enter their names at that time, and they will be selected by an impartial judge on the thirty-first. Further details will be made available as the time comes. Remember, classes begin tomorrow, so off with you now. Chop chop!”

As the students rose to leave, Harry’s eyes lingered on the visitors from the Ministry. With Umbridge involved, this couldn’t be good.

Appendix 1

G for Ginevra

by Peach Wookiee

Hello, fans of the man with the Lightning Scar! It has been some time since I’ve written for this fandom, but thanks to a fellow author here, I finally have a story to tell. I had to get S’TarKan’s permission for this tale and I thank him so much for granting it to me. This tale takes place in the first timeline of S’TarKan’s excellent tale, “Harry Potter and the Nightmares of Futures Past”.

Remember, remember the Fifth of November,

The Diagon Alley plot.

That the Twin Weasleys Mister

Avenged their sweet sister,

Will never be forgot.

It was the fourth of November 1998 when the Death Eaters finally began their siege on London. A few days previously, the citizens of Diagon Alley had barricaded themselves from what they knew was coming. The explosions of the Ministry of Magic, Parliament and so many other places had shaken Muggle and magical person alike. Those who were magical protected themselves within a place that the Death Eaters would hopefully ignore. However, the hope was extinguished as the sun set. Shopkeepers quickly took up their wands and began firing at the hordes of masked men and women that fired through the barriers.

“There is no escape,” came a magically magnified voice from the masked legion. “If you value your lives, you will surrender now! Do not act as those foolish children did at Hogwarts. Lay down your wands and join us!” Silence for a moment, and then his dying cry echoed through the Alley as a wand blast from one of the buildings took him down. The blasts that followed were heard all over Muggle London.

As the fighting grew worse, buildings shook and the rubble and bodies mounted. Civilians and what remained of the tattered Ministry of Magic fought valiantly against the masked horde, but it was becoming clear that the resistance would not last much longer.

The bells of a nearby clock tower rang over the combatants that remained. And in a bright purple building, decorated with a giant man in a magic top hat, his large arm blown off by an earlier blast, two redheaded young men lay on the floor. Oh, they weren’t hiding from the Death Eaters out of fear, but instead were making certain that their plan would not fail.

“That’s the last of them, brother of mine,” Fred Weasley whispered to his twin, George. They were identical right down to the last freckle, though at the moment Fred sported a gash on his face that George did not.

“Excellent, Fred. And now, brother of mine, shall we do this?”

“We shall,” Fred replied with a somewhat wicked grin. “The phonograph is ready. Still can’t believe we rigged this up with such short notice!”

“Yeah.” George smirked, though deep inside himself, his stomach twisted a little.

“I know,” Fred whispered back as if he could sense his brother’s gastric complaint. “It’ll work, brother of mine. At least…”

“…we go out the way we came in,” George finished.

“With a bang?”

“Indeed,” George answered, again managing a smile. “Though Lee’s cousin deserves thanks for lending us those Alan Moore comics, yeah?”

The twins clasped hands. “For Ginny?”

“For Ginny.” And together they tapped their wands on a large pink coat button.

Outside, the Death Eaters continued shooting, attempting to decimate what remained of Diagon Alley’s defenses. “All right, everyone! Their forces are nearly gone! Let’s finish this!” shouted their commander. As they strode through the wreckage, some of the Death Eaters heard what sounded like the clanging of church bells and the racing of bows over violin strings. Many of them, raised by pureblood-obsessive families did not recognize the piece of music, written by a Russian Muggle in the late nineteenth century. However, a few Death Eaters did recognize it and tried to shout warnings to their colleagues, but it was far too late.

A huge explosion and fireball consumed Number One Diagon Alley and then several explosions rang out, debris flying everywhere. And then as the music played on, several more buildings exploded, trapping the Death Eaters. But the final explosion was centred at Number 93. Fred and George held each other’s hands as the first bang sounded from the ground floor. And then all was fire and noise which mercifully took them in seconds. Outside, however, the Death Eaters not killed in the earlier explosions were caught in the final conflagration. Some were thrown a thousand feet away to be smashed against what buildings remained. Others were shredded by shrapnel. By the time the final explosion had died down, nearly every Death Eater lay dead. Though the Second Wizarding War would rage on and Diagon Alley was lost, Ginevra Molly Weasley had been avenged.

The End